<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:58:23 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>F1 title contender Oscar Piastri non-committal about helping Lando Norris win in Abu Dhabi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/oscar-piastri-and-lando-norris-in-abu-dhabi-grand-prix/106104724</link><description>Oscar Piastri dodges the question of whether he might help Lando Norris lift the world F1 title in Abu Dhabi, saying McLaren has not discussed the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7501564d8239c082852e90c9916d0fe5</guid></item><item><title>What time is the F1 Abu Dhabi Grand Prix and how to watch Oscar Piastri in championship race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/how-to-watch-f1-abu-dhabi-grand-prix-oscar-piastri-championship/105995180</link><description>The Formula 1 world drivers' championship has gone down to the wire, with three drivers set to battle it out for glory at the season-finale Abu Dhabi Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efcb0dbe407a7ea6832e9d01bc0a6e0f</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 6: The day scientists found evidence of water on Mars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/today-in-history-december-6-water-on-mars/106096326</link><description>Scientists said at the time that the flow of water would have filled multiple swimming pools.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">054766de87b60e22cc18569655b05e35</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri misses first practice at Abu Dhabi Grand Prix, finishes 11th in second session behind Lando Norris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-06/piastri-struggles-as-norris-leads-abu-dhabi-f1-practice/106109968</link><description>Lando Norris makes the best start of the title contenders in practice at the Abu Dhabi Grand Prix as Oscar Piastri endures a disappointing day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b2daef87913249292dfa8fdb35ccd6e</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri qualifies third for Abu Dhabi F1 Grand Prix, behind rivals Max Verstappen and Lando Norris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/piastri-only-third-verstappen-takes-pole-for-f1-finale-abu-dhabi/106111500</link><description>Oscar Piastri warns he's not out of the Formula One title hunt yet, even if many only now have eyes on a Lando Norris-Max Verstappen duel for the crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d778222828df96a3c4c0c6798717f29</guid></item><item><title>Concerns for the future of Canberra's public pools amid closures and redevelopments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/canberra-public-pool-lovers-concerned-about-future/106110222</link><description>As temperatures soar, advocates of public pools in Canberra say they want to see greater support and investment for facilities in the national capital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4eb3e09e4377b3f87e10776d2cb6cf95</guid></item><item><title>Where Oscar Piastri lost the Formula 1 world championship, McLaren teammate Lando Norris claims ultimate prize</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/oscar-piastri-missed-f1-world-title-through-minor-moments/106113184</link><description>Oscar Piastri missed out on winning the Formula 1 drivers world championship by just 13 points to his teammate Lando Norris, the culmination of multiple small moments throughout the season that cost him dearly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb082e3701f1fe8b29d4db1328f26f4e</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri praised as future formula 1 world champion by rivals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/oscar-piastri-praised-as-future-formula-1-world-champion/106113274</link><description>Oscar Piastri's chief rival, new formula 1 world champion Lando Norris, says the Australian will "get the better of me" after their tension-filled title race decider in Abu Dhabi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bdac8d42b6f4d2a864e6f566e20a472</guid></item><item><title>Rare brain illness could not stop Milly from making country netball history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/milly-brock-tongala-netball-encephalitis/106098456</link><description>A rare brain illness left Milly Brock unable to walk or speak, but eight months later, she was back leading her regional netball club on grand final day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">821bba383f0020f9d6f99b0b9a15f322</guid></item><item><title>Trump's quietly released national security document didn't escape Europe's attention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/donald-trump-foreign-policy-national-security-strategy-europe/106136354</link><description>When the White House quietly released its national security strategy late one night last week, it instead seemed to get lost in other news. Except, perhaps, in Europe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a638ba1f7a2b1556fc4a3782ee5651f1</guid></item><item><title>Iron deficiency is a challenge for many female athletes, like Super Netball's Zara Walters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/zara-walters-victorian-institute-of-sport-iron-deficiency/106108280</link><description>Zara Walters felt tired, dizzy and unable to recover from training sessions — then she found out she was low in iron. It's a condition that often goes undiagnosed, especially in female athletes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ee03bad452a9f38b43e0a5a4d93185d</guid></item><item><title>ASIO examined Bondi Beach gunman Naveed Akram in 2019 for close ties to Islamic State cell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-beach-attack-gunmen-father-and-son/106142630</link><description>Australia's domestic intelligence agency, ASIO, examined one of the Bondi Beach gunmen six years ago for his close ties to a Sydney-based Islamic State terrorism cell, the ABC understands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61d8702038585ef6be9d3817b6662640</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting gunman Naveed Akram was follower of pro-Islamic State preacher Wisam Haddad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/video-shows-bondi-beach-shooting-gunman-preaching-islam-to-teens/106145626</link><description>At least one of the gunmen who killed 15 people in Sunday's Bondi Beach terrorist attack was known to authorities as a follower of a notorious Sydney pro-Islamic State cleric, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b52ae302a33646b87014607b9cbabe0e</guid></item><item><title>Farmers' Facebook group racks up 100,000 followers as they seek support across seasons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/australian-farmers-harvesting-the-crop-facebook-group/106143522</link><description>A group dedicated to Australian grain farming created more than a decade ago has just cracked 100,000 followers with about 20,000 people following from overseas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45bd01ef5eb6e271490a8f818c46382c</guid></item><item><title>Sisters in Sweat — the Sunday football session that grew a sporting movement of over 15,000 Indian women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/sisters-in-sweat-football-movement-without-judgement/106099240</link><description>Eight years ago, Swetha Subbiah was asked to run a single football session for a friend. She ended up starting a sporting movement, which now has 15,000 women and girls as members across Bengaluru, Mumbai, Hyderabad and Delhi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed9651ef82e6b78ef579a015ead48f9c</guid></item><item><title>Despite warnings from Donald Trump, the push for Israeli control over the West Bank continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/push-inside-israel-to-annex-west-bank-approve-settlements/106171756</link><description>Despite US President Donald Trump's objections to the annexation of the West Bank, new settlement projects are approved, with some Israelis excited while Palestinians are left fearful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a926996550c67c96a2815d6df973734</guid></item><item><title>Runner Nancy Dickman, 83, prepares for her next marathon at 90</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/83yo-runner-nancy-dickman-preparing-for-her-next-marathon/106027164</link><description>Nancy Dickman has run marathons in London, New York, Rome and Sydney, and at 83 shows no signs of slowing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ce23e10ca9dfe12fea5638e3ceed667</guid></item><item><title>WA farming community loses 500 sheep, thousands of hectares of crops in fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/western-australian-farming-community-loses-500-sheep-in-fires/106153256</link><description>A bushfire emergency in Warradarge is over, but farmers say the work to recover what was lost has only just begun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80cdd9268fb9fd905e22ffb4920dd350</guid></item><item><title>Swan Hill tobacco shop rammed in failed firebomb attempt as tobacco wars continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/tobacco-shop-rammed-failed-firebomb-attempt-after-note-left/106184112</link><description>A tobacco shop is rammed with a vehicle weeks after receiving a shakedown note demanding the owner "contact the commission".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac7192d468ef920243fe742bbbb7643e</guid></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani sworn in as NYC mayor with midnight subway oath</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/zohran-mamdani-sworn-in-as-nyc-mayor-with-midnight-subway-oath/106192224</link><description>Zohran Mamdani is officially sworn in as major of New York City in a midnight, underground ceremony, with a more public affair to take place in hours time on the steps of City Hall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6014b207fdfdf1b13807a2bb5a8552b</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro held in New York prison described as 'hell on earth'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nicol%C3%A1s-maduro-in-the-new-york-metropolitan-detention-center/106199184</link><description>The facility where detained Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro has been taken is a notorious New York jail that has held a string of high-profile and celebrity criminals, from drug cartel leaders to hip-hop stars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">784a697b58d4fb284175a75608400421</guid></item><item><title>Ousted Venezuelan leader Nicolás Maduro and wife Cilia Flores plead not guilty in New York court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/venezuelan-leader-nicol%C3%A1s-maduro-appears-in-new-york-court/106201846</link><description>Nicolás Maduro and Cilia Flores, who were captured in Caracas at the weekend, face multiple drugs and weapons charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">893a666a98bd976fe476ea782d0fed9e</guid></item><item><title>Sixth man charged after livestock carrier allegedly used for cocaine drop in WA waters off Lancelin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/sixth-man-charged-over-alleged-livestock-carrier-cocaine-plot/106216218</link><description>A sixth man is charged over an alleged plot to import half a tonne of cocaine into Western Australia using an international livestock carrier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b13f0fc413d246d59124f501cd43ee40</guid></item><item><title>Australia wins World Cross Country Championships relay gold after Jessica Hull's anchor leg</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/australia-wins-cross-country-gold-medal-mixed-relay/106217508</link><description>Olympic medallist Jessica Hull guides Australia home in the mixed relay event at the world titles in Florida.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a06bfe83793d80a6ae82ba788f25bd13</guid></item><item><title>Former A-League player Josh Cavallo alleges Adelaide United was homophobic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/josh-cavallo-calls-out-adelaide-united/106222918</link><description>Australia's first openly gay male professional footballer, Josh Cavallo, has alleged his former club was homophobic, something it denies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e747ee180a4fff3d7cfcf815ca7067f</guid></item><item><title>SpaceX capsule begins return to Earth from International Space Station with sick astronaut on board</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/capsule-return-earth-international-space-station-sick-astronaut/106231168</link><description>The Crew Dragon capsule has undocked from the International Space Station carrying four astronauts, one of whom has a "serious medical condition", and is on its way back to Earth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d25be9004e38cad26b2fb726a3d2942c</guid></item><item><title>World champion Shelley Taylor-Smith runs swim group for women at Mettams Pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/world-champion-shelley-taylor-smith-runs-swim-group/106233342</link><description>They call themselves the "Sea Shells Teabaggers" — and with marathon swimmer Shelley Taylor-Smith at the helm, this ocean swim group has built something much stronger than good technique.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88fe7e0aea361e5c54721018e20ef4fc</guid></item><item><title>Sam Short's small leap to ocean swimming and the prospect of more Australian success in 2032</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/sam-short-to-swim-open-water-nationals/106232346</link><description>Sam Short will take on the country's best open water swimmers at the Australian Nationals this week, with a possible new event for Brisbane 2032 opening new opportunities for Australian gold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05aff475351925220d9e9ae9bf434b24</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Police seize firearms, drugs in Townsville bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/queensland-police-seize-firearms-drugs-in-townsville-bust/106244838</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a2c4c7945220150fcc8231b476b56cd</guid></item><item><title>Four arrested as Queensland Police seize guns, kilos of drugs in Townsville</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/townsville-police-arrest-guns-drugs-trafficking/106244526</link><description>Police find 100kg cannabis, 8kg of methamphetamine and 1kg of cocaine as well as illegal firearms hidden in bush at a Townsville property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecd99c93b49491f432b2888450905a34</guid></item><item><title>Crime gangs restocking shops 'up to 10 times a day' with illegal cigarettes and vapes, WA police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/behind-the-scenes-of-wa-s-illegal-tobacco-business-model/106252960</link><description>WA's police commissioner says the restocking is happening faster than authorities can seize the products, as tobacco black market violence escalates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c85e3ad402b68eddf68bb31ca5929a65</guid></item><item><title>Fiji police allegedly seize $780m cocaine shipment in drug operation targeting Pacific Ocean 'narco sub'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/fiji-vatia-alleged-cocaine-bust/106252766</link><description>Fijian chiefs reported suspicious activity along their stretch of coastline to law enforcement agencies — which then swooped on an alleged $780 million drug operation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7b65c9bfdd418c9e913eeb19db1490c</guid></item><item><title>To Lam wins second term to rule Vietnam through 2030</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/vietnam-to-lam-reelected-second-term-rule-2030/106263924</link><description>Vietnam's leader To Lam has been re-appointed as head of the ruling Communist Party for the next five years, and pledges to turbocharge growth in the export-reliant nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9955cc5f187fbcce22b63cc8db6f3dcd</guid></item><item><title>Majority of NSW beaches shut amid shark attacks to reopen for Australia Day long weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/nsw-beaches-to-reopen-for-australia-day-after-shark-attacks/106261374</link><description>Heatwave conditions and Australia Day long weekend activities are expected to draw crowds back to the water after a dangerous 48 hours on the New South Wales coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b26028194206b86204ce55f677e9d46</guid></item><item><title>A generation of activists like Grace Oo are taking up arms against Myanmar's military</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/taking-up-arms-against-myanmar-military/106252216</link><description>As Myanmar's military junta seeks international legitimacy through elections, its brutal repression of the pro-democracy movement is radicalising a new generation of activists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72a427ab5a1dcc938b3234c3d5fc1407</guid></item><item><title>Woman discovers Holocaust descendants through DNA testing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/australian-woman-dna-test-family-tree-jewish-holocaust/106252638</link><description>Adriana Turk grew up believing there were no survivors on her Jewish father's side after World War II, but a DNA test showed that was not the case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cff4f7c21a5e88d8d950ff7583a128cc</guid></item><item><title>David Speirs sees 'pathway' to standing for election amid eligibility questions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/david-speirs-pathway-to-election-amid-eligibility-questions/106281982</link><description>Former South Australian Liberal leader David Speirs says there is a way he could stand for the upcoming state election — but is yet to declare whether he will — despite the electoral commission declaring he is ineligible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fae2aef5067464d9cc7ec98c01ec275</guid></item><item><title>Coalition chaos drags on ahead of first official sitting week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/coalition-pauline-hanson-liberals-nationals-one-nation/106278234</link><description>Former prime minister John Howard once observed that Pauline Hanson was an "electoral gift to the Labor Party". His words proved relevant this week as the Coalition's chaos dragged on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e55fe948ed9cac9dfbe249d4a750510</guid></item><item><title>Queensland farm cashing in on US wellness industry demand for camel milk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/farmers-celebrate-us-interest-in-queensland-camel-milk/106283200</link><description>Camel milk is in hot demand in the wellness industry, now one Queensland farmer is seizing the moment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">441b865e5599c229e2ffa3008cb77db4</guid></item><item><title>Genetically modified purple tomatoes bound for fruit shops after regulator approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/gm-purple-tomato-approved-for-australian-growth-and-sale/106262696</link><description>The purple tomato was altered to make it taste better and boost nutrition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5bd1ac2234b9c2c680495f600b02f6f</guid></item><item><title>Beckham saga is an age-old heartache with an uncomfortably modern twist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/virginia-trioli-template/106252054</link><description>Cutting ties with your parents isn't a new phenomenon but having it painstakingly documented across social media is a contemporary problem.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab0df9a75b077d3b19090787e9d7ff93</guid></item><item><title>Bruny Island to get childcare solution but too late for the Archers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/bruny-island-to-get-childcare-solution/106290778</link><description>After fighting for years for a childcare solution for her community, Teisha Archer says the news it will be happening is "wonderful" — but will come too late to help her and others in her situation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29b0eedaed503b8b897f5fcf5c6433ba</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar election won by military-backed party in widely condemned poll marred by violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/myanmar-election-won-by-military-backed-usdp-party/106290376</link><description>The military's political party wins the vote in a result regarded as a forgone conclusion, with critics arguing threats and violence forced people to the ballot box in a country wracked by civil war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4d99c203ab0a5661b5ba91b73c4e306</guid></item><item><title>Inside the brand strategy behind the Beckham family drama — and who controls the narrative now</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/inside-the-brand-strategy-behind-the-beckham-family-drama/106284834</link><description>In a modern crisis, experts say control doesn't always come from speaking louder — but from knowing when, where and how briefly to speak at all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02c12da6214ed41b16eafa530a0cd912</guid></item><item><title>Clive Palmer rejects Steve Bannon influence claim in latest Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/palmer-denies-bannon-claim-of-election-campaign-influence/106293074</link><description>Clive Palmer denies newly surfaced claims that his 2019 federal election campaign was influenced by a senior advisor to US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c9c965c6b8ceddec345b1fe91952665</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic drops retirement hint, suggests 2026 could be his final Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/australian-open-novak-djokovic-hints-2026-could-be-his-last/106293450</link><description>Novak Djokovic did not go into detail on what he meant, nor did he confirm a plan to retire this year, but he chose his words carefully on centre court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55495032c4ad20750eb9060adf5c00fd</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic praises Carlos Alcaraz after Spaniard wins first Australian Open title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australian-open-carlos-alcaraz-novak-djokovic-final/106293372</link><description>Despite the hollow feeling of defeat, 24-time major winner Novak Djokovic heaps praise on Carlos Alcaraz following the Spaniard's history-making Australian Open victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87c4c2aa20dbeaeb5ed2b49f3037427b</guid></item><item><title>From Sabalenka to Djokovic and 'animals in the zoo', here are the best quotes from the Australian Open 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australian-open-2026-best-quotes/106291648</link><description>From tennis stars pushing for more privacy, to Djokovic saying he feels like an old man and a Kyrgios F-bomb, there have been some funny and weird quotes at this year's Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">092b0db1619ef3d506d5e88441d9fb8c</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Cam Myers becomes youngest ever winner of Wanamaker Mile indoor race in New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/cam-myers-wins-wanamaker-mile-new-york/106296836</link><description>Australia's Cam Myers becomes the youngest ever winner of the prestigious Wanamaker Mile, with the 19-year-old powering to victory in New York.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fe231aa9ecc5e5875525ccd47c21618</guid></item><item><title>ACT election data suggests neither Liberal nor Greens voters would want a coalition between the parties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/act-election-voter-data-greens-liberals-coalition/106294870</link><description>Greens voters overwhelmingly preference Labor over the Liberal Party across the country — and a look at the data from the 2024 ACT election suggests there's no reason to think that would be different in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53db3562aaf24beff1f311b356101d70</guid></item><item><title>More children suffering serious injuries on e-scooters, study shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/e-scooters-study-shows-more-children-suffering-serious-injuries/106295844</link><description>Between 2021 and 2024, e-scooter injury-related admissions at Queensland Children's Hospital more than doubled, the study found, with young boys accounting for three-quarters of admissions, with a median age of 13.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5055ed40c45ecede451d30dca9739b8e</guid></item><item><title>Belinda Bencic and Elina Svitolina make history as two mothers sit in WTA top 10 for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/belinda-bencic-elina-svitolina-wta-top-10-ranking-mothers/106298230</link><description>For the first time in women's tennis, two mothers are ranked inside the world's top 10 simultaneously.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e8a5c61f4dab9ec33ffdbe9458a4894</guid></item><item><title>Formula 1 driver Jack Doohan signs with Haas as reserve driver after leaving Alpine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/australian-f1-driver-jack-doohan-joins-haas-after-leaving-alpine/106302540</link><description>Former Alpine racer Jack Doohan signed with Haas as a reserve driver for the 2026 Formula 1 season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c6e6f34f5a9d7dddf2670f39f8be255</guid></item><item><title>Greens link Hospitality Tasmania's donations to Liberals to pokies card demise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/tasmanian-greens-question-hospitality-bodys-donations/106301766</link><description>The Tasmanian Greens have accused the state's peak hospitality group and the Liberal Party of a "political stitch-up" to kill off the proposed mandatory pokies card, after hundreds of thousands of dollars in donations were revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">838eaf69d7c4524d7958123e9e02f240</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds eye timely glimpse of Jamaica in Test series ahead of Commonwealth Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/diamonds-eye-timely-glimpse-of-jamaica-in-test-series/106304506</link><description>Australia's netballers expect to gain precious intelligence ahead of a showpiece tournament when they host Jamaica in a three-Test series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">535538818f21f4d078ae5407fa58b3bd</guid></item><item><title>Police lecture teen caught driving 189km/h on Sunshine Motorway at midnight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/police-teen-midnight-189kmh-sunshine-motorway-mountain-creek/106304564</link><description>The teenager on his P-plates was pulled over by police along a Sunshine Coast motorway driving at almost 200km/h.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">472c3c0a3258dde9fc72c9927268faec</guid></item><item><title>K'gari traditional owners hold smoking ceremony for Piper James on beach where she died</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/kgari-traditional-owners-hold-smoking-ceremony-for-piper-james/106283182</link><description>K'gari traditional owners have held a smoking ceremony for Piper James, who died on the island last month, to give her spirit a safe passage home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5195525635f75c9bb6c42ce2a24571ea</guid></item><item><title>Democrat victory in Republican stronghold could spell trouble for Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/texas-special-runoff-election-results/106308914</link><description>The US has been gripped by cold weather in recent weeks, but pundits say it is in Texas where hell has truly frozen over. A blue wave just swept a GOP stronghold, and Republicans are very worried.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e651758ff0d99631704edb4c046d58f8</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri defends McLaren and says he expects 'fair shot' at F1 title in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/oscar-piastri-defends-mclaren-expects-fair-shot-at-f1-title/106312458</link><description>Oscar Piastri insists the painful ending to his F1 title bid last season has only strengthened his resolve to be the "nice person" who brings the Formula 1 world drivers' crown back to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f69e6d4d4fe6ae4def48a780606469e8</guid></item><item><title>French authorities sink tonnes of cocaine bound for Australia, then release suspects</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/french-authorities-sink-five-tonnes-of-cocaine/106307438</link><description>French authorities intercept a ship carrying five tonnes of cocaine bound for Australia, before releasing the vessel and its crew.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9429ea7a44b7fd6eb152b561ab54a17</guid></item><item><title>The easiest way to clean your microwave and a common mistake to avoid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/what-is-the-best-way-to-clean-a-microwave/106307346</link><description>When was the last time you cleaned your microwave? According to experts, it's actually a lot simpler than cleaning other appliances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b708e459302ab8131d3d781a896a62ad</guid></item><item><title>Golden bandicoot numbers triple at Newhaven Wildlife Sanctuary in Central Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/golden-bandicoot-population-triples-newhaven-wildlife-sanctuary/106280368</link><description>A population of threatened golden bandicoots is booming at Newhaven Wildlife Sanctuary, north-west of Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">127ab3e60e9dc2ca6cffb951c58e803e</guid></item><item><title>Trump endorses Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi ahead of Japan's election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/trump-endorses-japan-pm-takaichi-ahead-of-sunday-election/106317102</link><description>One of Sanae Takaichi's first engagements after she was elevated to prime minister in October was to host Donald Trump in Tokyo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f8f972cb70cce67dc98a1070d0a9d46</guid></item><item><title>The moment turtle Terry was released from Sydney Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/the-moment-turtle-terry-was-released-from-sydney-harbour/106317662</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49c7dbf6c3e6b92b9cc8ad7b4bef2adc</guid></item><item><title>How the Liberals will justify Sussan Ley's ousting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/sussan-ley-liberals-coalition-leadership-spill-angus-taylor/106295860</link><description>A permission structure has been crafted for Liberals to ditch the first woman to lead the federal party room before she has even had a year in the role.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bc84b8c3a351135cabe86c86fa06316</guid></item><item><title>After the uprising, Bangladesh returns to the ballot with its wounds still open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/bangladesh-returns-to-the-ballot-with-its-wounds-still-open/106296274</link><description>Bangladesh is heading back to the ballot box in what is being billed as its first free and fair election in more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8836801d915258a766ff8ef0bd45738e</guid></item><item><title>Heat and fires expose ancestral remains in Victoria's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/heat-fires-expose-ancestral-remains-in-victorian-mallee/106304308</link><description>Ancestral remains that could be thousands of years old have been uncovered by erosion, dust storms and bushfires in Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49ce14146e6918e7cee89f1e59175fb2</guid></item><item><title>Piper James's parents say dingo management reform needed to prevent further deaths on K'gari</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/piper-james-parents-call-for-more-dingo-warnings-on-kgari/106317706</link><description>Piper James's parents are leaving Australia with their daughter's ashes and a determination to ensure she hasn't died in vain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ccf19d954997c8989ad2001fd781236</guid></item><item><title>One Nation capitalises on anti-immigration sentiment in a housing crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/one-nation-pauline-hanson-housing-crisis-immigration/106304670</link><description>Pauline Hanson might not have any substantive policies, but her rhetoric about reducing migration is clearly finding an audience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23968ca9459afcd8c2cf60c2582e68d7</guid></item><item><title>Japan PM Sanae Takaichi leads coalition to landslide election victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/japan-election-sanae-takaichi-landslide-victory/106320228</link><description>Sanae Takaichi's Liberal Democratic Party and its coalition partner are expected to hold upwards of two-thirds of the seats in Japan's lower house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fb71b428c5bbf7507c7f3ce7b77658c</guid></item><item><title>Thailand PM Anutin Charnvirakul confident of forming government after election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/thailand-election-result-anutin-results/106320270</link><description>South-East Asia's second-largest economy went to the polls on Sunday in a tight race between conservatives aligned with the military and the monarchy, and progressive elements represented by the reform-driven People's Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea445c2de3e44242cdf9e5b0f4e49cf0</guid></item><item><title>Kimberley cotton hits record high in first season with new processing gin in Kununurra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/kimberley-growers-wrap-up-first-season-processing-cotton-locally/106303718</link><description>From farm to fabric, West Australian cotton growers are finally able to grow, process and export record amounts of cotton locally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">463c2f3636108857669737fceede0d6c</guid></item><item><title>Mitchell Freeway head-on crash in Butler leaves two dead after ute driven on wrong side of road</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/two-people-dead-after-mitchell-freeway-butler-head-on-crash/106321408</link><description>A 56-year-old-woman and a 24-year-old man are dead after a head-on collision involving a utility that was being driven on the wrong side of the Mitchell Freeway in Perth's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366c71a2ba852d44551f4bb42a51335e</guid></item><item><title>Rain brings relief and road closures after record heatwave in South Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/rain-brings-relief-and-road-closures-in-outback-sa/106321082</link><description>High rainfall in north-eastern South Australia brings some relief for pastoralists after record-breaking heat, with a reprieve expected for metropolitan Adelaide this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8abb8433aa6e8a46aaa308bd29d9653</guid></item><item><title>ASIO was told about Bondi shooter's terrorist links years before attack, former spy claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/bondi-shooting-spy-claims-told-asio-terror-links-four-corners/106306092</link><description>The former undercover agent spied on the Akrams when he infiltrated a Sydney IS terror cell for Australia's intelligence agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38e7d75b35ff2d3c4a5b6be5b9bb9d73</guid></item><item><title>'Massive' Indonesian ghost barge washes up on tiny Torres Strait island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/mystery-indonesian-ghost-barge-washed-up-in-torres-strait/106323116</link><description>The barge drifted into Australian waters from Indonesia after breaking from its moorings during bad weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08b39ef063e5e2f00075ab3cf9dbea37</guid></item><item><title>Roblox on notice after 'disturbing' reports of child grooming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/government-puts-roblox-on-notice-reports-of-child-grooming/100020788</link><description>The government puts popular social gaming site Roblox on notice following media reports of children being approached and groomed by predators on the platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17bbfe956fe95675bddb65bf1b70eaed</guid></item><item><title>Native title holders take appeal over one of Australia's largest groundwater licences to High Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nt-high-court-singleton-station-aboriginal-groundwater-rights/106322626</link><description>The cultural value of water will be front and centre in the High Court in Canberra today as a group of native title holders from Central Australia fight to assert cultural rights over an aquifer under their lands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d334f651d8d34fed9db2b05f2f04adba</guid></item><item><title>Surgeon Kelvin Kong's life growing up Chinese and Indigenous in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/kelvin-kong-s-growing-up-chinese-and-indigenous-australia/106326388</link><description>Australia's first identified First Nations surgeon, Dr Kelvin Kong spoke about his Malaysian Chinese heritage during the annual Wang Gungwu lecture at Parliament House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3366e9b48200b228bb48ce12f315720</guid></item><item><title>Race against bulldozers to save ancient grass trees in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/race-to-save-grass-trees-south-west-wa/106323778</link><description>Some of WA's oldest grass trees are being rescued from land clearing and development amid a population and property boom, preserving a unique part of the South West's natural heritage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c035d16240b39fbe758a3a7788f5176</guid></item><item><title>100kg of cocaine allegedly hidden in timber found at Lismore and Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/men-charged-over-cocaine-allegedly-hidden-in-timber/106329936</link><description>Police in NSW and Queensland say an alleged cross-border criminal syndicate intended to extract $14 million worth of cocaine from four tonnes of timber.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d2e49f9e0a8a1ae5c6e0b3f1bdf6b4b</guid></item><item><title>Formula 1 2026: New engines and no DRS headline major changes in grand prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/formula-1-2026-new-engines-regulations-sprint-races/106325942</link><description>New engines, new regulations and an 11-team grid are just some of the changes in Formula 1 this season. Get up to speed with what is new in F1 ahead of the Australian Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fce942eea4fa4616a149450aa1c7158</guid></item><item><title>Cryptosporidium cluster at Waterworld leads to closure of Adelaide Aquatic Centre pools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/adelaide-aquatic-centres-close-after-cluster-of-gastro-cases/106330324</link><description>SA Health is urging people with gastroenteritis symptoms not to visit public swimming pools after eight cases at one swimming centre, including one child who was hospitalised and another who also visited the Adelaide Aquatic Centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">feaa7c2df6769e23acd9a68078708dfc</guid></item><item><title>Axed literary magazine Meanjin is resurrected by Queensland University of Technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/meanjin-magazine-finds-new-home-queensland-university-technology/106331850</link><description>The 85-year-old literary journal Meanjin will return to Brisbane, where it was first published, after it was controversially closed by Melbourne University Press last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8381f55200bc2cef76893ac168c73d93</guid></item><item><title>Bondi: Path to Terror</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/bondi-path-to-terror-four-corners/106332752</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3e3ec0c11f67bf60a856adfabe308d3</guid></item><item><title>Australian fans miss out on World Cup tickets as prices skyrocket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/world-cup-ticket-prices-aussie-fans-miss-out/106332736</link><description>A host of Australian fans will be denied the chance to watch the Socceroos World Cup campaign amid accusations of price gouging by FIFA as tickets to the tournament soar to astronomical prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cb80105f0eeb0984e8c6d7afad7d449</guid></item><item><title>Audio of Austin Appelbee's incredible Triple Zero call after marathon swim to save family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/audio-of-austin-appelbee-s-incredible-triple-zero-call-after-mar/106333512</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a07e12a8516d493dc30141c630813b8</guid></item><item><title>PM condemns 'white supremacy ideology' behind alleged Invasion Day terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/prime-minister-closing-the-gap-speech/106332998</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has condemned the "racism and hatred" and "white supremacy ideology" behind the alleged terrorist attack on the Invasion Day rally in Borloo/Perth last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e3643c30243d9459a9602b299a97cc4</guid></item><item><title>Lando Norris quickest on day one of F1 preseason test, Oscar Piastri drives well and Max Verstappen impresses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/f1-preseason-test-bahrain-norris-piastri-verstappen/106333906</link><description>McLaren's Formula 1 world champion Lando Norris was fastest on the first day of preseason testing in Bahrain, but Max Verstappen and Red Bull caught the attention with pace and plenty of laps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba0e6f82ba0e8d4236049cdf992c4cb9</guid></item><item><title>Baker Boy talks new album Djandjay, Riverboats festival and family legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/baker-boy-djandjay-album-riverboats-festival-racism-fresh-prince/106321578</link><description>The Yolŋu artist known as the Fresh Prince of Arnhem Land is the king of feel-good bilingual bangers. But heavy is the crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a7e4fe54da381b9b3169df148ff7976</guid></item><item><title>Labor releases audio of Liberal MP backtracking on $495 million cost of living policy at industry event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/labor-releases-audio-of-liberal-backtrack/106334676</link><description>South Australia's Treasurer says the Liberal Party has secretly dumped its major $495 million policy less than six weeks out from the state election, with the Opposition arguing it has to wind back Labor's tax due to state budget blowouts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41c94a52edb47ae2f974cc0fddf1c2cb</guid></item><item><title>Liberals' leadership machinations dominate the political week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/liberals-leadership-spill-angus-taylor-sussan-ley/106325872</link><description>The Liberals have spent the week embroiled in leadership woes as the party braces for a spill on Friday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">874320a6b150dbbf66b077e9b0f5d9b5</guid></item><item><title>New video shows violent arrest of Australian filmmaker James Ricketson at Sydney's anti-Herzog protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/video-shows-arrest-filmmaker-james-ricketson-sydney-protest/106337470</link><description>New video obtained by ABC NEWS Verify shows in vivid detail the arrest of a 76-year-old man, who was later released without charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8b85f342914cc4a1db8e8f827b072c</guid></item><item><title>Men face drug cultivation charges after $10 million cannabis bust in Victoria's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/men-face-commercial-drug-cultivation-charges-after-cannabis-bust/106338128</link><description>Police allege a drug bust in Victoria's north-west has uncovered 10 large grow houses cultivating $10 million worth of illegal cannabis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7d9fee7539b4a4ea68bd8031cfeac2b</guid></item><item><title>More than 100 Stolen Generations survivors gather for apology anniversary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/largest-gathering-of-stolen-generations-survivors-for-apology/106322950</link><description>More than 100 Stolen Generations survivors have gathered in Canberra for the apology anniversary. The government is pledging new money to help them heal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c81bef72da28cb61fb66cddb9bf13666</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen critical of new Formula 1 cars as preseason testing continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/max-verstappen-critical-of-new-formula-1-cars/106339508</link><description>Four-time Formula 1 world champion Max Verstappen says the 2026 cars are "not so fun", claiming the increasing energy management demands on drivers are "just not Formula 1".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">950bfbf36871e9c9d62401075e1fd446</guid></item><item><title>Keen to declutter this year? Here's how to start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/simple-ways-to-start-decluttering-at-home/106300708</link><description>Experts say you don't need to pull out the entire contents of a cupboard, beginning with one bag is best.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a8e041b72c037976f8eb5cb64a4f2a3</guid></item><item><title>Former Tottenham manager Ange Postecoglou says Spurs 'not a big club' in wake of Thomas Frank sacking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/former-tottenham-manager-ange-postecoglou-on-club-issues/106339490</link><description>Tottenham Hotspur are "not a big club" because of their policy in the transfer market, former manager Ange Postecoglou has said in the wake of the London club's sacking of head coach Thomas Frank on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ce56a4955c12cf141f86e6540834b3a</guid></item><item><title>Ley leaves Taylor an immediate electoral test with Farrer by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/farrer-byelection-sussan-ley-angus-taylor/106341236</link><description>Within two hours of being elected Liberal leader, Angus Taylor has already been delivered his first big electoral test, and it has come from the woman he deposed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a9957d8828440921d19f5f6180a2356</guid></item><item><title>AFL Origin 2026: Are footy fans still keen on interstate football?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/afl-origin-2026-history-of-interstate-football-state-of-origin/106341464</link><description>After a break of more than a quarter of a century, AFL State of Origin returns in Perth tomorrow with a battle between two proud football states, Western Australia and Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ac0aaab0d5f3f7f1e75b164d08b3c0e</guid></item><item><title>Bald Archy satirical art prize highlights political victories, a murder trial and protest movements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/bald-archy-prize-reveals-politics-crime-and-bob-irwin/106340644</link><description>From the trial of Erin Patterson to the landslide election victory, 2025 is pilloried in this year's satirical art prize, the Bald Archy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e360d2786aee3a4fd31acfa42d11981</guid></item><item><title>Maugean skate's endangered status not changing, Environment Minister Murray Watt says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/maugean-skate-endangered-listing-not-changing-murray-watt-says/106342278</link><description>Environment Minister Murray Watt says his decision to keep the status of a rare Tasmanian skate species as endangered rather than change it to critically endangered is based on scientific advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e900785b0c8d8f08f1f99a4eaf01e576</guid></item><item><title>Drug vessel MV Raider heading towards Sydney after being stripped of cocaine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/drug-vessel-mv-raider-sydney-bound-after-cocaine-seized/106337382</link><description>A ship caught carrying five tonnes of cocaine is making its way towards Sydney after being stripped of its cargo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62c02ce422ef3bc47452cda0114ef3d5</guid></item><item><title>Australia in danger of World Cup elimination after 'unbelievable' loss to Zimbabwe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cricket-australia-zimbabwe-t20-world-cup-live-blog-scores/106327068</link><description>Australia's hopes of advancing out of Group B are dealt an almighty blow as Zimbabwe claims one of the biggest upset wins in T20 World Cup history in Colombo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">476ca6531e7d6c07f466b52971129dba</guid></item><item><title>Sydney children's author Oliver Phommavanh jailed for sending sexually explicit messages to minors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/childrens-author-oliver-phommavanh-jailed-for-grooming-minors/106342160</link><description>Oliver Phommavanh is sentenced to six-and-a-half years in prison with a non-parole period of four years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c59431758c6b35c4dc27a1b4299ab7a8</guid></item><item><title>From Japan to Israel, elections are reshaping global politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/elections-japan-israel-ukraine-global-politics-trump/106337028</link><description>At a time when so much of the global conversation is about the rapid decline of democracy, it is striking what a huge impact elections are having on world events just now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bcebe10dbbdf738fed5ebfaac390428</guid></item><item><title>Michael Mohammed Ahmad confronts traumatic childhood abuse in his new novel, Bugger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/michael-mohammed-ahmad-new-book-bugger/106331764</link><description>Michael Mohammed Ahmad, author of The Lebs, marks turning 40 with the publication of his most confronting novel yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a057fc717dc6c9c31f1c40b18e69a8e</guid></item><item><title>Chickens help autistic teen Summer Farrelly make sense of humans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/chickens-help-summer-farrelly-understand-humans-autism-book/106308084</link><description>While growing up, people didn't make much sense to Summer, but chickens always did. Now, Summer is using what they learnt to help other children with autism understand human interactions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69b349a86894794e632c23899a5e2185</guid></item><item><title>What chickens can teach us about socialising.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/what-chickens-can-teach-us-about-socialising/106310344</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2649f1ee118f6ad2700c1b6be9107f2c</guid></item><item><title>Easy, tasty and nutritious recipes for sharing this Ramadan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/easy-tasty-and-nutritious-recipes-for-sharing-this-ramadan/106331120</link><description>Looking for easy, nutritious Ramadan recipes? These options will help you prepare for and break your fast well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb9d0165cd75c38640ee10f031f1d403</guid></item><item><title>Solo diver recounts brush with mako sharks off Tasmanian coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/diver-recounts-experience-with-mako-sharks-pulfers-reef/106307276</link><description>Phillip Ellis Wells was solo diving roughly 7 kilometres off the east coast of Tasmania when he noticed a shadow pass overhead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bf60fbc295b53fac0d5390d1a2f6c7f</guid></item><item><title>Innovative cattle loading ramp puts animal welfare at centre of design</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/wide-cattle-loading-ramp-reduces-transport-stress/106305408</link><description>A retired truck driver has developed a wide, steel, cattle-loading ramp that allows animals to walk side by side, mimicking natural herd behaviour and reducing noise, agitation and the risk of injury during transport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae83b1c62371e347cfe86622f6a1efe5</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri raises safety concerns ahead of F1 Australian Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/oscar-piastri-raises-safety-concerns-f1/106340156</link><description>Oscar Piastri has raised concerns about safety issues at the upcoming Australian Grand Prix, worried about potential chaos at the very start of the F1 season opener.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a19793fef3d4f087577e45c38422ab30</guid></item><item><title>Two women die in crash after police pursuit in Sydney's south-west as critical incident declared</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/two-die-man-arrested-in-camden-car-crash-after-police-pursuit/106345042</link><description>NSW Police say they pursued a red sedan after it had been stolen from a petrol station in South Hurstville and its owner allegedly assaulted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a6bcd2f85fbebbedf59cec9df86db23</guid></item><item><title>Easy ways to help protect your hair from chlorine and saltwater damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/how-to-avoid-chlorine-and-saltwater-hair-damage-when-swimming/106334202</link><description>Regular beach days or laps at the local pool can leave our hair looking and feeling quite different.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ed59e0b1894ab058082b567c448eb32</guid></item><item><title>AFL State of Origin coaches hail success of concept following Victoria's win over Western Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/afl-state-of-origin-coaches-hail-success-of-concept/106346486</link><description>Winning Victoria coach Chris Scott and his Western Australia counterpart Dean Cox call for State of Origin to be played every year after the concept's stunning return in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a2310e59675ad0bac9b0b865d9ebaef</guid></item><item><title>Townsville marathon swimmer crosses Cook Strait between NZ's South and North islands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/queensland-marathon-swimmer-crosses-cook-strait/106335994</link><description>Swimming in shark-infested waters across one of the most treacherous island crossings in the world was a challenge Townsville woman Liz Denyer could not pass up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1738aa6f290bcdbe2a076c44a027f8b1</guid></item><item><title>City of Melbourne quiet on plan for Southbank's 'ugly' red stairs, long after design competition announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/city-of-melbourne-southbank-red-stair-replacement-plan-stalls/106274362</link><description>A Melbourne council unveiled a lucrative competition to replace Southbank's much-derided red stairs. But a year after it was due to start, the plan appears to have gone nowhere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">074f26e344537a0ab6c98a25242c702d</guid></item><item><title>Australia defeated by India in opening T20 as Sophie Molineux era gets off to wobbly start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/australia-women-beaten-in-t20/106347920</link><description>Australia slumps to a rain-affected 21-run loss to India in their opening T20 at the SCG, after selectors opted to drop vice-captain Tahlia McGrath.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1d3ad1921ec592fc795d54bc3787c1b</guid></item><item><title>Future of fishing prosecutions unclear after multi-million-dollar abalone trafficking case collapses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/indigenous-fishing-prosecutions-future-unclear/106323308</link><description>Subpoenaed documents obtained by the ABC reveal NSW Police continued prosecuting seven men for illegally trafficking abalone despite advice that their case was likely to fail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed4fcebac968428222f50a2c0888f162</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners 'won't accept' handback of rehabilitated Argyle diamond mine site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/argyle-diamond-mine-closure-traditional-owner-concerns/106339850</link><description>East Kimberley traditional owners are concerned Rio Tinto's closure plan will leave them with "a giant hole in the ground forever".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">920c2b711109c2ab18519ecaf2822c30</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic type B killer whales seen for first time near WA's Bremer Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/visiting-orcas-steal-the-feed-of-local-killer-whales-in-wa/106345466</link><description>Sightings of Antarctic orcas in Australian waters are very rare. A tour group in WA saw what appeared to be a pod of Antarctic type B killer whales muscle in and steal the meal of a local group of orcas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39f109d1374dbb8d8c0891214ddd9157</guid></item><item><title>Maugean skate still faces 'catastrophic' risk from salmon farming, Commonwealth advice says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/maugean-skate-endangered-status-analysis/106348446</link><description>Official advice is unequivocal that salmon farming remains the main threat to the endangered Maugean skate. It remains to be seen if the federal environment minister will ask Tasmanian salmon farms to scale back their operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f16f18ad7cc496224dc41ec49e1e0093</guid></item><item><title>'Devastated' Australia on the brink of World Cup exit after Sri Lanka's record chase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/cricket-australia-sri-lanka-t20-world-cup-live-blog/106351564</link><description>Australia is on the cusp of a group stage exit from the T20 World Cup after crashing to an eight-wicket loss against tournament co-hosts Sri Lanka.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c69a6c4d3d6ed2d91ae06e9e0fd7374d</guid></item><item><title>Robert Duvall, star of The Godfather and Apocalypse Now, dies at 95</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/robert-duvall-star-of-godfather-and-apocalypse-now-dies-at-95/106352132</link><description>Oscar winner Robert Duvall, known for films such as The Godfather and Apocalypse Now, has died at the age of 95.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c557714626458849acf4e2f9e4b0c251</guid></item><item><title>Results show high levels of lead contamination in dust around Hobart, as EPA flags further tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/nyrstar-lead-pollution-epa-tests-hobart/106339682</link><description>High levels of lead contamination have been found in dust samples taken from suburban locations close to Nyrstar's Hobart zinc smelter, documents obtained by the ABC show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df4c929be90ce6716c442950274a84e2</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian Motor Accident Insurance Board suing Melissa Oates for $934k in damages over Jari Wise's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/maib-chasing-jari-wise-death-driver-melissa-oates-for-934k/106349758</link><description>A woman who hit and killed her partner with her car in 2020 is being pursued for almost $1 million in damages by the Tasmanian Motor Accident Insurance Board.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d18263c5f7c1d7f98b5e30fb65d32e7</guid></item><item><title>Juanella Donovan reflects on People's Choice win at National Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Art Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/artist-juanella-donovan-wins-natsiaa-peoples-choice-award/106350062</link><description>Juanella Donovan has taken out the People's Choice category at the National Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Art Awards for the second time, emerging as the public favourite from more than 200 entries across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">729bb7b7ed08ea9b03a622bdc521303a</guid></item><item><title>Own goal ends Macclesfield's FA Cup fairytale against Brentford</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/fa-cup-macclesfield-brentford-fourth-round/106352296</link><description>Non-league English football club Macclesfield's tremendous FA Cup run has come to an end, falling to Premier League side Brentford.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ef3637794f7ad3aecb3526517be191b</guid></item><item><title>Pod Save America and why Australians remain obssessed with US politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/pod-save-america-why-australians-are-obssessed-with-us-politics/106327878</link><description>Huge crowds have flocked to live shows for the popular and influential Pod Save America podcast, suggesting Australia's obsession with US politics isn't going away anytime soon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29fd6077abedec21a6c24a6198c4c894</guid></item><item><title>Australian production company Matchbox Pictures to be closed by Universal International Studios</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/matchbox-pictures-closed-universal-international-studios/106355260</link><description>Matchbox Pictures, the local production house behind Dog Park, The Survivors and Secret City, will be closed by its international parent company, Universal International Studios.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78b9d935e059c11895c3efac8807b716</guid></item><item><title>Sydney’s great fatberg hiding in the sewers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sydney-s-great-fatberg-hiding-in-the-sewers/106355414</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d86c2192d0e5b5504b2ff2bec1bd22ef</guid></item><item><title>ABC to move Adelaide office to new Tapangka site in CBD, alongside arts organisations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/abc-adelaide-to-move-to-new-cbd-arts-hub/106355280</link><description>The ABC has announced a new location for its Adelaide operations, moving to a new arts and media hub alongside other government arts organisation in the CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304f07af147679233a1ce91d82d122b7</guid></item><item><title>Aussie teen forced to wait for Olympic final as heavy snow wreaks havoc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-day-11-live-blog/106354466</link><description>Australia's Ally Hickman has to wait another day for the women's snowboard slopestyle final, as a snowstorm hits Livigno and causes scheduling delays.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0610df31fc2a456d285c9d60f0eeb066</guid></item><item><title>Jesse Jackson, civil rights leader and US presidential hopeful, dead at 84</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/civil-rghts-leader-jesse-jackson-dies-age-84/106356528</link><description>The two-time Democratic presidential hopeful remembered for powerful speeches died peacefully surrounded by loved ones, his family said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bef1e4b64b56ce290b7d00444b297818</guid></item><item><title>Aerials delay is not unusual, as snow causes chaos at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/aerials-delays-2026-winter-olympics/106356762</link><description>Delays are nothing new in skiing events, with weather and light a constant battle for event organisers. However, the Australian aerials team has an unusual method to handle the disruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f49e711941aae6ee00c9b528308bb80f</guid></item><item><title>Telstra accused of environmental breaches in culturally-significant area in SA national park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/telstra-investigated-environmental-breach-south-australia-site/106349226</link><description>Sources say the actions will likely affect Aboriginal communities and that the investigation was not shared with the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b5f492e4ab694c6050d7c2fadc97f21</guid></item><item><title>Real Madrid star Vinícius Júnior says Benfica's Gianluca Prestianni racially abused him in Champions League match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/champions-league-racism-vinicius-junior-real-madrid-benfica/106357730</link><description>Real Madrid forward Vinícius Júnior accuses an opponent of racially abusing him during a Champions League game against Benfica, leading to the game being halted for nearly 10 minutes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">659589228e0656b84af72920641782c0</guid></item><item><title>Legends slam Australia's 'not surprising' T20 World Cup crash out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/aussie-t20-world-cup-eliminated-shock-loss/106359106</link><description>For the first time since 2009, Australia won't advance from the group stage of a cricket World Cup and some of the game's greatest ever players are demanding answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbd3f4835d2882acc4aa5f3b0c0d541b</guid></item><item><title>Jesse Jackson helped lay the groundwork for Barack Obama and kept the fight for justice in the public eye</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/jesse-jackson-groundwork-for-americas-first-black-president/106359248</link><description>Reverend Jesse Jackson, who died on Tuesday aged 84, leaves behind a towering legacy in politics and the fight for justice in the United States and abroad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0665d46428bd50fafd1d8f2ab4989a0</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Macarthur FC captain Ulises Dávila fined $11k over A-League card fixing saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/ex-a-league-captain-ulises-d%C3%A1vila-fined-over-betting-scandal/106358086</link><description>Former Macarthur FC captain Ulises Dávila avoids jail time over his involvement in a card fixing scandal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d649323fcbad3f77ec947285f3251da</guid></item><item><title>More delays for Winter Olympics as 'severe' weather approaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/winter-olympics-day-12-live-blog/106358928</link><description>Milano Cortina organisers have been forced to postpone the men's aerials event, featuring Australian Reilly Flanagan, due to another forecast of inclement weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1afa317592e146df44942abefc37c8a4</guid></item><item><title>Driver charged over Camden fatal crash escaped Cumberland Hospital mental health care before incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/cumberland-hospital-patient-absconded-before-camden-fatal-crash/106361010</link><description>A driver charged over a double-fatal crash used a staff pass to escape hospital the day before an alleged Sydney stabber fled the same mental health facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9b460c845ba44fdb8e18d6fdf3752c5</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian EPA drops plan to implement tighter lead controls after pushback from Nyrstar smelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/epa-folds-after-nyrstar-pushback-on-tougher-lead-emissions/106352924</link><description>Three years ago, Tasmania's environment watchdog proposed to tighten lead emission limits from Hobart's zinc smelter to bring the state into line with national standards — but after pushback from the operator, that plan was dropped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8b8d1991b39bb3d2dd77b421c60cd3b</guid></item><item><title>Quiz: Which books are these literary quotes from?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/famous-book-quotes-quiz/106321984</link><description>Are you happiest with your nose in a book? Did you spend summer reading at the beach? This quiz is for you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93263cc459c19ed242af066f07f52020</guid></item><item><title>Danielle Scott's Winter Olympic silver ends years of pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/danielle-scott-aerials-silver-medal-2026-winter-olympics/106361322</link><description>In this most tension-filled Winter Olympic sport, it's no wonder tears are a by-product of both success and failure. Thankfully for Dani Scott, this time she was crying tears of pure joy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e5d5a3ecb08453f6f6bb9cdeaccc263</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Dog invades cross-country skiing, Americans get engaged as Ally Hickman feels the pain — day 12 quick hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-day-12-quick-hits/106360904</link><description>A pair of US athletes announce their engagement as Ally Hickman's medal bid turns sour and a dog steals the show at the cross-country skiing. Here are the quick hits from day 12 at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd59fe51c584fb48b6564fd085361a09</guid></item><item><title>M1 reopened after truck carrying 10,000 litres of molasses crashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/truck-crash-causes-molasses-spill-dapto/106361588</link><description>The M1 motorway reopens following an hours-long clean-up operation after a truck carrying 10,000 litres of molasses rolled during a crash, leaving two drivers with serious injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41449dca386716f27a0707318e6fc457</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane's Lang Park concert cap almost doubles under new trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/qld-lang-park-suncorp-concert-limit-to-almost-double/106360994</link><description>A one-year trial will see the number of concerts at Brisbane's Lang Park almost double from 12 to 21 per year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e40403a7bf49eabd7e064b1ff94cddfd</guid></item><item><title>How exclusion orders could ban Australian citizens from returning home indefinitely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/australian-citizens-banned-returning-overseas-exclusion-orders/106361634</link><description>One of the Australian women being held in a Syrian refugee camp has been barred from returning home after being given a temporary exclusion order — but the ban may not be as temporary as the name implies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b69ea4e5ccbec5d9f3ed7794e281795c</guid></item><item><title>SA secures Australian MotoGP, world-first street circuit announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/sa-secures-motogp-world-first-street-circuit-announced/106361722</link><description>The South Australian government has confirmed the Australian MotoGP will move to Adelaide from 2027, bringing with it huge economic benefits, but the opposition and Greens say the state has other priorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a957e6c008c2cd348424eaa2acecad49</guid></item><item><title>What is Skimo? The sport preparing to steal the show at the Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/skimo-debut-winter-olympic-games/106361848</link><description>Skimo, or ski mountaineering, is coming to the 2026 Winter Olympics. But what is the sport and why is it so exciting?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cc7441c0ae245bfcfcc6c6051609c64</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 13</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide/106361600</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b82fce97399d532a4a35eed6ae6a0ea9</guid></item><item><title>Rottnest Channel Swim organisers weigh cancellation as 55 kph winds forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/rottnest-channel-swim-threatened-cancellation-rough-seas/106363432</link><description>As thousands of people prepare to tackle Western Australia's iconic Rottnest Island Swim, rough weather is threatening to grind it to a halt just 48 hours before it begins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a39a33fd7de283d8a2e3ed71fb9cf4e</guid></item><item><title>American star completes comeback with figure skating gold after 'retiring' at 16</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-live-blog-day-13/106363160</link><description>Alysa Liu becomes the first American woman to win singles figure skating gold in 24 years, completing her comeback after retiring in 2022 when she was only 16 years old.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfe1fb096a25edbb2543b23f098e496e</guid></item><item><title>Abandoned Antarctic base is now a pollution threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/abandoned-antarctic-base-is-now-a-pollution-threat-/106365360</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49846b03030ffc2b913431f02159b7f8</guid></item><item><title>Michael Brian Becton sentenced to more than 24 years in jail for child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/man-sentenced-to-24-years-in-jail-over-child-sex-offences/106365380</link><description>Michael Brian Becton, 33, is handed a 24-and-a-half year prison term after pleading guilty to 77 child sexual offences against children and babies. WARNING: This story contains details that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">388c384c47b78f4a85d064f1750a1efd</guid></item><item><title>What we know about ex-prince Andrew's arrest on suspicion of misconduct in public office</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/what-we-know-about-former-prince-andrew-arrest/106365894</link><description>Police are searching two addresses in the UK, including Royal Lodge on the Windsor Estate where the former prince lived until last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8039d5e6abc316002657b559e90ee456</guid></item><item><title>Calls for protection of Tasmania's penguins amid reports of birds 'handled by the neck'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/people-interacting-with-tasmanian-penguins-and-harming-them/106361614</link><description>Each summer, tourists flock to Tasmanian beaches to marvel at penguins, but for some, admiring the birds from afar is not enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a8bc422a73f9012a025e072732b4fbb</guid></item><item><title>Police guarding former prince Andrew's residence in Sandringham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/police-guarding-former-prince-andrew-s-residence-in-sandringham/106366520</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">230140cfa446b0397fb1807d140d3ab6</guid></item><item><title>Voters divided as Barnaby Joyce considers contesting New England for One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/new-england-divided-over-barnaby-joyce/106353714</link><description>One Nation MP Barnaby Joyce says he might recontest his seat of New England as a candidate for One Nation if the party needs him to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8216e2cb0110f0bcd4db9bab70757914</guid></item><item><title>Car driving Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor leaves UK police station.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-released-after-being-in-custody/106366694</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5d1b414c5b63a2abd8afd19a7fb4208</guid></item><item><title>Amyl and the Sniffers singer in escalating legal battle with photographer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/amy-taylor-amyl-and-the-sniffers-court-cases-copyright/106361084</link><description>What began as a photo shoot with champagne, ice cream and humorous glamour shots of Amy Taylor, singer from punk band Amyl and the Sniffers, has escalated into a legal fight over copyright, the US Constitution and an application for a restraining order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eecb7daec40c63d6dec04c319e48120</guid></item><item><title>Coalition willing to help stop passports for IS-linked women— as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/federal-politics-live-albanese-taylor-labor-coalition/106363700</link><description>Angus Taylor says the Coalition is willing to help the government strengthen legislation so women with ties to Islamic State are not issued Australian passports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e73f6a4c21f2ed041db318fdf5bfddfe</guid></item><item><title>Major US fund's credit squeeze could 'blow up' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-friday-20-february/106366740</link><description>Shares in US asset manager Blue Owl have fallen sharply after it announced it was having challenges meeting investors' cash demands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8cfa058595f0f84f2b91273acd73f15</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says Andrew's arrest is a 'shame' for Royal family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/donald-trump-says-andrew-s-arrest-is-a-shame-for-royal-family-/106366752</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3ac836173af3ee6429afa5d754a1fc1</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: JD Vance laments Eileen Gu's choice and Scotty James channels Wolf of Wall Street — day 13 quick hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/winter-olympics-day-13-quick-hits-eileen-gu-jd-vance/106365688</link><description>Scotty James says he is not done, while Sweden claims the entire curling world is "against us". Here are the quick hits from day 13 at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a9ff45d94aa4dfae8c06d942bbc0bcd</guid></item><item><title>NT hit-and-run driver Jake Danby's sentence extended on appeal, as victim's family say they feel 'broken'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/jake-danby-sentence-extended-on-appeal-2-years-home-detention/106366800</link><description>The sentence of NT hit-and-run driver Jake Danby has been extended on appeal, meaning he will serve two years in home detention. Danby hit two pedestrians with his car in June 2024, killing one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f57345975c6d0ea9d3ea8d0e24b086a</guid></item><item><title>NT cattle sector backs draft buffel grass plan as environmental and Aboriginal groups say it favours industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/buffel-grass-weed-draft-plan-groups-say-it-favours-industry/106309368</link><description>Cattle producers support the NT's draft buffel grass weed management plan, but it has attracted criticism from traditional owners and environmental groups.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f63e14c6d52852a5e04560d27f31045b</guid></item><item><title>Eric Dane, star of Grey's Anatomy and Euphoria, dies aged 53</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/eric-dane-star-of-greys-anatomy-and-euphoria-dies/106188556</link><description>The star was best known for his role as Dr Mark Sloan in long-running medical drama Grey's Anatomy, and as the patriarch of the Jacobs family in teen hit Euphoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38f5c65f82f5e42103bcfbd84e4e18ea</guid></item><item><title>WA councils could make laws to stop cats roaming under proposed state legislation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/wa-councils-could-soon-have-power-to-stop-cats-roaming/106365476</link><description>The WA government announces plans to give local councils the power to require cats to be contained to owners' properties, to protect native birds and other wildlife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9304ac0385f2634a77bf6bab016498b8</guid></item><item><title>Cameron William Leslie Clark, accused of Easts Leagues Club stabbing, appears in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/easts-leagues-club-stabbing-accused-appears-in-court/106366762</link><description>Cameron William Leslie Clark is accused of repeatedly stabbing a 20-year-old female employee of the Easts Leagues Club in Coorparoo last Thursday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96ec27e06b17fd9990fde151bd53e7a1</guid></item><item><title>Senior Constable Stuart Parsonage charged with illegal surveillance by WA Police sex crime division</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/wa-police-officer-court-computer-crime-surveillance-charges/106365724</link><description>Geraldton Senior Constable Stuart Parsonage has been charged with the illegal installation of a surveillance device and unlawful use of a computer by WA sex crime detectives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ef0a162b68b5d35ea9dcd87f112ee98</guid></item><item><title>Mercedes F1 boss Toto Wolff defends team over engine drama ahead of Australian Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/mercedes-f1-boss-toto-wolff-calls-rivals-over-engine-saga/106368722</link><description>Toto Wolff accuses rival Formula 1 manufacturers of ganging up on Mercedes to pressure the governing FIA to change engine rules, but says it will make no difference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf062a44fa8f20ae64da57f3e573fc38</guid></item><item><title>Coroner delivers findings into James Tsindos's death from allergic reaction to delivery meal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/coroner-delivers-james-tsindos-nut-allergy-findings/106367040</link><description>A Victorian coroner hands down her findings into the death of a teenager who suffered a severe allergic reaction to a delivery meal — but it's unclear if more urgent treatment would have saved his life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebac18c8be8e4bab52fd1a3ef61d1b64</guid></item><item><title>Scientists model best-case and worst-case climate scenarios for Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/antarctica-faces-devastating-impacts-under-climate-change/106354182</link><description>Scientists say parts of Antarctica face "devastating" and "irreversible" impacts from climate change unless urgent action is taken to limit greenhouse gas emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f426dd0a1878420ce756c07766ef447c</guid></item><item><title>Woman who fatally struck 12-year-old Marshall Oakley-Stagg granted restricted driver's licence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/driver-who-killed-marshall-oakley-stagg-drivers-licence/106369656</link><description>A driver who struck and killed a 12-year-old boy outside his school in southern Tasmania in 2024 has been granted a restricted licence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ff01adff427a2aca0847f364c794ea9</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle man avoids jail for child abuse images and bestiality videos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/man-avoids-jail-for-possessing-bestiality-and-child-abuse-images/106369722</link><description>A man has avoided time behind bars and instead been handed a three-year community corrections order for possessing 34,000 child abuse images and more than a dozen bestiality videos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91107be62e03814cc5d9c575bcf0edc7</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand man Tamaohungia Joseph Tepatu-Edwards jailed for 26 years for attempted cocaine importation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/new-zealand-man-jailed-attempted-cocaine-importation/106368264</link><description>A man who tried to smuggle more than 800 kilograms of cocaine into WA – and was only caught when his boat broke down — will spend two decades in jail and is "likely" be deported.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe96af322e56c9cc85664c9573f21026</guid></item><item><title>Norway sets Winter Olympics record with 17th gold medal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/winter-olympics-milano-cortina-day-14-live-updates/106369192</link><description>Norway breaks its own record for the most gold medals won by a nation at a single Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e17b4999cf1076ac0d1642f69ec78c68</guid></item><item><title>Putin is betting Ukraine and the West run out of resources first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/russia-ukraine-four-year-war-vladimir-putin/106349238</link><description>Russian President Vladimir Putin is betting that the West and Ukraine will run out of resources first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11d7efa9b8e3b49ad2d1ac3d15d64f51</guid></item><item><title>Andy Griffiths, author of the Treehouse books, named new Australian Children's Laureate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andy-griffiths-author-australian-childrens-laureate/106331360</link><description>Famous for writing stories about toilets and tree houses, the bestselling kids' author is taking on a new challenge on the national stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4faf4f52c970006ea1d74e0f15c753b</guid></item><item><title>ABC 50/50 quiz: This week we're testing your knowledge of Ninja Turtles, Netflix and nagging pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/abc-5050-quiz-feb-21/106362470</link><description>Every question has only two options: One is right and the other is wrong. You have an even chance of guessing correctly each time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75de69d84e56309d413d4f77423b7583</guid></item><item><title>The art and origins of the courtroom sketch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/the-art-and-origins-of-the-courtroom-sketch/105817718</link><description>They're a small and curious cohort in a line of work rapidly evolving. Welcome to the world of courtroom artists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5051373d22a373be7ac83c73f3f9a4bb</guid></item><item><title>Peter Malinauskas is heading for a landslide win in SA. How crushing a victory will it be?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/sa-election-lots-to-learn-despite-predicted-labor-landslide/106363808</link><description>Even if it's a Labor landslide, we'll learn a lot from next month's South Australian election, writes Casey Briggs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2475f1de36b7f53be3206611dfb848d</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest shows money talks louder than women's testimony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-jeffrey-epstein/106349250</link><description>Why is an email about the trade trip apparently more compelling than the detailed and painful evidence of a woman?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c126708b2400a064fec41430e0ad12c1</guid></item><item><title>Farmer's hands-off approach creates unusual lamb with distinct flavour chefs say is like nothing else in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/braidwood-farmer-new-lamb-cooked-local-restaurant-expat-chefs/106358970</link><description>When Frank was forced to sell the sheep he'd been farming for more than 20 years, something had to change. His "experiment" is helping expats feel at home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">193e31303ed2bfa342879871031db171</guid></item><item><title>Queensland woman wakes from coma after contracting meningitis and septic shock on ski holiday to Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/queensland-woman-coma-meningitis-septic-shock-in-japan/106367880</link><description>When 24-year-old Anna Gallo woke up shivering in a Tokyo hotel, she thought it was food poisoning. Hours later, she was in a coma fighting for her life against a disease she thought she was vaccinated against.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df154e4e3de16e61796b2871c5c9fe9b</guid></item><item><title>North Queensland on high alert as deluge continues and rivers rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/large-parts-of-queensland-on-high-alert-as-heavy-rain-continues/106367672</link><description>Flooding is likely to become more widespread in northern and western Queensland over the next few days, with further heavy rainfall and road closures expected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b0a1461ea9964b523d17ba2f1d2a90d</guid></item><item><title>Daly River flood evacuees to return home after more than two weeks in Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nt-daly-river-evacuees-returning-home-after-flood-emergency/106368994</link><description>After spending more than a fortnight sleeping at a Darwin evacuation centre 220 kilometres away from their flooded community, bus loads of Daly River locals are set to return home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2098d8f0591a5fe0f965b8e16635f308</guid></item><item><title>Vulnerable flatback turtle numbers stabilise thanks to Mackay community action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/turtle-conservation-success-in-mackay-north-queensland/106342990</link><description>Local conservation groups have worked to protect turtle nesting habitats along the Mackay coast for more than 30 years, bringing generational change for these "ancient mariners".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43042541b1f4ac004b97ebb6c504760c</guid></item><item><title>Why economists hate low unemployment for inflation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/why-economists-hate-low-unemployment-for-inflation/106367852</link><description>The theory goes that if you have just the right amount of workers on the unemployment scrap heap, you can keep inflation in check. The problem is that no-one knows exactly what the magic unemployment rate is.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43e029d93818ef09b173d99095546fef</guid></item><item><title>Two teenage boys killed in fatal car crash at Crabtree, in Tasmania's Huon Valley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/double-teen-fatality-in-southern-tasmania-crash/106371746</link><description>Flowers have been laid for two teenage boys who died in a single vehicle crash in Tasmania's Huon valley overnight, with three others taken to hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04a217818d8de71afce27b22293179fd</guid></item><item><title>Women and children in Syrian camp "will end up in Australia" | Insiders On Background</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/insiders-on-background-abul-rizvi/106370578</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">429933e5b0b8244f26a5c83a2eef8995</guid></item><item><title>Balinese women find shared culture and community in WA's Pilbara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/balinese-indonesian-women-in-fifo-mining-town/106190742</link><description>The Pilbara is known for spinifex and mining, but has also become a melting pot of cultures from across the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">897c042e4f513ac1f82e6b02921636b5</guid></item><item><title>I had a miscarriage over the summer. It was nothing like I expected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/miscarriage-loss-grief/106308830</link><description>My understanding of miscarriage was built on a handful of Hollywood representations and snatches of stories I'd read. Outside of this, I had few reference points.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a18951e43e4efa639be7b2845bc9d57e</guid></item><item><title>A 'return to craft' for the NT's award-winning young artists showcased at this year's Exit Art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nt-exit-art-exhibition-return-to-crafting-darwin-gallery-museum/106368426</link><description>Almost a dozen high school-aged artists have received awards as part of a prestigious Northern Territory showcase, with a number of finalists exhibiting self-portraits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ed4262d4757e1158f4f7f9fb3c9f716</guid></item><item><title>Anna Murdoch-Mann, author and ex-wife of Rupert Murdoch, dies aged 81</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/anna-murdoch-mann-dies-aged-81/106371640</link><description>The author, journalist and philanthropist was Rupert Murdoch's "active partner" in his media empire News Corp over their 31-year marriage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4277353646eb61bcf0bb37d726dbda4</guid></item><item><title>NASA boss blasts Boeing and agency over bungled test flight that left astronauts stranded on space station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/nasa-report-reveals-starliner-mission-failings/106371706</link><description>A bungled Boeing mission that left two astronauts stranded on the International Space Station for nine months has been criticised by NASA's new boss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3928101430826cc338efc88bfa7afd86</guid></item><item><title>South Australian election countdown officially begins, campaign kicks off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-21/south-australia-election-2026-campaign-begins/106371978</link><description>Election campaigning in South Australia is officially underway, with candidates seizing the opportunity to begin making their formal pitches to voters before they head to the ballot box in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9242c102760eb4813ef7943f0f70998b</guid></item></channel></rss>