<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 10:58:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Cyber attacks that occurred this year and how you can protect your data</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/cyber-attacks-2025-and-ways-to-protect-your-data/106113950</link><description>More than 500 data breaches were reported in Australia over the first half of 2025 alone, but there are some ways you can minimise your risk of being caught up in one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6598bb0502d89389e7d5e5b3034648f</guid></item><item><title>How the teen social media ban is impacting Australia’s multicultural communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/teens-stay-connected-to-overseas-family-post-social-media-ban/106177038</link><description>Sydney teenager Ilia Kyrychenko was relieved to delete his accounts after the social media ban, but the change is making it more difficult to connect with his loved ones in Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a741447e2137a617d80fba502cade1e</guid></item><item><title>Experts say climate change bigger threat to biodiversity than renewable energy projects</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/renewable-energy-impacts-kentbruck-wind-farm/106157018</link><description>As the green energy boom gathers pace, experts say climate change is a bigger threat to biodiversity than wind farms and other renewables projects.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e664a3bfdc63f8077cf844a68acce4f</guid></item><item><title>Mother pushes for safer pool fences as Victorian family marks a year since drowning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/vic-mother-pushes-for-safer-pool-fences-one-year-since-drowning/106085692</link><description>A woman is calling for tougher pool fencing regulations after her daughter crawled through a faulty fence and drowned in a neighbour’s pool.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b9697825bef34b2e3b47c1348f778a8</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with two counts of murder after stabbing at Quakers Hill in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/man-charged-two-counts-of-murder-after-stabbing-quakers-hill/106182386</link><description>Emergency services were called to a Quakers Hill home just before 5am after reports of a disturbance to discover a woman dead and a man fatally wounded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1b73f6b2ba17ebd42fdac9e4c61a9e0</guid></item><item><title>What was on summer reading lists 100 years ago, in 1925?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/summer-reading-list-1925-human-experience-time-travel/106172974</link><description>There are books from authors that would become household names — F. Scott Fitzgerald and A.A Milne among them — and books that are now banned in some countries. But what can we learn from what people were reading in 1925?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d08c1d2e3ba6ff50a847933c46b8cd8a</guid></item><item><title>Mentors gave me confidence to navigate life with a disability. Now I'm giving back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/mentors-gave-me-confidence-to-navigate-life-with-a-disability/106169450</link><description>Other people with lived experience of blindness gave ABC reporter Nas Campanella the confidence to navigate life. Her mentee, Lily, is enjoying similar benefits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f2710fbd235d36e292f977452d42c6</guid></item><item><title>A rescued dingo puppy explores its new surroundings.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/a-dingo-puppy-walks-awkwardly-across-some-grass/106127112</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1548d921911e3b45201eeeaee566b96</guid></item><item><title>Dingo management should be 'non-lethal', traditional owners say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/non-lethal-dingo-management-push-by-traditional-owners/105807306</link><description>When Sonya sees a black-and-tan dingo, she feels a connection to family and Country, but many landholders see them as livestock-killing pests. Can graziers and dingoes co-exist?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dbd93a43b5a77e1ac9c73c36cabab5e</guid></item><item><title>Kennedy Center boss criticises musician who cancelled performance after Trump rebrand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/kennedy-centre-criticises-musician-cancelled-performance-rebrand/106182404</link><description>Musician Chuck Redd cancelled his Christmas Eve show days after the White House announced the venue would be renamed the Trump Kennedy Center.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47ac5e0cd46893de5399850e25e97e12</guid></item><item><title>Weatherald, Labuschagne, Green under Ashes selection pressure after MCG loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/australias-shaky-batters-face-scg-selection-scrutiny/106182432</link><description>Jake Weatherald, Marnus Labuschagne and Cameron Green all face selection pressure following double failures in Australia's jarring loss at the MCG.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50bc3003c4bc68d8bf3b70a89abf98a5</guid></item><item><title>What to know about the Islamic State militants targeted by US air strikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/trump-us-air-strikes-is-militants-nigeria/106181242</link><description>With US President Donald Trump hinting at plans for further strikes on IS militants in Nigeria, here's a rundown on what you need to know about the conflict.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">409b97b5b2a7281b8083c6c8490f3f06</guid></item><item><title>Hands-on memories spark connection for dementia residents at western NSW aged care home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/adult-activity-board-for-dementia-patients/106173414</link><description>Creating meaningful, sensory activities for people living with dementia can be challenging, particularly when many traditional options feel more suited to children than adults with a lifetime of lived experience behind them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a77900a93309dfceb04ffb9fbaf8f904</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate death of woman in Port Macquarie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/port-macquarie-woman-dead/106182606</link><description>A crime scene has been established after a woman died from unexplained injuries in New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ad5370394c4ded7958e20e860ceaf6e</guid></item><item><title>Man charged for allegedly displaying hate symbol tattoos at Newcastle beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/man-charged-for-allegedly-displaying-antisemitic-tattoos/106182526</link><description>A man has been charged for allegedly displaying what police have called "hate symbol" tattoos at a beach in Newcastle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f53322ab0acd29d0350f0c5924bc74bc</guid></item><item><title>From soapboxes to social media: Two artists shaping Queensland's bush art scene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/artists-shaping-queensland-s-bush-art-scene/106175014</link><description>Marion Moore is 101. Zarabella Bambling is 23. Despite their differences, both women have just celebrated the same major achievement as bush artists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">427d241e1ba0b484ea9d0a3fced806c4</guid></item><item><title>Why getting more migrants to swim has benefits for all of Australian society</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/australia-migrant-communities-overrepresented-in-drownings/106097704</link><description>Despite wanting to learn how to swim, many from culturally and linguistically diverse communities — particularly adults — face three key barriers to participating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc9a4c47ba3cefbc6c4f3c8fd3f5d26c</guid></item><item><title>The case of the Guayaquil Four places scrutiny on Ecuador's security crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/guayaquil-four-sentence-lays-bare-racism-and-security-in-ecuador/106173084</link><description>In the weeks before Christmas, four boys under 16 left home to play a game of soccer. Their forced disappearance at the hands of Ecuador's military has been labelled a national "turning point".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49b1ef624f5f479dd3ab2d8593a6c9e2</guid></item><item><title>'Grumpy' seal disrupts Blairgowrie boat race on Victoria's Mornington Peninsula</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/grumpy-seal-blairgowrie-petersville-regatta/106182708</link><description>A wild seal dubbed "Grumpy" causes some commotion at an annual boat race on the Mornington Peninsula, outside Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">083e2941bae98fafdb7d5202d1fe7c23</guid></item><item><title>MCG curator Matt Page admits Boxing Day Test pitch 'favoured the bowlers too much'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/mcc-boss-defends-curator-after-two-day-ashes-test/106182802</link><description>MCC boss Stuart Fox staunchly defends chief curator Matt Page after a wild Boxing Day Test finishes within two days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1acfc9a80c189932f3941f9cf9cb33be</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with assaulting Labor identity Tim Picton granted bail in Perth court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/tim-picton-family-statement-alleged-northbridge-assault/106182738</link><description>A 20-year-old man is granted bail after allegedly assaulting Tim Picton, a prominent Labor Party identity — an attack police prosecutors say may leave him permanently disabled, if he survives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">582a30d244334d7fc711737f77e529db</guid></item><item><title>SA independent MP Nick McBride charged with assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/sa-independent-mp-nick-mcbride-charged/106182668</link><description>Police say they responded to reports of a domestic assault at a home in South Australia's south-east on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc915b603692b5192afe65dd47c0b132</guid></item><item><title>Sending army to protect Sydney's Jewish community not ruled out by NSW premier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/army-protecting-sydney-jewish-community-not-ruled-out-premier/106182770</link><description>Sydneysiders can expect to see more police officers carrying long-armed guns in the weeks ahead, with the premier not ruling out sending troops to protect the Jewish community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a2eb33aae3894778271668f7910e5f8</guid></item><item><title>Taiwan's cunning tax compliance makes most shopping receipts a ticket in a lottery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/taiwan-receipt-lottery-win-money-from-shopping/106140828</link><description>Most shopping receipts in Taiwan are also tickets for a lottery run every second month by the government to increase tax compliance, and there are some big prizes up for grabs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25f5e0a517eb8eafa70303f39fc1010c</guid></item><item><title>Police say Indigenous woman's death in custody was result of 'medical episode'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/tennant-creek-death-in-custody-medical-episode-no-nurse-on-duty/106182578</link><description>Northern Territory Police say the death in custody of an Indigenous woman in Tennant Creek on Saturday was the result of a "medical episode", while admitting there was no nurse on duty at the time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54d756f855f2d37e4ec1bccbed6d2807</guid></item><item><title>Teenagers charged after alleged aggravated carjacking in Melbourne's south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/alleged-aggravated-carjacking-police-chase-hampton-park-pakenham/106183114</link><description>An overnight police chase across multiple suburbs has ended with the arrest of three teenagers after an alleged aggravated carjacking in Melbourne's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edb125df654714026d70f2fd71fcd94e</guid></item><item><title>Comanche wins Sydney to Hobart line honours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/comanche-wins-sydney-to-hobart-line-honours/106183250</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a72afefec57b8ae17123abe534199049</guid></item><item><title>Brigitte Bardot, iconic French actor, sex symbol and animal rights campaigner, dies aged 91</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/brigitte-bardot-dies-age-91/102626484</link><description>The French actor and singer was a screen siren of the 1950s and 1960s who in later life became a prominent animal rights campaigner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a8bea482f12114393ea501ba0b3a9a0</guid></item><item><title>Brigitte Bardot was the world's 'sex kitten'. Her nonchalance was all French</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/brigitte-bardot-sex-symbol-fashion-darling-and-french-icon/105927998</link><description>Few epitomised French chic like Brigitte Bardot, the doe-eyed beauty whose sensuality rocked a post-war world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60d23ab3a781560aba2c74662576b8d4</guid></item><item><title>Families of Bondi victims call for federal royal commission</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/bondi-beach-victim-families-call-for-federal-royal-comission/106183188</link><description>Loved ones of those killed and injured in the Bondi Beach attack say rising antisemitism requires a "powerful national response", piling pressure on Anthony Albanese for a royal commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6fc9a1e1906617a1395c8773838364e</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios defeats Aryna Sabalenka in latest 'battle of the sexes'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/nick-kyrgios-aryna-sabalenka-battle-of-the-sexes-live-blog/106182808</link><description>Australia's Nick Kyrgios defeated women's world number one Aryna Sabalenka in the latest "battle of the sexes". The Aussie, who has fallen outside the ATP top 600 after barely playing for three years, won 6-3, 6-3.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">190b8c7e84e5d376abc1085871d67f15</guid></item><item><title>A growing number of older women surfers are showing age is just a state of mind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/older-women-surfing-trends/105867538</link><description>When Katie Pahlow turned 60, she decided to finally bite the bullet and book herself in for some surf lessons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7393da40072bb0d63dcf47898161a0db</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Larcombe's journey back to the top of the paraclimbing world after devastating injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/sarah-larcombe-paraclimbing-injury-arapiles-world-championships/106018328</link><description>When Sarah Larcombe fell off Mount Arapiles in February, she thought she just sprained her ankle. What followed was months of ups and downs ending in a stunning world championships result.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f086b176ddcd0acf46baf29b3420471</guid></item><item><title>Aid agencies fear lifesaving program banned in Gaza under new Israeli requirements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/aid-agencies-fear-lifesaving-program-blockage-into-gaza-/106181964</link><description>The Israeli government has introduced new rules for aid organisations, including that they must not engage in any activities or criticism which "delegitimise" the state of Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd0ed41a1ad1defc29299a64e4369121</guid></item><item><title>Australia's driver courtesy wave dying out, say truckies, but experiment proves wave still alive on back roads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/australian-drivers-truckies-courtesy-wave/106152822</link><description>For generations, the courtesy wave has been etched into the Australian culture, but is it on the verge of dying?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab1044fced53244ab59b2127f9073c74</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says progress made on peace deal, but Donald Trump says 'thorny issues' remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/trump-meets-zelenskyy-to-discuss-ukraine-peace-plan/106183658</link><description>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says a security guarantee between Ukraine and the US as part of a peace deal is "100 per cent agreed", while Donald Trump says there are still one or two "thorny issues" to finalise in the deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06163790a274f36391c30a19988e561a</guid></item><item><title>Concerns medical weight-loss treatments are being advertised to vulnerable eating disorder patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/juniper-telehealth-concerns-weight-loss-treatment-glp1/106114626</link><description>Eating disorder bodies are raising concerns about weight-loss treatments being prescribed by telehealth companies, one of which ran a Black Friday sale to promote its services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d11ae8b27f1bc3eef0a9dee97b0a2f</guid></item><item><title>Young women join Country Women's Association Sydney branch in droves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/country-womens-association-cwa-in-sydney-young-women-joining/105941208</link><description>More young women are joining the Country Women's Association's city branches, with a passion for jams and scones along with social connection and purpose.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67607c13646f850e0435fa1c89495c0d</guid></item><item><title>Voter turnout lower than expected in Myanmar's first election since 2020</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/voter-turnout-low-myanmar-first-election-2020/106183648</link><description>Myanmar's election has been widely dismissed as a sham by many governments and human rights activists who have said the military will use proxy candidates to legitimise their rule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d51e58cecc72915c62d1db7781e09955</guid></item><item><title>Travis Head happy to see out Ashes as Australian opener before working out future role</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/australias-travis-head-not-fazed-on-opening-role-in-future/106183666</link><description>Australia star Travis Head says he is not precious about continuing to open the batting beyond this Ashes and will bat wherever the coaches tell him to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">922094f96e3a457a294c7309ef6a65a5</guid></item><item><title>AI powered 2025's economy to record highs. So why are only robots smiling?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/end-of-year-economics-analysis-wrap/106176480</link><description>This year saw economies survive tariff shocks and markets burst through record highs, but it doesn't feel like a party because so many people aren't invited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6da1698c0a40d26aaf7b2833b7f573d8</guid></item><item><title>Deadly varroa mite threatens half of Canberra’s beehives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/act-varroa-mite-wipe-out-half-bees-two-years/106148658</link><description>A fast-spreading parasite is expected to devastate local bee colonies over the next two years, affecting commercial and backyard crops.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8efde471e61f47b153c0556497f33df6</guid></item><item><title>LGBTQIA+ focused boxing class combatting loneliness amid warnings about social isolation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/lgbtqia-boxing-class-tackling-loneliness/106034550</link><description>One in three adults experience social isolation in what experts say is a "dangerous" issue in society. One suburban boxing group is working to tackle the issue, focused on the LGBTQIA+ community more at risk of loneliness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be1b7e6c38093ce747c6d1f9fa059918</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Hayley upgraded to category two system, as northern WA residents told to prepare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/cyclone-hayley-forms-off-wa-coast-broome-in-watch-zone/106182876</link><description>Residents in WA's north are on alert following the formation of Tropical Cyclone Hayley off the coast overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf432452bba2d586f8686b2bbf83b502</guid></item><item><title>Wet season's arrival prompts moves to shore up food security in Far North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/flooded-roads-cause-food-insecurity-in-far-north-queensland/106176990</link><description>Earlier this year, a once-in-a-century flood devastated Ingham and cut the main supply route between Cairns and Townsville. Now, as intense rainfall once again triggers multiple warnings and floods roads across northern Queensland, communities are taking steps to prevent another food shortage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9171d9c772b41bbf73794cbd198be777</guid></item><item><title>How vintage black-and-white films are making a splash back in colour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/revitalising-vintage-films/105721412</link><description>Would those classic black-and-white films be the same if viewed in full colour?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">920bdb4c48f10f5d070dc6a984c533b4</guid></item><item><title>Victorian master builder transforms Warrnambool house into castle for his son</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/builder-transforms-warrnambool-home-into-castle-for-son/106176624</link><description>They say "a man's home is his castle," but one builder from south-west Victoria has taken that literally when creating a dream home for his son.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">695b846b83e8f11dbad0909f3c891cba</guid></item><item><title>Mexico train crash kills passengers in country's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/passengers-dead-after-mexico-train-derails/106184194</link><description>Another five people are in a critical condition after the Interoceanic Train detailed in the southern state of Oaxana.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd8463a4b35c27f32cbc759da4ac54a6</guid></item><item><title>NSW government sets up hub to assist those impacted by Bondi Beach terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/nsw-government-announces-bondi-hub-for-impacted-locals-re-attack/106184248</link><description>The Bondi Hub will be open to the community and those directly or indirectly impacted by the December 14 shooting at the Chanukah by the Sea event at Bondi Beach, where 15 people were killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38290ea192f47497f85499cb84648cb0</guid></item><item><title>Australia coach Andrew McDonald says Usman Khawaja will play the final Ashes Test amid retirement speculation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/khawaja-guaranteed-for-scg-future-unclear-after-that/106184310</link><description>Usman Khawaja will play in the Ashes finale at the SCG, but Australian coach Andrew McDonald remains in the dark about the 39-year-old's future beyond that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d906fedef83a721543a674e8516f4cb</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese announces terms for Richardson review of Bondi terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/bondi-breaking-announcement/106184434</link><description>The PM says a former head of ASIO will assess whether multiple security and law agencies worked as effectively as they should have before the attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78790121282cd6631c15dcb53f6684a5</guid></item><item><title>NT police arrest woman for allegedly stealing from patients in Alice Springs Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/elderly-theft-alice-springs-hospital/106184326</link><description>A 30-year-old woman faces court after allegedly stealing from multiple elderly patients recovering from surgery in Alice Springs Hospital over an extended period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dadea0f3cdc0d06e06262cda42d00b4</guid></item><item><title>Coolongolook Rural Fire Service volunteers 'gutted' after robbery during fire season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/coolongolook-rfs-robbery/106184106</link><description>The volunteers discovered the theft when they arrived at the Coolongolook RFS shed to attend a car crash. Thieves stole hoses, breathing masks, radios and chainsaws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffcd8748790754acacd5a3346ef0c2ae</guid></item><item><title>England's pace bowling stocks stripped bare with Gus Atkinson out of SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/gus-atkinson-england-ruled-out-scg-test/106184680</link><description>England's pace bowling stocks will be stretched to their absolute limit for the final Ashes Test with Gus Atkinson ruled out with a hamstring injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22aefbd0e149e9e30254a8f87eca7bee</guid></item><item><title>Ahmed Al Ahmed recounts how he disarmed one of the gunmen in Bondi Beach terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/bondi-hero-ahmed-al-ahmed-recounts-story-of-wrestling-gunman/106183900</link><description>Father-of-two Ahmed Al Ahmed, who risked his life to disarm one of the Bondi gunmen during a terrorist attack, says he feels sorry for the 15 people who were killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6a49f3b62dec473e7ffccc0ed4079a2</guid></item><item><title>The right way to stack your dishwasher and the verdict on rinsing beforehand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/the-verdict-on-rinsing-dishes-before-stacking-the-dishwasher/106022382</link><description>Rinsing can actually send a message to your dishwasher that your plate doesn't need as much washing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b16a5e33ffb32c5a75404f38ecdbd73d</guid></item><item><title>Celebrating New Year's Eve in Melbourne? Here's how and where to bring in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/how-to-celebrate-new-years-eve-in-melbourne/106183938</link><description>Half a million people are expected in the CBD as Melbourne farewells 2025 and ushers in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a16b07aac66c36c7a236913dce6ccff6</guid></item><item><title>South Australian MP Nick McBride to remain in custody for next seven days</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/nick-mcbride-remains-in-custody/106183758</link><description>South Australian independent MP Nick McBride will spend the next week in custody, after being arrested and charged over the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23cfb7d551970cb59aa18a5b3f9cb66b</guid></item><item><title>China launches military exercise warning against Taiwan independence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/china-taiwan-military-exercise-independence/106184600</link><description>China has moved its military to surround Taiwan warning against its independence. But Beijing's action has been condemned by Taiwan calling for regional peace and de-escalation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37ecc5e002b8f8f0e07100aae2ff9ccb</guid></item><item><title>Sydney to Hobart competitors tell of 'horrendous' conditions during 2025 race ordeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/2025-sydney-to-hobart-competitors-endure-rough-seas/106184046</link><description>Those now safely onshore after finishing the 2025 Sydney to Hobart tell of "horrendous" conditions, resulting in injuries, broken boats and seasickness — even among experienced crew members.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3d61d78845f12e1a58903944ac9f4eb</guid></item><item><title>Prosecutors wrap up bribery investigation into South Korea's former first lady</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/kim-keon-hee-bribery-accusations/106184962</link><description>Kim Keon Hee, the wife of disgraced ex-president Yoon Suk Yeol, is alleged to have accepted lavish bribes including fine art, jewellery and designer handbags, and to have meddled in state affairs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b0d782413b3369dcb0aae4239acdf2c</guid></item><item><title>Kempsey community marks 10 years since death in custody of David Dungay Jr</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/david-dungay-jr-death-anniversary-rally/106183046</link><description>A decade after his death in a Sydney prison, David Dungay Jr's family hold with a memorial rally calling for change to a corrections system they say still fails to protect Indigenous people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bdd7f9e29a766e460ae327c8d02e857</guid></item><item><title>Slow TV for kids: Relax and unwind with low-stimulation shows on ABC iview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/low-stimulation-kids-tv-shows-stream-iview-abckids/106024290</link><description>Looking for screen-time options that won't leave your kids overstimulated? 'Slow TV' shows, with their soothing visuals and soundtracks, could be the answer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">428e608956327dc581fd5e961f4708a4</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Sydney Test a golden opportunity for Cameron Green to belatedly shine in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/ashes-cameron-green-home-test-struggles/106185032</link><description>He has already proven his quality away from home, but heading into the final Test of the Ashes summer, Cameron Green remains in search of his breakthrough moment in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58a0cbd79c3cf2c39cce515515f91558</guid></item><item><title>Legal loophole in Queensland's double jeopardy law closed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/dna-double-jeopardy-cases-qld-law-changes/106184178</link><description>Last-minute amendments to Queensland's double jeopardy laws could allow for the retrial of botched DNA cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1ca9a578ce596f77c5d8a343e7e5f45</guid></item><item><title>Australia is considered a "lifeboat" region for some threatened rhino ray species, but the numbers worldwide are grim.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/rhino-ray-numbers-northern-territory-indonesia-extinction/106185030</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a7a7eaa5ae38567db7ecf4dd704011b</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court over alleged Boxing Day murder in remote NT community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/greg-shaun-williams-faces-court-over-alleged-boxing-day-murder/106185286</link><description>A 39-year-old man appears in court charged with the stabbing murder of a man in a remote Northern Territory community north of Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5478d4449ea06d23f01082c453ddfd97</guid></item><item><title>Dozens of shark heads dumped outside WA Fisheries minister's office as demersal fishing ban looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/shark-heads-dumped-outside-jackie-jarvis-office-fisheries/106184674</link><description>Hundreds of kilograms of shark heads have been left dumped outside the WA Fisheries minister's office in Margaret River, just three days before a permanent commercial demersal fishing ban comes into effect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52da2612172243bdd59c8424d34d39b0</guid></item><item><title>ICC gives MCG pitch 'unsatisfactory' rating as two-day Test fallout continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/mcg-boxing-day-test-pitch-icc-verdict-unsatisfactory/106185382</link><description>The ICC has handed down their verdict on the controversial MCG pitch which led to this year's Boxing Day Test wrapping up after just two days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3eb403942ca3ba789e82b7d7f5975ab9</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says US offers Ukraine 15-year security guarantee as part of peace plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/us-ukraine-peace-plan-15-year-security-trump-zelenskyy/106185584</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy has held talks with US President Donald Trump, and says he would prefer a commitment of 50 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0aa54df231a7cd807859e7b8cfd504cc</guid></item><item><title>Hamas confirms death of ex-leader Mohammed Sinwar and spokesman Abu Ubaida</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/hamas-confirms-deaths-of-mohammed-sinwar-and-abu-ubaida/106185808</link><description>In a statement, the Palestinian militant group also confirmed the death of spokesman Abu Ubaida.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f362a4936393650952976ac9e08b35e</guid></item><item><title>Remembering the celebrities and public figures who died in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/celebrities-public-figures-who-died-2025-obituaries/105869472</link><description>From actors and designers to a Holocaust survivor and a broadcaster, these people made their mark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8ff6e8e6521b3764b05e9eb7af0051d</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 30: Beatles star George Harrison stabbed at home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/today-in-history-december-30-george-harrison-stabbed/106171844</link><description>Unlike his former bandmate John Lennon, George Harrison survived an attack by a fan, but the musician's friends and family speculated it hastened his death less than two years later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de21d23cf56392fd7ed419a58dc08c2</guid></item><item><title>Your most read ABC News stories of 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/your-most-read-abc-news-stories-of-2025/106150728</link><description>It was a year that bought us a federal election, ongoing war in the Middle East and Ukraine and a trial in a small Victorian town watched keenly around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0d7321c1ba593a47553562e53ff4f2d</guid></item><item><title>What happened when we tested a 'safe' AI mental health chatbot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/safe-mental-health-artificial-intelligence-chatgpt/106136202</link><description>Is it possible to make a "safe" AI therapy bot? We tested the limits of a new Australian-designed chatbot that's been carefully designed not to hallucinate or be your best friend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">845b6e5b1edf763fd5784d8b8777cd9e</guid></item><item><title>Household battery uptake booms on back of 'game-changer' rebate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/home-battery-uptake-soars-due-to-government-subsidy/106120730</link><description>Battery uptake is booming since the federal government rebate came into effect in July. Here's what you need to know if you are thinking of joining the thousands of Australians adding a battery to their home solar systems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30708c31c5d2c6ad77f5cc6b6d8e3c4c</guid></item><item><title>ASIC's remarkable turnaround as the tiger that found its teeth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/asic-the-tiger-that-found-its-teeth/106170504</link><description>After 20 years in the wilderness, the Australian Securities and Investments Commission's rehabilitation as a law enforcement agency seems almost complete.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f57bf412f7f38aa6ae3447a6261192d</guid></item><item><title>Josh Burns on juggling politics and fatherhood and being a Jewish MP</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/josh-burns-baby-federal-parliament-georgie-purcell-antisemitism/106162418</link><description>In a broad-ranging interview for the Politics Now podcast, the rising Labor star reveals he plans to take extended leave to care for his baby daughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79bb53732ced6ee8fa0288579b707fca</guid></item><item><title>Police search for alleged carjacker who was fought off by bystanders in inner Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/vic-police-investigate-carjack-attempt-richmond/106185972</link><description>Police are looking for a man who allegedly tried to steal a woman's car in Richmond earlier this year but was foiled by bystanders, including one person wielding a golf club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26e5e8466580c32f89d01a9fa9f34ac5</guid></item><item><title>Vision appears to show attempted carjacking in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/vision-appears-to-show-attempted-carjacking-in-melbourne/106186022</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9049f7aaa79bd452778e836be32f0bee</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill records seven earthquakes in 2025 — the most in recorded history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/broken-hill-records-seven-earthquakes-2025-most-recorded-history/106171264</link><description>It is not unheard of for the ground to shake in Broken Hill, but what is unusual is the number of earthquakes recorded by Geoscience Australia this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">326190426ea8ff0dda00f320deaf4623</guid></item><item><title>Transforming soft plastics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/transforming-soft-plastics/106185050</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6094f402939257049978e2d7b4f55c9d</guid></item><item><title>Soft plastics recycling is back in Australia. How does it work and where does it go?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/soft-plastics-recycling-is-back-in-australia-how-does-it-work-/105912070</link><description>Australia's first large-scale soft plastics recycling facility is processing huge loads each day, turning waste into a useful raw material.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d37c808f6bf403492a2a2b8dc150e76</guid></item><item><title>South-east Queensland's largest dam is 'full'. What does it mean?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/qld-how-wivenhoe-dam-works/106166620</link><description>South-east Queensland's largest water reservoir provides drinking water and protection from flooding. So, how does it all work?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f007ea1b086bd4b4b1ac973bbf0b4df</guid></item><item><title>Emergency warning issued as Cyclone Hayley nears WA's Kimberley coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/cyclone-hayley-strengthens-as-it-approaches-kimberley-coast/106184894</link><description>Tropical Cyclone Hayley continues to barrel towards the Dampier Peninsula on the Western Australian coast, where residents are being told to prepare for "severe impacts" when it makes landfall tonight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9170328b144f4be398818fe70b5d7545</guid></item><item><title>Hobart Hurricanes beat Melbourne Renegades thanks to vital cameo from Matthew Wade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/what-a-difference-a-wade-makes-as-canes-beat-renegades-in-bbl/106186014</link><description>Matthew Wade's fuss-free cameo helps Hobart chase down the Melbourne Renegades's 163 at Bellerive Oval, lifting the Hurricanes well clear of the pack in second spot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcdb9eef9e02f8f842aa649ae744602b</guid></item><item><title>Hiker Stella Thurbon leads herd of goats on trek through Victoria's High Country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/victorian-high-country-hiking-with-a-herd-of-goats/106119216</link><description>With bells tinkling, tails flicking, and panniers packed to the brim, adventurer Stella Thurbon has spent 26 days winding through the Victorian High Country with nine goats trotting faithfully behind her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6002a583dc507156847c083070b68f08</guid></item><item><title>Noongar elders say WA prescribed burn went ahead despite warnings of cultural heritage sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/noongar-elders-say-sacred-site-warnings-were-ignored-before-burn/106086072</link><description>Elders on WA's south coast say they tried to warn the state government about unregistered cultural sites in the path of a prescribed burn, but the burn went ahead anyway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c864bc1e20cca2ab1cdd845af6e7a45e</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says US 'knocked out' a 'big facility' in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/trump-says-us-knocked-out-big-facility-in-venezuela/106186078</link><description>A US strike on Venezuelan soil would be the first known land attack in the country since the Trump administration began ratcheting up pressure on its ruling regime, which Donald Trump accuses of "narco-terrorism".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f10cbadecf7188ee83cb32bce91c1d5</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police make more than 100 arrests, seize 30 weapons during first weeks of shopping centre operations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/vic-police-shopping-centre-arrests/106186088</link><description>A 15-year-old carrying a hunting knife was among more than 100 arrests during the first few weeks of a police operation at four of Melbourne's biggest shopping centres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eebe5b8532f4619245d8ae290a1bd689</guid></item><item><title>Charles Darwin University researchers leading the way in fight to protect globally threatened rays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/rapid-decline-rhino-ray-indonesia-northern-australia/106168084</link><description>Researchers from Charles Darwin University are leading the way in the fight to protect a group of globally threatened fish species, which look like "a shark and ray joined together".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d46b9b263f05e0812c8e68978b30e6a</guid></item><item><title>Deaf people saying no to cochlear implants choosing 'different way of seeing the world'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/cochlear-implants-debate-in-the-deaf-community/106044156</link><description>Cochlear implants can be a life-changing tool for people with hearing loss, but some Deaf people argue their use risks compromising their community's identity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c2c83166ba67cdac1d4df501e80252f</guid></item><item><title>Justice Department slammed for lack of strategic leadership as problems mount within WA prison system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/wa-justice-department-slammed-by-report-lack-of-leadership/106185476</link><description>A wide-ranging review into Western Australia's Justice Department finds that "forward planning is often overshadowed by immediate operational demands" which means it fails to address rising pressures like prison overcrowding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc650b98a523bb8c424d703f690ecca2</guid></item><item><title>Daria Kasatkina set for Brisbane International and Australian Open after mental health break</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/crowds-will-love-her-kasatkina-s-landmark-home-australian-open/106186126</link><description>Daria Kasatkina is being backed to return from her mental health break and quickly become a fan favourite at her new home grand slam, the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b501ed752fb06314d115d319194d988b</guid></item><item><title>How to celebrate New Year's Eve in Australia's capital cities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/new-years-eve-celebrations-and-fireworks-in-capital-cities/106184300</link><description>There are plenty of free events around the country to see out 2025 and welcome 2026. See what's happening in your city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3df11ee6558df8bcaf3428fcbe01e611</guid></item><item><title>The importance of preparing for death and creating an end-of-life health care plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/preparing-for-death-and-creating-an-end-of-life-health-care-plan/105886810</link><description>Dying in sudden, unexpected circumstances is not something people often consider, but there are plenty of reasons to create an end-of-life plan. So why do so few people have one?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5cd6645b8bb831142f96e95a26be9b7</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump calls for Hamas to disarm after meeting with Benjamin Netanyahu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/donald-trump-calls-hamas-disarm-netanyahu-meeting/106186218</link><description>The US president has been hosting Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu at his residence in Florida for talks on Gaza and several other issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32b65161fa32767ba4f01bfadf8d2ce8</guid></item><item><title>Overall Sydney to Hobart leader switches as boats race to get ahead of wind change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/tas-sydney-to-hobart-yacht-race-more-boats-finish/106186132</link><description>The two-person crewed BNC is the current favourite to secure an overall victory in the Sydney to Hobart, after crossing the finish line at 10:40 this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">156a49947e5d4819b67e8dd1ddb2c61b</guid></item><item><title>Metal detectorist discovers 1880s Zanzibar coin at Port Macquarie beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/1880s-zanzibar-coin-at-port-macquarie-beach-using-metal-detector/106184392</link><description>Metal detectorist Dale Oldham at first thought he had found a rusted Australian coin, until an online search revealed it was something much older and far more exotic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4210a4b87d548c95164d598de356af04</guid></item><item><title>NSW Parliament powerless to force witnesses to front inquiries after 19th-century laws struck down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nsw-parliament-powerless-to-force-witnesses-to-front-inquiries/106185518</link><description>The president of the NSW Legislative Council says he will not try to overturn a decision to strike down laws that purportedly allowed witnesses to be arrested for failing to appear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6d3dc528483abdb73cf850c25e53967</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania Fire Service confirms bushfire at Stieglitz near St Helens caused by household waste in fire pit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/stieglitz-st-helens-bushfire-caused-by-household-fire-pit/106186434</link><description>A fire that burnt through 1,200 hectares of vegetation and destroyed two houses started in a residential fire pit, Tasmanian authorities say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04f1c7859a3e272b2b75d816c9f8f0da</guid></item><item><title>It's backed by Maggie Beer and researchers alike, so why don't we eat more offal?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/eating-offal-and-why-we-should-eat-more/106093422</link><description>Despite becoming less popular in recent years, advocates like Maggie Beer say offal can be a delicacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46c988bca4e62653baff9eaa39fa9cbb</guid></item><item><title>Record number of NSW Police officers to patrol New Year's Eve events after Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nsw-police-increase-presence-at-new-years-eve-post-bondi-attack/106185980</link><description>More than 2,500 police officers will be out in force at New Year's Eve celebrations in Sydney in a bid to bolster revellers' confidence in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86ecb30515d3b6e2eea71ed64622d3aa</guid></item><item><title>Boxer Anthony Joshua involved in deadly car crash in Nigeria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/boxer-anthony-joshua-involved-in-deadly-car-crash-in-nigeria/106186500</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf762deb8912bbd1a5bb88546a70a37</guid></item><item><title>Former boxing world champion Anthony Joshua stable, two people dead after car crash in Nigeria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/boxer-anthony-joshua-stable-two-dead-fatal-car-crash-in-nigeria/106186330</link><description>Boxer Anthony Joshua escapes serious injury in a car crash in Nigeria that leaves two of his close friends and team members dead, a week after his multi-million-dollar fight with Jake Paul.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf62d02d3343abbd3ebcd09b72e73b66</guid></item><item><title>SA avoids major bushfire during extreme danger, but home and sheds destroyed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/sa-avoids-bushfire-during-extreme-danger-forecast/106186140</link><description>South Australia avoided a major bushfire as the state sweltered through a day of extreme danger on Monday, while two structure fires left a damage bill of $1 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ed19eec573ba107ba5711bfb40045ff</guid></item><item><title>China hasn't said it wants war in 2026. But it's showing the world it's ready for one</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/chinas-military-drills-around-taiwan-a-message-to-united-states/106186794</link><description>While Donald Trump was distracted, China launched its strongest-ever challenge against Taiwan. Beijing is showing it is ready for war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2396db44fea5a52c39bd09e3d8eb8a9c</guid></item><item><title>No evidence Bondi attack gunmen operated as part of a terror cell, AFP says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/bondi-attack-gunmen-operated-alone-afp/106186662</link><description>AFP Commissioner Krissy Barrett says there is no evidence the men were instructed to carry out the attack, which left 15 people dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84a0948716ba95899b69f3d9522c9b28</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire near Rockingham closes Mandurah train line, Warnbro station in Perth's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/fire-near-rockingham-closes-warnbro-train-station-and-train-line/106186550</link><description>A major train line and Warnbro station are closed as firefighters battle a bushfire burning near Rockingham in Perth's south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7509e8187abad58e22cf473c1439609e</guid></item><item><title>Ambulance Victoria reports increase in violence against paramedics over Christmas holiday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/violent-attacks-paramedics-christmas-period-ambulance-victoria/106186398</link><description>Ambulance Victoria says paramedics were assaulted, spat on and sexually harassed in a series of serious incidents over the festive period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6c96067a3fa4ada8769d73de5d41e88</guid></item><item><title>Shoppers spending billions on post-Christmas sales, but small retailers feel forgotten</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/spending-billions-post-christmas-sales-small-retailers-forgotten/106186838</link><description>Outlet centres around Australia were bustling on Boxing Day, but just down the road, some small retailers were feeling the sting. It's a trend that could shape the future of the Boxing Day sales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b88a27e6af003388ee98622e92bcc03e</guid></item><item><title>Donald Bradman's baggy green to go under the hammer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/donald-bradman-baggy-green-auction/106186852</link><description>A baggy green worn by Sir Donald Bradman during the 1947-48 series against India has gone to auction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45a4ea5f89b071b0f9bb4e2772af8c8b</guid></item><item><title>Nick Offerman hopes The Pout-Pout Fish delights tough child critics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nick-offerman-hopes-the-pout-pout-fish-will-delight-children/106185350</link><description>This Australian animation stars an international and local voice cast led by Nick Offerman and Nina Oyama, who can't wait for children to see the film.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0020d02c138202fc048dfeb5e6b91b11</guid></item><item><title>Coral Adventurer passengers begin journey home as cruise ship remains stranded on PNG reef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/coral-adventurer-passengers-begin-journey-home/106187482</link><description>Passengers of an Australian cruise ship that ran aground off the coast of Papua New Guinea have begun their journey home, as efforts to free the ship remain unsuccessful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1367a553c7dfdc2f4a388df36c7add99</guid></item><item><title>Gold, silver and palladium prices pull back sharply, worrying some economists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/precious-metals-gold-silver-palladium-crash/106187288</link><description>The price of palladium — used in electronics — tumbles from recent highs while the prices of other precious metals, including gold and silver, have also sharply declined in recent days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09492488be8fcdcec44fb283fd56f0fb</guid></item><item><title>Women wearing hijabs targeted in anti-Muslim abuse post-Bondi attack, says Imams Council</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/rise-in-islamophobic-incidents-post-bondi-beach-terror-attack/106186118</link><description>There are concerns women wearing hijabs are bearing the brunt of a "horrifying" wave of Islamophobia in the wake of the Bondi Beach terrorist attack, with the Australian National Imams Council reporting a rise of hate incidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d913d18ca4a43c398b550fff985d2d8</guid></item><item><title>Floods across western and northern parts of Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/floods-across-western-and-northern-parts-of-queensland/106187600</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">719b935069868e22b9576efd64e88ee7</guid></item><item><title>A bushfire is burning close to homes in the City of Rockingham in Perth's south.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/bushfire-burning-in-city-of-rockingham/106187704</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">638a510ce4d30fbc061dfca151360ee5</guid></item><item><title>Impact of abbreviated Boxing Day Test stretches far beyond the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/mcg-pitch-boxing-day-test-two-days-losses/106184878</link><description>The economic and social impact of the Boxing Day Test reaches far past the pitch and the repercussions of the two-day finish rippled all across Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d2b4fc5df4f281402988170ecdfbd88</guid></item><item><title>Police search for alleged carjacker who broke into Latrobe Valley home with axe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/carjacking-theft-breaking-entry-axe-moondarra/106187634</link><description>Police are combing eastern Victorian bushland for a man they allege broke into a house with an axe and stole multiple cars in the Latrobe Valley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2ed44a68fe403cc81cd1aded69d4818</guid></item><item><title>MH370 vanished in 2014. A new search aims to find answers families desperately want</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/mh370-search-resumes-for-malaysia-airlines-missing-plane/106186962</link><description>Malaysia Airlines missing flight MH370, which vanished in 2014, remains one of aviation's enduring mysteries. A new search is aiming to provide answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cb79e844eeb1b7e91d3be489f74d30c</guid></item><item><title>Russia's claim Ukraine attacked Putin's home 'doesn't make any sense', experts say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/putin-drone-strike-ukraine-experts-say-no-evidence-russia/106187456</link><description>A defence analyst tells the ABC an attack on the Russian President's state residence would be "technically" possible but would not make sense strategically for Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0818e8fdaab6370d04a12fe2c8e511f1</guid></item><item><title>NT Environment Protection Authority orders Santos, Inpex licence conditions review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/nt-epa-santos-inpex-licence-review-emissions-error/106185488</link><description>The Northern Territory environment regulator will re-examine the licence conditions of major gas facilities in Darwin, after one of its biggest operators admitted to under-reporting potentially toxic emissions at its Ichthys LNG plant on Darwin Harbour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366601fe83aede9fa18c4a99b62dc8eb</guid></item><item><title>Khaleda Zia, Bangladesh's first female prime minister, dead at 80</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/khaleda-zia-bangladesh-first-female-prime-minister-dead/106187666</link><description>Begum Khaleda Zia was leader of the main opposition Bangladesh Nationalist Party which was seen as the frontrunner to win the next parliamentary election in February.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bbe92168a4742ebaf2972720cbe6e25</guid></item><item><title>Australian laws changed in six important ways in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/australian-laws-change-ubereats-pets-sovereign-citizens/106187302</link><description>From food delivery to sovereign citizens, Australia's laws underwent some important changes this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a18d0b9e12e643b0d2c323088a0972dd</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide public transport, stations and interchanges join list of declared public precincts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/adelaide-public-transport-join-list-of-declared-public-precincts/106187762</link><description>Police have been given expanded powers to search people for weapons on every public bus, train and tram in the Adelaide metropolitan area ahead of New Year Eve's celebrations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">152f1e795e6672267dd0734ad7fde0a8</guid></item><item><title>The man was arrested in 2024 at his previous suburban residence for his role in the people smuggling scheme.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/people-smuggler-arrest-darwin/106187328</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17d2e1c7359a7fabbcc94c9cbd512310</guid></item><item><title>Here's what we know about the Coral Adventurer, the cruise ship that ran aground in PNG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/coral-adventurer-ran-aground-papua-new-guinea-explainer/106187276</link><description>The Coral Adventurer was carrying 80 tourists into the remote reaches of Papua New Guinea when it came to an abrupt halt on a reef off the Pacific nation's coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c0becda7da09f9389e9cdce6adf9424</guid></item><item><title>Bizzi Lavelle uncovers the hidden history of Blak burlesque in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/blak-burlesque-bizzi-body-lavelle/106148190</link><description>Bizzi Lavelle, a Queer Wakka Wakka and Arrernte writer and burlesque dancer known in the scene as Bizzi Body, is reclaiming the hidden legacy of this art-form one tassel twirl at a time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c77f27ecf9f0afac3611eda7ff1d27f</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian youth alleged to have 'large amount' of child exploitation material on phone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/youth-charged-child-exploitation-material-kik-messaging/106188268</link><description>Police have charged a southern Tasmanian youth after allegedly discovering a "large amount of serious child exploitation material" on his phone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5ddcacaf37a38b865771841a4fa655d</guid></item><item><title>An emergency-level fire came close to the Albemarle Kemerton plant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/fire-near-albemarle-kemerton-plant/106188330</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f227910294908307e103f1fddf71406</guid></item><item><title>A bushfire is burning close to homes in the City of Rockingham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/city-of-rockingham-fire-comes-close-to-homes/106188486</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d59c48cc8c7e65d5089c1ce0473ae1b1</guid></item><item><title>BNC, on brink of historic Sydney Hobart yacht race victory, faces a protest by rival Min River</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/protest-lodged-against-bnc-by-min-river/106188442</link><description>The two-person crewed yacht on the brink of winning the prestigious overall handicap prize in the Sydney to Hobart race is the subject of a protest by a rival, which could potentially deny it victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d63456818dfe61babc72bd9a6cf26b7</guid></item><item><title>Woodford Folk Festival's 38th year platforming Australian artists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/woodford-folk-festivals-thirty-eighth-year/106186650</link><description>More than 110,000 people have already walked through the gates of Woodfordia to be entertained by the 450-plus acts scheduled across the six-day folk festival — now in its 38th year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34d9f8a0bd0948cdb3228890b917263a</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Hayley downgraded to tropical low after thrashing remote Kimberley coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/severe-tropical-cyclone-hayley-crosses-kimberley-coast-downgrade/106187730</link><description>The storm has been downgraded after bringing severe winds and heavy rain to parts of the north-west Kimberley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a342d42e4452f6224ae78f5d24249f17</guid></item><item><title>South Korea bans bear bile farming with jail for those who breach the law</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/south-korea-bans-bear-bile-farming/106188716</link><description>South Korea is one of the few countries that allow farming to extract bile from bears, for traditional medicine or food believed to promote vitality and stamina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0a7ab9247aa9d1b35313e29e81bf61f</guid></item><item><title>Eurostar train services cancelled across Europe due to power issue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-30/eurostar-trains-to-paris-london-brussels-amsterdam-cancelled/106188734</link><description>A disruption on Tuesday prompted the rail company to request train customers postpone their journeys until another time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de3ccb9beca340e7942d3ba01eaf20c9</guid></item><item><title>Christmas cruise ends in chaos as Coral Adventurer passengers return home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/christmas-cruise-png-passengers-return-coral-adventurer/106186660</link><description>About 80 passengers on the Coral Adventurer are flown home after the cruise ship ran aground on a reef off Papua New Guinea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a12b92f399d1d29cd366ffaec633591</guid></item><item><title>UAE withdraws personnel from Yemen after Saudi Arabia air strikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/uae-saudi-arabia-yemen-strikes-port-weapons-shipment/106188568</link><description>The UAE has denied shipping weapons to Yemeni separatists after Saudi-led forces said they had bombed arms at the port city of Mukalla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c078ab15b8e1439c28c250f2d124813</guid></item><item><title>ABC Sports Quiz: The year that was 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/the-year-in-sports-quiz/106177164</link><description>It was another big year in sport, with Ashes series, world cups, world championships and a long-awaited comeback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ed43ddbfba2df7c7423250423ebb073</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 31: Vladimir Putin rises to power in Russia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/today-in-history-december-31-vladimir-putin-becomes-president/106174780</link><description>Vladimir Putin has towered over politics in Russia since ascending to the country's top office, initially as president for eight years, then as prime minister until that pesky thing called the constitution could be altered to allow him to run again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">456b7f4837ec6687b85010b33b25ff10</guid></item><item><title>The operators issuing fake corporate licences in the name of a tiny African island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/fake-gambling-licenses-anjouan-casinos/106158766</link><description>An ABC investigation has identified several individuals involved in a network of illegitimate corporate regulators and service firms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6913a0e20625d4f29bd0a7d2685cdb5</guid></item><item><title>Kakadu traditional owner says nature has long warned us about rising sea levels</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/nt-kakadu-sea-level-rise-climate-change-saltwater-intrusion/105752820</link><description>In wet season, Jonathan and his family have to drive, boat and drive again if they want to reach town. The remote NT traditional owner says nature has long been warning us about climate change, "but nobody's listening".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c61221d7a7e419755ea7ae07c0f7c52c</guid></item><item><title>Crowd-funding business campaigns falter, despite demand for tipple</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/gluten-free-craft-beer-a-healthier-option-for-drinks-investors-/106175338</link><description>Brewer Richard Jeffares's Victorian company raised about $2.5 million from 993 investors in a matter of days through a method called crowd-sourced funding, also known as equity crowdfunding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77f4b9ad49108a481dfc9b7c3a62283e</guid></item><item><title>Sportsbet pressured key watchdog into 'watering down' enforcement announcement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/sportsbet-pressure-acma-enforcement-announcement/106137264</link><description>Gambling giant Sportsbet pressured the Australian Communications and Media Authority into "watering down" enforcement announcement, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e01de2479c7e314611904a13ca22f4dd</guid></item><item><title>Human-operated Tokyo robot venture allows housebound people to work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/tokyo-robot-tourism-business-cafe-housebound-workers/106177054</link><description>Ory Yoshifuji's Tokyo business employs housebound individuals to operate robots as waitstaff at a cafe and as personal tour guides in the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee5510266f87235181771f4e5e3fa9b7</guid></item><item><title>What should you do during a violent mass attack?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/what-should-you-do-violent-mass-attack/106179978</link><description>The mass shooting in Bondi and other incidents of mass violence around the world have highlighted that violence can strike anywhere. Here are some expert tips on how to escape, hide, and stay safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c0de6bec2b16cb24966fa699f71bc8d</guid></item><item><title>Denmark becomes first country in world to end letter delivery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/denmark-postal-service-ends-letter-delivery/106188988</link><description>After 401 years, the Danish postal service has ended letter deliveries as the country fully embraces the digital age.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">527b1a7416978fbdc459d389b139e4a2</guid></item><item><title>Robbers steal $52 million from vault of German savings bank</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/robbers-steal-cash-jewellery-from-vault-of-german-savings-bank/106189018</link><description>According to police, the robbers drilled their way into the underground vault room of the savings bank from a parking garage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7000310909990d0892876846e48a929c</guid></item><item><title>For many South Australians, 2025 could be summarised as the year of searching for answers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/sa-2025-year-in-review-and-search-for-answers/106124586</link><description>As 2025 draws to a close and we look back at the stories that made headlines, for South Australians the year could be summarised as one where we searched for answers, with little results.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b594d8b07c4ab5c74b725ddbde48dc15</guid></item><item><title>Mechanic shortage driving Queensland businesses to look overseas for qualified workers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/qld-mechanic-shortages/106146022</link><description>The automotive repair industry says it is dealing with a major labour and skills shortage, and some mechanics are looking overseas for workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">677120ce168a39db717bbf44351334a6</guid></item><item><title>ASX ends 'stressful' year with gold and lithium stocks surging despite Trump's trade war threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/asx-ends-stressful-year-with-gold-and-lithium-stocks-surging/106188730</link><description>Several gold, lithium and other mining stocks have seen their share price double, and even triple, in 2025 as Australia's share market has had a much better than expected year despite tariffs, economic uncertainty and Donald Trump's ongoing unpredictability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d40112e062ed5ea83214da84bcdd4bb8</guid></item><item><title>Tatiana Schlossberg, granddaughter of John F Kennedy, dies aged 35</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/jfk-granddaughter-tatiana-schlossberg-dies-aged-35/106189118</link><description>Tatiana Schlossberg revealed in an essay published in November that she had a rare form of terminal leukaemia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">176bba8f13d8b78546e3a13fb3b4b903</guid></item><item><title>Perth Scorchers beat Sydney Thunder by 71 runs in Sydney, Ashton Turner stuck on 99 not out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/turner-stranded-short-of-ton-but-helps-rescue-perths-bbl-season/106189062</link><description>Ashton Turner narrowly misses out on a maiden BBL century as he helps launch Perth to a crucial 71-run win over the Sydney Thunder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8ffa1058e51dd04680c54d7caa49dc7</guid></item><item><title>Flocks of tourists dubbed the 'koala paparazzi' putting animals at risk in Byron Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/tourist-put-byron-bay-koalas-at-risk/106183054</link><description>Large crowds of tourists gather daily at the bottom of trees home to koalas in Byron Bay, leaving the animals stressed and their habitat trampled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb3d6a084b9bc480d26fa3ad7329d0bf</guid></item><item><title>Record year for Australian beef exports despite Donald Trump's tariffs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/record-year-for-aussie-beef-despite-trump-tariffs/106188120</link><description>When Donald Trump enforced a 10 per cent tariff on Australian beef, there were some concerns it would impact trade. But the opposite happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9906a7cbfa515375f6e8f5ee77ad5126</guid></item><item><title>Calls for tighter regulations after Woodside knowingly shed plastic into ocean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/woodside-knowingly-sheds-plastic-into-ocean/106184338</link><description>Documents reveal one of Australia's biggest oil and gas companies knowingly shed plastic into the ocean for two months before notifying the offshore regulator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62d064ab98b320241c481f7d14c044db</guid></item><item><title>Flooding claims a life as deluge cuts north-west Queensland roads, isolates towns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/major-flood-warnings-in-north-west-queensland-towns-isolated/106186966</link><description>Police have renewed warnings about driving in floodwaters after a tragedy in Queensland's Gulf Country as the region endures a fourth day of drenching rain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe978e32493bddcc48a21b19b4ff485e</guid></item><item><title>What are the new rules in 2026? Here's what's changing from New Year's Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/2026-new-rules-laws-regulations-come-into-effect/106186738</link><description>New Year's Day brings a host of new laws, regulations and guidelines into effect. Here's a quick breakdown of some of the changes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a403392408ee586524631c7c64585ec2</guid></item><item><title>AI technology gives swimming pool lifeguards an extra set of eyes this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/ai-system-to-help-lifeguards-in-pools-swim-safety/106172140</link><description>An AI system used in 120 public pools across Australia analyses swimmers' movements and sends an alert to a lifeguard's smartwatch if it detects someone in trouble.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4981359265166fe70bf2f7d449ec0d3b</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen wins F1 Driver of the Year award for fifth straight year, Oscar Piastri comes fourth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/f1-title-runner-up-verstappen-driver-of-the-year-five-in-row/106189130</link><description>Max Verstappen may not have won the F1 world title, but his fast finish to the year wins him Driver of the Year for the fifth straight year, while Oscar Piastri's disappointing end to the season is mirrored in the voting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">139a9f7e6a9116fb2078199393ba0042</guid></item><item><title>Russia claims nuclear-capable Oreshnik missiles have been deployed in Belarus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/russia-deploys-missiles-in-belarus/106189110</link><description>Belarusian President Alexander Lukashenko, a staunch ally of the Kremlin, announced the deployment of the Oreshnik intermediate-range ballistic missiles earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99fce8983aa1195491b577050eab8701</guid></item><item><title>Photos that captured the stories and people of regional WA in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/best-photos-of-2025-from-regional-western-australia/105974722</link><description>The stunning photos that captured the stories and people of regional WA in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77794688fd2b15f70f60c4b54130b9bb</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill gardeners chop down trees in battle with Queensland fruit fly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/fruit-fly-war-in-broken-hill/106179748</link><description>There was no fruit fly to be found in Broken Hill 20 years ago, but now gardeners are facing an uphill battle trying to rid themselves of the pest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce1af482ebd6c6b880eb979a75966489</guid></item><item><title>Calls for national strategy to tackle apprentice hazing and protect workers’ mental health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/tradie-apprentice-workplace-hazing-mental-health-advocates/106173610</link><description>TV presenter and former builder Barry Du Bois is lobbying Canberra for change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f8c43af3c57b7d491903a3ea007e37a</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire near Rockingham in Perth's south contained but not controlled as second WA blaze downgraded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/perth-bushfire-disruption-lingers-as-second-wa-blaze-downgraded/106189234</link><description>More than 140 firefighters spend a second night battling an out-of-control blaze near Rockingham, in Perth's southern suburbs, as an emergency warning for a second fire in WA's South West is downgraded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cfdb9e764a96bdda1f5931b015f6a88</guid></item><item><title>Costumes of Kylie, Rihanna, Lady Gaga, Amy Taylor and more showcased in new DIVA exhibition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/diva-at-ampa-costumes-kylie-rihanna-lady-gaga-marilyn-monroe/106037508</link><description>The exhibition at Melbourne's newest museum, featuring Kylie Minogue's catsuit and Elton John's Louis XIV-inspired 50th birthday outfit, celebrates the power of divas through time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18fbf72148bca9ca91ccd98753dab43b</guid></item><item><title>Min River takes out overall win in 2025 Sydney to Hobart Yacht Race after protest against BNC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/min-river-wins-overall-2025-sydney-to-hobart-successful-protest/106188552</link><description>Double-handed Min River makes history by becoming the first double-handed yacht to take out the overall win in the Sydney to Hobart Yacht Race and the first to do so with a female skipper.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c04f34eb3c878f18a3957e11bc219faf</guid></item><item><title>Race committee chair Lee Goddard announces the protest has been upheld</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/race-chair-says-protest-upheld/106189618</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c1274e13028dfb31d90a98609e92d1b</guid></item><item><title>Former Australian Test batsman Damien Martyn in an induced coma with meningitis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/former-australian-cricketer-damien-martyn-in-induced-coma/106189352</link><description>Former Australian Test and limited overs batsman Damien Martyn is in hospital in Queensland in an induced coma after falling ill this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">000eccb538931e74b5a025d77acd4b72</guid></item><item><title>Promise of bumper coffee crop in 2026 fuelled by explosion of white flowers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/australian-coffee-growers-hope-for-bumper-2026-crop/106177198</link><description>Australian coffee growers are hoping for a bumper 2026 season to meet increased demand for homegrown beans following a prolific flowering season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbc7154a6a59404143386fbf87463625</guid></item><item><title>Revellers gather at sites across Australia for New Year's Eve celebrations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/new-years-eve-revellers-celebrate-across-australia/106189124</link><description>Revellers are gathering to farewell 2025 at various sites across Australia's major cities, including Sydney, where there is a heavy police presence in the wake of the Bondi terror attack earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dfee4cfec47ce3e7087223ef94f3b9c</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Alex Hartley responds to criticism for talking about period on BBC commentary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/alex-hartley-period-chat-bbc-cricket-ashes-commentary/106189540</link><description>Alex Hartley says she was stunned by the reaction to her talking about her period during the BBC's radio commentary of the third Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da608c2e7fa4ac5a89d0568184e22de6</guid></item><item><title>Tom Kenny and Mark Hamill on SpongeBob's 'multi-generational appeal'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/tom-kenny-and-mark-hamill-on-spongebob-s-multi-/106189750</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50a2d7b4d8bdb50f66300432f070d28c</guid></item><item><title>Min River's Jiang Lin says it's unbelievable to be the first winning female skipper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/jiang-lee-first-winning-female-skipper/106189876</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0f91f9de45f91d891ae7349c59607da</guid></item><item><title>BNC lost Sydney to Hobart race honours due to use of pole extending past the boat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/sailing-breach-by-bnc/106189948</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2713dd670d895ee60db35bc0cd27de6</guid></item><item><title>'White Australia' flyer letterbox drop in Newcastle sparks police investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/racist-pamphlets-spark-police-investigation/106189416</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns said police would "throw the book" at anyone behind flyers distributed to inner-city Newcastle letterboxes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e058794461c7b877b4797f33d91d706</guid></item><item><title>Crown casino workers in Melbourne announce New Year's Eve strike amid wage row</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/crown-casino-melbourne-workers-strike-new-years-eve/106189942</link><description>About 500 workers at Melbourne's Crown casino will stop work tonight after rejecting a proposal they say will cut pay for new workers and imperil those currently employed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1995448a5ba1b50a8e7da28493f0585</guid></item><item><title>Dolphin Sands residents report looting after bushfire destroys 19 homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/dolphin-sands-residents-concerned-at-looting/106189822</link><description>After 19 homes were destroyed by bushfire in a picturesque east coast Tasmanian community, residents are now reporting instances of looting — described by the state premier as "disgraceful".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1647caee500a6e79557f02b539f1ea03</guid></item><item><title>Kimberley homes lose roofs as emergency services respond to ex-Tropical Cyclone Hayley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/ex-tropical-cyclone-hayley-clean-up-begins-as-damage-assessed/106189586</link><description>Emergency services travel to the Dampier Peninsula to assess the damage caused by the category three system, which crossed the coast on Tuesday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a30f8c7a35af88a6b89594b754b5970f</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos striker Martin Boyle in injury blow for Hibernian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/socceroos-striker-martin-boyle-in-injury-blow-for-hibs/106190128</link><description>Martin Boyle, no stranger to the heartache of missing major tournaments with the Socceroos, was taken off after injuring his hamstring for Hibernian in the Scottish Premiership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">555f74d5c866789a8613eb2631799bd4</guid></item><item><title>One dead in train crash near Machu Picchu, tourists among dozens injured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/train-crash-near-machu-picchu-leaves-one-dead-and-dozens-injured/106190060</link><description>A head-on collision between two tourist trains near Peru's most famous landmark kills a train driver and injures dozens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec4bcfa91be11609dfdef3ab0395747c</guid></item><item><title>Australia's top glassmakers are the focus of the exhibition Glass Chrysalis II</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/chrysalis-glassmaking-wagga-art-gallery-exhibition/105938918</link><description>The art of glassblowing was popularised in a recent reality TV series, but these Australian artists are forging their own paths in the creative process of sculpting this tricky medium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f5563b4d86d0813f53f80d3286c4f6f</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's new public child sex offender register now live under Daniel's Law</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/queensland-s-new-public-child-sex-offender-register-is-now-live/106189810</link><description>Queenslanders can search their local area for reportable sex offenders by providing proof of identification.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd12cba030448c6da7a5e58fd1bbe93b</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Alfred, exam bungles and revenge debt: Your most read Queensland stories of 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/qld-abc-stories-most-read-news-2025/106187722</link><description>From cyclones to earthquakes and everything in between, here are the most read Queensland ABC News stories of 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd585e3eb9bb7d083bd55f38c4afffb5</guid></item><item><title>Emergency workers carry away the injured after Machu Picchu train collision</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/emergency-workers-carry-away-the-injured/106190328</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">622193914e686084171d15825d1209ad</guid></item><item><title>Muslim community members sleep in mosques as Islamophobic threats rise after Bondi mass shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/islamophobic-attacks-surge-after-bondi-mass-shooting/106187910</link><description>A rise in Islamophobic incidents prompts warnings from Muslim organisations that their communities are at risk of "retribution" and "collective punishment" following the mass shooting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a32c72b67a14940c60a4c6ff3587ddad</guid></item><item><title>Sunshine Coast live music venue The Station to shut down as event bookings drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/sunshine-coast-live-music-venue-the-station-to-shut-down/106189286</link><description>The Sunshine Coast's largest live music venue is shutting down, with the owners stating that they need double the number of bookings to stay afloat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ea077bcc6921d955c042e0e909479a4</guid></item><item><title>Alleged car thief, home invader found after two-day police hunt in Latrobe Valley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/car-theft-axe-break-in-latrobe-moondarra/106189590</link><description>The two-day police search for a man who allegedly went on a crime spree in Latrobe Valley has ended with a stolen car crashing through a garden wall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7de9a11a6706a15804d853fce29442c8</guid></item><item><title>How BNC lost the Sydney to Hobart after 'silly mistake' breaches sailing rule</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/explainer-how-bnc-lost-sydney-to-hobart-overall-prize/106189890</link><description>They should be celebrating a historic win — instead, the crew of BNC is coming to terms with how a "silly mistake" cost them the "crown jewel" prize of Sydney to Hobart overall handicap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaef1d7662aba3eb3b6c2beed60e0a1c</guid></item><item><title>BNC co-skippers Yann Rigal and Michel Quintin react to protest result</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/bnc-skippers-react-to-protest-ruling/106189778</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">476d6775436acf5938c6b541ea47c3ff</guid></item><item><title>Driver in hit and run that killed woman on Darwin's Bagot road remains at large</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/darwin-hit-and-run-nt-police-investigation-continues/106190254</link><description>The search for a hit-and-run driver who allegedly struck and killed a 27-year-old Indigenous woman on one of Darwin's busiest main roads continues into its fifth day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16412ac2271ea486d0598b6b384b161b</guid></item><item><title>Pet owner's warning as dogs fall ill after beach visit amid algal bloom crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/dogs-fall-ill-ater-visiting-adelaide-beach-algal-bloom/106189458</link><description>Within 20 minutes of leaving an Adelaide beach dogs Lucy and Ella began breathing rapidly and fell "terribly sick", prompting their owner to issue a warning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6cf99b006e293aeae1a112225b2e336</guid></item><item><title>Car culture rolling strong in SA as unofficial event attracts thousands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/car-culture-rolling-strong-in-sa-as-event-attracts-thousands/106190230</link><description>Despite becoming unofficial several years ago, a community-driven event has attracted about 1,000 drivers and even more spectators in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c630030177e46471f9316c8b9221c96d</guid></item><item><title>Man drowns and boy missing after boat capsizes at Palm Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/man-drowns-at-palm-beach-sydney-new-years-eve/106190220</link><description>Police confirmed one man has drowned and a 14-year-old boy is missing after their boat capsized at Palm Beach on Sydney's Northern Beaches, with a search and rescue helicopter continuing to search the area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fbf5c54becdf54104160c141ae98e91</guid></item><item><title>Felix Auger-Aliassime hopes for deep Australian Open run after career-best year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/felix-auger-aliassime-united-cup-australian-open/106190574</link><description>After his best year on tour, Canadian star Felix Auger-Aliassime is looking to keep his hot streak running in the United Cup and at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df826417b7ef14f9689a9f9bbaa440aa</guid></item><item><title>Protests in Iran as inflation takes hold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/protests-in-iran-as-inflation-takes-hold/106190568</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">915e9b51b0a209d705134b983a3bb378</guid></item><item><title>Iranian president admits protesters have 'legitimate demands' as inflation fuels unrest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/iran-protesters-have-legitimate-demands-as-inflation-unrest/106190426</link><description>Protests over soaring prices and a collapsing currency are spreading across Iran, with students joining shopkeepers in calling on the government to take action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3a939c8c47bfe3e8dec28488760218e</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday Finance with Dan Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/wednesday-finance-with-dan-ziffer/106190736</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de67f028c9f77fb97d0d9c7d55d8191b</guid></item><item><title>Charges laid over alleged threats to The Age journalist Nick McKenzie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/journalist-nick-mckenzie-threats-police/106190734</link><description>Investigators from a taskforce targeting crime in the construction industry say a 31-year-old man threatened journalist Nick McKenzie in a Christmas Eve call.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">967ad6bb464da57a02f93be8e3db3794</guid></item></channel></rss>