<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 10:07:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Inside the brand strategy behind the Beckham family drama — and who controls the narrative now</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/inside-the-brand-strategy-behind-the-beckham-family-drama/106284834</link><description>In a modern crisis, experts say control doesn't always come from speaking louder — but from knowing when, where and how briefly to speak at all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02c12da6214ed41b16eafa530a0cd912</guid></item><item><title>Half of Adelaide University's Magill campus to be sold for housing, retirement units, aged care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/magill-university-campus-to-be-sold-for-housing-aged-care/106292672</link><description>South Australia's premier announces the future of Adelaide University's Magill campus, which sits on the boundary of two marginal Liberal-held electorates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e193029ad44654085cb191cee6aa9ce</guid></item><item><title>Where in your home is best to set up a work space?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/where-is-best-to-set-up-home-office-workspace/106279734</link><description>From garages to cupboards, we asked experts on things to consider before you choose where to set up a home office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">737207bd9fb86c2996d3d75fd5c289aa</guid></item><item><title>Found a PCOS 'cure' on social media? It might not be for you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/pcos-cures-myths-and-other-mistruths-to-be-wary-of/106286496</link><description>Advice on how to "manage", "treat" and "heal" PCOS is easy to come by online, but experts say a more personalised approach is usually what's needed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38340fdb3fa30f7c96f4dea3e5531ef0</guid></item><item><title>How decluttering your digital streaming subscriptions can save you money this year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/how-decluttering-your-digital-subscriptions-can-save-you-money/106294296</link><description>With Australian households now holding an average of 3.7 digital entertainment subscriptions each, doing an audit on what you're using and whether it's providing value can be a good place to start when looking to cut costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c13fa3915e6c9c3a59644cc8b377541</guid></item><item><title>Should I take a fish oil supplement for my heart, joints or mood?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/should-take-fish-oil-supplement-heart-joints-mood/106281540</link><description>Fish oil is one of the most popular dietary supplements. It's often promoted for protecting the heart, boosting mood, reducing inflammation, and supporting overall health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65db459e18e709e4acbdb0e1c9cf9b19</guid></item><item><title>Citizen scientists look for hope as the algal bloom persists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/kangaroo-island-citizen-scientists-algal-bloom-fight-sa/106131388</link><description>On Kangaroo Island – where the bloom has washed death ashore for almost a year – a group of citizen scientists are focusing their efforts on "what’s still out there".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86498380fc9493692055ee20a3b6a5ed</guid></item><item><title>Children with brain cancer given hope in trial of personalised vaccines across eight Australian hospitals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/brain-cancer-vaccine-trial-for-children/106294532</link><description>The four-year trial of about 70 children with "dismal prognoses" in eight hospitals across Australia will test the safety and effectiveness of the experimental treatment designed to harness the immune system to attack a child's tumour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd9820b0bf9253cde4f11cb68c42b639</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Ferguson offered Jeffrey Epstein woman with 'great body' after his release from prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/sarah-ferguson-emails-to-jeffrey-epstein-revealed/106302466</link><description>Emails contained in the Epstein files show former British royal Sarah Ferguson told the convicted child sex offender she knew a "single" woman with a "great body" he should meet, weeks after his 2009 release from prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8216f6d90bb222bab0daa5d9f345c016</guid></item><item><title>Drought-affected SA farmers able to access low-interest loans of up to $250,000</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/south-australia-government-low-interest-loans-farmers-drought/105129392</link><description>The SA government has stepped in with an "unprecedented" offer of direct low-interest loans to farmers hit hard by years of drought.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55741a05a8befe715a8b0655de10e0cc</guid></item><item><title>Up to 100,000 dead fish found on bank of Lake Menindee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/fish-kill-on-sunset-strip-shores-near-menindee/106302904</link><description>Residents of a far west New South Wales community found tens of thousands of dead fish on the banks of Lake Menindee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cb838985300290e2945ea85c41c9eb9</guid></item><item><title>Australian man Michael 'Micky' Hurst dies in Japan while skiing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/second-australian-dies-skiing-in-japan/106304484</link><description>Michael Hurst had a medical episode and died on the slopes in Hokkaido, making it three Australians in total that have died in Japan this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59bf4fadabbac5f06ebeb80894f1c005</guid></item><item><title>K'gari traditional owners hold smoking ceremony for Piper James on beach where she died</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/kgari-traditional-owners-hold-smoking-ceremony-for-piper-james/106283182</link><description>K'gari traditional owners have held a smoking ceremony for Piper James, who died on the island last month, to give her spirit a safe passage home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5195525635f75c9bb6c42ce2a24571ea</guid></item><item><title>Report points to exploitation, Medicare and visa concerns in Pacific islander jobs scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/palm-scheme-report-calls-for-change/106298514</link><description>Changing jobs is a basic right for most people, but it is not so simple for Pacific Australia Labour Mobility workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f21909b4c4949bb2d5b3a261ebd665c</guid></item><item><title>Grandmother removed from Toowoomba birth suite by security</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/nolr-hospitalcctvv3-0302-1-/106301434</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c66ca699e9beaede50daa31210346e5</guid></item><item><title>Australians in Japan say ski fields are safe after spate of deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/australians-in-japan-say-ski-fields-are-safe/106307558</link><description>Australians working in Japan's ski fields say while the sport has unpredictable risks, there are ways to be prepared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39a03324b4a4d2e1f6d635af5d43a345</guid></item><item><title>Russian captain of cargo ship Solong jailed over fatal North Sea collision</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/north-sea-collision-captain-jailed/106311942</link><description>A judge describes Vladimir Motin as "an accident waiting to happen" as he hands the Russian national a six-year jail term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87a1a23caacdafe5b4045a3c3b2ae840</guid></item><item><title>What Israel's President Isaac Herzog has said about Gaza, and why he won't be arrested in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/herzog-will-be-aware-controversy-wont-be-arrested-in-australia/106311734</link><description>When Israel's president lands in Australia this weekend, he can expect an official red carpet treatment. But he will be all too aware of the controversy his visit is generating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ffdecd9e59cf515e239536238754ac7</guid></item><item><title>Nearly 70 people rescued from New York ski mountain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/nearly-70-people-rescued-from-new-york-ski-mountain-gondolas/106312400</link><description>Rescuers have saved nearly 70 skiers who were stranded for hours, with some trapped up to 21 metres in the air, after a gondola malfunction in New York.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">261f6081b37000bb87f9f8c9e7dbfaa1</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Snook, The Newsreader and Bring Her Back triumph at AACTA Awards — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/aacta-awards-2026-live-blog-winners-sarah-snook-celeste-barber/106295178</link><description>Australia's answer to the Oscars — the AACTAs — lit up the Gold Coast tonight, with horror Bring Her Back and The Narrow Road to the Deep North dominating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">473742d5b25ca33648f2c7c0647748d5</guid></item><item><title>Pentagon reportedly asked to probe SpaceX for potential Chinese ownership seen as a 'national security threat'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/pentagon-asked-to-probe-spacex-chinese-ownership/106311868</link><description>Chinese investment in Elon Musk's company SpaceX has been cited as a "national security threat", according to senators Elizabeth Warren and Andy Kim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a14c66ba0a91388f5002547f0fc8165b</guid></item><item><title>Meringandan collector sells vintage tractors, trucks, machines on Queensland farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/meringandan-collector-sells-vintage-tractors-trucks-machines-qld/106305032</link><description>As the last man standing, 78-year-old cattleman Mervyn has parted with his collection of tractors and utes, pledging his estate to charity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">467219dc24b07990a0bbb37f1d3c6d41</guid></item><item><title>Tanker crash just off the M1 Motorway at Ourimbah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/nolr-ourimbahcrash-0402-1-/106303244</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d89f5d364e7ae58bfca114fa86ae61f</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania looks at allowing public hospital midwives to help with homebirths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/tasmania-looks-at-homebirth-model/105899984</link><description>The Tasmanian government is developing a public homebirth model that would allow midwives working in the public system to support women to labour from their homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b288cd9590708ea54ac6e8efd974f327</guid></item><item><title>Man dead, five others hospitalised after Sydney's Dreamstate music festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/nsw-dreamstate-man-dead-five-hospitalised-sydney/106318948</link><description>Several people suffered "medical episodes" at the trance music festival at Sydney's Olympic Park, according to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb0b81cbc6c892cc70ef52c02bb20db5</guid></item><item><title>Piper James's parents say dingo management reform needed to prevent further deaths on K'gari</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/piper-james-parents-call-for-more-dingo-warnings-on-kgari/106317706</link><description>Piper James's parents are leaving Australia with their daughter's ashes and a determination to ensure she hasn't died in vain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ccf19d954997c8989ad2001fd781236</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian government says illegal tobacco sales crackdown will deliver some of the 'toughest' laws in the country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/tasmanian-illegal-tobacco-vapes-crackdown/106318886</link><description>The Tasmanian government announces increased penalties for those caught selling illegal tobacco products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abb1e0b80c97bfdd83a60a814abd6175</guid></item><item><title>Five simple steps to saving cash (while still having a life)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/finance-tips-saving-money-new-year/106303046</link><description>Saving money is not about beating yourself up. It's also not about depriving yourself of all sources of joy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59b760f5e77d65279a49b68106aa5c6d</guid></item><item><title>Kimberley cotton hits record high in first season with new processing gin in Kununurra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/kimberley-growers-wrap-up-first-season-processing-cotton-locally/106303718</link><description>From farm to fabric, West Australian cotton growers are finally able to grow, process and export record amounts of cotton locally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">463c2f3636108857669737fceede0d6c</guid></item><item><title>Darkwaves research allows scientists to measure impact of 'underwater blackouts' on marine life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/darkwaves-research-scientists-measure-impact-on-marine-life/106314712</link><description>For the first time a group of international scientists have measured the impact of what happens to marine life when the lights go out underwater.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70eaaa35d2df02cbcf1d34ac0e2a4c3b</guid></item><item><title>SpaceX to build 'self-growing city' on Moon, Elon Musk says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/spacex-building-lunar-self-gowing-city-moon-elon-musk/106322472</link><description>Billionaire chief executive says the company will shift its focus from Mars and the project could be achieved within 10 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60090cd3e2417da1cd2217d495e8de23</guid></item><item><title>More people say they'll vote One Nation. What are they voting for?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/one-nation-policy-platforms-pauline-hanson/106296838</link><description>One Nation questions if man-made climate change is real, wants to wind back access to abortion care and plans to pay the HECS debts of doctors working in the regions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed4bdf450e353d8bca00c742667777f</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth asks to meet Roblox following reports of child grooming. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/commonwealth-roblox-reports-of-child-grooming/106323242</link><description>Roblox has been called to an urgent meeting with the federal government in the wake of reports that children are being groomed by predators and exposed to sexually explicit material on the popular online gaming platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8186dce135dbe17f29c38ae0b2e5a4fb</guid></item><item><title>Food ministers move closer to mandating Health Star Ratings on packaged food</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/move-to-mandate-health-star-ratings-on-food-and-drink/106231700</link><description>The nation's food ministers will this week take a crucial step towards mandating the Health Star Rating scheme on packaged food products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d49aa89b821cfcbaa27037bef0288134</guid></item><item><title>How to reduce loneliness while working remotely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/how-to-reduce-loneliness-while-working-remotely/106286338</link><description>Working remotely can be a lonely experience. Here's what you can do about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07ee38b05fb1af72edee6be374ac35ed</guid></item><item><title>Axed literary magazine Meanjin is resurrected by Queensland University of Technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/meanjin-magazine-finds-new-home-queensland-university-technology/106331850</link><description>The 85-year-old literary journal Meanjin will return to Brisbane, where it was first published, after it was controversially closed by Melbourne University Press last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8381f55200bc2cef76893ac168c73d93</guid></item><item><title>Transparency concerns as Bougainville's Panguna mine that sparked civil war on path to reopen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/bougainville-signs-secretive-deal-to-reopen-panguna-mine/106331778</link><description>The Autonomous Bougainville Government signs a secretive deal to reopen the huge Panguna gold and copper mine that sparked a catastrophic civil war three decades ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a5ff00e0503cc102c30c6e22dae858</guid></item><item><title>Declining birth rates in southern right whales alarm researchers in new study</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/climate-change-driving-down-southern-right-whale-calving-numbers/106332214</link><description>New research on the birth rates of southern right whales – once touted as a global conservation success story – has revealed an alarming decline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5d80284251a8c0cd3713b5fe505730a</guid></item><item><title>Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit to implement recommendations for workplace culture overhaul</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/toowoomba-hospital-maternity-unit-workplace-culture-findings/106338238</link><description>Staff at the Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit will be implementing recommended changes to their workplace culture following an independent review.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fffb7e8031442fc89790d85b110ac64c</guid></item><item><title>Marine biologists fight to save endangered seagrass species in Sydney Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/science-key-to-saving-endangered-seagrass-population/106337120</link><description>A centuries-old nautical technique is being redesigned within a small Sydney cove in a bid to save a tiny remnant population of a dying species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c23125b58cdf591c3340528784e5fcd</guid></item><item><title>Record-breaking heatwave leaves some flower farmers without Valentine's Day blooms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/flower-farmers-heatwave-victoria-losses-valentines-day/106329998</link><description>A record heatwave has destroyed a Mallee flower farm's Valentine's Day blooms, leaving its owner devastated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7db6c60336395b1e9aea3e528a183bc7</guid></item><item><title>Maugean skate's endangered status not changing, Environment Minister Murray Watt says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/maugean-skate-endangered-listing-not-changing-murray-watt-says/106342278</link><description>Environment Minister Murray Watt says his decision to keep the status of a rare Tasmanian skate species as endangered rather than change it to critically endangered is based on scientific advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e900785b0c8d8f08f1f99a4eaf01e576</guid></item><item><title>Ley didn't define herself by her gender but women might relate to her workplace woes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/liberal-party-women-sussan-ley-leadership-spill/106340280</link><description>The issue for the Liberal Party is not simply the toppling of a female leader. It's also about what happened to that leader while she was in the job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">596c3a295f267e6667ca697953519fbd</guid></item><item><title>Michael Mohammed Ahmad confronts traumatic childhood abuse in his new novel, Bugger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/michael-mohammed-ahmad-new-book-bugger/106331764</link><description>Michael Mohammed Ahmad, author of The Lebs, marks turning 40 with the publication of his most confronting novel yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a057fc717dc6c9c31f1c40b18e69a8e</guid></item><item><title>Chickens help autistic teen Summer Farrelly make sense of humans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/chickens-help-summer-farrelly-understand-humans-autism-book/106308084</link><description>While growing up, people didn't make much sense to Summer, but chickens always did. Now, Summer is using what they learnt to help other children with autism understand human interactions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69b349a86894794e632c23899a5e2185</guid></item><item><title>Parents fail to return consent forms as Far North Queensland HPV vaccination rate drops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/hpv-school-vaccination-rates-fall-far-north-qld/106341850</link><description>Cairns Public Health Unit says students are increasingly missing their school HPV vaccinations because they do not have parental consent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">692f4f5d7a21816cb5d9023a61a3d590</guid></item><item><title>Easy, tasty and nutritious recipes for sharing this Ramadan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/easy-tasty-and-nutritious-recipes-for-sharing-this-ramadan/106331120</link><description>Looking for easy, nutritious Ramadan recipes? These options will help you prepare for and break your fast well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb9d0165cd75c38640ee10f031f1d403</guid></item><item><title>Wool price jumps ahead of industry-first Chinese New Year break</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/wool-price-rising-ahead-of-chinese-new-year-break/106339658</link><description>As wool growers enjoy their best prices since 2019, the market will now pause to respect China's request for a week off to celebrate Lunar New Year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62ad96df10ee1750f91b3b33f2f16b56</guid></item><item><title>Taylor faces formidable task rebuilding Liberals' electoral fortunes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/angus-taylor-faces-big-task-rebuilding-liberal-electoral-fortune/106337012</link><description>The paralysing uncertainty that weighed on the Liberals' faces has lifted for now, but morale in politics follows results rather than reshuffles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faa611ea05322062dacd66ef69db7e11</guid></item><item><title>Sophie and Aud</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/director-sophie-hyde-with-her-child-aud-mason-hyde/106331574</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64cf2943fa0128e54dfbee310b1212aa</guid></item><item><title>These mums raise other people's children to secure a future for their own</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/children-left-behind-mother-foreign-domestic-worker-abroad/106303226</link><description>A generation of children in South-East Asia are growing up without their mothers, who have to work abroad for decades to make ends meet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8878ba8d8ea10df17fab402b2241fa7d</guid></item><item><title>Easy ways to help protect your hair from chlorine and saltwater damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/how-to-avoid-chlorine-and-saltwater-hair-damage-when-swimming/106334202</link><description>Regular beach days or laps at the local pool can leave our hair looking and feeling quite different.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ed59e0b1894ab058082b567c448eb32</guid></item><item><title>WA hop growers gear up for harvest as craft beer tastes evolve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/hop-growers-gear-up-harvest-western-australia/106340116</link><description>Local brewers are experimenting with new flavours, while some farms invest in US-made machinery to modernise and streamline the harvest process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0bb847882a1ace0ae5e8db0cba3fd16</guid></item><item><title>Statues of Amy Sherwin, Australia's first opera star, unveiled at Hobart's Hadley's Hotel in bid to cement legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/peter-schipperheyn-statues-of-amy-sherwin-opera-star-unveiled/106344982</link><description>An effort to bring new recognition to a Tasmanian opera star who became world famous, but who died poor, culminates in the unveiling of two statues of her in Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0073ccc352d93326f0623615a91690e2</guid></item><item><title>What is FAFO parenting and is it good for kids?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/what-is-fafo-parenting-and-is-it-good-for-kids/106321924</link><description>Is FAFO the 1980s parenting style today's generation of kids need, rebellion against gentle child-rearing, or exhausted parents just throwing their hands in the air?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27dfd8358d59f5a02bd8ef50448007a0</guid></item><item><title>Shark population may have fallen prey to algal bloom, SA ecologists fear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/port-jackson-shark-populations-algal-bloom-impact/106335834</link><description>South Australia's algal bloom could be responsible for pushing a local population of sharks to the brink of collapse, some researchers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e3cb6e84a9a4e4eba4a21a0e3320312</guid></item><item><title>Rescuers race to find entangled whale last seen near Wilsons Promontory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/search-continues-for-whale-entangled-off-victorian-coast/106347966</link><description>Authorities are looking for a juvenile humpback whale last seen entangled in rope off the coast near Wilsons Promontory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b0efabce5dd3fc47ee3b0e6aafbf4ff</guid></item><item><title>How the ABC Young Performers Awards helped launch the careers of these Australian musicians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/abc-young-performers-awards-launch-australian-classical-artists/106341202</link><description>The ABC Young Performers Awards have launched the careers of some of Australia's most successful musicians. Here are some of their stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd1d1f42c12f0cd8f19af90e90ca9734</guid></item><item><title>Chalmers mocks Taylor's proposal for bipartisan budget savings taskforce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/coalition-proposes-bipartisan-budget-taskforce/106348078</link><description>Angus Taylor wrote to the prime minister pitching the plan just days after being elected leader of the Liberal Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2e1b7a17f7bbb632412e2760a78b3ec</guid></item><item><title>Meet GayC/DC, the world's only all-gay AC/DC tribute band</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/gaycdc-interview-gay-acdc-tribute-band-australia-tour/106331786</link><description>They worship the riffs, rewrite the lyrics and win over the toughest crowds. GayC/DC is a tribute band like no other.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d75dfaf3925eb31093fd2815687fbbc</guid></item><item><title>Senior Liberals deny involvement in draft policy to ban migrants from Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/ley-draft-migration-policy-australian-values-statement/106348870</link><description>A leaked copy of the Liberal Party's migration policy prepared before Sussan Ley was ousted included plans to "elevate" the current non-binding Australian values statement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afcbb687b8d26ea4579377278e93aa57</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, February 17: 20 years since The Chaser's War on Everything premiered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/the-chasers-war-on-everything-20-year-anniversary/106340294</link><description>The Chaser's War on Everything didn't start the fire, but the embers from the beloved satirical current affairs show are still warm after two decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">745f78b8b02649b29035b0cec81e7085</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor bets on migration politics amid global rightward shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/migration-social-cohesion-language-support-division-policy/106348608</link><description>If migration is treated primarily as a cultural fault line, rather than an economic system embedded in national growth, the debate will remain loud. The structural reform will remain unfinished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86414a7a131a25b45dbc0a43798c1c16</guid></item><item><title>Robert Duvall, star of The Godfather and Apocalypse Now, dies at 95</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/robert-duvall-star-of-godfather-and-apocalypse-now-dies-at-95/106352132</link><description>Oscar winner Robert Duvall, known for films such as The Godfather and Apocalypse Now, has died at the age of 95.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c557714626458849acf4e2f9e4b0c251</guid></item><item><title>How to decide what type of car insurance is best for you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/how-do-i-know-what-car-insurance-is-best-for-me-/106260688</link><description>Choosing the right car insurance option can feel daunting, but it's the kind of task that it pays to get right. So, how can you decide which type is most suitable for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19c1a606228973fe803d3604b38ad3b1</guid></item><item><title>Results show high levels of lead contamination in dust around Hobart, as EPA flags further tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/nyrstar-lead-pollution-epa-tests-hobart/106339682</link><description>High levels of lead contamination have been found in dust samples taken from suburban locations close to Nyrstar's Hobart zinc smelter, documents obtained by the ABC show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df4c929be90ce6716c442950274a84e2</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate hike worries? Here's some good news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/why-the-reserve-bank-interest-rate-hike-may-be-a-one-off/106350914</link><description>Fresh warnings of further rate rises have been enough to send shivers up the collective spine of new homeowners, but if there's any comfort to be had, it's this: Don't believe a word of the forecasts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67fb51f52c86bc4d83c2be7c7d52564e</guid></item><item><title>Anti-slavery commissioner calls for tougher laws amid forced labour concerns for Ansell and Kmart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anti-slavery-commissioner-tough-laws-dumping-ground-kmart-ansell/106349728</link><description>Australia's anti-slavery commissioner calls for tough new laws forcing companies to take slavery in their supply chains seriously, as Ansell and Kmart face scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304d8b8d78c81209b940b9f107989101</guid></item><item><title>News quiz: Year of the Horse traditions, zodiac facts and festive customs across Asia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/lunar-new-year-of-the-horse-quiz-china-south-korea-vietnam-asia/106348886</link><description>How much do you know about the Year of the Horse and unique Lunar New Year traditions in Asian countries? Put your knowledge to the test with these 10 questions and see if you're a true Lunar New Year expert!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">664780860b8f5a75f0169a583ee380ca</guid></item><item><title>Irish rugby to investigate racial abuse towards Test debutant Edwin Edogbo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/ireland-rugby-test-debut-edwin-edogbo-racial-abuse/106352164</link><description>The Irish Rugby Football Union has said it will launch an investigation after turning comments off a social media post that congratulated the country's newest Test debutant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">261d685409d12066905edfb9104ada79</guid></item><item><title>Mould, asbestos, collapsed ceilings plague some South Australian schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sa-schools-in-need-of-repair/106334244</link><description>Almost two years after a state government report revealed 35 per cent of all buildings within the Department for Education's portfolio were past their design life, many schools are still plagued with issues including mould, asbestos and rotting windows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fabb2b4476c5886be92e1dda09f3283</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the ISIS-linked families in Syria who want to return to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/who-are-isis-linked-australian-families-in-syria-al-roj-camp/106352074</link><description>Australia has made limited progress in clearing a passage for the Australian women and their children, citing safety issues in and around the camps, and security concerns back home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b94dd1490b366423951626bba907299</guid></item><item><title>Illegal fishing vessels threaten Australia's agricultural sector as biosecurity concerns grow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/farmers-fear-pest-disease-outbreaks-from-illegal-foreign-boats/106349882</link><description>Australian primary producers say they are concerned about the risk of foreign pests crippling entire industries if overseas fishing boats continue to enter the nation's waters illegally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8f3a85baf70328cdbd85ce22cd6d1ae</guid></item><item><title>Pod Save America and why Australians remain obssessed with US politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/pod-save-america-why-australians-are-obssessed-with-us-politics/106327878</link><description>Huge crowds have flocked to live shows for the popular and influential Pod Save America podcast, suggesting Australia's obsession with US politics isn't going away anytime soon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29fd6077abedec21a6c24a6198c4c894</guid></item><item><title>Albanese says Australian government will not help ISIS-linked families leave Syria or return home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anthony-albanese-on-isis-families-trying-to-leave-syria/106352492</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese insists the federal government will not repatriate the Australian families with links to Islamic State fighters who remain in Syria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faa866e3881f2d6646422dcbe7b56295</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor reveals shadow ministry, elevating Andrew Hastie and Jacinta Nampijinpa Price</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/angus-taylor-preparing-to-unveil-shadow-ministry/106354092</link><description>The new Liberal leader announces his shadow ministry, elevating prominent right-faction supporters including West Australian MP Andrew Hastie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">989975fa7a8805821e114a08b60c7715</guid></item><item><title>Kyneton women's football players greenlit to join Central Victorian Football League</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/kyneton-womens-football-riddell-update-central-league/106354024</link><description>A long-running saga in country women's football is set to close as a central Victorian team that had been left without a competition will now be allowed to play in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54f16d5c55e8c9bba00d01c3d6d165d3</guid></item><item><title>French Polynesia drug haul hits $2.4 billion in a month as third shipment intercepted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/french-polynesia-third-drug-shipment-cocaine/106352864</link><description>French authorities seized a 2.4-tonne drug shipment near French Polynesia during a joint operation with the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8b05b9703fd79abe25cc2318a523413</guid></item><item><title>Australian production company Matchbox Pictures to be closed by Universal International Studios</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/matchbox-pictures-closed-universal-international-studios/106355260</link><description>Matchbox Pictures, the local production house behind Dog Park, The Survivors and Secret City, will be closed by its international parent company, Universal International Studios.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78b9d935e059c11895c3efac8807b716</guid></item><item><title>Private health premiums to rise at fastest rate in almost a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/private-health-premiums-increase/106355550</link><description>Private health insurance premiums will rise at their fastest rate in almost a decade, after the federal government approved a 4.41 per cent average increase from April.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cf53e80cc9f8f5821a0c50d3aa7dd87</guid></item><item><title>Mother of former Manly player Keith Titmuss breaks silence on lawsuit against NRL club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/keith-titmuss-mother-speaks-on-manly-sea-eagles-lawsuit/106354504</link><description>The mother of Manly player Keith Titmuss, who died of exertional heat stroke following a 2020 Sea Eagles training session, breaks her silence on her family's multi-million-dollar lawsuit against the NRL club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0be5af7a65024f5d1249c96c36ab639d</guid></item><item><title>Jesse Jackson, civil rights leader and US presidential hopeful, dead at 84</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/civil-rghts-leader-jesse-jackson-dies-age-84/106356528</link><description>The two-time Democratic presidential hopeful remembered for powerful speeches died peacefully surrounded by loved ones, his family said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bef1e4b64b56ce290b7d00444b297818</guid></item><item><title>Australia knocked out of T20 World Cup with one game left to play</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/australia-knocked-out-of-t20-world-cup/106356754</link><description>Australia can no longer catch up with Zimbabwe after it was awarded a point from a rained out match with Ireland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dfa50a4be411761518915d4c45e5985</guid></item><item><title>Millionaire Gary Stevenson's dire warning for Australian property market losing the 'fair go'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/economist-gary-stevenson-warns-australia-losing-the-fair-go/106342536</link><description>British economist Gary Stevenson is on a speaking tour, warning Australia will follow the path of the UK with "poverty exploding" unless politicians deal with inequality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f588e11282bda2e3e28ac0a5b4d7af5d</guid></item><item><title>HungryPanda riders say Chinese police intimidating families in China over Sydney protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/hungrypanda-riders-chinese-police-threats-sydney-australia/106353996</link><description>Riders embroiled in a dispute over pay and conditions with food delivery company HungryPanda in Sydney say Chinese police have asserted pressure back home to stop them protesting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00b78e0a081535d928622de443de63b8</guid></item><item><title>Long-term solution to repeated Waterfall Way landslips on the horizon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/long-term-solution-repeated-waterfall-way-landslides/106353438</link><description>The NSW government hopes to reopen a key east-west transport route by April, as a long-term solution to frequent landslips in the area is explored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a127abafb503c04ed7b234a9aa7f0e</guid></item><item><title>Hindmarsh Island bridge dispute told through Ngarrindjeri women's art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/ngarrindjeri-women-retell-hindmarsh-island-bridge-story/106282804</link><description>In the 1990s, a group of Indigenous women were accused of fabricating claims of sacred sites to stop the construction of a bridge south of Adelaide. It was a decision that has impacted a community for decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c8df9f180475c2f0cfe199f0433a284</guid></item><item><title>Riverland wine grape growers want to rezone land for housing to exit industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/housing-plan-riverland-wine-grape-crisis-rezoning-land-sa/106243944</link><description>The wine grape industry in South Australia's Riverland continues to face unprecedented levels of uncertainty, as growers look to exit the industry and turn their land into residential housing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b952a8705ecf3fd902de2cb20e0489c</guid></item><item><title>Pauline Hanson issues partial apology for suggesting there are no 'good' Muslims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/pauline-hanson-partially-apologises-for-muslim-remarks/106357130</link><description>The One Nation leader qualified her earlier remarks, which had been met with condemnation, while reiterating calls for tougher vetting processes for Muslim migrants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef8666bfdfbfd0c8dffd9a0c82b5b3cd</guid></item><item><title>Real Madrid star Vinícius Júnior says Benfica's Gianluca Prestianni racially abused him in Champions League match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/champions-league-racism-vinicius-junior-real-madrid-benfica/106357730</link><description>Real Madrid forward Vinícius Júnior accuses an opponent of racially abusing him during a Champions League game against Benfica, leading to the game being halted for nearly 10 minutes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">659589228e0656b84af72920641782c0</guid></item><item><title>As Donald Trump's first Board of Peace meeting approaches, Indonesians are watching their own president closely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/donald-trump-first-meeting-board-of-peace-indonesian-president/106348628</link><description>Ahead of the inaugural meeting of US President Donald Trump's Board of Peace, charged with leading the way forward in Gaza, Indonesian President Prabowo Subianto faces perhaps his most significant foreign policy test yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d30635e040376ea60c805df9793c8cb</guid></item><item><title>Is it ever a good idea to stay together for the kids?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/should-you-ever-stay-together-for-the-kids/106281890</link><description>When a relationships breaks down, sometimes we think staying in the familiar discomfort is less scary — and even protective — for our kids. But is it ever a good idea to stay in an unhappy relationship for the sake of the children?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbe4bbc74caa9ba1918949fae6630fe1</guid></item><item><title>Legends slam Australia's 'not surprising' T20 World Cup crash out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/aussie-t20-world-cup-eliminated-shock-loss/106359106</link><description>For the first time since 2009, Australia won't advance from the group stage of a cricket World Cup and some of the game's greatest ever players are demanding answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbd3f4835d2882acc4aa5f3b0c0d541b</guid></item><item><title>Chalmers suggests ex-RBA governor's spending critique is due to personal vendetta</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/chalmers-dismisses-criticism-from-philip-lowe/106359398</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers says Philip Lowe was critical of the government over spending because it did not re-appoint him as RBA governor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4578c9f616d6026ee0f378a69efa25e</guid></item><item><title>Mazda, Nissan, Hyundai and Subaru face multi-million-dollar penalties under NVES</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/new-vehicle-efficiency-standard-results-mazda-nissan-penalties/106358770</link><description>Major car brands are staring down the barrel of multi-million-dollar penalties for exceeding their emissions, the first results of the federal government's climate laws for new vehicles have revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45198840bd21329442d531c79bcbff0d</guid></item><item><title>Alcoa hit with record fine for unlawfully clearing WA jarrah forests for bauxite mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/alcoa-fined-for-clearing-jarrah-forest-for-bauxite-mine/106359988</link><description>US mining giant Alcoa is forced to pay $55 million after unlawfully clearing parts of a Western Australian native forest to mine bauxite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f74bb47c6f321183a916fc154005c8ee</guid></item><item><title>Former Coles manager admits 'human error' over Shapes 'Down Down' pricing in federal court showdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/coles-accc-discounts-federal-court/106358474</link><description>A former Coles manager has given evidence in the federal court on day three of a bombshell case between the consumer watchdog and supermarket giant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fac3387b11a41f3cb04ca5d82d1e043</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106359046</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">077e4b34cad227fccef803151960b1af</guid></item><item><title>Ex-cop granted bail over alleged stalking following neighbour dispute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/ex-cop-granted-bail-over-alleged-stalking-charges/106359998</link><description>A former Queensland police officer accused of allegedly wearing a balaclava and Easter bonnet to harass and intimidate a neighbouring family has been granted bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aea69af313928f8cdfdf95d42f0e5112</guid></item><item><title>Tackling 'blatant' fake discounting, restoring consumer trust among ACCC's priorities for 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/accc-outlines-priorities-for-2026-including-fake-discounting/106359994</link><description>ACCC chair Gina Cass-Gottlieb outlines the consumer watchdog's priorities for 2026, including targeting "blatant" fake discounting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2937ff2740ca14e3dac8a4082576d74e</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, February 19: Britpop, beats and a lust for life on Trainspotting's deathless soundtrack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/trainspotting-soundtrack-30th-anniversary-danny-boyle-britpop/106354570</link><description>Most films are lucky to get just one needle-drop moment embedded in the Zeitgeist. Trainspotting boasted several.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ab3fc2c71c82699927e06d1a58d6cf7</guid></item><item><title>Government spending is creeping up and threatening Australia’s 'low-debt' status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/government-spending-threatening-australias-low-debt-status/105579046</link><description>Australia will cease to be a low-debt country and be more vulnerable in a future crisis without a combination of spending restraint and tax reform, a new report has warned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13ac01b1668865c59fb5bf518f92a919</guid></item><item><title>Senate committee features climate disinformation, the Atlas Network, and Dr Karl's clash with One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/climate-disinformation-senate-committee-dr-karl-atlas-network/106350002</link><description>The scourge of AI-slopaganda, viral disinformation campaigns and online attacks against individuals and institutions is going to get far worse before it gets better, if the latest public hearings on the topic are any indication.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc806ab7e06e7cc45d048d4f225dbed0</guid></item><item><title>Danielle Scott's Winter Olympic silver ends years of pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/danielle-scott-aerials-silver-medal-2026-winter-olympics/106361322</link><description>In this most tension-filled Winter Olympic sport, it's no wonder tears are a by-product of both success and failure. Thankfully for Dani Scott, this time she was crying tears of pure joy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e5d5a3ecb08453f6f6bb9cdeaccc263</guid></item><item><title>Fiji's former prime minister Frank Bainimarama charged with inciting mutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/former-fiji-prime-minister-bainimarama-arrested-charged-mutiny/106360516</link><description>Long-serving Fiji prime minister Frank Bainimarama and a former police commissioner will face court on Tuesday on charges of mutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfb056a8d72b38a8175534edc2ea18aa</guid></item><item><title>Pyramid Hill residents rally to reopen aged care home closed five years ago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/aged-care-pyramid-hill-nursing-home-reopening-bid/106331078</link><description>Residents of a Victorian country town have taken over their aged care home, but now have to work out how to run it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97382073b597acd367df34d11d33a6ee</guid></item><item><title>From crime heists to a BDSM love story, here's what's in cinemas this month</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/what-to-watch-movies-february-pillion-crime-101/106352928</link><description>Australians will also finally be able to catch Sirât and The Voice of Hind Rajab, two movies that will be vying for Best International Film at the Academy Awards next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8040a86763a5a4d748d6c02c57f6603a</guid></item><item><title>How exclusion orders could ban Australian citizens from returning home indefinitely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/australian-citizens-banned-returning-overseas-exclusion-orders/106361634</link><description>One of the Australian women being held in a Syrian refugee camp has been barred from returning home after being given a temporary exclusion order — but the ban may not be as temporary as the name implies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b69ea4e5ccbec5d9f3ed7794e281795c</guid></item><item><title>Lakemba Mosque calls for more security after third threatening letter as Ramadan begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/lakemba-mosque-third-threatening-letter/106361678</link><description>Another threatening letter has been sent to Lakemba Mosque in Sydney's west, the third in recent weeks just hours before the start of Ramadan on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e08c365e2757731d8a0052e8d565fb82</guid></item><item><title>SA secures Australian MotoGP, world-first street circuit announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/sa-secures-motogp-world-first-street-circuit-announced/106361722</link><description>The South Australian government has confirmed the Australian MotoGP will move to Adelaide from 2027, bringing with it huge economic benefits, but the opposition and Greens say the state has other priorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a957e6c008c2cd348424eaa2acecad49</guid></item><item><title>The Kyneton women's football team's story was always about more than just one club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/kyneton-womens-football-story-widespread-issue/106338680</link><description>The women's team from Kyneton's 15-month public and bitter saga suggests it is the canary in the coal mine of a widespread issue for women's players across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af213a5a4c0ac76bfd7fb9926ae5b4ef</guid></item><item><title>Unemployment rate remains at 4.1pc in January, leading to talk of another rate rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/unemployment-rate-australia-january-2026-steady/106362428</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate remained at 4.1 per cent in January, with 17,800 more employed people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3deb22f01e8aa72f8fccc75f74faf25b</guid></item><item><title>Canberra bar declared a crime scene as police seize 'clearly satirical' posters under new Commonwealth hate laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/canberra-bar-declared-crime-scene-displaying-posters/106361644</link><description>Police have seized five posters on display in the window of a Canberra bar, declaring a "crime scene" while they investigate the artworks under new Commonwealth hate laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28f4acd2c8de3673dff101dd5a9f181e</guid></item><item><title>The heartwarming tribute to injured aerials star Laura Peel at the Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/heartwarming-aerials-tribute-laura-peel/106361392</link><description>This Winter Olympics aerials competition saw plenty of Aussies achieve lifetime goals, but they never forgot the one person who was missing — injured champion Laura Peel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837dd8955b1207595385711ea5af7ba8</guid></item><item><title>Police commissioner claims drones over Moree will not be used for surveillance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/drones-over-moree-not-for-surveillance/106358042</link><description>Police will control drones from more than 600 kilometres away from a rural town battling high crime rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20b610568fd73b396033918dcd0e2eb0</guid></item><item><title>Heavy rain through north Queensland leads to multiple floodwater rescues and Bruce Highway closures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/queensland-rain-bruce-highway-closure-mount-isa-rescues/106362844</link><description>Heavy rainfall across north Queensland has led to multiple rescues and the closure of several sections of the Bruce Highway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f93257abf07c3acbc49599880adb87</guid></item><item><title>In her memoir, Gisèle Pelicot reveals the secret love behind France's most infamous rape trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/secret-boyfriend-who-stood-beside-gis%C3%A8le-pelicot/106357080</link><description>The world knows Gisèle Pelicot as the woman who waived anonymity during France's most infamous rape trial. But in her new memoir she reveals an unexpected story — the boyfriend she kept hidden and the love that helped her face an open courtroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f0faacac57b0eb7bcc67090ad05c423</guid></item><item><title>Rescue helicopter arrives after avalanche near Italy's Courmayeur</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/rescue-helicopter-arrives-after-avalanche-near-italy-s/106362654</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c837af21d1993816a56b9e4e6d83fcf0</guid></item><item><title>Hanson digs her heels in, Taylor goes on tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/pauline-hanson-barnaby-joyce-angus-taylor-anthony-albanese/106349216</link><description>This week, the new opposition leader revealed his shadow cabinet while Pauline Hanson spun through a cycle she knows well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ea3a4f2179a8b0064925ee07ccfca6c</guid></item><item><title>Vegetable scraps to be turned into bioenergy by Scenic Rim farm as part of $291 million project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/qld-kalfresh-bioenergy-scenic-rim/106363982</link><description>A new $291 million project set to turn farm scraps to energy has begun construction in Queensland's Scenic Rim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db61a8e13ba17ab198287e56aca27dc2</guid></item><item><title>Coles manager moved product onto 'Down Down' promotion days after price hike to be more competitive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/coles-accc-federal-court-dog-food-down-down-pricing/106358664</link><description>A second Coles manager has been grilled in the federal court over whether rushing a product onto a "Down Down" promotion could have broken internal guidelines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41ca3a7b1fd4851df375d2220574fd44</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/thursday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/106364470</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4c5b51e530a659b7487c6517551d5d1</guid></item><item><title>Michael Brian Becton sentenced to more than 24 years in jail for child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/man-sentenced-to-24-years-in-jail-over-child-sex-offences/106365380</link><description>Michael Brian Becton, 33, is handed a 24-and-a-half year prison term after pleading guilty to 77 child sexual offences against children and babies. WARNING: This story contains details that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">388c384c47b78f4a85d064f1750a1efd</guid></item><item><title>Former prince returns home as police investigation continues — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-epstein-police/106365802</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor has returned to his Sandringham home after being arrested and questioned on suspicion of misconduct in public office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5fc074cadfc2697a563fee6e91b29af</guid></item><item><title>What we know about ex-prince Andrew's arrest on suspicion of misconduct in public office</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/what-we-know-about-former-prince-andrew-arrest/106365894</link><description>Police are searching two addresses in the UK, including Royal Lodge on the Windsor Estate where the former prince lived until last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8039d5e6abc316002657b559e90ee456</guid></item><item><title>Ally Hickman showed her grit at 2026 Winter Olympics after heavy fall on second run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/ally-hickman-crash-snowboard-slopestyle-2026-winter-olympics/106366350</link><description>In a Winter Olympics beset by both glory and injury, Ally Hickman's heavy fall in the snowboard slopestyle could have turned a happy day into another disappointing one. Instead, the young Aussie showed her grit to get back up and go again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a129ccb67369e26da08c0952f439ed6</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump suggests decision on Iran likely within 10 to 15 days</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/trump-indicates-iran-decision-likely-in-ten-days/106366370</link><description>Speaking at the inaugural "Board of Peace" meeting in Washington DC, the US president warns "bad things" will happen if a "meaningful deal" isn't reached in nuclear talks with Iran.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c17e84308d8d7bf043e1328663cd0215</guid></item><item><title>Former premier joins community calls for speed reduction at 'dangerous' fatal intersection in Newham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/community-calls-for-speed-reduction-newham-intersection-victoria/106364280</link><description>A community in central Victoria is calling for a 20 kph speed limit reduction at a "terribly dangerous" intersection after four major accidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d28bf645384eca294d072c5b45849511</guid></item><item><title>Sisters Lisa and Rachael Maza reunite on stage for the world premiere of Black Light</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/lisa-rachael-maza-sisters-black-light-malthouse-theatre/106357630</link><description>The former head of Indigenous theatre company Ilbijerri teams up with her sister Lisa for the world premiere of Black Light, which tells the story of three generations of Blak women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1799e84905988608fb42c35ca34a445</guid></item><item><title>Man On The Run: How Paul McCartney rebuilt his life after The Beatles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/paul-mccartney-documentary-man-on-the-run-review/106364370</link><description>Morgan Neville's new documentary is a fascinating portrait of an artist rebuilding himself while the world watches on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f4da03f75ed84529ea3aaf5400af393</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: Museum robberies, the Lunar New Year and a new shadow cabinet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/weekly-news-quiz-february-20/106362896</link><description>It has been a huge week in news. Did you catch these stories?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa766aab7e5861a7bbb39277f470de89</guid></item><item><title>Police guarding former Prince Andrew's residence in Sandringham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/police-guarding-former-prince-andrew-s-residence-in-sandringham/106366532</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0b22c5c404d8715f74def4f36af12a4</guid></item><item><title>Georgia Voll top scores as Australia beats India in second Twenty20 by 19 runs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/georgia-voll-following-alyssa-healy-footsteps-in-india-t20/106366526</link><description>The retirement of Alyssa Healy leaves a big hole at the top of the order, but Georgia Voll looks capable of stepping in after a career-best outing in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74487880f457828fe8e726b872f23c9d</guid></item><item><title>As electric car prices fall, will affordability win over drivers?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cart-electric-vehicles-becoming-more-affordable/106348534</link><description>The price tag of EVs has been a barrier to uptake. As cheaper models hit the market, will more drivers go electric?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8e8609bc047b4700deb6c7a5c8c5aa4</guid></item><item><title>Full list of 11 Australian women with ISIS links trying to leave Syria revealed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/eleven-australian-isis-brides-trying-to-leave-syria-named/106362024</link><description>The ABC can reveal the names of the 11 women connected to former Islamic State fighters in Syria who attempted to journey home to Australia this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b55cf419212aa7070f0842155fe39b42</guid></item><item><title>Voters divided as Barnaby Joyce considers contesting New England for One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/new-england-divided-over-barnaby-joyce/106353714</link><description>One Nation MP Barnaby Joyce says he might recontest his seat of New England as a candidate for One Nation if the party needs him to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8216e2cb0110f0bcd4db9bab70757914</guid></item><item><title>Anti-corruption police search home of former APY lands general manager</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/sa-richard-king-anti-corruption-police/106363880</link><description>Anti-corruption police have searched a home owned by the former general manager of the state's remote Anangu Pitjantjatjara Yankunytjatjara (APY) Lands as part of an ongoing investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf2ffa978d6df0ed03d39cc333e8b4d4</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest could end monarchy's 'never complain, never explain' mentality</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-a-problem-for-monarchy/106365934</link><description>British royals have lived by the adage "never complain, never explain", but these days, many of their subjects are demanding answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69ce80bb0d80419516702662a1c32494</guid></item><item><title>Study to test whether a new helmet will significantly reduce risk of concussion in football players</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/helmet-studied-to-see-if-it-reduces-concussion-risk-footballers/106358372</link><description>A lot of research has gone in to treating concussions, but now scientists are testing a new helmet to see if it can prevent them before they happen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f22fb72db16b8951d854fc6dc06f4c17</guid></item><item><title>Can Angus Taylor get beyond slogans to craft a sound immigration policy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/angus-taylor-immigration-pauline-hanson/106349268</link><description>The rifts in Australia's social cohesion can be seen in the blow-up over the so-called ISIS brides and their children, who want to come to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81483ff7c63fdba169c22b024c766cea</guid></item><item><title>Amyl and the Sniffers singer in escalating legal battle with photographer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/amy-taylor-amyl-and-the-sniffers-court-cases-copyright/106361084</link><description>What began as a photo shoot with champagne, ice cream and humorous glamour shots of Amy Taylor, singer from punk band Amyl and the Sniffers, has escalated into a legal fight over copyright, the US Constitution and an application for a restraining order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eecb7daec40c63d6dec04c319e48120</guid></item><item><title>Coalition willing to help stop passports for IS-linked women— as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/federal-politics-live-albanese-taylor-labor-coalition/106363700</link><description>Angus Taylor says the Coalition is willing to help the government strengthen legislation so women with ties to Islamic State are not issued Australian passports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e73f6a4c21f2ed041db318fdf5bfddfe</guid></item><item><title>More rainfall expected for parts of northern Queensland after wet week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/more-rainfall-forecast-for-northern-qld/106362726</link><description>A risk for further heavy rainfall and thunderstorms is possible in northern parts of the state today and into the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e9add29fa1f01a82340402c2e1aad56</guid></item><item><title>Major US fund's credit squeeze could 'blow up' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-friday-20-february/106366740</link><description>Shares in US asset manager Blue Owl have fallen sharply after it announced it was having challenges meeting investors' cash demands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8cfa058595f0f84f2b91273acd73f15</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says Andrew's arrest is a 'shame' for Royal family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/donald-trump-says-andrew-s-arrest-is-a-shame-for-royal-family-/106366752</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3ac836173af3ee6429afa5d754a1fc1</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says Andrew's arrest is a 'shame' for Royal family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/donald-trump-says-andrew-s-arrest-is-a-shame-for-royal-family-/106366754</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbd49febc62780f8993df386c9540c9c</guid></item><item><title>Federal authorities target black flights and drug importation in Far North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/afp-queensland-police-target-organised-crime-far-north/106366728</link><description>A joint police taskforce has been launched in Far North Queensland to target the importation of illicit drugs, forced labour and sexual servitude.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad129b09fc9d0b15be5f175dc0beddec</guid></item><item><title>Three men, one teen charged over gangland attacks linked to 'Coconut Cartel' conflict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/matt-utai-greenacre-shooting-coconut-cartel-four-charged/106366832</link><description>The group, police allege, have been charged in relation to the shooting of ex-NRL player Matt Utai in Greenacre and a firebombing linked to conflict with the 'Coconut Cartel'.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac15045bb9b3d9c7b128070559fb5b0a</guid></item><item><title>Sam Altman and Dario Amodei refuse to hold hands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/sam-altman-and-dario-amodei-refuse-to-hold-hands/106366814</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">674633a4739f236cc9b230c8d3679749</guid></item><item><title>Bill Gates pulls out of India AI summit amid Epstein files scrutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/bill-gates-pulls-out-of-india-ai-summit-amid-epstein-scrutiny/106366684</link><description>Microsoft co-founder Bill Gates pulls out of his keynote address at India's AI Impact Summit hours before it was scheduled to take place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46985f074b03fc243b85c6e6a2c7f890</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor released under investigation after almost 10 hours in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrested-misconduct-in-public-office/106366200</link><description>The former Duke of York has been released under investigation by British police, as officers continue to search his former Windsor home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94a6bbd07a298ae5c28f71caf5061d5c</guid></item><item><title>Bangarra Dance Theatre wins Golden Lion at international dance festival Venice Danza 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/bangarra-dance-theatre-golden-lion-venice-biennale/106366904</link><description>Indigenous dance company Bangarra Dance Theatre has become the first company and first First Nations performers to receive the Golden Lion at Venice Danza, the international festival of contemporary dance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1e2f7d948461775c920779a3628e602</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump hosts first 'Board of Peace' meeting with new pledges for Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/donald-trump-hosts-first-board-of-peace-meeting/106366982</link><description>A group of nations will provide billions of dollars and thousands of troops to rebuild Gaza, according to pledges made at the inaugural meeting of Donald Trump's "Board of Peace".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de8507029b17ae7487ff35961e9fef5d</guid></item><item><title>Canadian skier Cassie Sharpe's horrific crash in the halfpipe reminds us of Winter Olympics dangers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cassie-sharpe-canadian-freeski-halfpipe-crash/106366818</link><description>As Cassie Sharpe lay motionless on the base of the Livigno halfpipe, the excruciating tension reminded us all that winter Olympians are only ever seconds from disaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca8a04bde9604f081e69e3f402a12a68</guid></item><item><title>Fiji, Palau and Tuvalu set to show world leaders climate change impact ahead of COP31</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/pacific-nations-set-to-host-world-leaders-on-climate-change/106366110</link><description>Fiji, Palau and Tuvalu look set to host world leaders and climate change ministers in the lead-up to COP31 in a bid to encourage larger countries to accelerate cuts to emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efb0153cc3ad4a4f839fc3664ed151a9</guid></item><item><title>Is it OK to feed Australia's wild birds?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/is-it-ok-to-feed-australias-wild-birds/106349168</link><description>Many of us love interacting with and feeding wild birds, but experts say giving them the wrong types of food can do more harm than good.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eec910366a2f5aeb070b335682010295</guid></item><item><title>Australian exporters could face windfall if Trump tariffs ruled unlawful by US Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/australian-exporters-windfall-over-trump-tariffs-court-ruling/106363368</link><description>Modelling by consulting firm EY Australia shows Australian exporters would be owed more than $1.4 billion in refunds collectively if the US tariffs are struck down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7de8009fd822c72acadb5cc05ff6a69</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos lose World Club Challenge to Hull KR 30-24</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/brisbane-broncos-lose-world-club-challenge-to-hull-kr/106367354</link><description>After pulling off three straight comebacks to win the NRL premiership, the Brisbane Broncos fall just short of another miracle against Hull KR in the World Club Challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">226460c361ffc36183702882e85cf411</guid></item><item><title>Indra Brown's Winter Olympics medal contention doesn't remove the reality of school homework</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/indra-brown-qualifies-2026-winter-olympics-halfpipe/106366490</link><description>Sixteen-year-old Indra Brown came into the Winter Olympics as one of the top medal contenders in freeski halfpipe — a status elevated since she finished fourth in qualification — but it still doesn't get her out of maths homework.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c99296c009f79f41a37a2c64a4d0bb1</guid></item><item><title>David James Pye found guilty of murdering former Rebels boss Nick Martin after recruiting sniper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/david-pye-guilty-orchestrating-assassination-nick-martin-sniper/106365638</link><description>Bikie David Pye is convicted of murder after he paid a trained sniper to assassinate his former friend and ex-Rebels boss Nick Martin in front of horrified onlookers at a drag racing event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbf544938badafba7fef8c6ab33f86a3</guid></item><item><title>Timeline of key moments leading to former prince Andrew's arrest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-timeline-explained/106366940</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor has for years faced allegations over his contact with Jeffrey Epstein. These key moments led to his arrest on suspicion of misconduct in public office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a2f46ab3e75e5fbccb701232eb54201</guid></item><item><title>Eric Dane, star of Grey's Anatomy and Euphoria, dies aged 53</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/eric-dane-star-of-greys-anatomy-and-euphoria-dies/106188556</link><description>The star was best known for his role as Dr Mark Sloan in long-running medical drama Grey's Anatomy, and as the patriarch of the Jacobs family in teen hit Euphoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38f5c65f82f5e42103bcfbd84e4e18ea</guid></item><item><title>The Board of Peace meant to rebuild Gaza may well end up as another monument to Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/donald-trump-gaza-board-of-peace-speech-leaves-questions/106367958</link><description>Unless the Board of Peace begins to focus and genuinely tries to make the world a better place, this may well prove to be yet another monument to Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19b5df8e6b47a6791635a631e37275ff</guid></item><item><title>Complainant in former Liberal MP Rory Amon's underage sexual assault trial addresses court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/former-nsw-mp-rory-amon-opening-address-trial/106368066</link><description>The complainant in the sexual assault trial of former Liberal MP Rory Amon has told a court of the alleged incidents that took place in a car park toilet when he was 13.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47ab61a84a81d5d6cbe195e43a350ef1</guid></item><item><title>Eileen Gu says JD Vance is 'sweet' for saying she should be competing for US at 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/eileen-gu-jd-vance-us-china-row/106367168</link><description>Eileen Gu says she is flattered that JD Vance thinks she should be competing for the US, but feels his comments are driven by an anti-China bias from Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d89980fb1e4f346814c87b1cd907a8d</guid></item><item><title>Racist hate mail sent to politicians bears hallmarks of Lakemba Mosque letters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/racist-hate-mail-politicians-hallmarks-of-lakemba-mosque-letters/106367872</link><description>The ABC can reveal two of the threatening, hate-filled letters sent to Lakemba Mosque this month bear close resemblance to similar racist letters sent to multiple politicians since 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6e986afd5bf4027ac11562bd322c9fa</guid></item><item><title>Launceston council approve six-storey City Mission social housing project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/win-for-city-mission-launceston-community-precinct-project/106368388</link><description>Almost 50 new social and affordable homes will be built in Tasmania's north following a green light from council, despite some concern about parking and "anti-social behaviour".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5600bd55175547422ae8d4140aa441f3</guid></item><item><title>What to watch, read and listen to this weekend: Eternity, "Wuthering Heights" and new Meg Mac</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/what-to-watch-read-and-listen-to-this-weekend/106348892</link><description>From a cursed vagina to a classic retold, there's plenty of culture to dig into this weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de104c63d006fce83127b9a4e083d6bd</guid></item><item><title>Senior Constable Stuart Parsonage charged with illegal surveillance by WA Police sex crime division</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/wa-police-officer-court-computer-crime-surveillance-charges/106365724</link><description>Geraldton Senior Constable Stuart Parsonage has been charged with the illegal installation of a surveillance device and unlawful use of a computer by WA sex crime detectives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ef0a162b68b5d35ea9dcd87f112ee98</guid></item><item><title>Parents speak at sentencing hearing for Christopher Turner over fatal gas mix-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/christopher-turner-gas-pipe-mix-up-hospital-victim-impacts/106367440</link><description>The parents of two babies given nitrous oxide in a fatal gas mix-up at a Sydney hospital almost a decade ago express their pain and trauma at the sentencing hearing for the man responsible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e2ecb02a7ac2a45488be9175b75450f</guid></item><item><title>Mercedes F1 boss Toto Wolff defends team over engine drama ahead of Australian Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/mercedes-f1-boss-toto-wolff-calls-rivals-over-engine-saga/106368722</link><description>Toto Wolff accuses rival Formula 1 manufacturers of ganging up on Mercedes to pressure the governing FIA to change engine rules, but says it will make no difference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf062a44fa8f20ae64da57f3e573fc38</guid></item><item><title>Coroner delivers findings into James Tsindos's death from allergic reaction to delivery meal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/coroner-delivers-james-tsindos-nut-allergy-findings/106367040</link><description>A Victorian coroner hands down her findings into the death of a teenager who suffered a severe allergic reaction to a delivery meal — but it's unclear if more urgent treatment would have saved his life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebac18c8be8e4bab52fd1a3ef61d1b64</guid></item><item><title>Kyra Wheatley ready to ride the chaos and speed of ski cross at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/kyra-wheatley-ski-cross-speed-chaos-winter-olympics/106366406</link><description>The speed and chaos of ski cross is what attracted Kyra Wheatley to the sport, and to realise a dream 12 years in the making of competing at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1a4056e5ff034ff263b9864448b4429</guid></item><item><title>Darwin prisoner Clinton Daylight found, returned to custody two days after being freed from jail by mistake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/clinton-daylight-prisoner-mistakenly-released-nt-darwin-found/106368724</link><description>A 52-year-old inmate who was mistakenly released from the Darwin Correctional Centre two months before his sentence was due to end, due to an "administration error" by prison staff, has been found following a police search.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ab77d54005b5f557cf182cfc9c9d924</guid></item><item><title>Scientists model best-case and worst-case climate scenarios for Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/antarctica-faces-devastating-impacts-under-climate-change/106354182</link><description>Scientists say parts of Antarctica face "devastating" and "irreversible" impacts from climate change unless urgent action is taken to limit greenhouse gas emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f426dd0a1878420ce756c07766ef447c</guid></item><item><title>MotoGP Adelaide move raises concerns about rider safety, transport and trees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/motogp-adelaide-move-raises-safety-concerns/106368608</link><description>A rider, a reporter and a road safety expert say it will be difficult to make it safe for motorcycles to race around the Adelaide Parklands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25090531a9db489ad194e965a6815079</guid></item><item><title>How Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's 10 hours in police custody unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-arrest-and-birthday-in-police-lockup/106367644</link><description>Ostracised by his family and stripped of his titles, Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor celebrates his 66th birthday with police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7bfb3145d616df7e291cfa8889b3a52</guid></item><item><title>WA treasury takes rates from forestry plantations, leaving regional WA shires with funding shortfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/south-west-councils-essential-services-at-risk/106367148</link><description>Seven South West councils face $325,000 funding shortfall after forestry rate payments redirected to state Treasury. Shires warn residents could face higher rates or cuts to essential services as they push the state government for a solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49ee91f69c3c041af483070b49c5eeeb</guid></item><item><title>Woman who fatally struck 12-year-old Marshall Oakley-Stagg granted restricted driver's licence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/driver-who-killed-marshall-oakley-stagg-drivers-licence/106369656</link><description>A driver who struck and killed a 12-year-old boy outside his school in southern Tasmania in 2024 has been granted a restricted licence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ff01adff427a2aca0847f364c794ea9</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on day 14</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/winter-olympics-2026-quick-guide-what-to-watch-on-day-14/106369576</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">066e1fb6ed6f781b86c77bb6a6e1fa05</guid></item><item><title>Port Pirie's toddlers record highest blood lead levels in a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/port-pirie-blood-lead-levels-toddlers-highest-in-10-years-sa/106369868</link><description>The percentage of two-year-old children above the blood lead level threshold in Port Pirie is the highest in a decade, according to the latest figures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8f014a4524a788f30a87b5122219935</guid></item><item><title>Glider pilot creates aviation history in Central Australia flying 1,266 kilometres</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/glider-pilot-makes-history-central-australia/106364374</link><description>A Queensland pilot has made aviation history in Central Australia, flying more than 1,200 kilometres without an engine in a record-breaking glider flight launched from Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3a3e44b629b032cc34ddda0931e8d1e</guid></item><item><title>Ellyse Perry's evolution cements greatness as Australian cricket milestone looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/ellyse-perry-australia-cricket-350-matches/106369982</link><description>Cricket superstar Ellyse Perry will become the first woman to play 350 matches for Australia across all formats on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">588cdbd7c7f7eac8850144d63f6e89e7</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of performing Nazi salute at AFL exploring mental health defence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/man-accused-of-performing-nazi-salute-at-afl/106368658</link><description>Tylere Baker-Pearce, 39, was initially charged with giving the salute at the Gabba, and was later hit with two additional counts of the alleged offence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c6e6c8f054caf47133cd346d15cc0fc</guid></item><item><title>Nurses' strike at Adelaide's Lyell McEwin Hospital cancelled after pay increase ahead of state election start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/lyell-mcewin-hospital-nurses-strike-cancelled/106369750</link><description>The Australian Nursing and Midwifery Federation cancels a strike at one of Adelaide's largest public hospitals after securing a 2 per cent pay rise on top of a 4 per cent immediate increase in wages announced earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5d1b4eaf66ab459e38358e30373e1e9</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's new chief health officer Marianne Gale outlines future priorities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/chief-health-officer-queensland-marianne-gale/106367180</link><description>Marianne Gale reminisces about her time working for Doctors Without Borders to emphasise how she wants to shape the public health of the state – with a strong focus on equity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6f0812de7c10d62a596512830e7846b</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle man avoids jail for child abuse images and bestiality videos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/man-avoids-jail-for-possessing-bestiality-and-child-abuse-images/106369722</link><description>A man has avoided time behind bars and instead been handed a three-year community corrections order for possessing 34,000 child abuse images and more than a dozen bestiality videos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91107be62e03814cc5d9c575bcf0edc7</guid></item><item><title>Cockroaches peer out of a communications access hole in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/nolr-adelaidecockies-2002-1-/106370230</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9b44c3e5f01932b6f3f1754f8e80ace</guid></item><item><title>Cockroaches peer out of a communications access hole in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cockroaches-peer-out-of-a-communications-access-hole-in-adelaide/106370192</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e08605d17a90fbae10b53943eaeaeaeb</guid></item><item><title>Cockroach numbers surge in Adelaide during warm, humid weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/cockroach-numbers-surge-adelaide-warm-weather/106369934</link><description>Adelaide residents have been reporting increased numbers of unwelcome six-legged visitors in their homes, but with humid weather to continue amid a flood warning for the state's north, they are likely to stick around for a while yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c04f68c974214edc09ec93b26b653fd</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire at Gaffneys Creek in central-east Victoria burning out of control</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/bushfire-gaffneys-creek-woods-point/106370296</link><description>Residents in a remote Victorian community have been urged to evacuate as an out-of-control fire rages nearby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c59df8725d525da7ee9dbffbf8a24653</guid></item><item><title>Licence for use of antibiotic florfenicol in Tasmanian salmon industry may be suspended</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/antibiotic-florfenicol-licence-tasmanian-salmon-may-be-suspended/106370212</link><description>The federal agency that approved the use of an antibiotic for Tasmania's salmon industry has proposed to suspend that licence, in the wake of news the antibiotic has been found in native species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6c610d3b2ff6cbefab9c1f1ac62000e</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106369880</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dee6a5fc24b6baae934b701b2e8b0ec5</guid></item><item><title>SA state election polls could lead to one or no seats for Liberal Party, analyst says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/sa-state-election-polls-put-one-nation-ahead-of-liberals/106370280</link><description>Two opinion polls show fewer South Australians intend to vote for the Liberal Party than One Nation ahead of the official state election campaign period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acc64a6ce1e3c0960eff8e074cedbbdc</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand man Tamaohungia Joseph Tepatu-Edwards jailed for 26 years for attempted cocaine importation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/new-zealand-man-jailed-attempted-cocaine-importation/106368264</link><description>A man who tried to smuggle more than 800 kilograms of cocaine into WA – and was only caught when his boat broke down — will spend two decades in jail and "likely" be deported.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe96af322e56c9cc85664c9573f21026</guid></item><item><title>Rottnest Channel Swim cancelled due to strong winds, choppy seas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/rottnest-channel-swim-cancelled-amid-weather-concerns-/106367682</link><description>Perth's iconic Rottnest Channel Swim has been cancelled as forecast strong winds and unfavourable ocean conditions leaves thousands of swimmers and support crew disappointed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e022e3393793fa2b5ca1e4a824be305b</guid></item><item><title>Police receive ‘reports of crime’ in relation to Pauline Hanson interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/police-investigation-pauline-hanson-afp-one-nation-muslim/106370420</link><description>One Nation senator Pauline Hanson accuses the government of trying to put her "back in jail", after police received reports of a crime in relation to the senator's inflammatory comments about Muslims during a media interview.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">185dd63416cc7c6d747e0e5e37316352</guid></item><item><title>Live: Wheatley set for Olympic debut as women's ski cross begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/winter-olympics-day-14-live-updates-kyra-wheatley-bobsleigh/106369192</link><description>Australia's only ski cross athlete, Kyra Wheatley, makes her Winter Olympics debut tonight as seeding begins in the women's event. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6dfcf762819df9d71ed5895172c1567</guid></item><item><title>Trump wants federal agencies to release files on UFOs and extraterrestrials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/trump-orders-release-ufo-uap-extraterrestrials-files/106370826</link><description>US President Donald Trump says he will direct federal agencies to begin "identifying and releasing" government files related to UFOs and aliens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b5c0aa7eb838b64e8d4652b0c2bf97b</guid></item><item><title>Dolphins defeat New Zealand Warriors in NRL trial, Jackson Ford sin-bin for hip-drop tackle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-20/dolphins-defeat-new-zealand-warriors-in-nrl-trial-jackson-ford/106370914</link><description>The New Zealand Warriors' hopes of having no-nonsense forward Jackson Ford on deck for their season opener are in the hands of the NRL's match review committee after he was sin-binned in a 38-34 trial loss to the Dolphins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0de161440ddef1ca126b65b0d1b14faa</guid></item></channel></rss>