<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 09:45:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Hail and heavy rain batter West Australia's Great Southern and Wheatbelt region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/wild-weather-wreaks-havoc-for-west-australian-farmers/105978410</link><description>Severe weather has swept through large parts of the Great Southern and Wheatbelt, causing significant damage to crops during the critical harvest period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab1243c2637f701d0a104525f22b5197</guid></item><item><title>World Club Challenge returns as NRL premiers Brisbane Broncos schedule clash with Super League champions Hull KR</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/world-club-challenge-brisbane-broncos-hull-kr-2026/105979980</link><description>Brisbane will take on Hull Kingston Rovers in the World Club Challenge in late February with the NRL premiers confirming the return of the showpiece event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c115a6445c0023654348a8c78dc24615</guid></item><item><title>Port Adelaide coach Josh Carr denies Warren Tredrea has been kicked out of club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/afl-port-hasnt-kicked-out-tredrea-despite-board-sacking-carr/105979702</link><description>Warren Tredrea's premiership teammate Josh Carr says he will always remain a Port Adelaide legend despite being sacked from the club's board last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecb351caf43a6cbe86052df252e47321</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide artist Peter 'Jungle' Phillips dies aged 69 in his gallery home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/adelaide-artist-jungle-phillips-dies-in-his-gallery-home/105978944</link><description>Known for his generosity and a spectacular art gallery home filled with colourful works, Peter "Jungle" Phillips is remembered by those who loved him dearly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74cd35336a1a33fe6f9e4085f9876c8e</guid></item><item><title>Katter's present comes early, Coalition stalls on net zero New Year's resolution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/bob-katter-portrait-albanese-net-zero-coalition/105965242</link><description>"There will be a corner of this Parliament House that is forever Bob Katter," the prime minister said this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c305281e43e73daab6bb1a7f19966fb</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder over fatal vehicle strike during Timber Creek brawl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/nt-timber-creek-fatal-pedestrian-strike-murder-charge/105979596</link><description>Police have charged a 21-year-old man with murder for allegedly killing another man by driving a car into him during a brawl in a remote Northern Territory town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25e6733836e322baa4dbbd073e69ae40</guid></item><item><title>Walgett councillor charged over alleged assault of female bowling club worker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/walgett-shire-councillor-alf-seaton-charged-with-assault/105979450</link><description>A Walgett Shire councillor stands down while investigations continue into an alleged assault at a bowling club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02fabb09bc528759b2c954cf09122eea</guid></item><item><title>The art of price baiting — how real estate agents lure buyers to auction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/real-estate-agents-bait-buyers-to-auction-by-underquoting-prices/105973828</link><description>To advertise a property for $1 million, knowing it must sell above $1.3 million, is illegal. It is called underquoting, and in NSW it is rife, according to data analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad152ea0bc248bbeb98993ec6a464f97</guid></item><item><title>Boyfriend welcomes coronial findings about Simone Strobel's murder 20 years ago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/simone-strobel-inquest-findings-into-lismore-murder/105950872</link><description>The findings of a coronial inquest into the death of German backpacker Simone Strobel in Lismore in 2005 have been delivered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42466c411b08a01b8d9575837309708b</guid></item><item><title>Serial rapist Graham Kay pleads guilty to sexually touching Sydney schoolgirl without consent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/graham-kay-pleads-guilty-to-sexual-touching-young-girl/105980416</link><description>Convicted rapist Graham Kay will remain in custody after sexually touching a 16-year-old girl in the Sydney CBD while on a strict supervision order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">064862d4079098783e59817c5fa86f68</guid></item><item><title>Murdered doctor's family confronts killer during plea hearings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/ashley-gordon-murder-stabbing-plea-hearing-supreme-court/105440348</link><description>The convicted killer, who cannot be named, showed no emotion as Ashley Gordon's family members confronted him one by one during a plea hearing at court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2b7886121652da0f4332118d1dd698a</guid></item><item><title>Federal government approves expansion of Victoria's largest gold mine near Bendigo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/expansion-of-victorias-biggest-gold-mine-fosterville-approved/105820838</link><description>Fosterville Gold Mine in central Victoria is approved to continue running until 2045 despite concerns from neighbours and environmental advocates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82d57c3f7c894ffb523c7212f98b01f5</guid></item><item><title>Toddler dies after vehicle accident on rural property in Abergowrie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/toddler-dies-vehicle-accident-rural-property-north-queensland/105980178</link><description>A two-year-old boy has died in an accident involving a vehicle on a rural property in north Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37ebc0f513ba883de49eddc7a90c3b90</guid></item><item><title>Liberals recalled to parliament to thrash out net zero problem</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/liberals-recalled-to-parliament-to-thrash-out-net-zero-problem/105980878</link><description>Liberal MPs will return to parliament on Wednesday to thrash out a position on the party's net zero commitment ahead of a joint party room meeting with the Nationals next Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc6311e8941c1307e54a41f449b07dc4</guid></item><item><title>Male nurse charged over alleged rape of two elderly women at Greenslopes hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/male-nurse-charged-rape-elderly-women-greenslopes-queensland/105980938</link><description>Police allege the 41-year-old committed the offences against two women in their 80s in 2020 and 2024 at a hospital in Brisbane's south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">629a56f60615894c48c61a067fd0fd71</guid></item><item><title>Anti-corruption commission watchdog inquiring into NACC chief Paul Brereton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/nacc-inspector-inquiring-brereton-complaints/105980792</link><description>The inspector of the National Anti-Corruption Commission is inquiring into the agency's head, Paul Brereton, in relation to several complaints including from a former employee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cc388dddda1b38961125058526d275c</guid></item><item><title>How Zohran Mamdani's triumph in New York is making waves around the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/zohran-mamdani-political-landscape/105980512</link><description>The blistering rise of New York City's new mayor, Zohran Mamdani, has captured global attention. So what's going on and what does his win say about the American political climate?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fc1ddae3c5072f9c5b018033e43f0ca</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos not offended Hawthorn players missed Jasmine Garner's guard of honour after 100th AFLW game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/aflw-kangaroos-respond-hawthorn-garner-100th-game-snub/105981256</link><description>Hawthorn players were noticeably absent from the guard of honour for North star Jasmine Garner after her 100th AFLW game, but the reigning champs are not too fussed about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">947b1b6e8038390076adca24bebe6512</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/105980726</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce1026aaae1d4162b44c6311a14f390b</guid></item><item><title>India beat Australia in fourth T20I by 48 runs on Gold Coast, lead series 2-1</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/cricket-australia-india-fourth-t20i-gold-coast-live-score-centre/105981170</link><description>Australia lost 9-52 as India's spinners took control in a 48-run win in the fourth T20 international on the Gold Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">722f6d4d71e8d60751df3f2d947e6fe9</guid></item><item><title>Sena needed surgery, but she couldn't understand her doctors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/calls-for-more-translators-australian-medical-industry/105981340</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41daf6331b86a7c662ce645ab1e5cbb7</guid></item><item><title>Australia's $4 billion illicit tobacco trade has become one of the nation's most violent criminal markets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/black-market-cigarettes-cost-australia-4bn-in-one-year/105981786</link><description>Authorities stress the $4 billion figure is conservative, as it does not include illegal vapes and e-cigarettes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">358fd392575026d8d0bfb9140f325913</guid></item><item><title>German police investigate swastikas drawn in human blood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/german-police-investigate-swastikas-drawn-in-human-blood/105981882</link><description>The Nazi symbol was smeared dozens of times on cars, letter boxes and building facades, with tests confirming they were daubed in human blood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41adc70d01452049c09c2ce3b49ad188</guid></item><item><title>Typhoon Kalmaegi brings destructive winds and heavy rains to Vietnam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/typhoon-makes-landfall-in-vietnam/105981940</link><description>Typhoon Kalmaegi lashes Vietnam with fierce winds and torrential rain as it makes landfall, after leaving at least 188 people dead and 135 missing in the Philippines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">969151d8c2fd5d6cd66a0a856d0a86a8</guid></item><item><title>Louvre managers prioritised art over upgrading security in years before heist, report says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/louvre-security-flaws-years-report-finds/105982046</link><description>France's highest auditor says the theft of $157 million worth of jewels was a "deafening alarm bell" for the world-renowned Parisian museum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b9b0a8a2d754a58367472453e9a8c75</guid></item><item><title>Nancy Pelosi will not contest next US midterm elections, ending storied career</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/nancy-pelosi-announces-retirement-from-politics-us/105982126</link><description>Ms Pelosi was the first woman to serve as US speaker of the House of Representatives, and her decision will bring to an end a political career spanning four decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbd2134668961a6eda086b3c0329dc7a</guid></item><item><title>Inaction on 1.5C climate change target a 'moral failure', says UN secretary-general at COP30</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/cop30-moral-guterres-climate-change/105982176</link><description>Missing from the line-up at the key summit in Brazil are the leaders of four of the world's five most-polluting economies — China, the United States, India and Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a07f6a0bb6e4029d17283697f316ce4</guid></item><item><title>2025 among three warmest years on record, according to World Meteorological Organization</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/world-meteorological-organization-climate-report-2025/105978288</link><description>According to the global meteorological organisation, each of the past 11 years has been the warmest in 176 years of observations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cb2977efff310d29297c5ea7c8054f8</guid></item><item><title>Fashion boss Shmuel Tal to face trial over alleged violent sexual offences in Byron Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/fashion-boss-shmuel-tal-charged-with-rape-in-byron-bay/105979790</link><description>A millionaire fashion boss is banned from entering Byron Bay's party precinct as he awaits trial over violent sexual offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39d0212f0351f9768a4f4f594e3d8351</guid></item><item><title>Emerald community grieving after four people die in central Queensland house fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/emerald-community-reeling-after-four-people-die-in-house-fire/105979960</link><description>Investigators are trying to piece together the cause of a blaze in central Queensland that has left a family devastated and residents in shock.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4869f5fcc50042882bf3438ed8495173</guid></item><item><title>Carter Gordon named at flyhalf for Wallabies look to avenge Italy defeat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/carter-gordon-wallabies-fly-half-against-italy/105982282</link><description>The code-hopping Carter Gordon will be back in the starting No.10 shirt for the Wallabies against Italy in Udine as Tane Edmed reverts to the bench.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">421667137c4bd3e075b030baf7429356</guid></item><item><title>Alleged killers travelled from NSW for fatal hit on Melbourne man Athan Boursinos, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/nsw-link-to-athan-boursinos-melbourne-shooting/105982232</link><description>Police believe two men travelled to Melbourne from NSW to carry out the fatal shooting of 21-year-old Athan Boursinos in July.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6cfe7dfad8258196c99df263a140587</guid></item><item><title>Former RAH electrician to receive $2.26 million asbestos cancer damages claim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/electricians-asbestos-mesothelioma-damages-payout/105966144</link><description>An electrician diagnosed with a rare asbestos-related cancer has been awarded a $2.26 million payout for exposure to toxic dust and fibres while working for various employers, including at the old Royal Adelaide Hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e9d88e80042912bf743047d0cb690e0</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of Queensland babies may have missed vital newborn blood screening tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/queensland-newborn-heel-prick-test-genetic-conditions-screening/105979844</link><description>The ABC can reveal that in July last year, Queensland Health department became aware of "inconsistencies" in records of the newborn blood spot screening program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dce3c083fc6551907134d80e0b9251f</guid></item><item><title>Muswellbrook bans dongas at renewable energy and construction project sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/muswellbrook-shire-bans-temporary-workers-accomodation/105861466</link><description>An Upper Hunter council is banning donga-style temporary work camps and demanding that developers build permanent, reusable housing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8736d6937a9ef35c446f0370cf581bd</guid></item><item><title>Queenslanders warned about 'disaster chasers' targeting storm-hit homeowners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/queensland-disaster-chasers-storm-home-warning/105979750</link><description>When three men turned up on Geoff Wilson's doorstep offering to check his roof for damage he took them up on it. But a requirement that the repairs must be done by a builder of their choice put him on alert.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">170bd10a323106fec42ec1a570fcd0bc</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur learns ATP Finals fate as Carlos Alcaraz, Novak Djokovic await</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/alex-de-minaur-learns-atp-finals-fate/105982352</link><description>Australian hope Alex de Minaur must get past world No.2 Carlos Alcaraz and 24-time grand slam winner Novak Djokovic to progress at the ATP Finals in Turin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b4b740aa7d8f7cc3f42025e57e13637</guid></item><item><title>AI therapists don't judge, sleep or need an appointment — but experts urge it be used with caution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/australians-use-artificial-intelligence-ptsd-trauma-recovery/105946020</link><description>Artificial intelligence chatbots like ChatGPT are embedded in modern life, with some Australians using them to help work through PTSD and toxic work environments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b43e94f4a3d925501bbe637e2b4514c</guid></item><item><title>These charts show the effect of migration on Australia's housing story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/effect-of-migration-on-housing-in-several-starts/105980904</link><description>The role of migration is one of the most contentious elements to the housing debate. So what does the evidence show?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8543740585b56b408ae3d040ac180260</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Sussan Ley won't remark on 'good senator' Henderson's jab — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/federal-politics-live-blog-nov-7/105979976</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley would not be drawn on comments from Liberal senator Sarah Henderson who openly declared the Liberal leader was losing support in the party room.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">726387846ec6c6e0209cbacc76cb04d5</guid></item><item><title>ASX closes lower as Macquarie shares tumble, Tesla shareholders approve Elon Musk's trillion-dollar pay deal — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/asx-markets-business-live-news-nov-7/105981694</link><description>The Australian share market finished lower on Friday — its second consecutive weekly drop, with Macquarie shares tumbling on a disappointing earnings update.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1cb6c7aa7f3b84489f52bc0cc38a800</guid></item><item><title>Safety issues delay the reopening of six regional South Australian hospital helipads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/regional-hospital-helipads-delay-safety-issues-government-sa/105964072</link><description>Paul Logos may never know for sure if his wife's recent death could have been preventable by helipad access. Six helipads throughout regional South Australia remain closed due to issues in certifying their safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e41031a0a9ad4474703657f20e5b6cb</guid></item><item><title>Graphic flutterer dragonfly voted 2025 ABC Australian Insect of the Year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/2025-abc-insect-of-the-year-graphic-flutterer-dragonfly/105972966</link><description>What flies like a helicopter and devours mosquitoes? Meet the 2025 ABC Australian Insect of the Year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82a33712fb583edc2607c1fd29e62127</guid></item><item><title>How AFLW pioneer Daisy Pearce is helping the next generation of female footballers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/how-the-daisy-pearce-effect-is-helping-aflw-shine/105980538</link><description>With her West Coast AFLW side on the cusp of its first finals appearance, coach Daisy Pearce reflects on the huge strides the women's game has made since her own playing days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">514fa1e5403a2cdc7d246932800dffdc</guid></item><item><title>SunCable looks to Muckaty Station for solar project's proposed expansion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/nt-suncable-seeks-expansion-to-muckaty-station-solar-farm/105979824</link><description>An ambitious outback solar project backed by billionaire Mike Cannon-Brookes could soon grow even bigger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed167482908fbd833aa5f034d8b85f90</guid></item><item><title>China agrees to import 65,000 tonnes of Australian canola after five-year lockout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/china-imports-first-australian-canola-shipment-in-five-years/105974992</link><description>China is accepting the first bulk shipment of Australian canola in five years and farmers are hoping the trial leads to a formal resumption of the trade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd1ffdc4427559986ac764bd34757455</guid></item><item><title>Worker dies after being hit by vehicle at New England Highway construction site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/man-dies-hit-by-vehicle-workplace-incident-hunter-roadwork/105982476</link><description>Just before midnight, emergency services were called to the highway at Tarro, following reports a man had been hit by a vehicle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">751d19d3529d80cd2c68c2ee0d353b30</guid></item><item><title>Actress Pauline Collins of Shirley Valentine fame dies aged 85</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/shirley-valentine-ctress-pauline-collins-dead-at-85/105982708</link><description>Pauline Collins was adept at playing an array of roles, all of which she infused with her trademark authenticity that earned her the status of a "national sweetheart" in the UK.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29d512ce66a277e8ef1289555ba788c2</guid></item><item><title>Mount Gambier search for remains of missing woman Margaret Bernie unsuccessful</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/search-for-missing-woman-margaret-bernie-remains-unsuccessful/105982678</link><description>Police are not ruling out returning to a property near Mount Gambier where they searched yesterday for the remains of Margaret Bernie, who was last seen in the South Australian city in 1988.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcabe232d2b591b682db26c83b455018</guid></item><item><title>On November 11, 1975 I watched history being made, from the best seats in the house</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/michelle-grattan-whitlam-dismissal-november-11-1975/105965350</link><description>The main characters are dead. Some of those still around from the time maintain their rage, which has lasted through the decades, long after that election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">877f155b72c8e81b6b8cbaeffe350c80</guid></item><item><title>Queensland considers allowing dingoes to be kept as pets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/queensland-biosecurity-changes-would-allow-dingoes-as-pets/105936892</link><description>People could be allowed to keep dingoes as pets in Queensland under proposed changes to biosecurity regulations, but experts say the native animal is fundamentally different to domestic dogs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60df5a7da837045c29c745a761a545b8</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos name Manchester United teen for upcoming friendlies against Venezuela and Colombia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/socceroos-name-teen-for-upcoming-friendlies-venezuela-colombia/105983334</link><description>Two crucial Socceroos return for friendlies against Venezuela and Colombia while a teen sensation is among those earning a maiden call-up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c67d8b12b6f09e8f9f1a48cdfdb56162</guid></item><item><title>Daly Cherry-Evans leaves Manly-Warringah Sea Eagles for Sydney Roosters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/daly-cherry-evans-leaves-manly-for-roosters/105983484</link><description>Daly Cherry-Evans' decorated stint at Manly, spanning 352 games and plenty of highlights, is officially over after his move to a rival NRL club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fc70577bf63acfec6e98b1aae699f03</guid></item><item><title>What do statistics tell us about Victoria's crime wave?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/victoria-melbourne-crime-statistics-2025/105934040</link><description>As Victoria grapples with a crime wave, the ABC takes a deeper look at some of the numbers behind the rise in offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaf5c44065cfacc2552fccd487b30615</guid></item><item><title>Youth crime funding for bail accommodation in Moree and more therapeutic services for at-risk youth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/23-million-in-state-government-funding-to-tackle-youth-crime/105982422</link><description>The NSW government funding will be used to provide more therapeutic services for young offenders, as well as more caseworkers and bail accommodation in Moree.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61d691f15e8d69825aedecaddb2a878c</guid></item><item><title>Overseas-born workers filling a void in local government while loving country life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/overseas-workers-regional-shire-staff-wa/105944266</link><description>As rural shires struggle to attract workers, a wave of overseas born professionals are stepping into the roles and celebrating all that country life has to offer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fda2b764c3ae73eae267bbf17d89a18</guid></item><item><title>US prepares for travel chaos as one in 10 flights to be cut amid shutdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/us-domestic-flight-cuts-in-government-shutdown-explained/105978408</link><description>As many as one in 10 domestic flight services are set to be cut from daily operations at 40 major US airports due to the ongoing government shutdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2b704da6c63ce26d7b7568354c6c163</guid></item><item><title>Ex-NAB employee charged over alleged $200 million bank fraud syndicate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/nsw-nab-bank-fraud-charged-bonnyrigg/105983058</link><description>Police will allege the man used his position as a bank employee to assist the syndicate in applying for approximately $10 million worth of business loans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd6f670f6517e7e872a6ae5fc181f213</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios not taking Aryna Sabalenka lightly in Battle of the Sexes clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/nick-kyrgios-not-taking-aryna-sabalenka-lightly/105983950</link><description>Nick Kyrgios insists he won't be taking Aryna Sabalenka lightly but nor is he ready to be rolled by the women's world number-one in their Battle of the Sexes clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9651a459fee21a1de4bfb301b4f35ab3</guid></item><item><title>Jake Weatherald's 'pinch-yourself moment' as potential Ashes Test debut looms in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/jake-weatherald-pinch-yourself-moment-potential-test-debut/105984276</link><description>Jake Weatherald feared playing for Australia was out of reach when dropped by South Australia, but a move to Tasmania has him on the verge of a Test debut.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d3dbfe63278eccf4fae4239e0b4b1b9</guid></item><item><title>New NT Police anti-racism strategy to drive cultural reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/leanne-liddle-stateline-nt-police-anti-racism-strategy-reform/105976362</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17cd16e590a042703d4e822e8fe0672a</guid></item><item><title>Leanne Liddle speaks on the personal toll of tackling racism within the ranks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/leanne-liddle-speaks-on-the-personal-toll-of-tackling-racism/105981720</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fd20a7bcfb6239e072fdb0c26c6d071</guid></item><item><title>Leanne Liddle on the importance of fairness and avoiding judgement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/leanne-liddle-on-being-fair-and-avoiding-judgement/105981718</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">339781d75806927e64662af77f68a3ab</guid></item><item><title>Architect of NT police anti-racism strategy describes 'hardest job' of her life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/nt-police-culture-racism-leanne-liddle-interview-stateline/105971332</link><description>Leanne Liddle knows what it takes to cut it as a police officer, but says tackling racism within the ranks has been her toughest assignment yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34d254c595a75d0c1d2b6613e9d10e39</guid></item><item><title>Leanne Liddle says chief minister's position won't influence new NT Police anti-racism strategy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/chief-minister-will-not-influence-nt-police-anti-racism-strategy/105981712</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6643c755218734a551b80282067ed714</guid></item><item><title>Proposed job cuts at NSW EPA alarm industry and environmental groups</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/proposed-epa-job-cuts-alarm-industry-and-environmental-groups/105982462</link><description>Conservation groups warn that proposed job cuts to the NSW Environment Protection Authority will leave the state vulnerable to waste dumping and illegal logging.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04f5f0d4a33614aec8b10f615544c966</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley refuses to bite on leadership jab, as Liberals pour cold water on spill threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/ley-leadership-speculation-liberals-cold-water/105983516</link><description>Sussan Ley has refused to bite on speculation about her leadership, after a Liberal colleague suggested she was losing the support of her party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a30736f94a86333c443950e1f1dc04d3</guid></item><item><title>Elon Musk dances with robot at Tesla shareholder meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/elon-musk-dance-with-robot/105983990</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3628c33836ad17f4f57b154655b6af50</guid></item><item><title>Robot dances on stage at Tesla 2025 annual share holder meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/robot-dance-tesla-shareholder-meeting/105983996</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff8de58943b5881fd84bbb1589c66b43</guid></item><item><title>How Elon Musk lined up a potential trillion-dollar payday as Tesla shareholders approve deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/tesla-shareholders-vote-on-elon-musk-trillion-dollar-pay-package/105977686</link><description>Shareholders at Tesla's Texas factory chanted "Elon, Elon" as they overwhelmingly approved the largest-ever CEO compensation package for the company's controversial boss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87ef753ceac02f2a7a0c3fc7a0797751</guid></item><item><title>Child and woman die after car crash in remote Aboriginal community of Doomadgee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/child-woman-dead-doomadgee-after-car-crash-aboriginal-community/105983714</link><description>A 30-year-old woman and a 10-year-old girl are dead and another passenger remains in intensive care in the remote Aboriginal community of Doomadgee after a serious traffic crash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa8f007dd6390885e4cc1ba985f46a31</guid></item><item><title>India's World Cup victory will be remembered as a historic turning point for women's cricket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/cricket-india-womens-world-cup-historic-turning-point-analysis/105983948</link><description>In a short period of time, women's cricket in India has travelled from uneven, dusty grounds to floodlit stadiums packed with roaring fans. The team's upset victory promises yet more investment in the women's game from the world's most fanatical cricketing nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b44d34914bbae8743c29945fb53bf40</guid></item><item><title>Michael Jackson biopic trailer released online after reported legal troubles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/michael-jackson-biopic-trailer-released/105984044</link><description>Antoine Fuqua's movie was meant to be released months ago, but was delayed twice because of reshoots and eventually pushed back to April 2026 — a whole year behind schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c1fff10fe96f681805afc59d5d2e59e</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian farmed salmon industry granted emergency federal approval to use florfenicol antibiotic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/salmon-florfenicol-antibiotics-approved-tasmania/105983426</link><description>The industry's use of the drug is in response to an "endemic" bacterial disease that caused the deaths of up to 15,000 tonnes of salmon from January to April, resulting in dead fish material washing up on multiple beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60bcc94ef2d33d50f5f02dfc6b42ac6e</guid></item><item><title>Ramping in SA at six-month low as Health Minister apologises to patient stuck outside FMC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/sa-ambulance-ramping-hours-lowest-in-six-months/105983214</link><description>SA's Health Minister has apologised to a patient who was ramped outside hospital for several hours as the government releases its ambulance ramping data for October, which is at a six-month low.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b78bf2135ba9b2df3e7210cfa6c867ea</guid></item><item><title>Readers on the grief that comes with euthanasing a dog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/readers-share-grief-pet-death-euthanasia/105950642</link><description>This is what you had to say about the heartbreak that comes with the death of a pet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e585d7b537ab0957b2f0bb70820ce1a</guid></item><item><title>Fire danger information missing from new Bureau of Meteorology website</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/fire-danger-information-missing-from-new-bom-site/105984576</link><description>As bushfire season approaches, firefighters say the BOM's redesigned website is missing crucial safety data — a gap some fire chiefs fear could put lives at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62a0f103fe824d7430e18776e05f0f3c</guid></item><item><title>Craig Robert Dale jailed for $2.77 million fraud of Aboriginal community of Warmun</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/craig-robert-dale-warmun-fraud-sentencing/104871062</link><description>Craig Robert Dale is jailed for seven years for defrauding the remote Aboriginal community of Warmun out of $2.7 million, to fuel his gambling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39c7d051dac9804f3067b26c950cb1ea</guid></item><item><title>WA Premier says upgrade to Perth Convention Centre not value for money, after plans scrapped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/why-plans-for-perth-convention-centre-upgrade-were-scrapped-/105983466</link><description>The WA premier insists a cancelled upgrade of the Perth Convention and Exhibition Centre would not have been value for money, despite the deputy premier previously describing the building as a "cockroach".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">598d3581ebc3719708686455df720a6b</guid></item><item><title>Former NSW Police officer sentenced to 10 years' prison for $100,000 robbery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/nsw-police-sentenced-for-lightning-ridge-robbery-/105971126</link><description>A former police officer who travelled more than 700 kilometres to steal $100,000 from a convicted sex offender has been jailed for 10 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d306117e1fc00992589858bc912d84d</guid></item><item><title>Three men critical after car mounts footpath following Blacktown crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/three-critical-blacktown-crash-mounts-footpath/105985050</link><description>Three men are in a critical condition after a car veered onto a footpath where they were standing following a collision with another vehicle in Sydney's west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">582762ece63578f5b34c2c760befe72d</guid></item><item><title>One man dead and another critically injured after brawl at Goonellabah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/one-man-dead-and-another-critically-injured-in-goonellabah/105985940</link><description>Homicide detectives are investigating the death of a man whose body was found on a walking track near Lismore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a40afddb5ccda034c9ea77f53036871</guid></item><item><title>Queensland man charged with selling stolen sheep.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/queensland-man-charged-with-selling-nearly-900-stolen-sheep/105985390</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ce747cee7d171b1a9ff0878b1a25c81</guid></item><item><title>Alleged sheep rustler charged in southern Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/southern-queensland-sheep-theft/105985558</link><description>A 69-year-old man has been charged after allegedly stealing 880 sheep and selling them through a saleyard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f0935de27f0e9505b498c0e0fe3d563</guid></item><item><title>Questions raised after key election pledge TasInsure fails to appear in Tasmanian budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/tasinsure-fails-to-receive-interim-budget-funding/105983758</link><description>There were hats, jackets and a shop front, but when it came to budget day, there was no money set aside for the creation of TasInsure, which the Tasmanian Liberals promised would save households up to $250 a year during the election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">432264942f7d89e9259ca9d4c6ce513d</guid></item><item><title>Former Australian captain Mark Taylor tells Sam Konstas to ditch ramp shots in bid to earn Test recall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/cricket-mark-taylor-advice-sam-konstas-ramp-shots-test-recall/105986336</link><description>The former Australian captain believes it is time for the talented opener to go back to basics as he finds himself on the outer as the Ashes begin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4309a871a57a9bff1e954defbdf58491</guid></item><item><title>Chinese-made electric buses on Australian roads spark cybersecurity concerns after Norway flags issue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/chinese-electric-buses-in-australia-spark-security-concerns/105982738</link><description>The same Chinese company that makes electric buses now under review in Denmark and Norway also has electric buses on Australian roads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77608d57816d5695bf284b6f9cf56ba8</guid></item><item><title>Friday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/fins-frifinance-20251107/105986400</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e78a48d7370d3ad7e0bc67fb28165c8</guid></item><item><title>Perth man charged with sending sexualised messages to '14-year-old boy' then meeting at shopping centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/perth-man-charged-over-sexualised-messages-to-teens/105983648</link><description>A 31-year-old Riverton man appears in court after allegedly sending sexualised messages to two teenagers pretending to be a 14-year-old boy and then arranging to meet in Perth's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2f2106d73eab3e03d4be32dbd109d0a</guid></item><item><title>Compromise on WA's GST deal not an option, Treasurer Rita Saffioti says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/wa-government-offers-no-compromise-on-gst-deal/105986398</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c70f2551a227c4686691e4666b9e90d6</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos defeat Hawks by 39 points in first AFLW qualifying final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/kangaroos-defeat-hawks-aflw-qualifying-final/105986600</link><description>North Melbourne registers its 25th consecutive win with a 39-point drubbing of Hawthorn in the first AFLW qualifying final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20e0b0150b9dfebf0a497d96ff59493b</guid></item><item><title>A letter to Anthony Albanese could allow Labor MPs to speak up on gambling reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/albanese-government-free-vote-gambling-ad-reform-andrew-wilkie/105969714</link><description>Andrew Wilkie has asked the PM to allow a free vote on banning gambling advertising and it appears many Labor MPs would support it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c1fb7933c8c4d48fed937f5e719605f</guid></item><item><title>Europe's support is more important than ever as Trump checks out on Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/ukraine-russia-putin-trump-european-union/105966958</link><description>European leaders now feel a very existential threat from Russia but it seems their own problems at home are constraining them from doing anything about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a580f011f9ca535149323903ba204eff</guid></item><item><title>While Australians feel the pressure to buy a home this Austrian city embraces lifelong renters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/forever-renters-want-solutions-experts-say-look-at-vienna/105977338</link><description>Experts say the government should be looking to examples in countries where more social and affordable housing options are being developed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df5663d32fe6d4e8102c0cc97059a40e</guid></item><item><title>Country Fire Service prepares for summer season with smoke but no fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/cfs-airborne-drills-fire-season-firefighting-south-australia/105974770</link><description>Ahead of bushfire season, the SA Country Fire Service's air operations teams clear out the cobwebs and take to the skies to simulate bushfires in the Flinders Ranges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">523a216337f55e1c9422180666f9f508</guid></item><item><title>Hawks faced with fresh injury concerns after loss to Kangaroos in AFLW qualifying final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/aflw-qualifying-final-hawthorn-hawks-north-melbourne-kangaroos/105987230</link><description>Injury-ravaged Hawthorn is counting the cost of its heavy loss to North Melbourne in the opening AFLW qualifying final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9facdd94f943a8593385930fff207bb6</guid></item><item><title>Spring see-saw weather brings heat, storms and snow to eastern Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/australia-east-volatile-weather-continues-with-heat-storms-snow/105984906</link><description>Australia's weather has been highly volatile during the past fortnight, and this weekend will serve up another smorgasbord of atmospheric variability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93c00fa031af552f9fd32b1a8b0f4821</guid></item><item><title>Bilpin apple grower fears mystery failed crop could be linked to varroa mite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/nsw-bilpin-apple-failed-crop-weather-varroa-mite-blue-mountains/105962926</link><description>Across the Blue Mountains, apple farmers are noticing less fruit this season. Some are wondering if it's linked to varroa mite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24500daed96a185ccab43f89427a8cf2</guid></item><item><title>Unsettled weather forecast for Queensland with thunderstorms north-west to south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/storms-severe-weather-expected-inland-queensland/105984372</link><description>Storms are expected across a large part of inland Queensland, with the Darling Downs region set to cop another weekend of severe weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc4133e95f272a30033da722c3eb5231</guid></item><item><title>In Melbourne's west, residents say street violence has 'come to their door'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/melbourne-youth-crime-gangs-violence-concerns-melton/105984504</link><description>Five young people have died due to knife violence in two and a half years in the Melbourne suburb of Melton. Residents fear the situation is "out of hand".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7eb7f30685a70cb90a8052ca1082907c</guid></item><item><title>England's Football Association bans Milutin Osmajić for nine matches over racial abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/england-football-association-bans-milutin-osmajic-racial-abuse/105987260</link><description>Montenegro striker Milutin Osmajić is suspended for nine matches for racially abusing an opponent during a match in England's second-tier Championship last season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fd27c72b7b0717601f5e3d5b2319ec5</guid></item><item><title>How colourism and social media abuse have roiled Pacific beauty pageants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/pacific-island-beauty-pageants-colourism-cyberbullying/105966050</link><description>Beauty pageants remain serious business in the Pacific, but contestants are thinking twice before entering due to online bullying and discrimination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">595d60a7eb363d7b9b93b7b7d966e83a</guid></item><item><title>Private health insurance offered little relief for my dental woes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/private-health-insurance-dentist-/105965284</link><description>Do I walk away from private insurance and trust that health challenges will have me seen promptly enough in the public system?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c68f46aadab3aa1d49f1d3a4486e24</guid></item><item><title>James Watson, co-discoverer of DNA's double helix, dead at 97</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/james-watson-co-discoverer-of-dna-double-helix-dead-at-97/105987280</link><description>James Watson, the controversial American biologist whose 1953 discovery of the structure of DNA ushered in the age of genetics, has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">171d4fe307677372cb751b53f1133235</guid></item><item><title>Mildura council aims to take Melbourne's controversial Yellow Peril art in new tourism campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/mildura-council-campaign-to-take-yellow-peril-art-piece/105985016</link><description>Mildura Rural City Council says it wants Melbourne's Yellow Peril art piece to be moved to the regional centre as part of a new tourism campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cd0ac92ca72acad61276f251b799208</guid></item><item><title>Diagnosis of gestational diabetes rises 70 per cent in five years, linked to pregnant woman's age and weight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/gestational-diabetes-pregnant-women-postnatal-care/105978200</link><description>One in five pregnant women are diagnosed with the condition, which experts say is linked to age, weight and a lack of exercise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5c49876628bbc5a7d23ae405d5f8326</guid></item><item><title>Elon Musk’s win at Tesla shareholder meeting causes worry to some</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/elon-musk-tesla-shareholder-meeting-trillion-dollar-payday/105985856</link><description>The world's richest man's believers have once again agreed to enrich the Tesla boss to levels far beyond the realm of ordinary billionaires. But how much is enough?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea8afad07fd0d6f21baf551c807e3bd1</guid></item><item><title>Inside the race to restore Yass's unique 1939 art deco theatre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/inside-the-race-to-restore-yass-s-unique-1939-art-deco-theatre/105986354</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3aafce3c4b6abae3647ff60de234eff</guid></item><item><title>Yass art deco cinema screens first film in 51 years amid ambitious restoration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/act-inside-the-race-to-restore-unique-1939-art-deco-theatre/105980190</link><description>More than five decades since its heritage cinema closed, movies have returned to the big screen in the NSW town of Yass as part of an ambitious volunteer-led project to revive the town's historic art deco theatre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24e1513a01de6ff32a54894410a65c94</guid></item><item><title>They dared to believe and now this amateur English cricket club is taking on Gambia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/the-believers-amateur-english-cricket-club-gambia-national-team/105929550</link><description>Dodgy souvlaki, forgotten bails, and schoolboy defeats — even so, this unlikely group of amateurs are off to play in Gambia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">882ac8a7be7bf624292a328413df66c1</guid></item><item><title>Feral cat eradication on Christmas Island clashes with Malay culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/christmas-island-feral-cat-battle-to-save-native-species/105915526</link><description>On a speck of land in the Indian Ocean, one of the world's most ambitious wars is being waged against feral cats. But not everyone is celebrating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da40e1e6b8d7aad092f1109b55ce3d19</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka to face Elena Rybakina in WTA Finals title decider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/tennis-sabalenka-to-face-rybakina-in-wta-finals-decider/105987334</link><description>World number one Aryna Sabalenka books a showdown with Elena Rybakina, with both players eyeing off their first season-ending championship win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f93a1283d84977708535cee5f649a11</guid></item><item><title>A look at the legacy of Salt-N-Pepa, who will be inducted into the Rock &amp; Roll Hall of Fame</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/salt-n-pepa-inducted-into-rock-and-roll-hall-of-fame/105986642</link><description>Salt-N-Pepa will this weekend be inducted into the Rock &amp; Roll Hall of Fame in the musical influence category. The group, founded in 1985, has had a huge impact on popular music and culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d441a1f350068bf655868dea4f0b553</guid></item><item><title>Former prince Andrew's ex-wife Sarah Ferguson faces uncertainty after 30 years of bad headlines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/sarah-ferguson-faces-uncertainty-after-30-years-of-bad-headlines/105972406</link><description>From selling access to Andrew for £500,000 to dodgy dealings with Jeffrey Esptein, Sarah Ferguson has been creating headlines for all the wrong reasons for three decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bec96c0d2f28552c08c03dd06ed75eae</guid></item><item><title>Albury's Macquarie Textiles celebrated for decades of manufacturing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/alburys-rich-wool-and-textile-history-celebrated-in-exhibition/105958750</link><description>Textile manufacturing took Albury's work to the Opera House, federal parliament, the Olympics and beyond.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e79d3a3fce1ccbf4621429603303d231</guid></item><item><title>Compromise on WA's GST deal not an option, Treasurer Rita Saffioti says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/wa-government-to-win-over-australia-with-gst-deal-review/105973500</link><description>When it comes to Western Australia's slice of the GST pie, the state government is making no apologies for ruffling the feathers of other jurisdictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7da40547d52b41225197e0176651efec</guid></item><item><title>The first Wright Brothers invented the airplane, but these two are creating comics for kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/the-wright-brothers-comics/105978078</link><description>When boys write their own comics, they are bound to be full of fart jokes, stinky-eyed butt dragons and lots of crazy superpowers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f24ab95beeeca19672e6c6849bf5dfa9</guid></item><item><title>This punchy olive and feta salad will lift any meal - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/olive-salad-with-feta-lemon-garlic-dressing/105977258</link><description>With a mix of marinated olives, red onion, capsicum and creamy feta, tossed with fresh herbs and a zesty lemon-garlic dressing, this salad pairs perfectly with grilled meats, seafood or a mezze spread.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3896b173ccee1cd4e70fe166ede45d4</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Health reviews Gold Coast mental health service after youth suicides</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/queensland-health-review-into-gold-coast-mental-health-service/105983904</link><description>The review comes after the suicides of two young people in the past five years who received treatment at the service in Robina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">982b3fa6efa3b446ed0b41728976420f</guid></item><item><title>Amyl and the Sniffers, Tame Impala, Rüfüs Du Sol secure 2026 Grammy nominations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/grammy-awards-nominations-2026-kendrick-lamar-lady-gaga/105987408</link><description>Amyl and the Sniffers, Tame Impala and Rüfüs Du Sol will represent Australia at the 68th Annual Grammy Awards next year. Here is the full list of nominees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">597784cdc7ab08ac7f8b0a6ea6dea065</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos focus on 'wonderful opportunity' in final Ashes Test against England at Headingley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/nrl-kangaroos-determined-to-win-final-ashes-test-against-england/105987460</link><description>The Kangaroos may hold an unassailable 2-0 lead in the Ashes series, but they have not been completely satisfied with their performances in England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95b1521fc73adb839603b8b3397062a0</guid></item><item><title>Police officer stabbed with sword in Grasmere, man charged with attempted murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/police-officer-stabbed-sword-grasmere-attempted-murder-charge/105987472</link><description>Andrea Surache allegedly threw a spear at police officers before stabbing a probationary constable in the leg with a sword in Sydney's south-west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd02dd9b501e9355189796917e132e20</guid></item><item><title>Inquest hears of communication breakdown between corrections, health staff before death in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/nt-wayne-hunt-death-in-custody-inquest-prison-seizure/105972088</link><description>A coronial inquest into the death in custody of a Darwin prisoner has heard prison officers ignored concerns about the "comatose" man being placed alone in a cell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd1fa8d436521d5eb34ce9c9c23cf4d1</guid></item><item><title>Graham Richardson, former Labor powerbroker, dies aged 76</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/graham-richardson-labor-powerbroker-dies/7305430</link><description>The PM leads tributes for the former minister who was a political powerbroker from the time he dived headlong into Labor's factional brawls in the 1960s to his final days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">121bf79218b35a4092505b256a9c0502</guid></item><item><title>Sudan's crisis has entered a dramatic new phase — but it started years ago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/what-is-happening-in-sudan-who-is-fighting-and-why/105963190</link><description>The latest chapter in Sudan's civil war has captured the world's attention. To understand what's happening now it helps to understand some of the country's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c8e1b0d0bcece586a1810af8261681e</guid></item><item><title>Surge in discarded syringes on streets of Kalgoorlie-Boulder amid meth 'epidemic'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/discarded-syringes-on-the-rise-in-kalgoorlie-boulder/105974538</link><description>There has been a massive surge in the number of discarded syringes being collected from the streets of Kalgoorlie-Boulder, with more than 5,323 so far this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b1b64f436d0b6286470d7fbd7c6403c</guid></item><item><title>Former Labor minister Graham Richardson dead at 76</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/former-labor-minister-graham-richardson-dead-at-76/105987598</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54ec88d90f86924ecd50b89934861421</guid></item><item><title>Plan to save sacred Millstream aquifer welcomed amid water sustainability concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/millstream-water-aquifer-yindjibarndi-pilbara/105979000</link><description>With sacred springs and water holes in northern WA drying up, the WA government decides to relocate where it is extracting groundwater from.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebba099504d5bf52d2ba6a33a9641dea</guid></item><item><title>Nusa Penida before and after elevator construction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/nusa-penida-before-and-after-elevator-construction-/105987762</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edbaef4884b90a07f7d2a6c1735d09c0</guid></item><item><title>Fairlie Arrow abduction hoax: Why the Gold Coast singer faked her own kidnapping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/fairlie-arrows-abduction-hoax/105686102</link><description>Gold Coast singer Fairlie Arrow disappeared from her home in 1991. As a police kidnapping investigation unfolded and media attention ramped up, Arrow had to admit it was all a hoax.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6cb4134b92de8272b252150767feabc</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand's Shanice Parker to face Australia in Pacific Cup final in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/missing-piece-why-ex-wallaroo-shanice-parker-is-now-a-kiwi-fern/105987788</link><description>Shanice Parker is the daughter of a Jillaroos World Cup player, but meeting her biological father as a teenager has prompted her to represent New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72ee1259d2d6161b8f7bad06cb458a96</guid></item><item><title>Re-entering housing market after divorce hard for many due to loss of shared income</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/home-ownership-difficulties-for-divorced-women/105981414</link><description>Rising house prices and lower incomes due to caring for children can make it especially difficult for women to re-enter the housing market after a divorce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d001fbcfb754b43e0732507b94b2cbe</guid></item><item><title>Deepfake AI ad featuring WA Premier Roger Cook prompts latest scam warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/wa-premier-deepfake-ai-scam-prompts-warning-amid-cheaper-tech/105987626</link><description>WA's consumer watchdog says scams are getting more sophisticated and cheaper to make, as an AI video of state premier Roger Cook sparks new concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f30769f331491cf2e683ac85faec872</guid></item><item><title>Typhoon Kalmaegi rages across Vietnam as the Philippines prepares for a new storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/typhoon-kalmaegi-vietnam-philippines/105987870</link><description>Typhoon Kalmaegi left hundreds dead and as Filipinos are bracing for more extreme conditions as they mourn their loved ones and pick up the pieces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e24c4299a820b61852bb823b2d50ddc</guid></item><item><title>Health authorities issue a nationwide recall of various alfalfa sprouts due to salmonella outbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/alfalfa-sprouts-recall-nationwide-salmonella-outbreak/105988002</link><description>Salmonella symptoms usually start six to 72 hours after exposure to the bacteria and usually last for four to seven days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b40887a2d1db01b82d6ac47a6f98667</guid></item><item><title>Carlton beats West Coast by 41 points in AFLW elimination final at Princes Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/carlton-west-coast-aflw-final/105987988</link><description>Carlton stuns West Coast with a dominant AFLW finals win, as Mia Austin honours her late cousin Ben with an emotional goal at Princes Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0256083e030b8ee6db36120156bbc96b</guid></item><item><title>WA Premier Roger Cook shown in deepfake AI scam video</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/wa-premier-roger-cook-shown-in-deepfake-ai-scam-video/105988144</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd872fb60a72fb6a8319fd96e3ffb314</guid></item><item><title>Police allowed neo-Nazi protest outside NSW parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/police-allowed-neo-nazi-protest-outside-nsw-parliament/105987780</link><description>A neo-Nazi rally outside the NSW parliament on Saturday morning was deemed "authorised" because police had chosen not to oppose the public assembly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3b0c6f1c787fafb74b62126a4979b10</guid></item><item><title>India wins T20 series against Australia after washout at the Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/sport-aus-vs-ind-washout-gabba/105987568</link><description>Stormy weather ensures only 4.5 overs are bowled in the fifth and final T20 match between Australia and India in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a479c9019a2a8928be9ab1ea05181283</guid></item><item><title>Australia secure 3-0 Ashes whitewash with 22-point win over England in third Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/ashes-australia-england-rugby-league-third-test/105988440</link><description>The Kangaroos have secured a 3-0 Ashes victory with Harry Grant leading the way in a big win over England at Headingley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d8c2531ee96376811e22c0751da3c50</guid></item><item><title>F1 Brazil qualifying: Oscar Piastri crashes out of Formula 1 São Paulo sprint race, qualifies fourth for grand prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/f1-brazil-qualifying-oscar-piastri-crashes-sprint-race/105975222</link><description>Oscar Piastri will start on the second row of the grid for Monday's São Paulo Grand Prix. after crashing earlier in the sprint race and losing more ground to Lando Norris in the Formula 1 drivers' championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">317f938522abd78e36fb12bdcae5059c</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fall to Italy 26-19 in Udine Test to record consecutive defeats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/italy-vs-wallabies-rugby-union-test-live-blog-updates/105977302</link><description>The Wallabies slump to consecutive defeats on their spring tour, as Italy comes from behind to win in Udine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69613233f8d6a9253fe911222ce2f4aa</guid></item><item><title>How the dismissal of Gough Whitlam's Labor government in 1975 was sealed by the Senate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/whitlam-dismissal-gough-1975-kerr-fraser-senate-november-11/105978168</link><description>Before Gough Whitlam's dismissal and famous speech on the steps of Parliament House, there was silence — and strategy — in the Senate. This is the inside story of how a budget stand-off changed Australian democracy forever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80ddbe217c18224c0b7f6e74324b4104</guid></item><item><title>Australia's democratic system is unlike any other on Earth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/civic-duty-compulsory-preferential-voting-rules-aec-secret/105969502</link><description>Behind the quirks of Australia's incredible democratic system are a series of complex human backstories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">602b46846406188b518550f61414852d</guid></item><item><title>In regional Australia, country communities are forced to become developers amid a scarcity of downsize housing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/older-country-australians-dont-have-anywhere-to-downsize-to/105959030</link><description>In regional Australia, where baby boomers are being told to downsize to free up homes, country communities are having to become developers to build appropriate-sized housing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de6cd27a1b4e62278efd9c8254c9b34</guid></item><item><title>How Trump's deportation agenda is impacting the world's poorest country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/south-sudan-used-for-us-migrant-deportations/105869256</link><description>An expansion of the Trump administration's deportations to Africa, where impoverished and conflict-ridden states are hosting third-country migrants, may be a detriment to the most disadvantaged.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5be9a7477910dd1d9e475e00b58513c5</guid></item><item><title>Closure of Teen Vogue sparks concerns for youth-led journalism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/teen-vogue-closure-layoffs-threatens-youth-journalism/105972512</link><description>One of publisher Condé Nast's most acclaimed stories this year came from Teen Vogue. Now, it is shuttering the youth publication — and laying off the staff involved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd4b7d86fc86eb67a822483e60b7c3ad</guid></item><item><title>Are political differences impacting your relationship? Share your story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/politics-in-relationships/105965214</link><description>Research shows political differences are increasingly impacting relationships. Share your story here.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5334f7b0ee7a34c9bf7d2bb9b7075ab</guid></item><item><title>Mar wanted to be a professional basketballer. Desperate for money, he turned to selling drugs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/youth-gangs-crime-victoria-melbourne-violence/105982944</link><description>When Mar Riek was 13, he dreamed of being a professional basketballer. His family couldn't afford the fees, so he joined a gang and started selling drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef2214f7a80630f67e3e704e055aab4a</guid></item><item><title>IMF economists say inflation targeting hasn't performed brilliantly in recent years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/imf-economists-inflation-targeting-performance-after-2022/105975542</link><description>IMF economists say inflation-targeting central banks did not achieve better outcomes than others following the 2022 surge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9a471aa1e122ca0a4dc865d1ef2cc1d</guid></item><item><title>Cape Barren Island's Marra Wunna golf course, where shoes are optional</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/cape-barren-island-marra-wunna-golf-course/105741322</link><description>Golf has a reputation for being expensive and exclusive — but on this island in Bass Strait, things are a bit more relaxed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37569f28194e36a74f47f6b3e36fe659</guid></item><item><title>Developers being forced to build affordable housing could ease rental market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/mandatory-housing-contributions-possible-relief-sydney-renters/105971062</link><description>Carrie-Ann is now cooking in her own kitchen thanks to a mandatory affordable housing contribution scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">595c68d74b08a5cb4b5e27947b195a17</guid></item><item><title>'World’s first sex worker statue’ returns home after 30 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/nsw-sydney-joy-sex-worker-statue-bronze-loui-may/105965522</link><description>Joy, a sculpture by artist Loui May, was erected in Sydney's Darlinghurst in the late 1990s. After hundreds signed a petition for its return, a bronze version was created and placed in the spot it once stood decades ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a2baefb00374b37f19cda499dc24e01</guid></item><item><title>Samoan fans line the streets of Apia ahead of match against New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/samoan-fans-line-the-streets-of-apia/105973738</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d85f1fdf1521bc43cf846e9d69937584</guid></item><item><title>Pacific, pride, and pancakes with Papa's father-in-law</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/samoa-pacific-championship-final-junior-paulo/105963222</link><description>The passion of the Pacific shines through in Samoa's rugby league team, and the pride the people have is evident on the island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a82a41387df51b8638c27b07726ec22c</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Police data reveals almost 50 per cent drop in recorded road safety enforcement in five years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/queensland-police-data-road-enforcement-drop-as-deaths-rise/105971932</link><description>Queensland Police concedes less time is being spent enforcing road safety than before the COVID pandemic, amid a rising number of traffic tragedies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10be56059c70344ab918aafdc61bc8c3</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Will you get lucky and ace this quiz? I wouldn't bet on it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/105951652</link><description>I applaud your courage for having a go. That's about it, though.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3096b4a5fd4e9711ae4d1cfd9dceb43</guid></item><item><title>Elena Rybakina defeats Aryna Sabalenka to win WTA Finals and collect record prize money</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/elena-rybakina-beats-aryna-sabalenka-wta-finals-record-prize/105988902</link><description>Elena Rybakina has defeated world number one Aryna Sabalenka to win the season-ending WTA Finals, 6-3, 7-6(0).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f9ed6f64d8247ccc38291999576e6de</guid></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani gave these New York women 'a glimmer of hope'. They helped make him mayor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/how-women-powered-zohran-mamdani-into-mayors-office/105976734</link><description>Zohran Mamdani's victory in Tuesday's New York City mayoral election looked unlikely at one point. Polling shows it was women who helped power him into office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">078497554693bcc4a818e09d4c85af8d</guid></item><item><title>Die My Love filmmaker Lynne Ramsay on realising a punk rock adaptation of Ariana Harwicz's novel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/die-my-love-movie-jennifer-lawrence-martin-scorsese-lynne-ramsay/105948060</link><description>After reading Die My Love in book club, Martin Scorsese knew it had to be made into a film. Now it's rewriting cinema's portrayal of womanhood and postpartum depression.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29c1a0907c89d421b1eca6f5a2ff1940</guid></item><item><title>Students, teaching staff face challenges amid Adelaide University merger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/sa-adelaide-university-merger-challenges/105981104</link><description>From late next month, the University of Adelaide and the University of South Australia will begin to cease operations and transform to become Adelaide University. But as the clock ticks, some students and staff are feeling the pressure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c123dfb42ccd86d2baee9b5ff5650d87</guid></item><item><title>Australia Kangaroos coach Kevin Walters says rugby league Ashes needs to continue after defeating England 30-8 in third Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/australia-kangaroos-kevin-walters-calls-for-more-ashes/105988958</link><description>Australia coach Kevin Walters has dismissed suggestions the Kangaroos' whitewash series win over England was "a walk in the park", praising his counterparts following the third Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81eb3a1c79c08642579eba7fd63087e2</guid></item><item><title>UN photographer Martine Perret turns lens on women of Australia's hinterland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/photographer-martine-perret-exhibition-on-rural-women/105970848</link><description>Parisian-born UN photographer Martine Perret turns her lens to capture the resilience and strength of women in rural Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dd9d7f6c20a06b93d7e20d35c390c83</guid></item><item><title>Bisalloy Steel defends '20-plus-year' relationship with Israeli companies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/steel-company-bisalloy-defends-israel-trade/105983828</link><description>Bisalloy Steel's Unanderra site has been the target of multiple pro-Palestine pickets, and has defended its trade with "several Israeli" companies during its 2025 annual general meeting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cccb4ed17ad8c34a5081f35bd2e1ef7f</guid></item><item><title>Bragg says ditching net zero 'too silly for words' as Liberals play semantics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/bragg-says-ditching-net-zero-too-silly-for-words/105988972</link><description>Ahead of meetings to agree on a Liberal climate policy, the leading moderate says his party must retain a focus on achieving net zero better than Labor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf6c48c91681fb602c3962f1cd03dcda</guid></item><item><title>Boyne Island boy Nayte Scott diagnosed with Duchenne Muscular Dystrophy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/nayte-scott-duchenne-muscular-dystrophy-cq/105980892</link><description>When Skye Scott took her son to a paediatrician, she never imagined he would be diagnosed with the life-changing Duchenne muscular dystrophy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74517c62f7fdfa2b0820bc0a09f72f64</guid></item><item><title>Russian strikes on apartment building, energy sites in eastern Ukraine kill four</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/russian-strikes-ukraine-apartment-building-energy-sites-kill-4/105988992</link><description>A Russian drone slams into an apartment building in eastern Ukraine, killing three people, while another is killed at an energy site, Ukrainian authorities report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad26ba06c97aeb7164e73d961dbedff8</guid></item><item><title>New food safety rules for produce in Tasmania have smaller growers worried</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/uncertainty-for-small-scale-farmers-over-new-food-safety-rules/105987666</link><description>The new regulations would bring Tasmania into line with national standards, but smaller growers are worried they will have to pay the same fees and meet the same auditing requirements as large-scale growers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea43d0153ebd9741638bdae6f60b3f69</guid></item><item><title>Women's pain inquiry finds Victorians' suffering worsened by male-centred healthcare system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/womens-pain-inquiry-victoria-released/105988930</link><description>A Victorian inquiry has found a dismissive and disrespectful healthcare system centred around men is contributing to poorer outcomes for women and girls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97b42a22ed7dc4f3b24481877f1e85de</guid></item><item><title>Princess Anne attends service at Hall of Remembrance in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/prince-george-steals-the-show-at-festival-of-remembrance/105988988</link><description>Royal loyalists celebrate the Princess Royal's visit to Australia amid the scandal engulfing her brother, Andrew Mountbatten Windsor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2813ffebcd6efa7e843c9face138f1a3</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies lament poor performance in 26-19 Test rugby loss to Italy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/wallabies-hurting-after-test-rugby-loss-to-italy/105989132</link><description>Wallabies captain Harry Wilson says he is "hurting" after Australia's 26-19 loss to Italy, while coach Joe Schmidt is lamenting his side's "flat performance".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f395db4e9511bada325db3685525bcf</guid></item><item><title>Bread tags, soy fish sauce bottles on list of plastic items to be phased out in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/bread-tags-among-more-plastic-items-banned-in-nsw/105988924</link><description>The second phase of the NSW government's plan to tackle the plastic pollution crisis will roll out in stages from next year until 2030.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e555dd9c930e1ff17ef5334f696b2a92</guid></item><item><title>Bragg pledges to do ‘right thing’ if Liberal party scraps net zero commitment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/bragg-pledges-to-do-right-thing-if-liberal-party-quits-paris/105989218</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95924ee28599aa1808fd65ee5530c803</guid></item><item><title>Oasis leaves Australia after triumphant sold-out tour, with no signs of brotherly discord</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/oasis-leave-australia-triumphant-after-gigantic-sold-out-tour/105989138</link><description>Playing to a combined audience of about 320,000 people, Liam and Noel Gallagher's return to Australia for this much-hyped tour has been nothing short of a triumph.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">883dbd25a69cd42a192c3f1eff216dbd</guid></item><item><title>The J Awards has been loud and proud about Australian music for 20 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/20-years-triplej-j-awards-autralian-music-awards-trophies/105982742</link><description>The centrepiece of triple j's Ausmusic Month celebrations, the J Awards is celebrating its 20th anniversary in 2025. Here's how it all began.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84e0ee4f58f21e327f519d2b53f7f2ef</guid></item><item><title>International students are struggling with Australia's cost of living — and experts say there is no quick fix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/international-students-struggle-with-costs-in-australia/105815354</link><description>International students are grappling with Australia's high cost of living, and experts warn there are no quick fixes to their financial stress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cb710bcd57d50943fca862b30c8ebaf</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate reports of gunshot heard near Dezi Freeman's property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/dezi-freeman-gunshot-witness-report-investigated/105989122</link><description>Police are investigating witness reports of a single gunshot heard near Dezi Freeman's property shortly after he allegedly killed two police officers in August.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0900e5562376d0c709980e6a0083493d</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroo activity increasing on South Australian regional roads, with collisions up by about 40 per cent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/kangaroo-collisions-up-on-regional-south-australian-roads/105985252</link><description>Drivers on regional roads are being warned of an increase in kangaroo activity on South Australian roads, with large mobs of roos seen lining roads at dawn and dusk, creating growing safety concerns for road users.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ffc608e763b860e89f0b1d912a3c686</guid></item><item><title>Concerns about missing signs on Kojonup road raised before fatal crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/missing-safety-sign-flagged-months-before-fatal-kojonup-crash/105978238</link><description>A former road safety assessor says he wrote to authorities about missing signage months before a man in his 40s died on a winding road in southern Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fae7e3c83310c5802a5392c8cde88b47</guid></item><item><title>Annemarie Manders reflects on 35 years as a lavender farmer in the Yarra Valley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/annemarie-manders-lavender-farmer-victoria-yarra-valley/105968732</link><description>Annemarie Manders reflects on how she became a lavender farmer in the Yarra Valley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8ddd247877e780f0420e95e8b7914da</guid></item><item><title>Grampians hosts Oceania's only World Trail Majors race as ultra-runners ascend Gariwerd</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/grampians-hosts-international-ultra-marathon-event/105973226</link><description>Nepali runner Sangé Sherpa returns to the Grampians with an unconventional race tactic and a global field of competitors chasing him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b34c8a35db790d9517d925d6f7e1e1e</guid></item><item><title>Labor Party members vote for fracking ban to be extended across all parts of WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/labor-party-members-vote-for-fracking-ban-to-be-extended/105987602</link><description>Labor party members call for hydraulic fracturing, or fracking, to be banned across the whole of WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb88d973a3a4eba4ce761eeb9c94d282</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters battle out-of-control blaze in New Zealand national park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/new-zealand-fire-tongariro-national-park/105989176</link><description>Fire and Emergency New Zealand says an out-of-control wildfire in Tongariro National Park has swelled in size to about 1,000 hectares, leading to the evacuation of dozens of hikers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a2f8a4b263733a754b20d295e223a04</guid></item><item><title>The telltale signs the Louvre heist was not a 'professional' job</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/the-clues-the-louvre-thieves-left-behind/105976148</link><description>A series of missteps shows the theft in the Louvre was far from a sleek operation. Instead, French authorities believe petty criminals executed it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">379d0791d365cf3ec0d312e2c1674a3c</guid></item><item><title>Tongariro National Park’s wildfire surges in size</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/tongariro-national-park-s-wildfire-surges-in-size-/105989368</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37e5349f55c5e9582473ce0a490d83f3</guid></item><item><title>Man in custody after 'catastrophic' crash that killed his partner and stepdaughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/28yo-qld-man-custody-fatal-traffic-crash-doomadgee/105988936</link><description>A man in police custody since a crash killed a woman, 30, and a girl, 10, in the Queensland community of Doomadgee has been confirmed as the partner of the woman and father and stepfather of the children in the vehicle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dab44183f71f9b3d1ce9e5cdce90135</guid></item><item><title>Thinking 'outside the box' to bolster WA's housing supply</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/bolstering-wa-housing-supply-/105988264</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b111ceff86da2a1a2403f236793155e</guid></item><item><title>Feelings of failure and being unseen. What it's like to be a stepmum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/what-it-is-like-to-be-a-stepmum/105938274</link><description>There is no road map for step-parenting, and experts say a common mistake is assuming it will be easy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcaca49a049cbf4e2f158b501d96e271</guid></item><item><title>AFLW finals: Brisbane Lions beat Melbourne by 13 points to reach prelim final, Adelaide beats St Kilda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/aflw-finals-demons-lions-crows-st-kilda/105989048</link><description>Brisbane defeats Melbourne for the first time in AFLW finals, as the Lions win on the road to clinch a preliminary final spot, and Adelaide ends St Kilda's season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">783e8c84dc0c13742cade1773ff8dd09</guid></item><item><title>Australia beats New Zealand 40-8 to defend Women's Pacific Cup crown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/jillaroos-kiwi-ferns-pacific-cup-final/105989340</link><description>Julia Robinson scores twice as Australia defeats New Zealand 40-8 to claim a second consecutive Pacific Cup in emphatic fashion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aaeba66355bcfad2c606f83355b18cbd</guid></item><item><title>Cook Islands qualify for Rugby League World Cup, beating South Africa 58-6 in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/cook-islands-grab-last-spot-at-rugby-league-world-cup/105989280</link><description>Cook Islands book their spot in a fourth Rugby League World Cup, turning it on to beat South Africa 58-6 in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff515a028324ba5a02c348e53f5de2a7</guid></item><item><title>Police should have broken up neo-Nazi stunt, NSW opposition says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/neo-nazi-protest-nsw-parliament-house-police/105989586</link><description>NSW Police should have gone to court to stop a neo-Nazi stunt outside Parliament House, Opposition Leader Mark Speakman says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beb3faae14c04dfcb07de3c45a563c01</guid></item><item><title>Coverage of embattled Perth builder, WA's 'most vulnerable child', among award-winning journalism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/abc-stories-recognised-at-meaa-awards-/105989352</link><description>Coverage of the collapse of Perth builder Nicheliving, WA's 'most vulnerable child' and the state's guardianship system is among the award-winning journalism at the state's media awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eb6943dc996eb5c2f9706004c0d3c41</guid></item><item><title>Canberra police watch house closed again after sewage 'spewed out all over the place'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/sewage-leak-forces-closure-of-canberra-ciy-watch-house/105989604</link><description>The police union calls for Canberra's city watch house to be condemned and a new one built after faulty sewerage forced the site to be temporarily closed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75530bb3615de7ec5bf883c1467707a6</guid></item><item><title>Majority of Australia's first Ashes Test squad to feature in Sheffield Shield round four</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/sport-australian-cricketers-to-play-in-shield/105989694</link><description>Fourteen members of Australia's 15-man squad for the first Ashes Test will take part in this week's Sheffield Shield fixtures, while England will play an intra-squad game in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f06f06bd6cce4e527bcbde29b1bf50d1</guid></item><item><title>Spooked investors worry the AI bubble could pop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/spooked-investors-worry-the-ai-bubble-could-pop-/105989746</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">327fcc0b1b97e2103865236e0093a929</guid></item><item><title>Salt-N-Pepa, White Stripes inducted into Rock &amp; Roll Hall of Fame</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/rock-n-roll-hall-of-fame-induction-2025/105989584</link><description>A star-studded line-up including Elton John, Chappell Roan, Stevie Wonder and Cyndi Lauper performs at LA's Peacock Theatre for a ceremony to induct Salt-N-Pepa, Warren Zevon, Sound Garden, Outkast, Bad Company and the White Stripes into the Rock &amp; Roll Hall of Fame.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3daf76b4262deb4f50b2d9dcd753e720</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand defeats Samoa 36-14 to claim Pacific Cup and farewell Kieran Foran in style</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/new-zealand-wins-pacific-cup-against-samoa/105989564</link><description>New Zealand overturns an eight-point half-time deficit to defeat Samoa 36-14 and claim its second Pacific Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3229f026d372afdafeab2d87b2cab02c</guid></item><item><title>Why the Pacific Championship final should be a look into rugby league's future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/samoa-new-zealand-pacific-championship-final/105989560</link><description>New Zealand stopped Samoa from making history in the Pacific Championship final but the match was a tantalising reminder of what's possible for rugby league in the days to come.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cf9448afcd59240beb63ed8bbeee4fd</guid></item><item><title>Veteran radio broadcaster John Laws has died aged 90</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-09/veteran-radio-broadcaster-john-laws-has-died-aged-90/105989816</link><description>Known as the "Golden Tonsils", Laws was one of Australia's most recognisable voices in talkback radio.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15179999e340b6c78bcb2afa20024dc2</guid></item></channel></rss>