<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jan 2026 13:25:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Former North Melbourne AFL player Phoenix Spicer dies aged 23</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/afl-former-north-melbourne-player-phoenix-spicer-dies/106197350</link><description>Phoenix Spicer, who played 12 AFL matches for North Melbourne, has died at the age of 23.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfa0dfdd5a10b7ce680fca27b175557a</guid></item><item><title>How artificial intelligence is being used across the ACT to provide vital services</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/how-act-government-is-using-ai-across-services/106137618</link><description>Artificial intelligence is a controversial subject, but as the debate rages it is already being used by ACT government departments, doctors and the people running firefighting operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10d58a3640f58092e04e8f0b3594fff5</guid></item><item><title>Top End dams overflow as parks come to life in the wake of Cyclone Fina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/fogg-dam-darwin-river-cyclone-fina-monsoon/106194820</link><description>The Northern Territory's Top End has been transformed into a lush green paradise by a cyclone and a monsoon that have brought an unusually heavy start to the annual wet season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bbc1a06303d5df7cdf15ccf7111d910</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2026: Bad light halts England's charge as Harry Brook and Joe Root dominate spinless Aussie attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/live-updates-ashes-australia-vs-england-fifth-test-day-one/106197464</link><description>The top two men's Test batters in the world make hay against a spinless Australian attack, only to be stopped by the weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d9e95b3c067548eb7455d61911bd1a7</guid></item><item><title>Collector with 50 pinball machines in his shed hopes to create a playable museum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/western-australia-pinball-collector-greg-sharpe-bally-williams/106190702</link><description>This shed in Western Australia is filled wall-to-wall with collectable pinball machines, all in working order. Greg Sharp hopes to one day share it as a playable pinball museum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">551adce7b764201eb76b53d9fbddfb07</guid></item><item><title>US makes 'bold' grab for oil as financial markets brace for price change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/us-intervention-in-venezuela-impact-on-oil-prices-unclear/106197522</link><description>Oil futures do not trade until Monday, Australian time, and financial market participants are divided over whether there will be a spike or correction in the price of oil in Asian trade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cddf5973a667bf5403f659045cd625dd</guid></item><item><title>Evonne Goolagong Cawley's life story immortalised in screen drama</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/evonne-goolagong-cawley-tennis-lila-mcguire/106121294</link><description>Lila McGuire on the pressure and joy of playing former world number one and winner of seven grand slam singles titles, tennis legend Evonne Goolagong Cawley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17b39dbac2a0c60bd0858768f09e02d7</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan diaspora divided over US capturing of leader Maduro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/venezuelan-diaspora-divided-over-us-capturing-of-leader-maduro/106197588</link><description>Venezuelan migrants across Latin America and other parts of the world cheered in the streets, supporting the US mission to capture Venezuela's deposed president, Nicolás Maduro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bb59c27e88d19c330d4a4cf93d035c4</guid></item><item><title>SCG pays tribute to Bondi heroes, weather frustrates and Australia goes spinless — quick hits from day one of fifth Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/ashes-fifth-test-at-scg-day-one-quick-hits/106197510</link><description>Australia opts not to pick a spinner for another Test, breaking a streak of 138 years at the SCG, which rises as one to honour the heroes of the Bondi terror attack. Here are the quick hits from the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb302c1928946d6230d618f585d1ea1b</guid></item><item><title>Weary Australia eyes Ashes finish line at the SCG as England senses opportunity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/ashes-fifth-test-day-one-weary-australia-eyes-ashes-finish-line/106197850</link><description>Only the rain could slow England's progress on day one in Sydney, as a weary Australia reflected its coach's claims the series really ended in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0673d5a9a75261e6fada5da482bd264</guid></item><item><title>Australian cricket great Damien Martyn awakes from induced coma after falling ill with meningitis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/australian-cricket-great-damien-martyn-awakes-from-coma/106198212</link><description>Former Australian Test batsman Damien Martyn is awake and talking after being in an induced coma for several days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c44eb726bb83ef6540bbd5a1ffa2f384</guid></item><item><title>Thanasi Kokkinakis tears up and Nick Kyrgios chills out as Special Ks return at Brisbane International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-04/nick-kyrgios-thanasi-kokkinakis-special-ks/106198254</link><description>Thanasi Kokkinakis said he didn't think he'd be able to return to tennis after a 2025 blighted by injury. Instead he's made a winning return alongside doubles partner and all-round showman Nick Kyrgios.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7aef09a3f488ce63cc4a9cf1fddbcb21</guid></item><item><title>Venezuela updates: Maduro arrives at Manhattan court, Trump doubles down on oil plans for Venezuela - as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/venezuela-maduro-in-custody-blog-january-5/106198380</link><description>Deposed Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro and his wife have been transferred to a New York courthouse as Donald Trump doubles down on oil plans for Venezuela — as it happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dfd5b587b46b480d65b9556a0e4fc6b</guid></item><item><title>Death toll rises in Iran as anti-government protests spread</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/iran-protests-spread-death-toll-rises/106198320</link><description>At least 16 people have been killed in a week of demonstrations fuelled by the rising cost of living.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95d5d3870c71498c6f6b04fccea8017d</guid></item><item><title>Cookbook Club Naarm is bringing strangers together over food</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/cookbook-supper-club-community-events-cooking-books-chef-potluck/106092308</link><description>Each month, strangers and friends meet to share dishes from a chosen cookbook. But Cookbook Club Naarm is more than a foodie feast, it's a reminder of food's power to bring us together.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7003e991adab8bd16875eb0360f89db3</guid></item><item><title>Inflation, tariffs, EVs: What the ABC's business experts are watching in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/economy-markets-predictions-2026-business-experts/106156688</link><description>What are you watching in 2026 when it comes to the economy or markets? That's the question we put to the ABC's experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8e64e8827c29ee9a51c9b365ad229e5</guid></item><item><title>Repeated brain injuries linked to memory changes in intimate partner violence survivors, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/brain-injury-concussion-strangulation-partner-violence-study/106159980</link><description>An Australian-first study finds evidence of previously undetected, long-term cognitive changes in women more than six months after they experienced repeated concussions and strangulation during intimate partner violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3515faea792fbbea3ef26d94212d5fbf</guid></item><item><title>Value of Australian dollar now dependent on interest rates, commodities prices and geopolitics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/australian-dollar-now-dependent-on-interest-rates-commodities/106186480</link><description>The value of Australia's currency could move significantly up or down depending on the direction of interest rates. But the global economic backdrop will also be crucial in determining its direction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7e2086e93d1eeda3b7369847e469d66</guid></item><item><title>Were the US actions in Venezuela legal under international law?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/were-the-us-actions-in-venezuela-legal-under-international-law/106198134</link><description>International law is created by all states, not just the powerful few. This makes international community reactions to breaches particularly important.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a0e863241ad26e5cd8c8ea505ef6198</guid></item><item><title>National donor conception register would prevent 'potential trauma', advocate says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/national-donor-conception-register-for-key-information-call/106188336</link><description>Hundreds of people have accessed South Australia's Donor Conception Register in its first year, lifting decades of secrecy surrounding anonymous donations — an outcome that has prompted calls from a leading advocate for similar moves at national level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ccef3ff92f6b64b2e7e9c03e5e15da5</guid></item><item><title>Nicolás Maduro's allies maintain power in Venezuela, rejecting US claims they will 'comply'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nicolas-maduro-allies-take-power-in-venezuela/106198570</link><description>The Trump administration insists Venezuela's leaders will now comply with American demands after the extraordinary capture of president Nicolás Maduro — but his allies are resisting US pressure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83250884e03b7c92ee18975a7269611d</guid></item><item><title>Daria Kasatkina defeated at Brisbane International as Ajla Tomljanović reaches second round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/brisbane-international-tennis-daria-kasatkina-ajla-tomljanovic/106198664</link><description>Daria Kasatkina admits she held back tears and dealt with severe nerves during an agonising three-set loss at the Brisbane International.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a32d0120141242f52a751aac1eeffec</guid></item><item><title>Emergency departments ill-suited for mental health crises, advocates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/patient-traumatising-hospital-care-act-crisis/106157462</link><description>A 24-year-old NSW border resident says dismissive treatment in hospitals, long waits for care and limited access to services have pushed her away from support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f1c951190641b270ccdeaceac77ed09</guid></item><item><title>First stock loss figures reported as Western River at Winton reaches major flood level</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/qld-wet-weather-richmond-winton-flood/106197638</link><description>As widespread flooding maintains its grip on north-west Queensland, thousands of livestock are reported missing or dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c62a51b2e3d40a513de6bd79879eb19a</guid></item><item><title>This sacred 'forbidden island' in Japan is World Heritage listed and completely off limits to women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/okinoshima-island-world-heritage-listed-gender-ban/106017014</link><description>Boasting thousands of years of history and a World Heritage listing, Okinoshima is Japan's very own treasure island. It's also completely off limits to women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6008aa4cf4f81cb4dd85f39230b6299</guid></item><item><title>NT police data shows crime down in Alice Springs, locals worry it will be short-lived</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/alice-springs-crime-rates-down-long-term-solutions/106177896</link><description>After years of negative headlines, crime rates in Alice Springs are showing signs of turning a corner but some locals remain worried the change could be short-lived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3d99161c25f0c4a1425171ad43ced0f</guid></item><item><title>Property crime down in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/property-crime-down-in-alice-springs/106197874</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1cbcc1a35ba7dec0ef7328c01fe3199</guid></item><item><title>Australia urged to back spinners after Todd Murphy's omission from fifth Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/ashes-scg-test-australia-critcises-for-leaving-out-spinner/106198718</link><description>Leg spinner Mitchell Swepson wants Australian cricket officials and curators to buck the growing trend of producing pitches that heavily favour seam bowlers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94e68ac134662be379513200ede43cac</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelans march in Caracas to oppose Maduro's capture.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/venezuelans-march-in-caracas-to-oppose-maduro-capture/106198748</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dd0da9fbce5906065ad8e4f58fa4553</guid></item><item><title>Rufous scrub-bird DNA project aims to safeguard ancient and elusive songbird</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/dna-project-to-save-rufous-scrub-bird/106191878</link><description>The Rufous scrub-bird is one of the world's oldest surviving species of songbird, but scientists believe fewer than 2,000 of the birds remain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9303e143d26a1ac223b41d18d2f75fda</guid></item><item><title>What is developmental delay and how can you to tell if your child has one?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/how-to-tell-if-your-child-has-a-developmental-delay/105888348</link><description>Developmental delay will be a big part of the new NDIS alternative for some kids. But what does the phrase mean and how can you tell if your child has one?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c55d7c08342830d440475646461211de</guid></item><item><title>Is sustainable forestry certification protecting Australia's bushland?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/sustainable-timber-certification-concerns/105904122</link><description>Questions are being raised about sustainable timber certification in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d5dcc7b9702ebd2eb291f96d40e8434</guid></item><item><title>Country league president reported to AFL integrity unit over alleged 'gender weirdness' comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/kyneton-womens-fc-report-league-president-to-afl-integrity-unit/106190264</link><description>A country football league president has been reported to the AFL Integrity Unit over alleged comments about a club's "grooming and gender weirdness" after it was involved in blocking the club from entering a neighbouring competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ceb9c73f6adf9f57f90bb1caae08180</guid></item><item><title>Ditching Sydney for a wheat header, French farmer travels 17,000km to pick up where dad left off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/french-farmer-travel-to-australia-brittany/106192804</link><description>When 22-year-old Tanguy Bodiguel's friends said they were travelling to Australia, he left them in Sydney to work on a farm with sentimental value.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cf0435bf977df35b5865638e1562af7</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2026 live updates: Australia 2-166, Travis Head 91* after Stokes-Labuschagne clash on day two of fifth Test at SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/ashes-cricket-scg-test-day-two-live-blog/106199006</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne falls two runs short of a Test half-century, nicking off to Ben Stokes immediately after clashing with the England captain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc60eeb2c778ab5b08f78ec8147d9340</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic exits Professional Tennis Players Association ahead of Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/novak-djokovic-exits-professional-tennis-players-association/106199048</link><description>Novak Djokovic is stepping away from the Professional Tennis Players Association citing concerns over transparency and governance within the organisation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">970d55f22cdf9cf67d04dfab8333e33e</guid></item><item><title>This toad busting group is determined to take back Magnetic Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/magnetic-island-cane-toad-busters/106136446</link><description>On a tropical Queensland island, 'toad busters' have decided the cane toad's spread across northern Australia should not be a lost cause.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8dc5263c05317f292acb302d1806c9f</guid></item><item><title>South-East Asian powers offer strong criticism of US operation in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/asian-powers-express-grave-concern-over-us-venezuela-operation/106198804</link><description>Indonesia, Singapore and Malaysia express "grave concern" over the US capture of Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24e70a3542fee7391f5108367731680e</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Liberal Party deputy leader Sam Groth will exit politics at next election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/sam-groth-victorian-liberal-party-deputy-leader-exit-politics/106199004</link><description>Sam Groth, the deputy leader of the Victorian Liberal Party, has announced he will not contest the upcoming state election in November, saying he made his decision after realising that some recent negative public pressure had come from within his own party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f5b5f8c41cda77210cad523d0a9e51b</guid></item><item><title>Tributes flow for founding father of Australian beef industry, Sir Graham McCamley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/australian-beef-industry-mourns-loss-of-sir-graham-mccamley-93/106198876</link><description>From building one of Queensland's most respected cattle empires and championing the Brahman breed, Sir Graham's lifelong dedication to agriculture and his community was truly remarkable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53678aa9f26c57b78d0c160062c6859c</guid></item><item><title>Critics Choice Awards 2026 winners: One Battle After Another wins best picture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/critics-choice-awards-2026-winners-list/106199058</link><description>Now in their 31st year, the Critics Choice Awards are historically known to be the most accurate predictor of the Academy Award nominations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8952945cea491eff7e8aa4654529ec63</guid></item><item><title>Eels sign Brian Kelly as potential replacement for Zac Lomax ahead of 2026 NRL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nrl-parramatta-eels-brian-kelly-zac-lomax/106199350</link><description>In the wake of Zac Lomax's sudden departure, Parramatta makes a move in the player market as it looks to lifts its fortunes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac27c637175a2fbeca89c1866fa2c76</guid></item><item><title>Jacob Elordi and Sarah Snook win at Critics Choice Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/critics-choice-awards-2026-key-moments/106199154</link><description>Australian actress Sarah Snook takes out Best Actress in a Limited Series or Movie Made for Television with All Her Fault while Australian Jacob Elordi takes out Best Supporting Actor for Frankenstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8693e491b3fd4de2f6d37b7e51d742e6</guid></item><item><title>Measles alert as Adelaide and Sydney airports among possible exposure sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/measles-case-travelled-from-adelaide-to-sydney-on-qantas-flight/106198812</link><description>SA and NSW health authorities have issued alerts about a potential measles exposure risk, after a person with the disease recently caught a flight from Adelaide to Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">871c233d42ef3773ef479cf4dcf379c7</guid></item><item><title>Trump's Venezuela move assumes his base will support his foreign interventions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/donald-trump-venezuela-foreign-policy-honduras/106199368</link><description>Donald Trump has long defied political gravity but whether his followers in Congress and the MAGA movement will follow him into a new colonialism is a big gamble.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fa61fc0754b3cf4b15eaf2e43ea3549</guid></item><item><title>NSW residents urged to check if they are owed share of $300m in unclaimed cash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/about-300-million-in-unclaimed-money-in-nsw/106199820</link><description>Almost $300 million in refunds, dividends and cheques remain unclaimed by households and businesses across New South Wales, with locals urged to take action to secure the money they are owed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7337b84bfbea19ae477d4850fbbd042f</guid></item><item><title>Joe Root best since Donald Bradman says Darren Lehmann after second Ashes century on Australian soil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/joe-root-second-century-scg-don-bradman/106199570</link><description>Joe Root is hailed as the greatest cricket player since Don Bradman after adding a second century to his tally this Ashes tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a3694ac0d0eba32578e8d3615060f54</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate burglary at offices of comedy troupe Sooshi Mango</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/sooshi-mango-burglary-crime-melbourne/106199662</link><description>The group posted CCTV footage on social media appearing to show a man breaking into an office in Carlton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6519ffa9603a05f81a708440735d5eb5</guid></item><item><title>Emergency departments ill-suited for mental health crises, advocates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/act-emergency-departments-ill-suited-mental-health-crises/106200130</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb03edf77794382a8abaf4029cb90a38</guid></item><item><title>Autopsy unable to determine cause of Tennant Creek woman's death in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nt-tennant-creek-watch-house-death-in-custody-post-mortem-result/106199844</link><description>Police say the cause of a woman's death in a Northern Territory police watch house last month remains "undetermined" following a post-mortem examination conducted on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1fb0594a4e3a0f4ef5d5114e677138e</guid></item><item><title>Langi Kal Kal prison escapee threatens farm worker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/prison-escapee-attacks-farm-worker-langi-kal-kal/106199880</link><description>A farm worker says he was threatened by a man who escaped from Langi Kal Kal prison near Ballarat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22a240d35a388433f5b60959e32c27ab</guid></item><item><title>Key points to understand US attacks on Venezuela and capture of President Maduro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/what-happened-us-strikes-venezuela-maduro-captured-what-next/106198900</link><description>These are the key points to get up to speed with what we know about the US strikes on Venezuela and the current state of play after its president was ousted and removed from the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8831a0d03d39f3b5a7c9e57fd010b6ca</guid></item><item><title>Alleged driver in fatal Darwin hit-and-run Pairat Junsomran bailed, allowed by court to travel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nt-fatal-hit-and-run-alleged-offender-bail-bagot-road-darwin/106200298</link><description>A 61-year-old dual national charged over a fatal hit-and-run in Darwin has been granted bail, less than 10 days after the crash which claimed the life of a 27-year-old woman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74a2bbea3e8cba37941ac669bd8be510</guid></item><item><title>Police are investigating three shooting incidents in Hobart's outer northern suburbs.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/police-investigate-shootings-in-outer-hobart/106200794</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3e159a2c2a3f2568f6e4773a03d920c</guid></item><item><title>Denmark tells Trump to back off over 'threats' against Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/denmark-rejects-us-trump-threats-greenland/106199700</link><description>The leaders of Denmark and Greenland have urged US President Donald Trump to stop threatening to take over Greenland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90f98d74a11dbe632e6e2a20575310b9</guid></item><item><title>Small aircraft crashes at airport in Adelaide's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/small-aircraft-crashes-at-airport-in-adelaide-s-north/106201012</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09b85a9721ddc253f7442a89b4ba7b0d</guid></item><item><title>Pasta, slow-cooker recipes and tray bakes: Our top 10 recipes from 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/your-favourite-recipes-of-2025/106091718</link><description>Easy weeknight meals were your favourite (again), with tray bakes, soups and noodles amongst the most loved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8de5c8d7977a031014b35aa3f1495f1</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro held in New York prison described as 'hell on earth'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nicol%C3%A1s-maduro-in-the-new-york-metropolitan-detention-center/106199184</link><description>The facility where detained Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro has been taken is a notorious New York jail that has held a string of high-profile and celebrity criminals, from drug cartel leaders to hip-hop stars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">784a697b58d4fb284175a75608400421</guid></item><item><title>Senior Queensland doctor cleared of allegations after 14-month suspension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/chief-medical-officer-reinstated-mackay-charles-pain/106200692</link><description>Mackay's chief medical officer, Charles Pain, returns to work after an external investigation cleared him of allegations of poor clinical governance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85b480f0b3f7daeb998b973f37ba8781</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne prises farcical wicket, Cam Green's agony continues, Travis Head sparkles — quick hits from day two of SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/ashes-scg-test-quick-hits-day-two/106199122</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne picks up a farcical wicket, Cam Green can't catch a break and Joe Root enters rare air. Here are the quick hits from the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63d637764db6fed8ea8267c149c9b46d</guid></item><item><title>Energy company ENGIE promised pensioner refund then sent debt collectors after him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/engie-energy-makes-mistake-sends-debt-collectors-after-pensioner/106132388</link><description>Australia's energy prices continue to soar as questions continue to be raised about the actions of providers, including by this pensioner who was overcharged and then had debt collectors chasing him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f33b84b38f7a914084ecd3e5659b2fe6</guid></item><item><title>Travis Head and Joe Root bring batting class to bowlers' Ashes on a fiery second day of SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/batting-class-prevails-for-head-and-root-ashes-scg-day-two/106200104</link><description>In what has been a bowlers' series, the class of Joe Root and Travis Head again shone on day two in Sydney, where it often took something silly for a wicket to fall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c0d5da305e3e8babfb546559bd6132d</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/gold-and-silver-jump-after-us-attacks-venezuela-oil-down-slightl/106201488</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6baf356d650d49c9ff9bf950dca45c81</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump claimed Venezuela stole US oil assets but the issue is more complicated than that</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/why-venezuelan-oil-is-not-stolen-from-the-united-states/106200804</link><description>US President Donald Trump has said Venezuela stole United States oil assets. Experts say the truth is much more complex than that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1185033f9bae9e894518bb6079f6eeb6</guid></item><item><title>A Paris court finds 10 people guilty of cyberbullying France's first lady Brigitte Macron</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/10-charged-for-cyberbullying-brigitte-macron/106201796</link><description>Several defendants told the court their comments were intended as humour or satire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5382845bf3ac9a036f487b1f6faa3210</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann launches High Court appeal in latest defamation fight, alleging findings 'compromised'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/bruce-lehrmann-launches-high-court-appeal/106201754</link><description>Former Liberal staffer Bruce Lehrmann takes his appeal to the High Court against the findings that he, on the balance of probabilities, raped Brittany Higgins in 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">446e771832ca4322175a527c2b872641</guid></item><item><title>Ousted Venezuelan leader Nicolás Maduro and wife Cilia Flores plead not guilty in New York court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/venezuelan-leader-nicol%C3%A1s-maduro-appears-in-new-york-court/106201846</link><description>Nicolás Maduro and Cilia Flores, who were captured in Caracas at the weekend, face multiple drugs and weapons charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">893a666a98bd976fe476ea782d0fed9e</guid></item><item><title>How this new Melbourne suburb is dodging baking heat in summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/clyde-tree-canopy-requirement-casey-council/106174988</link><description>Thousands of young trees dot the streets and front gardens of this outer Melbourne suburb as part of a neighbourhood-wide push to create more shade and curb the urban heat island effect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">416a36938699bfbb40f85c53e408d39c</guid></item><item><title>How much do you know about the meat pie? Test yourself (or treat yourself)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/dr-karl-how-things-works-pie-quiz/106086912</link><description>From pastry processing to mass-cooking meat — test your knowledge on the humble meat pie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7992118d27286ee078a2f7a57c588df</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's 'bold' oil grab in South America appears to be a major chess move</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/venezuela-oil-donald-trump-power-grab/106200092</link><description>In a world awash with oil, US President Donald Trump's takeover of Venezuela seems to be more about power than production.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c448111ae1ca3e26a21c7187e2bfbb4b</guid></item><item><title>'Most significant' heatwave in six years brings temperatures above 45C</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/australia-heatwave-most-significant-in-six-years/106200088</link><description>The "most significant" heatwave south-eastern Australia has seen in six years is likely to trigger an extreme fire danger alongside searing hot temperatures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62b8cc56863c610fcfcc3d2abaf4eee4</guid></item><item><title>UN chief António Guterres warns of wider instability following US operation in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/un-security-council-meets-to-discuss-us-attack-on-venezuela/106201850</link><description>The warning by the UN chief comes during an emergency session of the United Nations Security Council, just blocks from where Nicolás Maduro and his wife Cilia Flores are facing a Manhattan judge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4231245359710a0d66c24b6639109fa</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's bioluminescence unrelated to salmon farm nutrients, scientist says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/algal-bloom-concerns-near-tasmanian-salmon-farms/106199152</link><description>Scientists say a bioluminescent algae causes the red tides at the centre of recent environmentalist concerns — but that's not to say the magnificent display is totally harmless to marine life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e53ddd06679985fe547fe80d6ac07c62</guid></item><item><title>What to expect from Reserve Bank and interest rates in 2026 with rate hikes on the table</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/what-to-expect-from-rba-interest-rates-in-2026-hikes-on-table/106200132</link><description>Mortgage borrowers and savers may have used the new year as an excuse to get their financial affairs in order, but things may be set to change within a matter of months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">750d17a1fe3aa50c384088d78725fa3d</guid></item><item><title>Walk while you work: Are the extra steps using an under-desk treadmill worth the cost?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/is-a-desk-treadmill-worth-the-cost/106195036</link><description>Many people know what it feels like to sit at a computer all day, then sit on the living room couch all night. Would a desk treadmill help?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffcf1a90a47f29dce8bb12e93387795c</guid></item><item><title>Woolwich Marina expansion rejected but locals worry about future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/local-groups-stop-woolwich-marina-expansion-but-fear-isnt-over/106194942</link><description>Local groups that helped save heritage-listed Kelly's Bush Park from being impacted by a marina expansion proposal are calling on the NSW government to do more to protect the foreshore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ef73f7409172d89acff9defaf0a59bc</guid></item><item><title>Venezuela updates: Venezuelan opposition demands release of all political prisoners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/venezuela-maduro-in-court-new-york-live-blog-january-6/106201828</link><description>Nicolás Maduro and his wife face court in New York after being captured by US forces as House Democrats leader Hakeem Jeffries accuses US President Donald Trump of lying to the American people about the reason for the attack — as it happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38c7711ad0e476096b4dbf0305c9525e</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Emerson Jones wins through at Brisbane International as Kimberly Birrell and Olivia Gadecki advance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/brisbane-international-emerson-jones-kimberly-birrell/106202016</link><description>At 17, Emerson Jones shows why she is one of the brightest prospects in Australian tennis, as she wins through to the second round in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">800c2bb4f3ed164cde54cbd1807eaea6</guid></item><item><title>Maduro and wife transferred from detention centre to court in New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/maduro-and-wife-transferred-to-court-in-nyc/106202054</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd07f46d83eb576b4df4c5fc6cebc18d</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister announces $38 million for flood-affected communities across north-west Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/northwest-queensland-flooding-continues-as-low-approaches-coast/106201374</link><description>A number of communities remain on flood watch, while a traveller is in hospital after walking through knee-deep mud after he became bogged in outback Queensland on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b23fad379a4df846e138e9df38237487</guid></item><item><title>Mother of 13yo who fell pregnant in state care says system 'ruining lives'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/13-year-old-pregnant-sexual-assaults-state-residential-care/105980432</link><description>Child safety experts say the case of a 13-year-old girl who became pregnant while in state care highlights the dangers of the residential system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4012124523dbc441aaf538ab50f821f</guid></item><item><title>Maduro and wife transferred by helicopter to court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/maduro-and-wife-transferred-by-helicopter-to-court/106202094</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35c6b6e3ade017ade73d2288cf30473d</guid></item><item><title>Coco Gauff loses singles but US makes United Cup quarterfinals with win over Spain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/united-cup-us-coco-gauff-taylor-fritz/106202112</link><description>The US secures a United Cup quarterfinal berth after Coco Gauff makes up for a shock singles loss by helping win the deciding mixed doubles rubber.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4f0ace718e668a337e3e9da17513cb6</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's other goal in the Venezuela strike was to get China out of Latin America</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/us-venezuela-strike-to-get-china-out-of-latin-america/106201438</link><description>Venezuela has spent years getting cosier with China. Now Donald Trump is sending a clear warning to Beijing — get out of his backyard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfdc10ffe823e9f14d299014d36b82fe</guid></item><item><title>Before Venezuela there was Panama and the first US capture of a Latin American leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/panama-and-the-us-capture-of-manuel-noriega/106199932</link><description>Thirty-six years to the day before this week's capture of Nicolás Maduro the United States's invasion of Panama led to the capture of its de facto ruler General Manuel Noriega.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f6098c33c7542886efa28300790ad0</guid></item><item><title>As Victoria's grassland dries with warmer weather, the CFA warns of increased fire risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/victoria-bushfire-risk-high-despite-rain/106096142</link><description>Grassland in Victoria has dried significantly since September, including in the north-west of the state and in outer Melbourne, putting firefighters on edge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56648e0798244c53feb8995a6632532a</guid></item><item><title>Yarloop locals mark decade since bushfire destroyed 160 homes and killed two people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/yarloop-bushfire-10-year-anniversary-marked/106155544</link><description>Ten years after a bushfire took just seven minutes to tear through Yarloop, residents say community spirit and support from neighbouring towns helped get them through the tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7088a5388f230abfd0c35a9b80b27d3</guid></item><item><title>Council criticised for removing 'illegally planted' trees from sensitive sand dunes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/council-criticised-for-removing-illegal-trees-from-dunes/106174826</link><description>A Queensland council is being criticised for uprooting unauthorised saplings from sand dunes amid a long-running vegetation battle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f71c6b7a0767545c69d6fe4ce8e7d3d3</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic withdraws from Australian Open lead-up event at Adelaide International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/australian-open-novak-djokovic-out-of-adelaide-international/106202328</link><description>With the Australian Open on the horizon, Novak Djokovic does not feel he is well enough prepared to contest next week's Adelaide International.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1bf5f795fc9797030df50d8ec0a5d3a</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2026: Steve Smith fires Australia to dominant position on day three of fifth Test at SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/ashes-live-scg-test-day-three-australia-england/106202206</link><description>Australia leads England by 134 first-innings runs after a dominant day three at the SCG, punctuated by centuries to Travis Head and Steve Smith.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e17568c8efb295c226cff3da05c270b</guid></item><item><title>Site selection delayed for desalination plant Lower Great Southern needs 'to survive'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/plans-pushed-back-for-desalination-site-the-lower-great-southern/106189738</link><description>Plans for a desalination plant in Western Australia's Great Southern are delayed as the clock ticks to secure a critical water source.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69d1703d9bcf7f663d90b817178ed0ae</guid></item><item><title>Top Trump adviser refuses to rule out military action to take over Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/trump-move-on-greenland-would-mean-end-of-nato-danish-leader/106202286</link><description>Stephen Miller, Mr Trump's chief of staff for policy, said the Trump administration believed Greenland should become an American territory in order for the US to "protect and defend NATO".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22c6960cd900eb92db5bc309f548541a</guid></item><item><title>Dragons sign Keaon Koloamatangi from Rabbitohs on massive five-year NRL deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/nrl-keaon-koloamatangi-signs-with-dragons-from-rabbitohs/106202500</link><description>Dragons supporters will have to wait until 2027 to see Keaon Koloamatangi wearing the Red V, but the club describes his signing as the "biggest" in their recent history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed9ce3b0406bc0a0762d38d5e4b6f92</guid></item><item><title>Woman who lost home in Koolewong bushfire reunited with cat seriously injured in blaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/koolewong-cat-sassy-injured-in-nsw-bushfires-on-road-to-recovery/106202244</link><description>Sassy the cat was almost killed when a bushfire razed a Koolewong home on NSW's Central Coast. Now, the lucky pet has been reunited with her family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">655f04089e2ac7fcb3a3b0f3e05c923e</guid></item><item><title>US cuts number of vaccines recommended for children including flu, hepatitis A and B</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/us-changes-vaccine-advice-for-children/106202478</link><description>The US government takes the unprecedented step of cutting the number of vaccines it recommends for every child, a move long sought by Health Secretary Robert F Kennedy Jr. But medical groups say it undermines protections against diseases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d878d401a8589bb4ad51f1bb7e74fa83</guid></item><item><title>Former Queensland senator Ron 'Bozzie' Boswell dies aged 85</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/former-queensland-senator-ron-boswell-nationals/100104534</link><description>Known as "Bozzie" to his mates and colleagues, Mr Boswell's political career spanned three decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6ba7206268efa5b012eaf2bd0f93624</guid></item><item><title>Man charged in connection to alleged Hanukkah car arson in Melbourne's south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/hanukkah-car-alleged-arson-arrest-st-kilda-east/106203066</link><description>A man is charged after an alleged arson attack on a vehicle with a Hanukkah decoration on Christmas morning in Melbourne's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">452095e39da6542d075c9c43a35624de</guid></item><item><title>BlueScope Steel weighing up $13 billion takeover by Kerry Stokes's SGH and US partner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/bluescope-13-billion-takeover-bid-by-stokes-sgh-us-steelmaker/106202730</link><description>Kerry Stokes-controlled firm SGH has launched a $13.2 billion takeover bid for BlueScope Steel, in partnership with a US steelmaker.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9cd553dbb824a883ccd91d871eba7e6</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal mother of five identified after death in NT police watch house</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/nt-indigenous-woman-identified-death-in-custody-tennant-creek/106201448</link><description>A Sydney-based law firm says it is representing the family of a 44-year-old Aboriginal woman who died in custody at the Tennant Creek police watch house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acd19c10c7c229b3ecd8e6257a7c199b</guid></item><item><title>Denmark and Greenland PMs condemn Trump's territorial ambitions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/denmark-and-greenland-pms-condemn-trump-s-territorial-ambitions/106203154</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5513a4fb1df7d2930c5e6aa5ff3eb34f</guid></item><item><title>South Australian MP Nick McBride will contest state election after assault charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/mp-nick-mcbride-home-detention-bail-decision-/106201364</link><description>South Australian independent MP Nick McBride says he will run for re-election, as he remains on home detention after spending 10 days behind bars for an alleged assault against his wife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99cc8ee41c421db2557998824483a304</guid></item><item><title>Madison Keys, Aryna Sabalenka kick off Australian summer of tennis with wins at Brisbane International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/brisbane-international-madison-keys/106203350</link><description>Defending Australian Open champion Madison Keys and last year's runner up Aryna Sabalenka both got their Australian summer off to winning starts with straight-sets victories at the Brisbane International.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a7a6bd704fac9f604729a9fa583f543</guid></item><item><title>Homicide Squad investigates death of Port Macquarie woman Megan Tangye</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/murder-investigation-port-macquarie/106200890</link><description>Police are investigating the death of 31-year-old Megan Tangye, who died hours after she was taken to hospital on the NSW Mid North Coast last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4995641f6cb457b993d7cfb3e5bfb9f1</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese doesn't rule out calling royal commission into Bondi terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/anthony-albanese-doesnt-rule-out-royal-commission-bondi-attack/106203368</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese does not rule out calling a royal commission into the Bondi Beach terrorist attack, but says his immediate priority is the review of intelligence and security agencies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28656b90ee40aa91243855a4aec8d59f</guid></item><item><title>Here's how sinkholes can form underground long before anyone realises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/sinkhole-explainer-environment-erosion-soil/106202498</link><description>The sudden collapse of a sinkhole in Melbourne's north-east left residents shocked on Tuesday. Here's an explanation of how and why they form.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b240d0d648a4f0432199dbb426a7fbb</guid></item><item><title>Public library visitor numbers return to pre-COVID levels as cost-of-living crisis bites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/public-libraries-australia-visitors-up-cost-of-living-crisis/106152152</link><description>Public libraries in Australia are experimenting with inventive ways to attract new members — but a lack of funding means they must do more with less.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e273b68565ad26ab3ff69f3d903723a</guid></item><item><title>After Venezuela, Donald Trump's other threats ring alarms around the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/after-venezuela-donald-trumps-other-threats/106203334</link><description>Donald Trump is talking about where US forces might venture next. But one of his cabinet secretaries could provide the clearest clues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">250a454241e20cae5504c394f87e089d</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police commissioner extends restrictions on Sydney protests for another fortnight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/nsw-police-protest-restrictions-decision-mal-lanyon/106203890</link><description>The NSW police commissioner will extend temporary protest restrictions across Sydney for another two weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0745c4340b305515c7295e0f60908cc</guid></item><item><title>WA Police raid Bunbury tobacconist after suspected firebomb of different vape store</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/police-raid-tobacco-shop-bunbury-after-vape-store-incident/106199506</link><description>Police seize vapes and cigarettes from the South West WA store days after two different shops were destroyed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74b2a96d2b8637c8c416829ecffeb71c</guid></item><item><title>Ben Austin died in a cricketing tragedy. His parents Jace and Tracey blame no-one as they speak out for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/ben-austins-tragic-death-parents-jace-and-tracey-speak-out/106203078</link><description>Ben Austin died in late October after a being struck by a cricket ball. For the first time his parents speak exclusively about the incident and their belief no-one is to blame for the tragic accident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f56edd19cac4ec08635e690f74444c07</guid></item><item><title>Some NSW farmers say 10 guns are not enough ahead of planned restrictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/some-nsw-farmers-say-10-guns-are-not-enough-firearms-cap/106203318</link><description>New gun laws in NSW will limit farmers to 10 guns but the industry says this is not enough, and the change could see "a whole lot more firearms and ammunition" moving between farms in vehicles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f530343703d6e087769daf3a394e93af</guid></item><item><title>Sam Groth to relinquish deputy Liberal leadership at February party room meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/sam-groth-to-step-down-deputy-liberal-leader-february/106204434</link><description>The outgoing MP will vacate the deputy leadership role in February, clearing the way for a refreshed leadership team to carry the opposition to this year's election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dc93df5e6ebe8534501516dabb634d1</guid></item><item><title>Bondi terror attack royal commission pressure trumps Albanese's beliefs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/bondi-terror-attack-royal-commission-anthony-albanese/106202808</link><description>Whether or not Anthony Albanese believes a federal royal commission is necessary, or even the best use of resources, is now politically irrelevant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fd413938019ae14f86ed8d2268fdb30</guid></item><item><title>Teen faces court over Baldivis convenience store arson linked to illegal tobacco trade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/teen-charged-arson-attack-baldivis-convenience-store/106204496</link><description>A boy who allegedly set fire to a Baldivis convenience store may be facing threats from organised crime figures, Perth Children's Court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef902b7ab40b6d39d9ea83f52d1c0efa</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith plays his greatest hits as Will Jacks drops sitter and Ben Stokes burns reviews— quick hits from day three of the SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/ashes-quick-hits-day-three-scg-test/106202476</link><description>Steve Smith plays all his greatest hits en-route to a century as England suffers in the field on all fronts. Here are your quick hits from day three.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b94f234b7a07d22d230ae94a78f3a7d2</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith treats Sydney to a Smudge Day, in all its weird and wonderful glory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/ashes-fifth-test-day-three-steve-smiths-smudge-day/106203528</link><description>Steve Smith was at his bizarre best on day three in Sydney, grinding England into the dust with his scintillating strokeplay and trademark oddness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">323f9319839ca877e27543eeb68bc9df</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/tuesday-finance-with-david-chau/106204516</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af844bcc6a4cee1825a23893cb37c003</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios out of Brisbane International as reality of multiple surgeries hits home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/nick-kyrgios-out-brisbane-international/106204148</link><description>Nick Kyrgios limped out of the Brisbane International at the first hurdle as the 30-year-old's ailing body lets him down once again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">def25752ecb77df1a086f86ca64f48de</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Jenna the second system to lash Cocos Keeling Islands in less than two weeks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/cocos-tropical-cyclone-jenna-keeling-islands-indian-ocean/106203486</link><description>Residents of the islands clean up following heavy rain and winds brought by Tropical Cyclone Jenna, less than two weeks another system battered the region on Christmas day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd6ee8f687d014634b9cb4ac57cf1730</guid></item><item><title>Human remains found in search for snorkeller missing off WA's Ledge Point</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/human-remains-found-in-search-for-snorkeller-missing-wa/106204822</link><description>Police confirm human remains have been found washed ashore north of Perth, believed to be those of a 32-year-old man missing since New Year's Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">115d2e3da7e9c4da7c8cc4508e5df6e4</guid></item><item><title>The tragic death of young cricketer, Ben Austin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/the-tragic-death-of-young-cricketer-ben-austin/106204520</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9c63ee090c555390c147aaa8b6f089c</guid></item><item><title>What Venezuela's deposed president and first lady are accused of</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/drug-trafficking-allegations-against-nicolas-maduro/106202616</link><description>The US has justified the seizure of deposed Venezuelan leader Nicolás Maduro and wife Cilia Flores by arguing they had breached US domestic law. So what exactly have they been accused of doing?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">941caf9bf09b2b36e2322b47582fc864</guid></item><item><title>Stuart Clark denies confrontation with Cricket Australia chief Todd Greenberg over controversial comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/cricket-stuart-clark-todd-greenberg-controversial-comments/106205010</link><description>Stuart Clark opens up on his conversation with Cricket Australia chief Todd Greenberg after his stinging criticism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73e49b8eeecfd23e60b4e690b997ae88</guid></item><item><title>Australia books United Cup quarterfinal berth after Alex de Minaur's high-pressure double act</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/de-minaur-dazzles-to-restore-australias-cup-hopes/106205120</link><description>Twin wins from Alex de Minaur drags Australia off the canvas and into the United Cup quarterfinals with a do-or-die victory over Czechia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34a9d1647547c2c1fe6030a93748a2c7</guid></item><item><title>US set to back Ukraine defence coalition if peace deal made with Russia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/coalition-of-the-willing-paris-ceasefire-defence-coalition-us/106205340</link><description>A draft statement outlines what Ukraine's allies could commit to if Russia attacks its neighbour again in the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b290e391153bf910a66318327fd97287</guid></item><item><title>Fire safety inspections lapsed for years at Swiss bar where 40 died in New Year's blaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/fire-safety-inspections-lapsed-for-years-at-swiss-bar/106205302</link><description>Swiss authorities admitted that fire safety inspections hadn't been carried out since 2019 at Crans-Montana bar where 40 people died on New Year's Eve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">203c64a84bd26fbac5e8e795ee2f8b36</guid></item><item><title>Military force 'always an option' for Greenland, White House says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/european-leaders-back-greenland-after-trump-threats/106205394</link><description>The US president and his officials are continuing to push for an American takeover of the Danish territory, saying the island is needed for national security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ec6b2a38e5d7036a528511a65d3cf0c</guid></item><item><title>Trump's intervention in Venezuela heralds an incomparable era</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/venezuela-comparisons-donald-trump-greenland-argentina-panama/106200808</link><description>The global shock caused by the Trump administration's interventions in Venezuela sent analysts scurrying for historic comparisons, but nothing really compares to what happened at the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eafc52c7e0c0236e11977d346ff247b</guid></item><item><title>Total fire ban declared for parts of Victoria and SA as heatwave begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/victoria-south-australia-authorities-brace-for-fires-heatwave/106203894</link><description>Firefighters in Victoria continue to battle a bushfire in the state's north-east as a heatwave brings temperatures near 45 degrees Celsius to some parts of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8543476943a44e681083f27e5a4c34a</guid></item><item><title>A severe heatwave is crossing Tasmania.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/severe-heatwave-tasmania-beuro-meteorology-explainer/106204770</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9cb2d1d6d6ccecd45016fdcc2f499ef</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 7: Guy Menzies walks away from upturned plane after becoming first to fly solo over Tasman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/today-in-history-january-7-first-solo-flight-over-the-tasman-/106185272</link><description>In 1931, a young pilot named Guy Menzies became the first person to fly solo across the Tasman. It was a secret midnight mission that secured his place in history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8b33bc962fa8a80de7c575a9a535873</guid></item><item><title>María Corina Machado vows to return to Venezuela following ousting of Nicolás Maduro by US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/maria-corina-machado-vows-to-return-to-venezuela/106205438</link><description>In her first interview since the ousting of President Nicolás Maduro, María Corina Machado says she is confident she will win any election held in Venezuela.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8110fa3a018590501d787a5146695b37</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelans celebrate a future reclaimed — but insiders say the power struggle is just getting started</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/venezuela-hope-dreams-maduro-machado-voices-challenges/106202872</link><description>Venezuelans celebrate what once felt impossible — but inside the country, armed powerbrokers, nervous officials and rival factions are already jostling over what comes next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87806b5b8b7126e30bdf16d46f45c499</guid></item><item><title>Day-by-day weather guide to most severe southern Australia heatwave in years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/weather-heatwave-southern-australia-day-by-day-temperatures/106204522</link><description>Southern Australia will collectively bake this week through the most intense spell of heat in years as temperatures soar up to 15 degrees Celsius above the mid-summer average.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e21756b0b8879ad9d5f4e98b480fc5d8</guid></item><item><title>Angie Fuller disappeared three years ago near a road infamous for missing persons and murders, police remain baffled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/angie-fuller-missing-reward-tanami-highway-suspected-murder/105996614</link><description>Angie Fuller has been missing for three years. Police are offering an equal record reward for information into what they believe is a suspected outback murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a0b818f166a394a25408233dd10ab2f</guid></item><item><title>Marion librarians create viral videos to show libraries are about 'more than books'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/city-of-marion-librarians-go-viral-on-social-media/106202866</link><description>The team at Adelaide's City of Marion Libraries grows a legion of fans on social media and sees their videos go viral, clocking up millions of views.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70023d3617acc968ece7351733f22eea</guid></item><item><title>Trump has no plan after removing Maduro, Schumer says, after 'troubling' classified briefing — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/venezuela-us-maduro-mission-kills-dozens-live-blog-january-7/106205158</link><description>The Democrats' Senate leader, Chuck Schumer, says he has received a classified briefing from the White House on Donald Trump's plans for Venezuela — and is dismayed by the lack of detail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4495ddff889e8e107378952b7869a9c</guid></item><item><title>Echidna population count underway in Queensland amid urbanisation and climate change fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/echidna-population-count-queensland-conservation/106127158</link><description>The lack of knowledge about the species has experts worried echidnas could decline without anyone noticing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebe1f96569f58475e6456590bd3d4df5</guid></item><item><title>Police search for teenagers after machete attack in Caroline Springs park in Melbourne's west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/police-search-for-teenagers-machete-attack-caroline-springs/106205458</link><description>Police are seeking help from the public to identify a group of teenagers wanted over what detectives have described as an ambush and machete attack in Caroline Springs, in Melbourne's west, last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41349f0c4ad47fc1e83898cb5eac7210</guid></item><item><title>Push for QVB's colourful glass to be made clear for more 'visibility' into stores</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/nsw-sydney-queen-victoria-building-coloured-glass-clear-proposal/106200064</link><description>Dozens of people express opposition against a proposal to remove some of Queen Victoria Building's iconic coloured glass windows, after a development application stated they were not "fit for purpose in the eyes of global retail brands".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b4ea71bfbb3bcf4b67c2fa6e78cdd29</guid></item><item><title>Australians trapped on Yemen's Socotra island after Saudi Arabia, UAE flare-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/australians-trapped-socotra-island-yemen-saudi-arabia-uae/106205342</link><description>Australians are among hundreds of tourists scrambling to leave a remote Yemeni island, as a crisis on the mainland between Saudi Arabia and the United Arab Emirates causes travel chaos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7346dab8aa0ee77f69c1857ff1a7cba</guid></item><item><title>Berry Street residential care staff fear being 'drug affected' at work due to high ice use</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/berry-street-residential-care-drug-use-staff/106129258</link><description>Emails show staff working at Berry Street residential care homes may have been exposed to ice by children using drugs at its facilities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">491d9e974e9941b98d8f03252b17ad34</guid></item><item><title>Half of Canberra's Commonwealth Avenue Bridge is closing for two years. Here's what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/canberra-commonwealth-avenue-bridge-closures-for-upgrade-works/106199138</link><description>Commuters in Canberra are facing major disruptions as Commonwealth Avenue Bridge undergoes two years of major upgrades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31b1cd56ebd627daa7150ecefe614db5</guid></item><item><title>Gulf Country prepares for weeks of isolation, as north-east Qld coast braces for tropical low</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/gulf-country-faces-intense-flooding-as-tropical-low-forms/106204784</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology has issued a severe weather warning for the north Queensland coast as a tropical low approaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58cc38b6d810ecbeaac01b89f1b48b11</guid></item><item><title>Fire on southern NSW property likely sparked by cigarette butt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/cigarette-butt-sparks-fire-at-the-rock/106199936</link><description>A southern NSW landholder is urging smokers to think twice when disposing of their cigarette butts, after a grassfire razed her property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee174ccb428fe82617770620b9ba9036</guid></item><item><title>Insurer Prosura hit by cyber data breach, customers contacted by 'threat actor'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/car-excess-insurer-prosura-hit-by-cyber-breach-customer-data/106204198</link><description>Australians who have rented cars have been caught up in a cyber incident affecting excess insurer Prosura, with customers receiving modified invoices from a self-proclaimed "threat actor".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">330ce98f3590ee330d11c93cbff6b1c7</guid></item><item><title>Ajla Tomljanović departs Brisbane International as Rinky Hijikata advances</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/brisbane-international-tennis-ajla-tomljanovic-rinky-hijikata/106205544</link><description>Australia's Ajla Tomljanović loses a tense three-set match to world number 20 Karolína Muchová, while Rinky Hijikata is the last remaining local hope in the men's draw.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7618bf0a970b03ef1fbbdb7de8a5c3f2</guid></item><item><title>ASX closes marginally higher as inflation slows more than expected in November — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/106205112</link><description>The CPI rose 3.4 per cent in the 12 months to November 2025, according to the latest ABS data, down from 3.8 per cent in October and below economists' expectations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e20efd5f4ddf823ad54a4b4f3fd19c70</guid></item><item><title>Outback NT hotel at centre of Peter Falconio mystery barred from serving alcohol</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/outback-pub-barrow-creek-hotel-liquor-licence-suspended/106203732</link><description>The Barrow Creek Hotel was thrust into the global spotlight during the investigation into British backpacker Peter Falconio's disappearance. Now its liquor licence has been suspended for breaching Northern Territory licensing laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">116c019736e660595b4c4da2ae2cde7d</guid></item><item><title>Kids at tiny school work to save extremely rare 'flying jewel' purple copper butterfly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/meadow-flat-primary-school-purple-copper-butterfly/106173306</link><description>It's the size of a 10-cent piece and matures under the guard of protective ants, but the purple copper butterfly needs more help to survive — and a group of NSW primary school students has stepped up to the challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a78ff0b822d201d809f27d33c730147</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine's allies agree to security guarantees in 'significant step' towards ending Russia's invasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/ukraine-european-leaders-security-guarantee-agreement/106205560</link><description>At a key meeting in Paris, officials from Europe, Canada, the US and NATO say they will provide Kyiv's frontline forces with equipment and training, and back them up with air, land and sea support to deter any future Russian attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac913b2f29ba0b935dd20a68fea2cf4d</guid></item><item><title>The tough balance of circumstance and support systems as WA woman faces eviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/balance-of-circumstance-and-support-system-wa-mother-eviction/106205110</link><description>As protesters strive to keep a woman from community housing eviction, the complexities of her situation collide with a housing provider's options.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d8ea6cf63b10324e9c1f2392dfdf238</guid></item><item><title>Travellers urged not to rely solely on navigation systems for directions following recent strandings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/travellers-urged-not-to-rely-solely-on-gps-after-strandings/106202818</link><description>A young couple got bogged on a remote dirt road in north Queensland and was forced to walk hours in search of help after trusting their navigation app to find a 24-hour fuel station.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40bf85ccc108f1d047799f881ca9deb2</guid></item><item><title>Emergency warnings issued for Victorian fires as heatwave sweeps southern Australia — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/australia-heatwave-victoria-sa-fire-risk-january-7/106205674</link><description>Southern Australia is enduring its most intense heatwave in years, with temperatures set to soar from today until the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29f88aaecce24da4d9954d44b6c2e769</guid></item><item><title>Students help teacher pop the question at remote WA school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/wyndham-teachers-proposal-kimberley-school-engagement/106173942</link><description>Students at one of Western Australia's most remote schools help play a part in a special proposal for two of their teachers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">297e91fe74a4c81ae377d26d4e7cc956</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2026: Jacob Bethell stars on day four, Beau Webster triple strike halts England momentum at SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/ashes-live-scg-fifth-test-australia-england/106205818</link><description>England ends day four with a 119-run lead after a sparkling century to 22-year-old Jacob Bethell, with Beau Webster's late wickets halting the tourists' momentum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">140fe7472242f514894179d9b94c62ae</guid></item><item><title>Man denied bail over alleged Gold Coast bus stop attack that left man in intensive care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/man-charged-gold-coast-bus-stop-attack-attempted-robbery/106205770</link><description>A 20-year-old has been denied bail after being charged with grievous bodily harm and attempted robbery following a New Year's Day incident on the Gold Coast that left another man in intensive care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc3819936b4f2f95956610be634fe891</guid></item><item><title>Mystery over safe with beef jerky inside recovered from Shark Bay's ocean floor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/shark-bay-treasure-safe-found-on-seafloor-with-beef-jerky/106200058</link><description>While hoping for treasure, a nervous Quoin Sellenger was left with a (sadly) inedible salty snack after retrieving a safe from the bottom of WA's Shark Bay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca0339a8741aa48f5393316a5365d03d</guid></item><item><title>Men charged over alleged international car theft syndicate targeting Toyota LandCruisers and Prados</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/men-charged-toyota-landcruisers-prados-stolen-brisbane/106205532</link><description>Queensland Police say 60 Toyota LandCruisers and Prados were stolen across Brisbane between October 20 and December 1.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d28d81f828e897d2d0edf4c0f3bb424</guid></item><item><title>Nicole Kidman and Keith Urban are officially divorced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/nicole-kidman-keith-urban-divorce/106205820</link><description>After 19 years as one of the entertainment world's most recognisable couples, actor Nicole Kidman and musician Keith Urban are officially divorced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84c49a1aaa2c8beb82ce114ad6d6cf18</guid></item><item><title>Perth Bears sign Bulldogs forward Josh Curran ahead of 2027 NRL entry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/nrl-perth-bears-sign-josh-curran-from-bulldogs/106205922</link><description>The Perth Bears land their most experienced NRL player so far in their recruitment drive, signing Canterbury's Josh Curran on a three-year deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f1eaf3d731fb881f7716731cf26348f</guid></item><item><title>Business as usual at Venezuela-Colombia border crossing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/business-as-usual-at-venezuela-colombia-border-crossing/106205998</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cead50a0f479e6089caaf1b0b7cb3c5c</guid></item><item><title>AI hallucinations and the dilemma of false or misleading information</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/aavegotchi-artificial-intelligence-hallucinations-analysis/106169730</link><description>When a journalist emails a company with questions looking for answers, the least they expect is a real person to feed them the spin, half-truths or outright lies. Not a machine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1955222755afe2ff3d8fb649200d65d</guid></item><item><title>Concerns children's personal details vulnerable to data breaches under NSW government's Digital Hub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/childcare-data-breach-concerns-under-nsw-digital-hub/106184168</link><description>NSW is rolling out a digital hub that centralises early childhood centres' information, but some are worried it could be vulnerable to data breaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58510bc3c4728a9a0cc06dfb9e3f3dc3</guid></item><item><title>Bayer's Monsanto sues Pfizer, BioNTech and Moderna over mRNA technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/monsanto-sues-pfizer-biontech-moderna-over-covid-vaccines/106206038</link><description>Bayer's Monsanto has sued Pfizer, BioNTech and Moderna for allegedly misusing its messenger RNA technology in COVID vaccines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">652acbaa5c23a6ce009f8e42f4322919</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur to miss Australia's Davis Cup tie against Ecuador in February</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/davis-cup-alex-de-minaur-to-miss-davis-cup-tie/106206082</link><description>For the first time since making his debut in 2018, Alex de Minaur decides to sit out an Australian Davis Cup tie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99a4561d15c5e9c503bf09212d80fb7a</guid></item><item><title>Inflation cools in November with consumer prices rising 3.4pc but still above the RBA's target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/inflation-abs-monthly-cpi-for-november/106205848</link><description>Inflation cooled in November, with the consumer price index rising 3.4 per cent over the year, down from 3.8 per cent a month earlier. Some economists continue to forecast a February rate hike, however.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f13348eb885b0fed864738fbce93301b</guid></item><item><title>Journalist says armed gangs patrolling Caracas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/journalist-says-armed-gangs-patroling-caracas/106206312</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e2c056612ef2a79dcdf09a4138bc39a</guid></item><item><title>Who is Nicolás Maduro Guerra, the son of Venezuela's deposed leader?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/who-is-nicol%C3%A1s-maduro-guerra-son-of-venezuelan-leader/106202664</link><description>Nicolás Maduro Guerra rose through the ranks of his father's government and remains in Caracas. It's uncertain for how long.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dabc89c15f5459e8a52d8629ce14dc1</guid></item><item><title>Ben Stokes limps off during fourth day of final Ashes Test at SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/ben-stokes-limps-off-fifth-ashes-test-scg/106206318</link><description>Ben Stokes left the field during the first session of the fourth day at the SCG, with England confirming their skipper was being assessed for a right adductor injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0e602a309ffcc4c39cd0fb90e32f2ec</guid></item><item><title>Former Sydney detective Peter Meagher honoured in last Bondi terror attack funeral</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/funeral-for-bondi-attack-victim-ex-nsw-police-peter-meagher/106205580</link><description>A retired detective has been remembered as an "incredibly moral and honest man" at a funeral service three weeks after he was killed in the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5d894bb7ec001e9983cf3cc15be4b1c</guid></item><item><title>Poland to face Australia in United Cup quarterfinals after Hubert Hurkacz wins singles against the Netherlands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/poland-to-play-australia-united-cup-quarterfinals/106206422</link><description>Poland will meet the host nation in the last eight of the mixed-teams event after in-form Hubert Hurkacz beat Tallon Griekspoor of the Netherlands in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64fe6cf10297ec2f374a68bff622d074</guid></item><item><title>How to protect yourself from heat-related illness as temperatures soar this week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/heatwave-illness-and-how-to-protect-yourself/106205872</link><description>Extreme heat forecast for the next few days has prompted warnings form health experts. Here's how to stay safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">697d4b3b3f2b3f0a17e64bf6fd46fdc4</guid></item><item><title>Past works reimagined in Second Look — Legacy, the Australian Design Centre's final exhibition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/australian-design-centre-second-look-legacy-exhibition/106192528</link><description>Second Look — Legacy celebrates sustainable making while paying homage to one of the most influential figures in Australia craft and design.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6796a5ca7d920ad8561aac2789c84e6</guid></item><item><title>Truck crashes into five cars on Picton Road at Cataract, north of Wollongong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/truck-crashes-into-cars-picton-road-cataract-wollongong/106206524</link><description>More than a dozen people were assessed by paramedics after a truck smashed into several cars on a major road north of Wollongong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b99241ec366186e5801a4130d581da96</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne tram enthusiasts join fight to save India's last tram network</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/melbourne-tram-enthusiasts-fight-to-save-kolkata-tram-network/106204938</link><description>Melbourne's iconic trams thrive in a car-centred world, but Asia's oldest tramway is now facing extinction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce54859611aa9ff045d5ded24b2b723c</guid></item><item><title>Walwa fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/walwa-fire/106206724</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49d89cae11cf54b3b9a9615739d3c05b</guid></item><item><title>Why does Trump want Greenland and why is it so important?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/why-does-trump-want-greenland-and-why-is-it-so-important/106203650</link><description>Donald Trump's continued interest in Greenland is part of his "America First" agenda to dominate the Western Hemisphere and contain China's interests in the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe83050ed01b2f0d3c705e4286721003</guid></item><item><title>Council calls in diggers as big swells deposit masses of seaweed on Sydney beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/diggers-called-in-as-seaweed-masses-on-sydney-beaches/106206160</link><description>Piles of kelp were removed from a popular Sydney beach, although some councils prefer to leave the seaweed for its environmental benefit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5637b05772499f34725d36a017b4e93c</guid></item><item><title>Israel clears final hurdle to start settlement construction that would cut the West Bank in two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/israel-clears-final-hurdle-west-bank-settlement-construction/106206464</link><description>Critics say the E1 project would prevent the establishment of a contiguous Palestinian state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f1db5685c633ee1809bb2f0e2a944b5</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal artist Bobbi Lockyer in tears as Australia Post loses $4k painting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/auspost-loses-4000-dollar-bobbi-lockyer-artwork-before-xmas/106206356</link><description>Indigenous artist Bobbi Lockyer has been left frustrated after she sent a $4,000 custom artwork of the Pilbara to a buyer in Queensland, only for an empty cardboard sleeve to be delivered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9d27135931651e6a5ebc9706fc2eba9</guid></item><item><title>Prisoners charged over death of Shannon Daniel Norgate to face court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/prisoners-charged-over-death-of-shannon-daniel-norgate/106119896</link><description>Two men are set to face court over the alleged murder of another prisoner in a Queensland jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ad977be3d0d4048879d23297720c39c</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave conditions likely to bring increase of flies and maggots</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/how-to-reduce-flies-maggots-at-home/105941190</link><description>Forecast heatwave conditions across large parts of the country could mean flies and maggots are more prevalent. Here's how to deal with them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd44e594d644af51a17c967e875c59ba</guid></item><item><title>Kimberly Birrell, Olivia Gadecki, Emerson Jones suffer second-round losses at Brisbane International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/aussie-emerson-jones-out-brisbane-international-gadecki/106207056</link><description>Australian players Kimberly Birrell and Olivia Gadecki have fallen in the second round of the Brisbane International, along with rising star Emerson Jones, who went out after a high-quality encounter with the world number 17.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b35e2c4b3e39d3d89b44578a759a1ad6</guid></item><item><title>WA fishing ban sees fishers flock to coastal hamlet Windy Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/wa-demersal-fishing-ban-crowds-at-windy-harbour/106206190</link><description>WA's new ban on demersal fishing sees fishers flock to a coastal hamlet unaffected by the new rules, but locals say the crowds are unsustainable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7e8e64cd04b4c294f9f1e3b82a81601</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with attempted murder after allegedly stabbing man multiple times with steak knife</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/woman-charged-attempted-murder-steak-knife-lowanna-st-braddon/106207390</link><description>A 37-year-old woman has been charged with attempted murder after allegedly stabbing a man with a steak knife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dd535b675f9669a80a38a752d35f000</guid></item><item><title>Songs from the Hottest 100 of 2005 that should have been higher</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/songs-from-hottest-100-of-2005-should-have-been-higher/106145224</link><description>Arctic Monkeys were that low!? These are the tunes from triple j's Hottest 100 of 20. years ago that deserved to have placed higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afe7a93ca4bda33c4967345c3488e4f4</guid></item><item><title>Staff at new Noarlunga mental health unit 'visibly distressed and crying', union says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/sasmoa-raises-concerns-staff-pressured-at-mental-health-unit/106206512</link><description>South Australia's doctors' union has raised concerns that clinicians were distressed when asked to admit more patients at a new mental health unit at Noarlunga Hospital when staffing levels were "not clinically safe".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18ada848b526514d9d9fdbfb12165814</guid></item><item><title>Cosmetic nurse banned for two years after injecting botox without consulting doctor or obtaining prescription</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/qld-cosmetic-injectables-nurse-banned-ahpra/106206780</link><description>An AHPRA investigation found Thia Sullivan injected a patient without doctor consultation or a script, falsified records, and urged patients not to co-operate with police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24ab7c914abb7698629cc451740e2e66</guid></item><item><title>Sam Welsford aiming to cap new Ineos-Grenadiers contract with National title in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/sam-welsford-hopes-to-cap-new-ineos-contract-with-national-title/106207662</link><description>Sam Welsford, one of the drawcards at this week's Australian road cycling championships, has thanked fellow sprinter Caleb Ewan for advice on his new contract.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b26e538dd44c7761d9bf597a7f780f3f</guid></item><item><title>Ex-CIA agent Aldrich Ames who sold US secrets to the Soviets dies in prison at 84</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/cia-turncoat-aldrich-ames-who-sold-us-secrets-to-the-soviets-die/106207464</link><description>Aldrich Ames, who was 84, betrayed Western intelligence assets to the Soviet Union and Russia in one of the most damaging intelligence breaches in US history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e3f840337e699cc44ea7256e63057d7</guid></item><item><title>Beau Webster sparks another English meltdown and Jacob Bethell brings tears — quick hits from day four of the SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/ashes-quick-hits-day-four-scg-test/106205924</link><description>Beau Webster sparks a classic English meltdown as Jacob Bethell brings tears while Ben Stokes fails to finish another series. Here are your quick hits from day four of the SCG Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c2b6e11a4423ebcc8a55b02204c09a9</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/wednesday-finance-with-david-chau/106206784</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32abbb1c99e93571bc99a25151991c64</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2026: Jacob Bethell, England's biggest hope and biggest blunder, sets up Sydney finale</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/jacob-bethell-englands-hope-sets-up-sydney-finale-day-four-scg/106206644</link><description>Jacob Bethell's brilliant maiden Test century sets up an intriguing finish in Sydney, but leaves everyone bemused as to where this precocious young player has been all summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31da6c565da8a3ff2614cf41621bb413</guid></item><item><title>Maida Vale, High Wycombe fire extinguished after closing parts of Roe Highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/residents-in-city-of-kalamunda-urged-to-take-shelter-bushfire/106207782</link><description>Ground and aerial crews successfully control a bushfire that closed a section of Roe Highway and brought traffic to a standstill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09de7784b5375473f30d3a264f7b54b3</guid></item><item><title>UK citizen described as 'good friend' by White Australia movement to be deported</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/uk-citizen-suspected-far-right-links-set-to-be-deported/106207522</link><description>A foreign national has his visa cancelled and is facing deportation from Australia, amid claims of links to the "White Australia" movement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8779a314bf0c22e615dd612d64bea90d</guid></item><item><title>Nestlé recalls select batches of Alfamino infant formula</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/nestl%C3%A9-recalls-select-batches-of-alfamino-infant-formula/106207844</link><description>The precautionary measure is over concerns that the product could contain a toxin that can cause food poisoning symptoms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5d3dc52ac89a785c547074fcbc7903b</guid></item><item><title>Hottest day in years recorded across southern Australia as bushfire warnings remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/southern-australia-heatwave-emergency-bushfires-victoria/106207086</link><description>South-east Australia has sweltered through its hottest day in years as firefighters in Victoria continue to battle multiple out-of-control blazes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d84ee309ce10d03c8fdc762f798bab1</guid></item><item><title>Fresh probe for answers on missing woman in NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/fresh-probe-for-answers-on-missing-woman-in-nt/106207612</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f04830b581e9dc47670b333f87db977</guid></item><item><title>WA police respond to reports of man firing gun near Mullewa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/reports-of-man-with-firearm-in-wa-town-mullewa/106208060</link><description>Significant police resources are being deployed to the area after the gunman discharged the weapon, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bf6207e7d8e932f4f229f3e27c354a8</guid></item></channel></rss>