<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 21:39:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Afghanistan earthquake kills more than 1,400 as rescuers struggle to reach remote villages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-02/afghanistan-earthquake-kills-more-than-one-thousand-people/105727308</link><description>Rescuers are still working to try and find those trapped in the rubble of buildings scattered across the country's remote eastern provinces, as international aid trickles in.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">586adfab872829a4eb99a0340dc13821</guid></item><item><title>Port Lincoln's Kevin Warren retires from commercial flying after six decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-03/kevin-warren-veteran-commercial-pilot-retires-83-eyre-peninsula/105699924</link><description>From the wilds of the Great Australian Bight to the thrill of low-altitude crop dusting, pilot Kevin Warren has lived his dream job for six decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec29ad2016dea5823446b3bd92735f49</guid></item><item><title>Morley Market shopping centre razed by fire, destroys small businesses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-03/morley-market-fire-destroys-small-businesses/105727928</link><description>After initially declaring a fire that gutted the Morley Market shopping centre was deliberately lit, police backtrack on that claim and deem the blaze "non-suspicious".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">063273edc88ab34833b0bccb39907fa2</guid></item><item><title>SA premier claims 'major victory' in dispute over Whyalla port ownership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-03/premier-claims-major-victory-in-whyalla-port-ownership-dispute/105730778</link><description>The administrators of the Whyalla steelworks have had their ownership of the infrastructure on the port site confirmed by the Federal Court, paving the way for the steelworks to be sold as an integrated asset.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8299ef2b57b95fbf0aabd4dfd11b74d</guid></item><item><title>Brewer Asahi to buy barley from growers with data on grain's sustainability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-03/beer-brewer-asahi-to-buy-barley-from-growers-with-esg-data/105729138</link><description>Australia's largest beer business will soon buy barley from farmers who have gathered data about how sustainably their grain was produced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d331778189b849bc06bf6f44305939f</guid></item><item><title>Wine and spirit bottles to be included in container deposit scheme in NSW and SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-03/wine-and-spirit-bottles-included-container-deposit-scheme/105729040</link><description>New South Wales and South Australia will expand their 10-cent container deposit schemes to include wine, spirit, and some other large drink containers by late 2027.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b73c08abb550d4fc5e87e5459a51a96</guid></item><item><title>'Every family has lost someone': Afghan Australians describe horror after earthquake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-03/afghans-lead-their-own-relief-aid-effort-after-quake/105728852</link><description>Afghan Australians are rallying to raise funds after a deadly earthquake left more than 1,000 people dead and entire villages in eastern Afghanistan in ruins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e03221674e354019a3a568a40b53423</guid></item><item><title>Fire that gutted Morley Market shopping centre not deliberate, authorities say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-03/morley-market-fire-not-deliberate-authorities-backdown/105730656</link><description>A fire that gutted a shopping centre in Perth's inner north-east is deemed to be non-suspicious, after authorities reviewing CCTV initially mistook the reflection of a car's windscreen for a molotov cocktail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7027f656d983789cd34a499784ff2db9</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of investors caught up in First Guardian, Shield collapses told super trustees may pay 'remediation'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-04/superannuation-fund-platforms-shield-first-guardian-compensation/105731472</link><description>Thousands of investors who were exposed to heavy losses by investing their retirement savings into the First Guardian and Shield managed investment schemes have been told they may be able to get "remediation" from the superannuation trustees that ran platforms that housed their investments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">915e4bc97d6480ebeafc5f4d0f841f50</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane pill testing clinic's reopening delayed amid 'safety and privacy' concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-04/brisbane-pill-testing-clinic-reopening-delayed-gov-uncertainty/105733066</link><description>The Queensland government had threatened to shut down the service, saying it would either "legislate or regulate" to stop drug checking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d506a5bd59aff7679020bfc86624aa98</guid></item><item><title>US Open tennis 2025: Amanda Anisimova upsets Iga Świątek in straight sets to move through to semifinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-04/us-open-tennis-2025-amanda-anisimova-upsets-iga-swiatek/105733308</link><description>American Amanda Anisimova defeats Poland's Iga Świątek 6-4, 6-3 in the US Open quarterfinals to make her third major semifinal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbcf80ca25658fb571760e5be0ae83f4</guid></item><item><title>Who you can nominate as a beneficiary for your superannuation if you are single without kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-04/nominating-a-superannuation-beneficiary-when-single-without-kids/105706712</link><description>For people without a spouse or children, choosing someone such as a parent or sibling to leave their superannuation to is not straightforward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2d3df5a7a06253945705f67e6f0b508</guid></item><item><title>Third earthquake hits Afghanistan already stretched by 'death and destruction'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-04/afghanistan-earthquake-challenges-taliban-health-aid-workers/105732408</link><description>A third magnitude-6 earthquake strikes Afghanistan, pushing the limits of a country the United Nations says is already at "breaking point".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f027e280b07303ac1b47009aff13c9c1</guid></item><item><title>Moruya hotel owner captures suspected arson attack on business on CCTV</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-04/police-investigate-suspected-moruya-arson-attack-caught-on-cctv/105733588</link><description>Police are investigating a suspicious fire that destroyed two businesses on the far south coast of New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c4929e512909889f3cbfb2d93336f97</guid></item><item><title>Comedian Graham Linehan faces court over transgender social media posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/graham-linehan-in-court/105737630</link><description>The Father Ted co-creator is accused of "relentlessly" posting abusive comments online about trans women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0588602de2a814e52b96ac1fd718c0c8</guid></item><item><title>Solo mothers seek financial and emotional compensation over 'discriminatory' fertility policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/qld-ivf-class-action-socially-infertile/105736050</link><description>Women without partners, or in same-sex relationships, had to pay thousands of dollars for at least two rounds of fertility procedures before they could access rebates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">519e9f0f162ebd5b84227b56e54d8e7f</guid></item><item><title>Solo mothers seek financial and emotional compensation over 'discriminatory' fertility policy</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/qld-ivf-class-action-socially-infertile/105736050</link><description>Women without partners, or in same-sex relationships, had to pay thousands of dollars for at least two rounds of fertility procedures before they could access rebates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd73f58ae6769106b93527d761e1ef15</guid></item><item><title>Queensland prepares for hot, windy weekend with high fire danger at Birdsville Races</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/high-fire-danger-warning-issued-for-channel-country/105736360</link><description>Travellers in Channel Country and the state's south-west are urged to be aware of high fire danger conditions and strong winds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0569e9e44742df9c7d5d8a64fb1b44d</guid></item><item><title>Robodebt pushed victims to the brink, and some did not live to see justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/robodebt-compensation-settlement-victim-suicides/105734508</link><description>The federal government's $475 million compensation to Robodebt victims may do little to alleviate the "pain and anguish" for those who lost loved ones over the scandal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2662e3b4420876ed6a99a24bee3c8ca9</guid></item><item><title>Ballina tip audit shows clothes discarded in near-perfect condition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/ballina-tip-audit-clothing-waste-fast-fashion/105724116</link><description>A Ballina Council audit finds 80 per cent of clothes thrown away are in perfect or near-perfect condition, sometimes with the tags still on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90222814b8fb47e9300798a64966e257</guid></item><item><title>Germany loses 2-0 to Slovakia in first-ever away World Cup qualifier defeat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/germany-in-trouble-after-first-ever-away-world-cup-qualifier-los/105738644</link><description>Germany has been one of the dominant nations in world football for decades, but the team has to lift to avoid play-offs to make it to the World Cup after a stunning loss to Slovakia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0352f515eb574d2480b9bbd5786d3193</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr set to return for Chelsea this weekend in boost for Matildas and Australian fans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/sam-kerr-finally-returns-after-acl-injury/105738920</link><description>Matildas superstar Sam Kerr is named to play for Chelsea this weekend in the Women's Super League opener.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f44eb63aaebadf779cc1321cc2634ba</guid></item><item><title>NT government exempts US military fuel tanks built unlawfully on Darwin Harbour from certification</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/nt-us-military-fuel-tanks-darwin-government-exemption-foi/105736876</link><description>The Northern Territory government has exempted 11 massive US military fuel tanks built unlawfully on Darwin Harbour from needing occupancy certification.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">281cf1a6cd78c0d9604e9924c954ffed</guid></item><item><title>US Open tennis 2025: Defending champion Aryna Sabalenka beats Jessica Pegula to reach final, Amanda Anisimova outlasts Naomi Osaka</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/us-open-sabalenka-pegula-osaka-anisimova/105737610</link><description>Women's world number one Aryna Sabalenka is one win from defending her US Open title as she beats American star Jessica Pegula in a rematch of last year's final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06fd676ad5182885ba472d437e2bfd09</guid></item><item><title>Caged eggs to stay on supermarket shelves until 2030 as Coles abandons pledge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/coles-caged-egg-ban-delayed-until-2030/105739120</link><description>Coles says the cost of living and supply chain disruptions are behind its decision to continue selling caged eggs until 2030. A consumer expert says it is likely the supermarket's competitors will follow suit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90008e02e348ad552dde52e6a0b7146e</guid></item><item><title>Relationship feeling a bit stale? Here's how to hit refresh</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/small-ways-to-reconnect-in-your-relationship/105666432</link><description>We hear a lot about spring cleaning at this time of year, but it's not only your home or wardrobe that might need a refresh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d535e075ef7da09e2eaf8f41667e540c</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos beat New Zealand 1-0 in Canberra after Max Balard's debut goal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/socceroos-new-zealand-live-blog/105736610</link><description>Central midfielder Max Balard scores two minutes into his international debut as the Socceroos defeat New Zealand 1-0 in the first leg of the Soccer Ashes in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dee8917d97b9a46659af85b01ccafc21</guid></item><item><title>A leading WA doctor has laid bare the increasing crisis inside WA hospital emergency departments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/a-leading-wa-doctor-has-laid-bare-the-increasing/105742296</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5905093a4a0b9ca80475c26b18638829</guid></item><item><title>Superannuation death benefits have been going to domestic abusers. The industry wants it to stop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-06/molly-wilkes-domestic-violence-but-super-went-to-abuser/105686332</link><description>Perpetrators of domestic violence and financial abuse can gain access to the superannuation benefits and life insurance proceeds of their victims. A parliamentary inquiry finds super laws should be changed to prevent it continuing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6131aafa7de5242ea51680bcd687b15c</guid></item><item><title>Labor's hesitation on super tax a bad omen for more substantial reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-06/superannuation-freedom-of-information-jim-chalmers-jacinta-price/105720438</link><description>This week in Canberra the government seemed to be getting cold feet on its superannuation tax plan and the Coalition reckoned Labor was being less than transparent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73a77c7e67ed576f07e1652c7b6380d1</guid></item><item><title>Spring outlook positive for east coast farmers, but some still struggling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-06/abares-spring-outlook-good-for-grain-growers-livestock-producers/105725376</link><description>The weather bureau forecasts above-average rainfall across the east coast in coming months, which is good for some farmers and challenging for others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0d58f79b8882710ace35e4e07a2b1eb</guid></item><item><title>Memories help us make sense of who we are but how do they work?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-06/core-memories-eve-of-destruction-shaun-micallef/105695200</link><description>Some memories fade away, while others stay with us for life. But why can we remember some things and not others? And can you "make" a memory? This is what the experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcb0e364695cabd4be5afd0787a624e9</guid></item><item><title>Migrants, refugees make up worker shortfall in Ararat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-06/migrants-and-refugees-make-up-worker-shortfall-in-ararat/105735256</link><description>Ararat, like most regional towns, has an ageing population and a drift of young people to the cities. But a migrant resettlement program is reinvigorating the town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">330b96076441e7b018499ff729b657d8</guid></item><item><title>Massive blaze destroys historic wedding venue in NSW Hawkesbury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-06/massive-blaze-destroys-loxley-wedding-venue-in-nsw-hawkesbury/105742992</link><description>Couples hoping to tie the knot at a popular wedding venue in the Hawkesbury are waking up to the news it has been destroyed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">829a80c7ed2fe2f1536581bf47b76910</guid></item><item><title>Family urges support for loneliness, isolation after international student death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-06/family-urges-support-after-international-student-dies-in-albany/105707230</link><description>After a young Indian national died, likely by suicide, in 2024, his family and experts call for improved support systems to help ease migrant loneliness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6080348d3fc5f6365909174c32166e26</guid></item><item><title>Fire guts heritage wedding venue in Hawkesbury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-06/fire-guts-heritage-wedding-venue-in-hawkesbury/105743184</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dc1c30b4ebc12b4748ebc0a96091139</guid></item><item><title>Morley Market businesses seek support after fire destroys Perth shopping centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-06/businesses-call-for-financial-aid-after-morley-market-fire/105733978</link><description>Business owners affected by a fire which gutted a shopping centre in Perth's north-east are calling for state government support as they begin the recovery process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94d8213e6a0b096556795840c2f56820</guid></item><item><title>More men are being diagnosed with eating disorders, but experts say Australia is '10 years behind'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-07/eating-disorder-awareness-men/105739330</link><description>As more men are being diagnosed with eating disorders, experts say stereotypes are still making recovery harder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c0206e54b1f11665f1cd810d3301a1a</guid></item><item><title>Deep-sea mining for critical minerals has become a global flashpoint. Here is how it works</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-07/deep-sea-mining-explained-as-global-fight-brews/105725488</link><description>A push to extract minerals from the depths of the Pacific Ocean is gaining momentum. Here is how it works and why it has become a global flashpoint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b42594402a4ac030c3a163af80c4191d</guid></item><item><title>Calls for AFL to do more to address systemic racism and falling Indigenous numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-07/afl-indigenous-representation-racism/105739448</link><description>Ten years after AFL great Adam Goodes was forced to leave the game, Indigenous player numbers have dwindled, online racist abuse is rife and insiders say elite private schools have dramatically narrowed the talent pathways. How can the league turn it around?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5177384eaa515c99bff2f04b64dc1c49</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government to close Parentline in October after 25 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-07/victoria-parentline-counselling-service-closed/105741118</link><description>After 25 years in operation, Victoria's Parentline service will shut on October 31 as the government withdraws funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac6f54236b13f640968a9c288f806625</guid></item><item><title>Remote WA community buys prefab Chinese houses after decades in unfit homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-07/calls-for-housing-investment-in-remote-wa-desert-communities/105580560</link><description>Sick of waiting decades for repairs and new homes, an Indigenous community in WA pools funds to buy two houses, made in China from shipping containers, to house its most vulnerable residents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec2d8255e1d4a3746d9325faa50aa6cf</guid></item><item><title>On Father's Day, men reflect on how having kids has changed them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-07/men-on-how-fatherhood-has-changed-them/105703614</link><description>From learning patience and gratitude, to pushing past their comfort zone, we hear from six dads about the "transformative" experience of having children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6aa6421b495ce4dfedeb25dcc03cc07c</guid></item><item><title>Carlos Alcaraz beats Jannik Sinner in US Open final, reclaims world number one ranking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/tennis-us-open-mens-final-sinner-vs-alcaraz-live-blog/105744794</link><description>Carlos Alcaraz wins the men's US Open, reclaiming his world number one ranking by defeating Jannik Sinner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3e38f0de65b1740196844af5d838f7a</guid></item><item><title>Deep-sea mining entrepreneur Gerard Barron is banking on Trump to help him realise his dream</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/deep-sea-mining-minerals-gerard-barron-trump-four-corners/105733478</link><description>He has the chic of a Silicon Valley tech bro and a clean energy pitch for investors, but will Gerard Barron's deep-sea mining dream do more harm than good?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee1bcf920a3edd3fa187c97467f88fad</guid></item><item><title>National Drought Forum convenes in SA to put policy under scrutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/national-drought-forum-convenes-in-sa-farmers-want-policy-review/105739102</link><description>The nation's drought supports will come under scrutiny at a major national forum today as southern farmers continue to battle dry times.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">396bdee2ec757393ed7b2bec61d19392</guid></item><item><title>Trump security delays US Open men's final, frustrating fans ahead of Alcaraz-Sinner showdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/donald-trump-delays-us-open-final-frustrates-fans/105746630</link><description>Donald Trump receives a mixed reaction at the US Open after security delays frustrate fans ahead of the Jannik Sinner vs Carlos Alcaraz men's singles final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef4509413ec4b8a57d53b2dd3b7a99cf</guid></item><item><title>Food and garden organic waste bin system on verge of collapse across WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/fogo-bin-system-failing-in-south-west-wa-amid-wider-perth-push/105737394</link><description>As more Perth councils bring in a third bin for food and organic waste, some of the early adopters of the system in WA's South West are just months away from potentially scrapping the system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56eb7b4a37f457a287c3a1793ced7e5a</guid></item><item><title>Comfort viewing 'feels good' but rewatching movies, TV shows can have a downside</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/comfort-viewing-why-we-rewatch-tv-shows-and-movies/105728730</link><description>Whether it is an 80s classic or a Disney favourite, many of us watch old TV shows and films when we crave comfort, but there is a downside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d39d6b78f15a5c9e720de9ff7a073d91</guid></item><item><title>Four dolphins found dead in Huon Aquaculture salmon farm pens during six month period</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/four-dolphins-dead-in-six-months-at-huon-aquaculture-pens/105747094</link><description>Data shows in the first six months of this year, four dolphins died from becoming entangled in salmon farm enclosures in Tasmania's southern waters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4265694663528d24e75edec2f1eafab2</guid></item><item><title>Wignalls Wines owner 'broken' after lithium-ion battery fire burns warehouse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/battery-fire-destroys-wignalls-wines-warehouse-albany/105747356</link><description>A long-time winemaker says he opened his door to explosions and a black ball of smoke as a fire caused by a cordless screwdriver destroyed a lifetime collection of tools and machinery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae661f56b89f262a523886d2f96efedf</guid></item><item><title>New Banksy mural of judge striking protester at London's High Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/new-banksy-artwork-at-london-s-high-court/105750648</link><description>The latest mural from the British street artist depicts a judge beating a protester and is being seen as a reaction to the arrest of hundreds of demonstrators supporting banned group Palestine Action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ad37ecbf77ee6170428c87f749a209f</guid></item><item><title>BHP scraps renewable energy projects, casting doubt on emissions targets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/bhp-scraps-renewable-projects-says-emissions-reductions-on-track/105735266</link><description>BHP has dumped plans for major renewable energy projects in the Pilbara, prompting concern the miner is backing away from emissions reduction goals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a36068c540c5aa0a8236e17bc96fe415</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout leads rising generation of Australian stars at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/australian-athletics-stars-inspired-and-highly-motivated/105749554</link><description>Armed with the largest team ever assembled for a major athletics meet, Australia enters the World Athletics Championships with a sense of excitement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf3b0645d7e3d89f855a7e1f8ba88881</guid></item><item><title>Jai Hindley targeting podium in 'crucial' Vuelta a España final week</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/jai-hindley-targeting-podium-in-vuelta-a-espana-final-week/105751220</link><description>Jai Hindley is in prime position to land his third career grand tour podium ahead of a crucial final week at the Vuelta a España.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5d6cab3c8d6d14464b2436e7f9bc62a</guid></item><item><title>Jai Hindley targeting podium in 'crucial' Vuelta a España final week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/jai-hindley-targeting-podium-in-vuelta-a-espana-final-week/105751220</link><description>Jai Hindley is in prime position to land his third career grand tour podium ahead of a crucial final week at the Vuelta a España.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">982f54c99cf509d403f056d09e4d7a61</guid></item><item><title>Victoria becomes first Australian state to formally table treaty legislation in parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/victoria-treaty-legislation-parliment-first-peoples/105749692</link><description>Victoria's historic treaty is promising to "reckon with the past" and empower the state's First Peoples — and explicitly declares it will not take anything away from the broader community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f54f2a5a02f55dc06122d607cdb98826</guid></item><item><title>'Low levels of satisfaction' with healthcare in Canberra for endometriosis, menopause, identified in Women's Health Matters survey</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/women-health-canberra-survey-access-affordability-not-serious/105748894</link><description>A survey of women in Canberra about the state of their wellbeing and health reveals large gaps in access and affordability, as well as the staggering statistic that almost half of respondents felt doctors weren't taking them seriously.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">124301288b396763dfdb1ac672cdfeb3</guid></item><item><title>Australian writers shocked and 'disgusted' by closure of 85-year-old literary journal Meanjin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/australian-reactions-to-meanjin-closing-the-conversation/105751988</link><description>Melbourne University Publishing, which has housed the magazine since 2007, has cited "purely financial grounds" for the decision to close Meanjin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa72ae028c67b497533dfcfcfe944a23</guid></item><item><title>Climate change forces BOM to overhaul El Niño and La Niña analysis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/climate-change-prompts-bom-el-nino-la-nina-analysis-overhaul/105753896</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology is making a major change to how they assess El Niño and La Niña, the world's most dominant drivers of weather variability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9f387dd1c43a1f705ab0b9c38dc0f3b</guid></item><item><title>Border Force turns to Recfishwest app to crack down on illegal fishers off northern Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/border-force-recfishwest-app-illegal-fishing/105751918</link><description>The Australian Border Force is launching a reporting function on a popular fishing app, but stakeholders in the far north say the technology means little without more boots on the ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8803e9bb71ecebb91a10bdb49dc643ac</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou returns to Premier League management with Nottingham Forest after Nuno Espírito Santo sacking</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/ange-postecoglou-named-nottingham-forest-manager-epl/105752408</link><description>Australian's Ange Postecolgou has been named as new head coach of Premier League side Nottingham Forest after the sacking of Nuno Espírito Santo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">784fb523e0f9affd4662ea187bea2826</guid></item><item><title>Women's Rugby World Cup players trialling flashing mouthguards to help predict concussions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/women-rugby-world-cup-concussion-flashing-mouthguards/105732190</link><description>The Women's Rugby World Cup, currently being held in England, is trialling a revolutionary approach to concussion management. Players are wearing LED mouthguards which light up when a player sustains a hit that could result in a concussion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cac3259c78755b6836d00648b4bdd3a2</guid></item><item><title>Hopes Australia's first treaty with Aboriginal people will help close the gap</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/victorian-treaty-model-for-other-states-and-territories/105751796</link><description>For Aboriginal people, it has been centuries in the making. As Victoria tables legislation for the country's first treaty with First Nations people, Indigenous leaders are urging other states and territories to follow suit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0be2e8c821a3bee985131fd82524667e</guid></item><item><title>Construction workers are at higher risk of suicide. Here's how to look out for them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/supporting-loved-ones-who-work-in-construction/105724124</link><description>Construction workers are nearly twice as likely to take their own lives as other employed Australian men of the same age. Understanding the risks can help us better support those we know in the industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d30f05b9ecbefa716057acb813bf159</guid></item><item><title>Home-buying dream of Australians pushed further away by RBA rate cuts, making life 'more difficult'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/australians-home-buying-dream-impacted-by-rba-rate-cuts/105752532</link><description>While most Australians with a mortgage have been benefiting from the Reserve Bank cutting rates this year, not everyone is celebrating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64e3e627d4bf9570b8e5ed57fb8e40bd</guid></item><item><title>World Athletics Championships will face 'heat challenges' in Tokyo, says Seb Coe</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/world-athletics-championships-tokyo-will-face-heat-challenges/105755994</link><description>The president of World Athletics, Sebastian Coe, takes aim at world leaders for their inaction on climate change, saying the upcoming World Championships will face "heat challenges" due to a Tokyo heatwave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d732b09585a08ccb0dc3db19b3f1481</guid></item><item><title>World Athletics Championships will face 'heat challenges' in Tokyo, says Seb Coe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/world-athletics-championships-tokyo-will-face-heat-challenges/105755994</link><description>The president of World Athletics, Sebastian Coe, takes aim at world leaders for their inaction on climate change, saying the upcoming World Championships will face "heat challenges" due to a Tokyo heatwave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e692c08117b0a5bf775f7ae56bd55e7</guid></item><item><title>WA's Containers for Change program to include wine, spirit bottles from mid-2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/wine-spirit-bottles-included-in-wa-containers-for-change/105757946</link><description>A popular recycling program in Western Australia is being extended to include wine and spirit bottles for the first time since the scheme launched five years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ddf4a29d6e06cf217882bf3dc02f824</guid></item><item><title>The Assembly's former students return to work on season two with Leigh Sales</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/the-assembly-aspiring-journalist-students-return/105671820</link><description>Aspiring journalism students with autism are back to grill some of Australia's most prominent figures, and this time they've got seasoned peers behind the camera cheering them on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">693f309bde09fa98607d09728c2d11d5</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs suicide prevention walk bolstered by funding announcements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/alice-springs-to-receive-new-mental-health-care-centre/105757588</link><description>A study will work with Indigenous researchers who will map cultural assets and integrate traditional healing to improve outcomes in remote centres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">045de6ea6f4fa81d910d27a8d38966e8</guid></item><item><title>Bali streets submerged in floodwaters amid heavy rain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/bali-streets-submerged-in-floodwaters-amid-heavy-rain/105760262</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06c8b7ba14cbe31f44b936dff0d6fb3b</guid></item><item><title>Ford markets new electric ute to farmers but diesel expected to remain top choice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/new-ford-electric-ute-will-farmers-use-ev/105747446</link><description>The Ford F150 Lightning is being touted as the first viable EV for farm work, but it comes with a hefty price tag.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3c7feb61dc26980ec88ba7964a36f0b</guid></item><item><title>Heritage protection top priority for Pilbara traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/heritage-protection-top-priority-for-pilbara-traditional-owners/105748362</link><description>The traditional owners of Juukan Gorge have celebrated 10 years of native title determination and shared plans to safeguard heritage sites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2b63dfb64660699087909555e221c07</guid></item><item><title>NT mud crab industry to close for three months to protect stock</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/nt-mud-crab-industry-closure-for-christmas-to-protect-stock/105756524</link><description>The Northern Territory's mud crab industry will temporarily shut down after a fisheries assessment found stock numbers had fallen below a "trigger point".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eefa0a3cc9324d7ad4b98a5646d1da10</guid></item><item><title>Is the pink soap scum in my bathroom mould, or something else?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/why-is-the-soap-scum-in-my-bathroom-pink-and-orange-/105721212</link><description>Have you ever noticed a pink or orange-coloured substance in the tile grout or around taps in your bathroom? In most cases, it's one of two things.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9deb3308036c00d500826ba08d50f062</guid></item><item><title>How Hawthorn and Gold Coast proceed to the AFL preliminary finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/how-hawthorn-and-gold-coast-get-to-prelim-finals/105762028</link><description>Hawthorn and Gold Coast go into their cut-throat semifinals with reasons for some confidence against the Crows and Lions. Cody Atkinson and Sean Lawson look into the factors driving both teams' September runs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bee6f2e0e1aee53ecd326cca279df14</guid></item><item><title>'Bubble curtain' ready to protect cuttlefish as algal bloom persists in SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/algal-bloom-bubble-curtain-ready-as-asthma-advice-defended/105761978</link><description>A "bubble curtain" is set for activation as part of South Australia's fight against the ongoing algal bloom, as the state government defends its handling of health advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c99d09af36c76bdbcccd8ef52874b9da</guid></item><item><title>Sprint great Usain Bolt says Gout Gout needs the right support and focus to succeed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/it-s-never-just-easy-usain-bolt-message-gout-gout-world-titles/105763446</link><description>Usain Bolt delivers a simple piece of advice to Gout Gout as the Australian teenage sprint sensation prepares for his first world championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bbe4c5df31d0eaa97dba1aeafad326e</guid></item><item><title>Growing group of Labor MPs urge 2035 emissions target above Climate Authority's floor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/labor-mps-urge-2035-target-within-climate-authority-advice/105762592</link><description>A growing cross-factional group within Labor is privately urging for Australia's next major climate target to respect the advice of the Climate Change Authority, which will hand its opinion on a 2035 target to government any day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366f414d754ce8a4269105ca01955ee0</guid></item><item><title>Sydney live music venue embraces grant for soundproofing amid noise complaint concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/nsw-government-grants-soundproofing-sydney-live-music-venues/105748102</link><description>When the Red Rattler theatre in Sydney's inner west installed acoustic foam in the walls behind its stage, it didn't just make the venue soundproof — but future-proof.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ff16aa762f54c42d123cbb2a78c68e5</guid></item><item><title>Toni Jordan spent her childhood at the greyhound track, inspiring her new novel Tenderfoot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/toni-jordan-books-tenderfoot-interview/105754310</link><description>The acclaimed author's father was a greyhound trainer and her mother ran a TAB. Her unconventional childhood inspired her eighth book, Tenderfoot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19370cb777b009a92f1855e8361e9d09</guid></item><item><title>Northern Territory Corrections Department honours 20th anniversary of Elders Visiting Program in prisons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/aboriginal-elders-visiting-nt-prisons-program-20th-anniversary/105762476</link><description>A decades-long partnership between Indigenous elders and the Northern Territory’s prison system is helping prisoners reconnect with culture and encouraging them to turn their lives around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d147bcd5d79a00f7cbb9532900da3288</guid></item><item><title>Outback hairdresser a 'hero' to Wilcannia residents longing for a pampering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/outback-hairdresser-travels-1000kms-to-pamper-remote-residents/105636488</link><description>The "salon" is an op shop and the round-trip commute's a doozy, but Juliann Mutch is happy to go the extra distance to pamper her grateful Wilcannia clientele.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">078b38e392f5ace6b92b8e4e40ed7b88</guid></item><item><title>Voter turnout as low as 10 per cent in NT local elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/nt-local-government-council-elections-see-dip-in-voter-turnout/105760662</link><description>Two out of five of the NT's enrolled voters failed to vote in the jurisdictions recent local government elections, with experts concerned voting fatigue has taken hold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">889f1bd29f1f4d9c6b5541f52d7a7f70</guid></item><item><title>What happens to your data when you trade or recycle your device?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/what-happens-to-data-when-disposing-of-old-devices-in-ewaste/105681804</link><description>A cybercrime expert says trading or recycling electronics may not completely erase personal data and users should adopt a "risk-adjusted strategy" when disposing of devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a43950c96dbc6efda59bd57a5459809</guid></item><item><title>The simple system I use for composting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/simple-system-use-for-composting/105648580</link><description>Koren Helbig has devised an easy and effective method of turning her food waste and plant trimmings into a nutrient-rich compost for her Adelaide/Tarntanya food gardens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79967d2cf242f317c83d0a075a76ca87</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne names Geelong assistant Steven King as new senior coach as Nathan Buckley is overlooked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/afl-steven-king-named-melbourne-demons-coach/105767854</link><description>Melbourne surprises the AFL world by naming Geelong assistant Steven King as its new senior coach despite persistent links with Nathan Buckley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fea7a235f5c0090787551364ca3b7d77</guid></item><item><title>Quote Quiz: Who said it, Lachlan Murdoch or Succession's Kendall Roy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/quiz-who-said-it-lachlan-murdoch-or-kendall-roy/102946532</link><description>As Lachlan Murdoch's ascension to the head of the family business is cemented, can you tell his quotes apart from Succession's self-proclaimed "eldest boy", Kendall Roy?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cddc5ea62e8e2529ae1aade17a00dfd</guid></item><item><title>Artists and users boycotting Spotify over AI use and CEO's military tech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/spotify-boycott-daniel-ek-ai-music-military-tech-fenn-wilson/105765846</link><description>A growing number of artists and users are leaving Spotify. What's changed with the streaming giant? And what comes next?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dce4c940b969890ecfdfb4e37ad98c9</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian government consulting on public homebirth model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/tasmanian-government-consulting-on-public-homebirth-model/105767780</link><description>A proposal by the Tasmanian government to introduce a public homebirth model has been welcomed by those in the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9fdea3108a66149f4d49c462aee9cca</guid></item><item><title>British YouTube creator Yung Filly to travel home to UK on bail for sexual assault charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/youtube-creator-yung-filly-allowed-to-fly-overseas-on-bail/105094220</link><description>British YouTube content creator Yung Filly, who's facing trial in Perth on sex assault charges, is granted permission to travel home to the UK for the first time since he was arrested.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c89f9603e811b96cf1412b9f341613a</guid></item><item><title>Judge awards man $450k in damages after ex-premier's police officer son falsified evidence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/man-gets-450k-damages-for-daniel-keneally-fabricating-evidence/105767836</link><description>A Supreme Court judge has awarded NSW man Luke Moore $450,000 in damages after the disgraced police officer son of former senator Kristina Keneally falsified evidence about alleged death threats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11118a489badd08a9a50abbfccbc184e</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump and his 'good man' Anthony Albanese share some common ground</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/donald-trump-anthony-albanese-common/105756898</link><description>The MAGA president's grip on the Republican party is near total while Albanese holds a sway over his left-leaning caucus like few of his Labor predecessors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88bb570d5f115243764edac358fd6925</guid></item><item><title>Former minister Greg Hunt works for Brethren company whose owners made millions on COVID contracts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/greg-hunt-plymouth-brethren-liberal-party-four-corners/105767402</link><description>The Sydney-based church has been described by former members and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese as a "cult".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4328a557e1520bd5030668231cb9ac20</guid></item><item><title>Journey Home, David Gulpilil shows the film icon's remote homeland 'for the first time'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/new-documentary-journey-home-david-gulpilil-screens-in-darwin/105765450</link><description>Legendary Yolŋu actor David Gulpilil held an ambition throughout his career to share a part of himself and his culture that the world had never seen before. A new documentary does exactly that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d65721a64e5ebe2a1f5e94ea75d0c3b0</guid></item><item><title>When does Gout Gout run in the 200m at the 2025 World Athletics Championships in Tokyo, and other key events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/when-does-gout-gout-run-at-the-world-athletics-championships/105748430</link><description>The 2025 World Athletics Championships in Tokyo sees Australia's largest-ever team tackle the best athletes on the planet. Here are the key events you won't want to miss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed7a4e602de605c0371a42019cfce15a</guid></item><item><title>More than a dozen women complain about Brisbane doctor accused of performing 'sexually motivated' checks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/complaints-against-brisbane-doctor-accused-unnecessary-checks/105761406</link><description>Dr Stan Theodoros is facing disciplinary proceedings, lodged by Queensland's health ombudsman, in the Queensland Civil and Administrative Tribunal (QCAT).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">741e87aaa3667ced3bea58af9748de48</guid></item><item><title>Keio Yoshida tells queer stories differently in their new book, Pride and Prejudices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/keio-yoshida-pride-and-prejudices-queer-lives-and-the-law/105658412</link><description>In their latest book, author and human rights lawyer Keio Yoshida draws on their personal experience and legal expertise to demonstrate the importance of sharing queer stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">325fafb6f4714080b832c5a0148c1ee0</guid></item><item><title>Adrianne Lenker on Big Thief's evolution and the making of Double Infinity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/big-thief-double-infinity-adrianne-lenker-new-album-interview/105754728</link><description>At the peak of their success, Big Thief faced a major emotional rupture that reshaped the group from the inside out. Now, they've returned with their sixth album, shaped by deep creative trust and a renewed commitment to collaboration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c838f7561646302e00adf2a4fa4ff7b4</guid></item><item><title>Nourishing and easy sweet potato and lentil bowls - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/easy-roasted-sweet-potato-and-lentil-bowl/105643934</link><description>This jazzy little bowl is made from simple ingredients. The sweet potato is roasted gently with spices and tinned lentils are roasted until crisp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f14ee49334cef10b8f95233d1889d9e</guid></item><item><title>Recyclers aim to stop 30,000 tonnes of mining tyres being buried every year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/tyre-recycling-facility-hopes-process-more-mining-waste/105642522</link><description>Australia's mining industry has been burying enormous, worn out tyres for decades. But a new facility is offering a solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e88f7f8fefbb3e349ddbc89682fdd00e</guid></item><item><title>Bush band tells Aboriginal people's side of the Maralinga nuclear weapon tests story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/bush-band-song-tells-story-of-maralinga-atomic-bomb-tests/105765452</link><description>For Liam Tunkin, making music is about continuing his late father's legacy and sharing a dark part of Australia's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b898813878aa4745672fc29e28ce560b</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fall to 28-26 defeat against Argentina in The Rugby Championship in Sydney</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/live-updates-wallabies-vs-argentina-the-rugby-championship/105753320</link><description>The Wallabies have fallen just short of a magical comeback against Argentina, losing 28-26 in a thrilling Rugby Championship Test in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5469c7b464e3dc361d956d14cd5a474c</guid></item><item><title>Advocates call for action on brain health as AIHW reveals dementia is leading cause of death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/australians-dying-from-dementia-more-than-any-other-cause/105768682</link><description>Advocates warn the number of people with the condition could exceed 1 million without government intervention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b35bf8bb29f6390428b007c4fc10877</guid></item><item><title>Labor win Kiama by-election as voters replace disgraced MP Gareth Ward</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/kiama-byelection-polls-close-votes-counting/105770414</link><description>The NSW Premier said Kiama now has the ear of the government after it claimed victory in the by-election triggered by the resignation of convicted rapist Gareth Ward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f8148eb8e329e6cf74190c6118a0a8f</guid></item><item><title>Torrie Lewis makes semifinals at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo, Day 1</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-in-tokyo-day-1/105770190</link><description>Torrie Lewis broke the national record to claim a spot in the women's 100m semifinal, as Lauren Ryan recorded Australia's best finish in a 10,000m final since 2003 on day one of the World Athletics Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1fd0acc71517e138058f6992507918f</guid></item><item><title>Torrie Lewis makes semifinals at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo, Day 1</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-in-tokyo-day-1/105770190</link><description>Torrie Lewis broke the national record to claim a spot in the women's 100m semifinal, as Lauren Ryan recorded Australia's best finish in a 10,000m final since 2003 on day one of the World Athletics Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6652d1f08f16b540b48134b5be6a9914</guid></item><item><title>From Formula 1 to creating the 'world's best' croissant, how baking saved Lune founder Kate Reid's life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/cars-to-croissants-kate-reid-and-the-lune-empire/105750472</link><description>Kate Reid's Lune croissants have been called the world's best. But how did a young woman struggling with a near-fatal eating disorder end up perfecting pastry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d09b350f758690100795053d1425df1</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Think you're contestant material? Prove it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/105746846</link><description>It's time to show me your exceptional trivia knowledge. Ha!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03f61e05a2d928ef5dd5a855914f188a</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal artist Emily Kam Kngwarray becomes first Australian with solo exhibition at London's Tate Modern</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/emily-kam-kngwarray-nt-artist-solo-exhibition-tate-modern/105748722</link><description>Emily Kam Kngwarray has been recognised as "one of the world's leading artists" after becoming the first Australian whose work is the subject of a solo exhibition at the Tate Modern Gallery in London.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80742075f005deb3851d847eafa37b21</guid></item><item><title>Perth had its wettest winter in 30 years. Why aren't its dams full?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/perth-dam-remains-low-despite-the-wettest-winter-in-30-years/105767386</link><description>The last time it rained that much in winter, Perth's drinking water dam overflowed. Now it's barely half full. It's telling the story of a water crisis that's not only affecting Australia, but the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">520afffe8e8f2b9614549ec3a2399a4d</guid></item><item><title>'White-hot anger' in the bush as Victorians fight government on multiple fronts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/why-regional-victorians-are-angry-at-state-government/105761034</link><description>Rural residents and local councils are deeply unhappy with new taxes, renewable energy, bad roads and mining companies, accusing the state government of "city centric" policymaking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">975ae86896e7894f15dfe756b7e0f4f9</guid></item><item><title>'Where to now?' Liberals soul searching after heavy loss in Kiama by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/nsw-kiama-by-election-analysis/105768772</link><description>For a party that had just suffered a heavy defeat, the mood at the Liberals' post-election event was surprisingly upbeat on Saturday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0324f2b1e17e0afe58c8b2fdb2342585</guid></item><item><title>How to watch the 2025 Primetime Emmys in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/how-to-watch-the-emmys-2025-primetime-awards-los-angeles/105751936</link><description>Your pocket guide to watching the Emmy awards in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec791c67cc32865ea8679b33207acf56</guid></item><item><title>Victorian farmers welcome spring forecast despite long-term climate concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/farming-faces-global-warming-challenges-bom-csiro-forecasts/105698854</link><description>As spring brings a flicker of hope, some farmers cautiously embrace optimism while others face mounting pressures and climate uncertainty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eefc8f08701a2e9f48f36a96143be8ca</guid></item><item><title>How to give your indoor plants a spring clean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/how-to-spring-clean-indoor-plants/105754044</link><description>As gardens, parks and nature strips start showing signs of spring, our indoor plants might need a little help to jump into the new season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7041345f64a52b3d64fb6ac2ef82f3b</guid></item><item><title>Lachie Neale gives himself '50 per cent' chance of improbable grand final appearance after calf injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/afl-brisbane-lions-lachie-neale-50-per-cent-chance-gf/105771982</link><description>Lachie Neale admits medical professionals are not holding out much hope of him recovering from a calf injury in time for the grand final, but he is not giving up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a19957fc35f1ad280cdb57d03a33c7d3</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull cruises to 1,500m final at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-in-tokyo-day-2/105772150</link><description>Jess Hull made light work of a rough semifinal to progress in the women's 1,500, but Linden Hall and Torrie Lewis both fell just short of making the final themselves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39c5cb5168fcdf8bebc8a609614fd1e0</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull cruises to 1,500m final at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-in-tokyo-day-2/105772150</link><description>Jess Hull made light work of a rough semifinal to progress in the women's 1,500, but Linden Hall and Torrie Lewis both fell just short of making the final themselves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3251a6322d104d5e8dec69a8eb3f155</guid></item><item><title>The year Australia is due to blow its carbon budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/australia-carbon-budget-2035-emissions-target/105341080</link><description>Unless Australia lifts its ambitions, its "fair share" of carbon emissions will be spent 14 years early. With the government announcing a 2035 climate target this week, there is intense debate on how high the government should aim — and whether it will be enough to help limit global warming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92c26486065559e6e68fc907f4300c31</guid></item><item><title>The higher Australia's 2035 emissions target, the more necessary a carbon tax will be</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/albanese-government-2035-climate-emissions-target/105771566</link><description>Australia's emissions reduction number is, in short, a laugh-or-cry-o-meter, or perhaps more accurately, a tax-o-meter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5aae41b286ff6b7c3400069e180e67f</guid></item><item><title>Dads leaving sex education to mums, report finds, with concerns young boys are missing out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/dads-leaving-sex-education-to-mums-boys-missing-out/105761172</link><description>New report finds mothers do more of the sex education at home, raising concerns that young boys are missing out on key information from their dads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09373ae607cb293f5028b7499dce7b5a</guid></item><item><title>Family violence survivors waiting years for social housing as demand surges in Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/social-public-housing-wait-times-victoria-family-violence/105655044</link><description>As family violence survivor and mother-of-two, Maya was assessed as a high priority for social housing. Eight years later, she's finally moved into a suitable home in outer-suburban Melbourne, with vulnerable Victorians left waiting for years as the social housing waitlist soars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e74302190404e5284428c6e45ccbce8a</guid></item><item><title>Fortunes change quickly in AFLW as round of upsets shakes up ladder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/round-of-upsets-shakes-up-aflw-ladder-mid-season/105772256</link><description>After a tough start to the year, Geelong sit just outside the top eight and equal on points with the reigning grand finalists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a314ed873d6767758eb39088f9f9e0f6</guid></item><item><title>Traditional custodian readies for 'challenge' over North West Shelf gas project extension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/traditional-custodian-fights-north-west-shelf-approval/105770306</link><description>Environment Minister Murray Watt approved the extension of Australia's biggest gas project last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fff78b1c904abb60057a8fd295536c56</guid></item><item><title>Emmys 2025 red carpet: Jenna Ortega, Lisa, Sydney Sweeney, Aimee Lou Wood, Walton Goggins, Selena Gomez and Pedro Pascal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/2025-emmys-red-carpet-fashion/105752046</link><description>The stars of the television industry are bringing the drama with their fashion choices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85981e3d6d9c2977cda8244d6580248c</guid></item><item><title>WA's expanded container deposit scheme to cost wineries, distilleries millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/container-for-change-wa-wine-expansion-hits-small-business/105763914</link><description>Producers in Western Australia's premier wine region say the state government's expanded bottle recycling scheme is set to cost them millions of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16ff8a6ec9140b73f0af3e85a003dec0</guid></item><item><title>Emmy Awards 2025: The Pitt, Adolescence and The Studio win big as Owen Cooper makes history — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/emmy-awards-2025-live-blog-latest-updates/105757172</link><description>The Pitt wins Best Drama at the 77th Annual Primetime Emmy Awards, with The Studio, Adolescence and even Stephen Colbert walking away as the biggest winners of the night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f0dab0d1494400d0b01fc6483c43b32</guid></item><item><title>Outback ringmaster Fred Brophy takes his boxing tent to Birdsville for last time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/fred-brophy-takes-boxing-tent-to-birdsville-for-last-time/105761756</link><description>Fred Brophy will sell you a ticket, spin you a yarn and dare you into the ring, but at 73, the outback ringmaster is slowing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9c596e0ff31abe53e3cdc3f15b54fcc</guid></item><item><title>First climate risk assessment finds 1.5m Australians at risk from sea level rise by 2050</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/climate-risk-assessment-sea-level-rise-2035-target/105765456</link><description>One and a half million Australians are at risk from sea levels rising by 2050 unless climate change can be limited, Australia’s first national climate risk assessment warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84bc65afd0d8a3b350ab90314dff5f21</guid></item><item><title>From Tantanoola to Essendon, Angus Clarke reflects on AFL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/angus-clarke-on-south-east-sa-breakfast/105773582</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32b5ad4ec4dbc2210f1b5997bfa6ec36</guid></item><item><title>AFL State of Origin will return, with Western Australia-Victoria clash confirmed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/afl-announces-state-of-origin-return-with-wa-vic-clash-confirmed/105773392</link><description>AFL chief executive Andrew Dillon confirms Western Australia will play Victoria in Perth next February in the first State of Origin match since 1999.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d22aa23c3e429a537fcaf8a6093051d</guid></item><item><title>Prince Harry says he has no regrets about 2023 memoir Spare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/prince-harry-defends-his-memoir/105773344</link><description>Prince Harry has defended his tell-all autobiography Spare, insisting he has no regrets about its publication.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">822f9b8bfc9e038c4a05c240f351b362</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with giving Nazi salute at Brisbane Lions v Gold Coast Suns AFL game at the Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/qld-man-charged-nazi-salute-at-afl-game-banned/105773522</link><description>A 39-year-old man has been charged with giving a Nazi salute at the AFL semifinal in Brisbane on Saturday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10247763ed0af9c91511f307aea12cd7</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Roosters confirm ACL injury for Tarryn Aiken on eve of NRLW finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sydney-roosters-confirm-tarryn-aiken-acl-injury-nrlw/105773930</link><description>Tarryn Aiken will miss the Sydney Roosters' NRLW finals campaign, with scans confirming a knee injury that will require a knee reconstruction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">880a495525ca619936ce2de16f4379d3</guid></item><item><title>Inquest hears prison system failed Aboriginal inmate before he died</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/inquest-examines-clinton-austin-death-loddon-prison/105735924</link><description>A coronial inquest hears the system failed First Nations prisoner Clinton Austin before his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3728f892b4b408407004793ea3dc66f</guid></item><item><title>Emmys 2025 winners: Adolescence, Severance, The Pitt and The Studio win big</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/primetime-emmy-awards-ceremony-winners-list/105752034</link><description>The 77th Primetime Emmy Awards are honouring the best and brightest in the US television industry. Here are the shows that picked up the trophies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d8d75f9c20e7825a51aab42eb0d2ca3</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of pigs feared dead in fire at Dublin's Andgar piggery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/fire-dublin-andgar-piggery-animal-cruelty-sa/105775484</link><description>It has taken all day for a fire at a controversial piggery north of Adelaide to be put out. RSPCA inspectors are attending the piggery, which was already under investigation over cruelty claims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa9cf9f12e59456af1cd840c58c97688</guid></item><item><title>Cricket Tasmania seeking ways to make proposed Macquarie Point stadium 'compatible' for matches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/cricket-tasmania-support-macquarie-point-afl-stadium/105774588</link><description>After initial concerns that the roof design of the proposed Hobart AFL stadium at Macquarie Point would hinder cricket matches, sporting authorities have thrown their support behind the build, saying "we will find a way".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52fc9b1b49c5b01644f528cf1efb60b0</guid></item><item><title>Australia's richest person among hundreds of donors to NT senator's legal fund</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/gina-rinehart-jacinta-nampijinpa-price-defamation-legal-fund/105775036</link><description>Australia's richest person, Gina Rinehart, has helped fund Senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price's crowd-funded defence to a defamation action brought by the head of a Northern Territory land council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d91909126ee3a35177e1e241ad2e0c3</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle Knights announce Justin Holbrook as new NRL head coach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/-newcastle-knights-justin-holbrook-nrl-head-coach/105776208</link><description>Sydney Roosters assistant coach Justin Holbrook has been named the new head coach of the Newcastle Knights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1dd4d58f20f4f23adda8178a9bef8c9</guid></item><item><title>Shadow minister Andrew Hastie says he will be 'without a job' if Liberals don't abandon net zero</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/andrew-hastie-flags-resignation-or-sacking-over-liberal-net-zero/105776432</link><description>Liberal frontbencher Andrew Hastie indicates he will quit or be dumped from the shadow cabinet if the Coalition does not abandon the target of achieving net zero greenhouse gas emissions by 2050.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d65a81fca15feb36d2a53c3d3bdd85a3</guid></item><item><title>Whispering Jack: The John Farnham Musical to premiere in Sydney Theatre Company's 2026 season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/whispering-jack-john-farnham-musical-sydney-theatre-company-2026/105766868</link><description>Whispering Jack: The John Farnham Musical is one of 13 plays coming to Sydney Theatre Company next year, alongside shows starring David Wenham and Miranda Otto.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ade2dd75f87979058d05fced4a9318</guid></item><item><title>NRL announces preliminary finals dates, Melbourne Storm on Friday, Brisbane Broncos play Sunday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/nrl-preliminary-finals-dates-melbourne-brisbane/105776416</link><description>The NRL has shaken up its preliminary finals weekend, electing to host one of its grand final qualifiers on a Sunday for the first time in 18 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29c35159922bc6cf9a11532627c3c244</guid></item><item><title>Armand Mondo Duplantis breaks world record, Kurtis Marschall wins pole vault bronze at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-in-tokyo-day-3/105774960</link><description>Kurtis Marschall wins bronze in the men's pole vault final on day three of the World Athletics Championships in Tokyo, as Armand Duplantis soars to a 14th world record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a75c97c2c4e50d1aabaf437d14731d7d</guid></item><item><title>Former MMA fighter Conor McGregor drops out of Irish presidential race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/conor-mcgregor-drops-out-of-irish-presidential-race-/105776960</link><description>Critics say the former MMA fighter's pre-emptive dropout was to save face in a likely knockout at the hands of Dublin City Council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60f1b0734e35fba4e5506343df9a6d2a</guid></item><item><title>Use constitutional power to raise age of criminal responsibility nationwide, lawyers tell PM</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/pm-letter-raise-the-age/105748868</link><description>Forty years ago, the federal government used the constitution to halt construction of the Franklin Dam. Now lawyers want the Albanese government to do the same to keep kids out of jails.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7b875978506038b9b93d5a66cdfdece</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull believes in world championship 1,500m glory against serial winner Faith Kipyegon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/jess-hull-believes-in-world-championship-1500m-victory/105772376</link><description>Australia's Jess Hull has self-belief, despite facing an uphill task to beat three-time world and Olympic champion Faith Kipyegon over 1,500m at the World Athletics Championships in Tokyo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">101bafefa4e4f1f51f1ac514223465df</guid></item><item><title>Fears parts of Queensland will have to 'retreat' amid predicted sea level rise and increased severe weather events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/climate-report-national-climate-risk-assessment-queensland/105775976</link><description>The warning comes amid a national report finding up to 185,000 residential buildings in Queensland could be in "very high-risk areas" if climate change is not addressed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c13eb12a1db1234d6f66dae28d2620c</guid></item><item><title>The hidden impact of injuries costing AFL clubs millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/the-hidden-costs-of-injuries-costing-afl-clubs-millions/105777624</link><description>New research highlights the financial impact of injuries in the AFL, with one club losing $13 millions over six seasons, nearly 17 per cent of its total player salaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1df9a60d5e14380c28dd088a5cbf203a</guid></item><item><title>Shire of Coolgardie awaits decision on future after giving evidence to minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/shire-of-coolgardie-show-cause-notice-response/105774072</link><description>The embattled Shire of Coolgardie waits to hear whether it will be suspended ahead of local government elections over concerns about financial and managerial mismanagement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a60af1587b72855d0965e133f66c3a65</guid></item><item><title>Lisa Reihana's exhibition, Voyager, recasts history through an Indigenous lens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/lisa-reihana-ngununggula-exhibition-voyager-indigenous-maori/105760474</link><description>The internationally renowned Maori artist's technically complex, visually mesmerising exhibition spans nearly a decade of artwork.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ed46a76298102094bcf604b8536fb9b</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Olympics inflatable art reappears after 25 years in rural NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/sydney-olympics-reg-mombassa-inflatable-art-reappears-in-nsw/105735020</link><description>A Coonabarabran artist made a lucky find at an online auction two years ago when she recognised a Reg Mombassa art piece from the Sydney Olympics mixed in with advertising devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f4eacf145efc7f64bf56ffdaca13099</guid></item><item><title>Where and how to watch the 2025 Primetime Emmy award-winning shows in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/where-and-how-to-watch-the-emmy-award-winning-shows/105778142</link><description>From The Studio to The Pitt, here's how to stream the biggest winners of the 2025 Primetime Emmy Awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">243532cd9f64922ef9206ce0ccd4940d</guid></item><item><title>Aaron Chen talks comedy, faith, and moving to New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/aaron-chen-take-5-comedy-interview-music-tonight-fisk/105773602</link><description>How Aaron Chen went from being booted out of Sydney pubs to winning Logies and chasing global stardom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd43f88c371be470e8b83b1b925f650a</guid></item><item><title>How Isabelle Kelly shook off getting her 'teeth pushed back' to return for Roosters' NRLW finals charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/isabelle-kelly-injury-jaw-teeth-roosters-nrlw-finals/105780582</link><description>Isabelle Kelly was meant to rest up for a few weeks after suffering an oral fracture that nearly cost her several teeth but the Roosters skipper missed just one match and has now returned to lead the club's premiership charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">062a7201f7cd32cadeb54c8069a61337</guid></item><item><title>China has a 'chokehold' on the rare earth supply chain. Could Australia offer an alternative?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/china-rare-earths-monopoly-australia-alternative-supplier/105748058</link><description>Rare earths are critical for manufacturing everything from electric vehicles to wind turbines and defence equipment, and with China's dominance over the supply chain, they have also become inextricably enmeshed in geopolitics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7e66c6df15c930bf8fa103970dac05b</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of pigs die as Andgar Proprietors piggery catches fire with two sheds burning for over 12 hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/andgar-piggery-fire-kills-200-animials-sa/105780636</link><description>The Department of Primary Industries and Regions says about 200 animals died in the blaze while another 45 pigs were euthanised by the department and RSPCA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8d637dff0fa3ce0bdf9aee2457db201</guid></item><item><title>Approval of $453 million battery project angers Kiewa Valley residents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victorian-premier-approves-kiewa-valley-battery-project/105779392</link><description>The state government approves the development of a $453 million energy storage system by a Chinese company in the state's north-east, angering nearby residents who say their concerns have been ignored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0714747da477ffd0c9e429861e28643d</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull wins 1,500m bronze, Peter Bol crashes out at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-jess-hull/105778240</link><description>Jess Hull claims bronze in the women's 1,500m at the World Athletics Championships, after Peter Bol was eliminated from the 800m in the heats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7250f2b7b3eaaed7b8f51092ef3fc818</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull wins 1,500m bronze, Peter Bol crashes out at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-jess-hull/105778240</link><description>Jess Hull claims bronze in the women's 1,500m at the World Athletics Championships, after Peter Bol was eliminated from the 800m in the heats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4471a0f3ff41f8922f8593e3df2e2d0</guid></item><item><title>What time does Gout Gout run at World Athletics Championships? How to watch Gout Gout's 200m heat</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/when-does-gout-gout-run-200m-at-world-athletics-championships/105775006</link><description>Gout Gout will make his World Athletics Championships debut at the Tokyo National Stadium on Wednesday night. Here's how to watch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7315f72a5d8077aedc6f3d9a8a9dfde9</guid></item><item><title>Fingal Post Office saved from closure after local farmers confirmed as new operators</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/fingal-post-office-in-tasmania-saved-by-local-pig-farmers/105779962</link><description>A rural Tasmanian community has fought to keep its post office open, fearing losing the important service could lead to their hometown disappearing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08e347abc9bfa22abeb9447ad06020ab</guid></item><item><title>Fire threatens Gold Coast's Burleigh Headland national park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/fire-threatens-koala-habitat-at-burleigh-headland/105781982</link><description>Police are investigating how a suspicious fire started in the popular tourist spot overnight, burning through around 75 per cent of the grass under the boulder clusters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a9ef095f199bc494bedacf6b3ab64f2</guid></item><item><title>New doco Signorinella: Little Miss celebrates the Italian women who shaped modern Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/signorinella-little-miss-documentary-italian-film-festival/105774428</link><description>Signorinella: Little Miss, the new documentary from the filmmakers behind Lygon St — Si Parla Italiano, celebrates the tenacity of Italian Australian women in business and beyond.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc3ea23b27aab754a73fa0319a25aee</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull completes second act at World Athletics Championships as quest for gold continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/jess-hull-world-1500m-bronze-medal-wants-gold/105781748</link><description>Jess Hull claimed Australia's best result in a 1,500m at the world championships with a bronze medal, but she wants to make it gold next time around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b678c9c3d3bc90e24f522348f78b840</guid></item><item><title>Macquarie Point stadium report recommends project not proceed, as Tasmanian Planning Commission flags concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/tasmania-hobart-afl-macquarie-point-planning-commission-findings/105781448</link><description>The proposed Macquarie Point AFL stadium in Hobart should not proceed, a long-awaited assessment from the Tasmanian Planning Commission recommends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a468158b9bcb2474776c465e5ce225</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters honoured for Black Summer efforts as CFA warns about fire season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/black-summer-five-years-on-albury-wodonga/105761592</link><description>Firefighters say they learnt a lot from the Black Summer bushfires, but fear Victorians have become complacent in preparations ahead of this fire season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fccaf6727b3b5a68b220b1fb5f86623b</guid></item><item><title>Khapra beetle, a threat to grains industry, discovered in imported nappy pants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/khapra-beetle-found-in-imported-nappy-pants-threatens-grains/105782306</link><description>Authorities are investigating how khapra beetle, the number-one-priority pest for the grains industry, entered Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c65ef8036bcd15cd64dcb1342bb737aa</guid></item><item><title>Warnings of flash flooding after torrential rain drenches Far North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/weather-warning-rain-far-north-queensland/105783282</link><description>Huge rainfall totals of more than 300 millimetres have taken even rain-hardened Far North Queenslanders by surprise at a typically drier time of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4fd41dcd4db489d39bf56181f35eeaf</guid></item><item><title>Robert Redford's most notable movies with Jane Fonda, Barbra Streisand and Paul Newman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/robert-redford-movies-jane-fonda-barbra-streisand-paul-newman/105782412</link><description>The Hollywood icon leaves a legacy of classic films with a career that stretched over decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a65466a8bed654c5a2f46954d2cfb614</guid></item><item><title>Hawks AFL coach Sam Mitchell reacts to speculation over Zach Merrett meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/afl-sam-mitchell-zach-merrett-hawthorn-hawks-essendon-bombers/105784298</link><description>As his young Hawks squad prepare for their preliminary final against the Cats, Sam Mitchell opens up about the club's pursuit of Bombers captain Zach Merrett.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">862f69660065f08d0572520ae7565aab</guid></item><item><title>Farmer asks partner to marry him with special canola crop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/farmer-asks-partner-to-marry-him-with-canola-crop/105783070</link><description>NSW farmer Will Henderson had no choice but to bide his time to pop the question. In the end his efforts were rewarded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05e5cefa73531016d6c02d243bfa85a7</guid></item><item><title>In Donald Trump's America, questions not to the president's liking are met with hostility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/president-donald-trump-and-hostile-relationship-with-media/105783964</link><description>As America enters a dark tunnel of dangerous internal divisions and an increasingly violent public discourse, Donald Trump is escalating his attacks on many of this nation's institutions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d3fbf6b1e6db2875d16740bdc3f6ed4</guid></item><item><title>Australia's first Aboriginal parliamentarian Neville Bonner commemorated with bronze sculpture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/first-indigenous-parliamentarian-neville-bonner-bronze-sculpture/105784526</link><description>Neville Bonner is honoured as Australia's first Indigenous parliamentarian.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f34625e3694dce1ffe76963cc385cf62</guid></item><item><title>Hasan Piker opens up on Charlie Kirk's death, Donald Trump and Elon Musk's campaign against him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/hasan-piker-speaks-charlie-kirk-death-and-death-threats-trump/105784072</link><description>Prominent left-wing commentator Hasan Piker opens up to 7.30 on Donald Trump's left-wing crackdown, the Charlie Kirk he knew and attempts to have him deplatformed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b7081bd7a10cb144ba6685b100983fa</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout, Torrie Lewis, reach semifinal of 200m at the 2025 World Athletics Championships</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-gout-gout/105784336</link><description>Gout Gout powers home to claim third place in his heat and secure a spot in the 200m semifinals at the World Athletics Championships in Tokyo, after Torrie Lewis ran a PB to reach the semifinals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2bd26af0d05e7b906491f983575b44c</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout, Torrie Lewis, reach semifinal of 200m at the 2025 World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-gout-gout/105784336</link><description>Gout Gout powers home to claim third place in his heat and secure a spot in the 200m semifinals at the World Athletics Championships in Tokyo, after Torrie Lewis ran a PB to reach the semifinals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30386c1b59e0b9ff2526e8b4bc706a4f</guid></item><item><title>European Commission lays out new tariffs and sanctions on Israel over war in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/eu-lays-out-new-tariffs-and-sanctions-on-israel/105786322</link><description>The European Union's executive arm has made a series of proposals aimed at forcing an end to the Israel–Hamas conflict.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcf8968b74aefc70146386449173685e</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout shows class to reach 200m semifinal at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/gout-gout-indication-of-his-class-in-200m-heats-world/105786404</link><description>Gout Gout could have been rattled competing against some of the world's best in the 200m at the World Athletics Championships, but powered through with an assured display beyond his years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6d7f2bf3ba5b9a59022718d9b78e480</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Sussan Ley says Labor's 2035 climate modelling is in 'fantasy land' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/federal-politics-live-september-18/105785620</link><description>The government has released the much-anticipated climate targets for 2035.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbb240b6ed756440d61ce6cf2d9fedbe</guid></item><item><title>Tom Atkins says players are just 'cogs in the machine' for Geelong ahead of AFL finals clash with Hawthorn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/geelong-vs-hawthorn-tom-atkins-on-being-a-cog-in-the-machine/105786768</link><description>Tom Atkins hasn't missed a final since being dropped in the 2020 season, and the midfielder says one mindset helped him accept the heartache of that season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a802e345a2162e1c3058d232c408a238</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill launches LGBTQIA+ festival Rainbow in the Outback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/broken-hill-lgbtqia-festival-rainbow-in-the-outback/105782774</link><description>The outback city of Broken Hill is no stranger to celebrating the LGBTQIA+ community, with a new festival focusing on diversity and inclusion launching last weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cca328c6d304217ca3ecde48d89cfac4</guid></item><item><title>Palliative Care Australia art prize inspires conversations about death and grieving</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/palliative-care-australia-art-prize-helps-process-grief/105763880</link><description>In its fifth year, Palliative Care Australia's Live Well, Die Well national art prize continues to spark important conversations about dying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b336b74532eacba654f9700b7c36e0</guid></item><item><title>Cats coach Chris Scott regrets run-in with AFL staffer after qualifying final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/geelong-cats-chris-scott-afl-staff-qualifying-final/105789664</link><description>Geelong coach Chris Scott says long-held frustration with the AFL was behind his regrettable post-qualifying final win outburst at a junior league employee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64f8afe41599735121373a93d14d1aff</guid></item><item><title>Domestic violence comments on fishing show breached classification rules: ACMA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/domestic-violence-comments-on-channel-seven-in-breach-says-acma/105789254</link><description>An exchange about domestic violence between 'Bush Cook Ranger Nick' and the host of Step Outside with Paul Burt, broadcast on 7mate, was in breach of classification rules, the watchdog has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0793754492a6a1f2c4bb7b9112a6cb41</guid></item><item><title>Roosters hand Victor Radley 10-match ban for bringing NRL club into disrepute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nrl-sydney-roosters-victor-radley-10-match-ban/105790722</link><description>The Sydney Roosters suspend Victor Radley for 10 matches without pay following media revelations he allegedly requested an illegal substance from former teammate Brandon Smith.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0476c9486f857e18734c6e0056795098</guid></item><item><title>Bindi Magic art exhibition opens in Alice Springs as organisation celebrates 25 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/bindi-magic-art-exhibition-opens-in-alice-springs/105789908</link><description>For 25 years Bindi Mwerre Anthurre Artists has been helping people with a disability to communicate through creativity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac6f9add20cd12006d1f874f0c4e4ec</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout, Torrie Lewis miss finals in brilliant 200m semifinal displays at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/live-updates-gout-gout-200m-world-athletics-championships-2025/105789710</link><description>Gout Gout and Torrie Lewis have missed the final of the 200m, both running to a hugely respectable fourth place in their semifinals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd0573ba05c5938664bb57cbe96a6139</guid></item><item><title>UK police make arrests for spying as Lithuanian prosecutors target Russia-linked arson network</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/uk-and-lithuania-target-alleged-russian-spies/105791030</link><description>British and Lithuanian authorities have detained people on suspicion of carrying out intelligence-related activities on behalf of Russia</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ddf2a16d6410fbb83734a321a8f2918</guid></item><item><title>First Guardian, Shield superannuation disasters expose deep flaws in Australia's $4.3 trillion retirement system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/first-guardian-shield-collapse-asic-and-superannuation-flaws/105783328</link><description>The failed First Guardian and Shield schemes have cost about 12,000 Australians more than $1 billion in retirement savings and exposed deep flaws in how Australia's $4.3 trillion superannuation sector is regulated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b80687a0c984dcbca73fbbe0b5a3dbb7</guid></item><item><title>Therapists, patients raise concerns over The Hobart Clinic closure with fears it could be 'dangerous' for some</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/hobart-clinic-therapists-patients-raise-concern-over-closure/105788162</link><description>For more than four decades, The Hobart Clinic has provided private mental health services to clients. Since the announcement of its October closure, clinic staff, therapists and patients have warned of the negative impact on those reliant on the service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fbc511d8b370e60dea926bbab98c0ab</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout's understanding of patience shows World Athletics Championships performance in 200m semifinal won't be one off</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gout-gout-patience-and-time-at-world-athletics-championships/105779054</link><description>Gout Gout's promise and progress are on full display at the 2025 World Athletics Championships. But by showing patience, he could get even better.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c9ef3dbda73df2a2a812697ef7e45b1</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout's understanding of patience shows World Athletics Championships performance in 200m semifinal won't be one off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gout-gout-patience-and-time-at-world-athletics-championships/105779054</link><description>Gout Gout's promise and progress are on full display at the 2025 World Athletics Championships. But by showing patience, he could get even better.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5091c293c2d85d7e3aebae30a5ecf2b5</guid></item><item><title>New Huon Aquaculture head Charles von der Heyde says salmon review followed spread of 'gossip'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/huon-aquaculture-new-ceo-charles-von-der-heyde/105789320</link><description>Huon Aquaculture's new chief executive officer has described the upcoming review of Tasmania's salmon industry as "unnecessary", saying that a pause on expansion would not stop the company's plans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd9a2d49083a01e8bc6ceb46139fee35</guid></item><item><title>Home owners warned to consider 'liveability' of properties amid climate change impact warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/climate-change-impact-on-housing-warning-queensland/105786926</link><description>Property experts say a "dizzying" report forecasting the impacts of worsening climate conditions on Australian properties has sounded a clear warning for the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3721e9130b606a97a1dbc326ef394a9</guid></item><item><title>Market live updates: ASX to rise, Nvidia backs rival Intel, Wall Street rallies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/asx-markets-business-live-news-september-19/105792346</link><description>The Australian share market is set to gain on Friday, after Wall Street's S&amp;P 500 hit a record high. Tech stocks starred as Nvidia invested in rival Intel. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a824ad58cb292f6dfdd5a044e5b3e806</guid></item><item><title>Actress Joan Marion never returned to Tasmania, but 'her heart was always in Launceston'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/tasmanian-actress-joan-marion-maintained-links-to-launceston/105774964</link><description>Tasmania's Joan Marion became a star of the screen and stage abroad; her granddaughter says she maintained a connection to Launceston for much of her life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e512ba130678906d9cf74447a7e0d32</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with performing Nazi salute at Brisbane anti-immigration rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/qld-man-charged-performing-nazi-salute-anti-immigration-rally/105792450</link><description>ABC News made police enquiries after being sent a photo of a man raising his arm in what is alleged to be a Nazi salute at the Brisbane rally on August 31.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">450cdefce4b6278dffcbabbca339d49d</guid></item></channel></rss>