<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 20:55:05 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Social media ban: Families, teens question new access and verification rules — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/social-ban-experts-blog-media-under-16/106118846</link><description>Ten major platforms are now expected to check the ages of all their Australian users and prevent anyone found to be under 16 from holding an account. Our experts have been answering your questions to help clear up confusion around the new access and verification rules. Look back on our live coverage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fda3457cf8713a8cb496b9c238627241</guid></item><item><title>Rare brain illness could not stop Milly from making country netball history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/milly-brock-tongala-netball-encephalitis/106098456</link><description>A rare brain illness left Milly Brock unable to walk or speak, but eight months later, she was back leading her regional netball club on grand final day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">821bba383f0020f9d6f99b0b9a15f322</guid></item><item><title>Houses destroyed in bushfire near St Helens as 'hundreds' flee to evacuation centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/tasmania-st-helens-stieglitz-bushfire-houses-destroyed/106123090</link><description>At least two properties have been destroyed in a bushfire burning near St Helens, on Tasmania's upper east coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13ff35bca8f1bf640e6b0f90c5a6c228</guid></item><item><title>In Data Dreams: Art and AI at the MCA, 10 artists explore the impact of AI on contemporary life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/data-dreams-art-and-ai-mca-sydney-christopher-kulendran-thomas/106115358</link><description>Can you tell what's real and what's fake online? Data Dreams: Art and AI at the MCA, featuring a Kim Kardashian deepfake, looks at the impact of AI on everyday life</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6da8bd58bdbf5d37f5aac827b55e6a1</guid></item><item><title>Dancing gorilla wins Comedy Wildlife Photo Awards 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wildlife-comedy-photo-awards-winners-2025/106123480</link><description>The winning images pair talented nature photography with humour that often relies on capturing a moment at just the right time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50aafd52b8ccb489374be2add3c97440</guid></item><item><title>Wells says 'gut reaction' to travel claims fair but she has 'upheld' rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/anika-wells-gut-reaction-travel-expense-rules/106118512</link><description>Communications and Sports Minister Anika Wells accepts her taxpayer-funded travel claims have prompted a "gut reaction" in people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b44d2a73090ecce02214e2201b1dfe7e</guid></item><item><title>Testing on supermarket imported honey finds some is not all honey</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/testing-finds-some-imported-honey-not-honey/106119344</link><description>Australian beekeepers are funding their own investigation into the authenticity of imported honey, with tests showing other products are being added.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a452fb7b1b2545a83a7b102f3a342b2</guid></item><item><title>Crucial koala corridors are dwindling in Sydney's south-west, conservationists warn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/koala-corridors-under-threat-in-sydney-conservationists-warn/106099774</link><description>Key wildlife links between two of Sydney's major rivers are under threat from land clearing for housing, according to a koala conservation group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f91af6ff105daa364b7ab66152f69f9a</guid></item><item><title>AI to be trialled at Royal Perth Hospital in bid to reduce pressure on WA health system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wa-health-system-turns-to-ai-in-bid-to-free-up-doctors-nurses/106124964</link><description>A trial of artificial intelligence at Royal Perth Hospital is announced in an attempt to help health workers focus on patient care, as new data reveals WA's emergency departments are among the most stretched in the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">916420c5a5be3e9614bebad33b7e6ec3</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste remembers Indonesian invasion 50 years after military assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/timor-leste-invasion-indonesia-anniversary/106118850</link><description>Survivors still have clear memories of the invasion by Indonesia, as Timor-Leste this week commemorates the beginning of a brutal 24-year occupation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb2d22cb023e1625be40a01636cd7005</guid></item><item><title>Taliban arrests young men in Afghanistan for Peaky Blinders dress-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/taliban-arrests-afghan-men-for-peaky-blinders-dress-up/106119104</link><description>Morality police in Afghanistan detain several influencers who have gone viral for dressing up as 1920s gangsters in the style of BBC series Peaky Blinders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b60e2a3095ffcf14564a6d30d3f6b72f</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne nutrition influencer died from postpartum haemorrhage after freebirth, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/stacey-warnecke-free-birth-death-coroner-investigates/106124514</link><description>A coroner's court has heard Melbourne nutrition influencer Stacey Warnecke died from a postpartum haemorrhage following a freebirth in September.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5cfcb104032fdb91e4e566b5242f6c8</guid></item><item><title>CFS firefighter Peter Curtis's 'great courage' remembered at funeral service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/cfs-firefighter-peter-curtis-remembered-at-funeral-service/106123650</link><description>Peter Curtis, who died at a bushfire ground on SA's Eyre Peninsula last month, has been remembered as a loving husband, father and grandfather, and a firefighter who "led from the front" and was a "bloody good bloke to have around".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4caa694bc7bc38cedf0419b7e3011d0</guid></item><item><title>Stieglitz residents stay to defend homes amid bushfire near St Helens on Tasmania's east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/st-helens-stieglitz-locals-praise-community-spirit-bushfires/106124180</link><description>As a bushfire rages on Tasmania's east coast, bayside resident Paul Worsteling shelters in his car, charging his phone while saltwater rains down on the roof.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">becb31f702320a39f9b429aefcc7cad1</guid></item><item><title>From peacekeeping in Timor-Leste to PTSD in Afghanistan: The beauty and terror of being an official war artist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/being-an-official-war-artist/106074572</link><description>Australia has been sending artists to the frontline since World War I, with more than 50 local artists taking part since then. But what's it actually like to head into war armed with a paintbrush?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0869c324d87322e512f070bec50429fd</guid></item><item><title>WA opposition blames police staffing levels for slow response to Boulder ambulance emergency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wa-opposition-blames-police-numbers-for-slow-ambulance-response/106119620</link><description>The WA Liberals say a slow police response to a violent incident involving St John Ambulance officers in the Goldfields is due to understaffing but the claim has been rejected by the police minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89a501a2552c0abb67b6dad738e4d227</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's bushfire danger arrived suddenly. Here's how to prepare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/tasmania-bushfire-preparation-explainer-what-to-do/106125742</link><description>Tasmania's bushfire season has suddenly arrived, with two catastrophes within days of each other. Here is how to prepare if one comes your way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b16253a54f55c77704f587d31bb4f7d</guid></item><item><title>Halls Creek man arrested after allegedly selling $45k worth of alcohol in dry WA communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/halls-creek-alcohol-sly-grogging-money-laundering-charge/106126488</link><description>The man allegedly bought large quantities of beer, champagne and rum in Darwin before selling it in WA's Kimberley region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2051a7f7ce917ea09a9f94d88ea4d89</guid></item><item><title>Victim statements redacted in 2014 fatal SA freeway crash court hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/south-eastern-freeway-fatal-crash-victim-impact-statements/106126356</link><description>The daughters of a man who died in a truck crash at the bottom of the South-Eastern Freeway in 2014 have their heavily redacted victim impact statements read aloud in court, more than 11 years after their father died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1dc19e37a9e8742d452e5c79fcaebad</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of men march against domestic violence in Alice Springs on Human Rights Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/hundreds-of-men-march-against-domestic-violence-alice-springs-/106126534</link><description>Up to 300 men — and a similar number of women — have taken part in the annual Ingkintja Men's March Against Domestic Violence under the slogan End the silence! Stop the violence! in Alice Springs, coinciding with the International Human Rights Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afb9de3eaad61b077c62d7b9feab54d1</guid></item><item><title>New order banning supply of NSW North Coast green prawns a 'death knell' for industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/five-year-ban-on-nsw-raw-prawn-supply-due-to-white-spot-disease/106123412</link><description>White spot disease in prawns has led the NSW government to issue a new, five-year control order which will ban the sale of green prawns caught in affected waters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49297718e7446a4d6c754181c2e15c1d</guid></item><item><title>New crocodile management plan draws mixed response in north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/north-queenslanders-split-over-new-crocodile-management-plan/106125448</link><description>The new management plan sees the expansion of crocodile removal zones across north and far north Queensland. Some say it will not increase safety without better community education.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d527c03e914a223eb5eb665d7dd0aa2</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106127258</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e85aeff20efe1d71f9c55706e4551a44</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne expect to land former number one AFLW draft pick Kristie-Lee Weston-Turner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/north-melbourne-aflw-former-number-one-pick/106127740</link><description>North Melbourne have been unable to trade for Kristie-Lee Weston-Turner but the two-time defending AFLW premiers are still confident they'll secure the former number one draft pick.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ea6b8b1cac99bb7b87d916611cd573f</guid></item><item><title>Cambodia pulls team out of Thailand's Southeast Asian Games over border conflict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/cambodia-withdraws-atheletes-southeast-asian-games-thailand/106127382</link><description>Cambodia withdraws its team from the Southeast Asian Games in Thailand for safety reasons, as a border conflict between the two neighbours rages for a third day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7945fa312f967c8741bb7b2e62a2856f</guid></item><item><title>Climate crisis is threatening disabled Australians' access to nature</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/climate-crisis-access-to-nature-disability/106116294</link><description>From bushfires and decreasing air quality to flooding and erosion, climate change is threatening our relationship with nature, and people with disability are being disproportionately impacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e6030aecdfc7bd4bfb090bffc4c8061</guid></item><item><title>Inquest into toddler's septic tank death sparks calls for improved maintenance in remote NT public housing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/septic-tank-death-kumanjayi-fly-public-housing-coronial-inquest/106118886</link><description>Aboriginal housing advocates are calling for urgent improvements to the way remote public housing is maintained in the Northern Territory, after the coroner found the death of a toddler who fell into a backyard septic tank could have been prevented.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">caec77585ea2e595da2a95f4e9e2f192</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire survivors tell their stories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/bushfire-survivors-tell-their-stories/106127052</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f9198ace2ad8d8c040b9d805abdc884</guid></item><item><title>Australia records highest number of Indigenous deaths in custody since 1979</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/largest-number-of-indigenous-deaths-in-custody-since-1979/106121828</link><description>Australia has recorded the highest number of Indigenous deaths in custody since 1979. Experts say over-incarceration remains a national crisis and prisons are neglecting the physical and mental health of vulnerable people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beaf475b8b27faa178ef96c69cf1409b</guid></item><item><title>Marco Rubio orders US State Department to revert to Times New Roman font, calling Calibri adoption 'wasteful'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/us-state-department-reverts-times-new-roman-font/106127732</link><description>In a leaked internal cable, Secretary of State Marco Rubio calls the department's decision to adopt Calibri in 2023 a "wasteful" diversity move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f98705a0075c776b00b9cb6290441f9</guid></item><item><title>US backs Japan in dispute with China over radar incident as tensions escalate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/us-backs-japan-in-dispute-with-china-over-radar-incident/106128020</link><description>China and Japan have given differing accounts of the incident, which was a major escalation in tensions between the two nations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f7c862084fd730289846293bc733530</guid></item><item><title>Nearly 200 children conceived from sperm donor with increased cancer risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/children-conceived-from-sperm-with-cancer-risk/106128026</link><description>Between 2006 and 2022, the man's sperm was sold to 67 clinics in 14 countries, whereas 99 children were fathered by the donor in Denmark alone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cd952c66ea268a278bb59c7d05297ca</guid></item><item><title>Half a million people flee Thailand–Cambodia border conflict as Trump moves to intervene again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/half-a-million-people-flee-thailand-cambodia-border-conflict/106128158</link><description>Thailand has rejected Donald Trump's plan to call both sides to achieve peace, with half a million people forced to flee the fighting along the border.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2187d0404028679ddc4bb7ef75216c4e</guid></item><item><title>Sophie Kinsella, author of the best-selling Shopaholic novels, dies at 55</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/sophie-kinsella-author-of-shopaholic-book-series-dies-aged-55/106128174</link><description>Kinsella, who also published under her real name, Madeleine Wickham, announced in April 2024 that she had been diagnosed in late 2022 with glioblastoma, an aggressive form of brain cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5df3ad8902d66540f2d3c6b1a47afb4</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 11: How a van full of armed men and millions of dollars inspired Goodfellas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/today-in-history-december-11-lufthansa-heist/106116722</link><description>It has been almost 50 years since armed men burst into the Lufthansa cargo terminal at New York's John F Kennedy International Airport and got away with stealing millions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa60e0fd4333897c002bc02951aff74a</guid></item><item><title>Landmark case aims to force betting agencies to return gambled stolen millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/case-seeks-to-recover-gambled-stolen-millions-from-bookmakers/106127214</link><description>A landmark legal case against three of Australia's biggest online betting agencies has been filed in the Federal Court, aimed at recovering millions of dollars' worth of stolen money that was gambled away and kept by corporate bookmakers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdbffe5eb41d9639002ebac899132190</guid></item><item><title>Nationals MP's high family travel bill highlights generous rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/nationals-mps-high-family-travel-bill-highlights-generous-rules/106126842</link><description>Calls for politicians' family travel entitlements to be tightened are growing, as analysis shows one Nationals MP was allowed to charge taxpayers more than $80,000 to fly his spouse to and from Canberra 27 times in two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7e02c292ccefc5d6bca00c1bf777cbb</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's bushfires may be an indication of what's to come this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tasmania-summer-bushfire-drivers-and-outlook-bom/106126762</link><description>Just days into summer, Tasmania is battling bushfires and their presence can be linked back to a rare spike in temperatures above Antarctica back in September.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc7f21634c642fd281ef2a19b45bb506</guid></item><item><title>Third time is the charm as long-running soap opera Neighbours wraps up, again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tv-neighbours-ends-again/106127164</link><description>After more than 40 years on air, the final credits will roll on the iconic soap Neighbours — again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9294b4c1ba5afc18d168fbb6beb71c5a</guid></item><item><title>NSW government acquires two outback stations to convert into national parks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/corinya-and-tasman-stations-to-be-converted-into-national-parks/106125500</link><description>Two outback stations 800 kilometres west of Sydney are purchased by the state government in an effort to protect the environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e08563b4690939a2d3bb0a924a889be</guid></item><item><title>Australia's education system 'highly segregated' says former minister Susan Close</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/susan-close-on-socio-economic-divide-in-schools/106126084</link><description>South Australia's former deputy premier Susan Close has called out what she describes as "extreme" socio-economic segregation in Australian schools.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0a681652a4d06ad13dadca8a80d4be4</guid></item><item><title>Australia's grand social media experiment is finally live. Teens say nothing has changed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/social-media-ban-under-16s-day-one/106120020</link><description>After a year of waiting, Australia's world-leading laws to block kids from accessing social media are officially enacted. But the teens they're meant to impact say not much has actually changed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">605110735879eabae4a76f4e3ea6f4d8</guid></item><item><title>Australia's strategic fleet tender stalls amid growing maritime vulnerabilities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/delay-in-national-marine-strategic-fleet/106121772</link><description>Australia's long-promised strategic fleet tender is delayed, raising concerns over the nation's maritime resilience and skills pipeline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">734021665b72b27a2e31f4fa3009b052</guid></item><item><title>Fears of 'another Cronulla riot' 20 years on from violence at beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/fears-of-another-cronulla-riot-20-years-on-from-sydney-fights/106120526</link><description>Two decades on from the racially-fuelled brawls at Cronulla, experts warn something similar could happen amid anti-immigration rhetoric.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">530eb8b1f8a7882b31e610972e8f7881</guid></item><item><title>National Library of Australia reveals its treasures with exhibition showcasing books from throughout history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/national-library-australia-exhibition-reveals-treasures/106126192</link><description>The NLA has more than 10 million items, but they are all in storage. Now a new exhibition reveals a selection of its hidden treasures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">225fb88ccc28e7fd81c2aa21f6d60d91</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka adamant 'Battle of the Sexes' clash against Nick Kyrgios will help women's tennis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tennis-aryna-sabalenka-nick-kyrgios-defend-polarising-match/106128302</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka is adamant her upcoming clash against Nick Kyrgios will not prove to be a gimmick that damages women's tennis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4923bb3d0bc8d79da189a795d6da956</guid></item><item><title>Cabinet ministers debate whether gas reservation plan can cut power prices as hoped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/gas-reservation-power-price-fears/106125184</link><description>A long-awaited scheme to force east coast energy giants to set aside gas for Australian use is being finalised in down-to-the-wire negotiations between half a dozen cabinet ministers grappling with concerns it may not lower prices as much as hoped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">863c406b91f7e9e36fe01e9992b3f2b5</guid></item><item><title>National Anti-Corruption Commission chief updates official declaration of interests to disclose defence link</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/nacc-chief-updates-official-declaration/106126738</link><description>National Anti-Corruption Commission chief Paul Brereton formally discloses his consulting work for the defence watchdog after the ABC reveals the links.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d086faaba53f92740d46dcb677157195</guid></item><item><title>'Zombie-proof' EV ad tops complaints list as social media cases rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/the-most-complained-about-ads-of-2025/106105394</link><description>As more businesses look to do their own advertising, audience complaints for social media ads are growing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3859fe975c24dd1d54d1615daa78299f</guid></item><item><title>Seasonal conditions lead to supersized strawberries in Australian stores</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/supersized-large-stawberries-in-australia/106120026</link><description>Seasonal conditions are leading to big berries this summer, with the fruit on the larger side in some regions because of a wetter spring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f94adb5d206a0c79c684f67387fce243</guid></item><item><title>US seizes oil tanker off coast of Venezuela, Donald Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/us-seizes-oil-tanker-off-coast-of-venezuela/106128382</link><description>US President Donald Trump says the tanker is "the largest one ever seized".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df8042715ed4912de309799be119c949</guid></item><item><title>Murray River water thieves hit with $558,000 fine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/david-littore-jindalee-road-wines-water-theft/106124764</link><description>Jindalee Road Wines and its former manager have been penalised $558,000 for illegally tapping into an irrigation pipeline and stealing water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d3c35e88314dc643b4f56233b142cd3</guid></item><item><title>From stacking supermarkets to 'chairman of everything', David Gonski exits uni leadership job</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/education-figure-david-gonski-retires-interview-on-education/106124520</link><description>Best known for his review into schools funding, David Gonski feels optimistic about the future of education in Australia, despite the growing challenges posed by AI and funding pressures on universities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fca3e751b522dce04afc6baf6012d4b</guid></item><item><title>Federal Court hears bid from Regis Resources to overturn protection order that stopped McPhillamys Gold Mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/regis-resources-bid-overturn-nsw-gold-mine-protection-order/106123596</link><description>Regis Resources argues the federal environment department was "uncritical" in accepting evidence about a First Nations Dreaming story that led to its proposed gold project being halted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d92a43c5ba9086c9d1d582cb8395d195</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi Islands become 700,000-hectare Indigenous Protected Area under federal agreement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/nt-tiwi-islands-becomes-indigenous-protected-area-ipa/106126788</link><description>The agreement with the federal government sees the Tiwi Islands included in Australia's national parks and reserves system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15956b1a0b81e5bb1868c3a086c4fabd</guid></item><item><title>Woman dies in house fire in Elizabeth Vale</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/72yo-woman-dies-in-house-fire-at-elizabeth-vale/106128448</link><description>Firefighters called to a large blaze at a house in Adelaide's north find the body of a 72-year-old woman inside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51bd4799c12a205ab70616c7a016b96f</guid></item><item><title>Flare activated in residential backyard during extreme bushfire warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/flare-fire-resident-geraldton/106102690</link><description>A woman in WA's Midwest says she found a lit flare in her backyard in the early hours of the morning during extreme bushfire conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1587f0c3e44c2d84c39dda8e78948c4c</guid></item><item><title>Threat eases from Stieglitz bushfire near St Helens on Tasmania's east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tasmania-st-helens-stieglitz-fire-threat-eases-road-reopening/106128334</link><description>Firefighters have reopened access for residents of a bushfire-struck community on Tasmania's east coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">771055f203fc1c8421dd97504bd5a741</guid></item><item><title>Half Big Brother, half late-night talk show: The WNBA stars revolutionising sports media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/wnba-studbudz-natisha-hiedeman-courtney-williams-sport-marketing/106090546</link><description>The WNBA's 'StudBudz' are using live streaming to build a brand and community, while providing lessons in marketing women's sports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cd56cfc0c9fbc505e1e9c6f24777a14</guid></item><item><title>Nicole Kidman to co-chair Met Gala with Beyoncé, Venus Williams and Anna Wintour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/nicole-kidman-beyonce-venus-williams-chair-met-gala/106128614</link><description>The museum also announced a gala host committee, chaired by designer Anthony Vaccarello and filmmaker Zoë Kravitz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eac6c7a5126cc2aca138e618c40905d8</guid></item><item><title>US authorities seize Venezuela oil tanker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/us-authorities-seize-venezuela-oil-tanker/106128742</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a31913eac113556360db67ab47e0eaf7</guid></item><item><title>Superannuation giant HESTA hit with extra licence restrictions as APRA raises governance, risk concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/super-fund-hesta-hit-with-extra-conditions-apra-governance-risk/106128664</link><description>APRA says the fallout of HESTA's planned outage led to a "severe, prolonged disruption" that caused direct harm to some of its 1.1 million members, in a damning assessment of the fund.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35554f5c84bc7088fdb2609c8d5613dc</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood employee resigns after alcohol-fuelled incident at Alice Springs training camp</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/afl-collingwood-employee-resigns-alcohol-fuelled-incident/106128612</link><description>A Collingwood employee hands in his resignation following an incident on an interstate trip that required an investigation by the club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21f893a5d3a036c1e738cb694cfb4f8b</guid></item><item><title>This Grand Designs Australia house cost $320k to build. Here's how its owners pulled it off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/grand-designs-cheap-house-320k-how-couple-did-it/106102674</link><description>Bespoke architectural builds on small budgets may seem like an impossible housing dream, but James and Rita managed to turn their vision into a reality — without breaking the bank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1959b70829d84196ecd189375f3325da</guid></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology makes major changes to $96.5m website after refresh backlash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/weather-bureau-updates-new-website-after-critisicm/106128956</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology has updated the rain radar, temperature information and warning displays on its new website in response to public feedback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b3801ebd5ac3764a1b79ef836e78a63</guid></item><item><title>Aussie travellers who criticise US most at risk as Trump administration proposes social media disclosures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/us-travel-social-media-privacy-concerns/106128910</link><description>Australians travelling to the United States could soon face an unprecedented invasion of privacy, an international law expert has warned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61166d67d8b553711c2276287271feff</guid></item><item><title>Italian cooking and its rituals get United Nations designation as World Heritage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/italian-cooking-and-rituals-recognised-by-unesco/106129504</link><description>Already loved around the world for its palate-pleasing tastes, UNESCO has now added the rituals surrounding Italian food preparation and consumption to its list of the world's traditional practices and expressions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ed96ff5eeafa5a64158ddeaafd999c</guid></item><item><title>Iceland becomes fifth country to boycott Eurovision 2026 over Israeli participation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/iceland-not-participating-in-eurovison-2026/106128592</link><description>Iceland has joined Ireland, the Netherlands, Spain and Slovenia in boycotting the competition in protest against Israel's participation in the song contest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">202f76c005b4117588c215f1ac71821b</guid></item><item><title>AC Milan Serie A Perth soccer game in serious doubt amid FIFA roadblock</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/ac-milan-serie-a-perth-soccer-game-in-trouble-rita-saffioti-fifa/106129592</link><description>Plans to host seven-time European champions AC Milan in Perth for an Italian league game are in trouble, with growing concerns soccer's global governing body will not sign off on the event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4f29263e2e479f6c6974d076a7c091f</guid></item><item><title>PM distances himself from politician spending rules amid Anika Wells controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/pm-distances-himself-from-politician-spending-rules-anika-wells/106130760</link><description>Pressed on whether his government should review the rules that allow politicians to fly their families around the country in business class, the prime minister says his focus is on the social media ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">daea64309046e0955b2f7c7122665131</guid></item><item><title>States lash Commonwealth's revised public hospital funding offer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/albanese-offers-extra-funding-for-public-hospitals/106130754</link><description>The prime minister wrote to states and territories this week, upping the Commonwealth's offer for public hospital funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81a7feea6b061580a3e2b8c23982ed32</guid></item><item><title>The Golden Spurtle takes audiences into the heart of the World Porridge Making Championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/the-golden-spurtle-porridge-making-championship-documentary/106118710</link><description>Every year, the Scottish town of Carrbridge hosts a porridge competition. Its contestants and chieftain are larger than life and celebrated in the new Aussie documentary The Golden Spurtle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12ad0434302f24dc80fd695083ecdc14</guid></item><item><title>The two Navy officers breaking ground, heading towards Winter Paralympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/navy-officers-breaking-ground-towards-winter-paralympics/106126742</link><description>It has been 20 years since Australia sent a biathlete to the Winter Paralympics, but two serving Navy personnel are hoping to change this.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51d23b79d9fb3944846f47d09d70d0b7</guid></item><item><title>Coalition agrees to sweeping changes to NSW workers' compensation scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/workers-compensation-scheme-changes-coalition-kellie-sloane/106129434</link><description>NSW Opposition Leader Kellie Sloane says changes to the state's workers' compensation scheme are an important "reset".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7bc0b41a8aaabca09dc7bc682b92037</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic science and logistics given $208m federal funding boost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/antarctic-science-and-logistics-given-208-million-funding-boost/106130794</link><description>The federal government has announced more than $200 million in additional funding over the next seven years for Antarctic science and logistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec45dc9da2fbe532cb1d7bb4cc378f8f</guid></item><item><title>Australian hooker Harry Grant awarded rugby league Golden Boot for 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/harry-grant-golden-boot-australia-dylan-brown/106131732</link><description>New Zealand's Dylan Brown seemed a certainty to claim the Golden Boot as rugby league's best international player for 2025 but the Kiwi five-eighth has missed out in a stunning twist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6805ac76cd4379fd23324a09498cabc3</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government moves to lift ban on political donations from property developers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/political-donations-qld-property-developers/106130862</link><description>The attorney-general said the proposed laws would level the political playing field, labelling the ban as a "gerrymander" by the former Labor government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c49306a158c5f48a15cc52eee8051bcc</guid></item><item><title>SA algal bloom testing shows positive signs ahead of peak summer temperatures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/positive-signs-amid-algal-bloom-monitoring/106131392</link><description>Authorities say the "best signs" in a "long time" have been observed in the latest round of monitoring of the state's algal bloom crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f43189df2fdae26a1fc3f1a9c4713c41</guid></item><item><title>China's huge trade surplus shows Trump failed to tame Beijing's export juggernaut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/china-trade-surplus-tariffs-beijing-donald-trump-global-economy/106130778</link><description>China's record breaking one trillion-dollar trade surplus shows Trump's tariffs have done little to tame Beijing's export juggernaut. In fact, they might have turbocharged it instead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52ab115a4db0a42fa89da402d0849146</guid></item><item><title>Two bushfires downgraded from emergency warnings in Bullsbrook and Kenwick in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/kenwick-wattle-grove-maddington-beckenham-bushfire/106132334</link><description>Fires in the city's north-east and south-east are downgraded to watch and act levels, while lives and homes remain possibly under threat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">601d34af889bff85be5f7ef21eb19da6</guid></item><item><title>Tom Silvagni revealed as man from high-profile Victorian family convicted of rape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tom-silvagni-identified-as-man-found-guilty-of-rape/106129488</link><description>Tom Silvagni, the son of Carlton Football Club great Stephen Silvagni, can now be identified as the man last week found guilty of raping a woman in 2024, after a court lifted a restriction on publishing his name.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">751f404865b43c78142d4e1039955304</guid></item><item><title>Six-ingredient rocky road is perfect for last-minute Christmas prep - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/easy-milk-chocolate-rocky-road-with-pretzels-peanuts-licorice/105748720</link><description>This milk chocolate rocky road is easy to make. It creates 12 large slices, perfect for gifting or dessert if you're bringing a plate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cdd96d64ada5a866ca3dab538b13228</guid></item><item><title>Motherhood and sport 'can co-exist': AOC offers cash incentives for Olympian mums</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/motherhood-and-sport-can-co-exist-olympic-funding-alyce-wood/106130494</link><description>The Australian Olympic Committee hopes to keep more athletes in sport by offering cash incentives for women who return after having children, and tens of thousands of dollars for retiring Olympians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3f91d46921c6acb74f8b555d5e5839e</guid></item><item><title>Barry O'Farrell expected to return as Wests Tigers chairman 10 days after shock sacking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/barry-ofarrell-wests-tigers-chairman-return-ceo/106132934</link><description>The boardroom dramas at Wests Tigers take another turn with Barry O'Farrell and multiple other ousted independent directors expected to return to the club at the NRL's demand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f582a4d420f02eb4105d1d3ed8715d1b</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106132750</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12df59ada546783e55ba420b144dc6d4</guid></item><item><title>NACC chief Brereton's claim recusal 'unnecessary' openly disputed by his deputies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/brereton-nacc-deputies-dispute-recusal-unnecessary/106131710</link><description>The National Anti-Corruption Commission's chief personally drafted lines in a media release saying his recusal from defence cases was "unnecessary". His deputies have publicly disagreed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cae8f4ef1ed66eddb7c09281bb69cf2c</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers defend Tanya Plibersek's part protection of McPhillamys mine site from development</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/court-hears-sensitive-dreaming-story-halted-mcphillamys-mine/106129606</link><description>Lawyers for former federal environment minister Tanya Plibersek have defended the Commonwealth's acceptance of the Blue Banded Bee Dreaming to protect part of a gold mine site from development.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65830e06d72c3debf4dc2c4804e44158</guid></item><item><title>Regulator 'disappointed' over Tasmanian salmon industry's antibiotic plan, emails show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/tas-regulator-salmon-company-at-odds-over-antibiotic-rollout/106133156</link><description>A salmon company gave Tasmanian authorities a week's notice before it planned to start using a new antibiotic in the state's waterways to combat a disease outbreak, sparking a strong rebuke from the industry regulator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe49df76809cdcb291c6661fc8992caf</guid></item><item><title>Gas company Beetaloo Energy clears final hurdle for fracking in the Beetaloo Basin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/beetaloo-energy-australia-final-investment-decision/106131964</link><description>Major global oil and gas companies are expressing "serious interest" in the Beetaloo Basin for the first time, one analyst says, now that Beetaloo Energy has reached a final investment decision and committed to developing its fracking project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8f88b833f4900ab198fa1aad2f73766</guid></item><item><title>Living seawalls bringing life back into harbours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/living-seawalls-bringing-life-back-into-harbours-/106132946</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0f91ef051c3f6e980bd8c742b12c6fd</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Sweeney on her role as boxer Christy Martin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/sydney-sweeney-on-her-role-as-boxer-christy-martin/106132960</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5213004b483816fd8283c7d2a5068318</guid></item><item><title>More than 3,000 aged care patients stuck in hospital beds, new national figures show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/aged-care-patients-stuck-in-hospital-beds/106123998</link><description>State health ministers had their final meeting of the year with their federal counterpart on Friday armed with figures showing a 25 per cent increase in just three months of aged care patients stranded in hospitals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c03287d6958c33610fb0a30c5858954</guid></item><item><title>NATO chief Mark Rutte tells allies: 'We are Russia's next target'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/nato-chief-warns-allies-they-are-russia-s-next-target/106133866</link><description>Mark Rutte said Moscow could be ready to use military force against NATO in five years, adding Europe should be prepared for war comparable to what "our grandparents and great-grandparents endured".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">321984e9b2339427483c5b69928b0aea</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar army bombs hospital in Rakhine state killing at least 31 people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/myanmar-junta-bombs-hospital-in-rakhine-state-killing-31-people/106133832</link><description>The latest strike reportedly killed multiple members of the same family and a months-old infant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2ad33947bedae1ccd83360aaeba6e5a</guid></item><item><title>TIME magazine names 'The Architects of AI' as 2025 Person of the Year, confirming leak to betting markets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/time-person-of-the-year-2025-announcement-ai-architects/106133986</link><description>The magazine cites the tremendous technological advances made by the artificial intelligence industry over the past year in bringing on the age of "thinking machines".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abeef511c965985fc244ffdf6bc99599</guid></item><item><title>Alleged co-owners of Goa nightclub Birch by Romeo Lane detained in Thailand following fire that killed 25 people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/brothers-detained-in-thailand-after-deadly-goa-nightclub-fire/106134092</link><description>The blaze killed 25 people, with authorities arresting six other people in the case so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b06cd0c0e475e73175c7102ebe16889e</guid></item><item><title>Amnesty International report finds Hamas committed crimes against humanity with October 7 attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/amnesty-report-accuses-hamas-of-crimes-against-humanity/106133834</link><description>Amnesty's investigation finds Hamas's crimes against humanity included murder, extermination, imprisonment, torture, rape and other inhumane acts, including during its time holding more than 250 people hostage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dd2a0d4486d2093112de32eb07b2b26</guid></item><item><title>Trump's oil tanker seizure raises questions about potential Venezuela blockade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/venezuela-donald-trump-foreign-policy-oil-tanker-seizure/106130650</link><description>Donald Trump's assertions on foreign policy since his return to the White House have literally stretched from one end of the Western Hemisphere to the other.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d842a6a85a3696c7316e477f68d4ab6</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 12: Australian dollar floated amid financial chaos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/today-in-history-december-12-floating-the-dollar/106131892</link><description>It was a pivotal moment in the nation's history, forever changing the way we were governed and the way in which we interacted with the rest of the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd71ceb4b77b3d734f62bf79dd415dcc</guid></item><item><title>NSW guidelines proposed to prevent hospitals from refusing abortion care based on personal beliefs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/document-reveals-plan-to-limit-blocking-of-abortions/106091562</link><description>Hospital managers and executives in NSW will be barred from blocking abortions because of moral and religious views, according to a document obtained by the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3d3062cf75f3a97bc05383490ea6084</guid></item><item><title>After opposing the Coalition's 'robo' NDIS reforms, Labor accused of going down similar path</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/ican-ndis-planning-system-creating-deja-vu/106116170</link><description>The finer details of a new NDIS planning system are yet to be finalised, but it's already drawing comparisons to failed Coalition-era reforms, write Nas Campanella and Evan Young.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c59b3bf4ebdd059df618b5e2606e4e58</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Racing Club under fire as members allege conflicts of interest and governance failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/brisbane-racing-club-members-allege-conflicts-of-interest/106132016</link><description>Members of Queensland's richest horse racing club are demanding answers after they discovered its former chairman struck a lucrative deal with the developer of its luxury residential precinct while he had oversight of the $850 million project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2322f470081bf0736f0df8942416368d</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's social media ban is bold reform, but it will take years to judge its real success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/teen-social-media-ban-albanese-government-david-coleman/106129676</link><description>Parents will thank the government for giving them more agency in dealing with the social media issue but kids aren't voters and it is hard to see the issue deciding votes either way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ba9b0802fb9c08f9a407ad1c8f7fc8c</guid></item><item><title>Bendigo Writers Festival council report recommends one-year hiatus amid reputational damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/bendigo-writers-festival-council-report-recommends-one-year-off/106130278</link><description>Council officers recommend a one-year hiatus for the Bendigo Writers Festival to work on repairing the reputation of the event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">306011983281fc9bdfa5556f1412eaf9</guid></item><item><title>Labor tries to end Ashton Hurn's 'honeymoon' early</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/ashton-hurn-state-election-honeymoon/106131140</link><description>Only days after taking her party's top job, Liberal leader Ashton Hurn is under pressure on a key election promise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd3b1f568f6ebc41c5f0a0db8e74e9db</guid></item><item><title>Bathurst mother Emma Mason's advocacy for social media ban piques interests of global leaders and media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/emma-mason-reflects-on-tilly-legacy-social-media-ban-australia/106116832</link><description>Bathurst mother and lawyer Emma Mason's advocacy for Australia's social media ban has always been in honour of her late daughter, Tilly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">365bf04a741bb8fe7551d2415fe34461</guid></item><item><title>Calls for vending machines in hospitals after women denied period products</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/women-denied-period-products-in-hospital/106121588</link><description>When Samantha Bruce got her period in hospital she wasn't able to get a pad or tampon. She says the response left her feeling "small and dehumanised".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8843f9f4fe4254b5fb036f3785f37d54</guid></item><item><title>How schools of excellence are changing the future of girls rugby league in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/qld-rugby-league-girls-school-of-excellence/106125352</link><description>A growing rugby league excellence program is helping change the future of Queensland girls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b310cf7908a68687ea21ed87a25ad3e8</guid></item><item><title>Landlords eligible for $3,500 rebates for putting rooftop solar on rentals under Queensland scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/queensland-landlord-renters-rooftop-solar-scheme-rebates/106131208</link><description>The $26 million pre-election commitment from the LNP is estimated by the government to save 6,500 households around $700 on energy bills, with applications opening on Friday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2f9d58591b92e12f616cee8f282142b</guid></item><item><title>How 'snakeheads' are redirecting illegal migration from China toward Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/chinese-nationals-walking-the-routes-to-australia-boat-explained/106124082</link><description>Recent boat arrivals in Western Australia offer a glimpse into how routes through South-East Asia, particularly Indonesia, are being used to reach Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96570f64d21f4ef9f4cbcb03f5bb70d6</guid></item><item><title>Why the football Dylan Brown showed for New Zealand can make his record-breaking move to Newcastle pay off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/dylan-brown-golden-boot-newcastle-knights-contract/106126952</link><description>The football Dylan Brown played for New Zealand should have won him the Golden Boot but it could also be the key to his record-breaking move to Newcastle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b66459bac729932c38199a2ed35baba1</guid></item><item><title>Australian rare earth processing plant to be ready for use in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/rare-earth-processing-facility-mining-south-australia/106123882</link><description>The processing market is dominated by China, but Australia is building its capabilities in an attempt to boost the domestic industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76cd3cd1ea5800ec9707c1a72f6776cd</guid></item><item><title>States and territories reject Commonwealth public hospital funding offer — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/federal-politics-live-blog-dec-12/106134352</link><description>States and territories have rejected a public hospital funding offer from the federal government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e473ad0ef6aac29b4fbaefd35a9388e1</guid></item><item><title>Police Commissioner Grant Stevens appointed to Adelaide Football Club board</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/police-commissioner-grant-stevens-joins-adelaide-crows-board/106133692</link><description>South Australia's top cop has taken on an extra role, joining the Adelaide Football Club's board of directors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09e93f9c48e604eb3ccb6fcdbd02e0c3</guid></item><item><title>Perth Scorchers into WBBL final as Beth Mooney continues sparkling form to down Sydney Sixers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/cricket-beth-mooney-stars-scorchers-into-wbbl-final/106134414</link><description>Sydney Sixers keeper Alyssa Healy misses a glorious chance to dismiss Beth Mooney, and the Aussie left-hander makes her pay big-time with a sparkling innings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f23135c1ee0b7703fe9b9e8aea71299</guid></item><item><title>Markets live update: ANZ to defend legal action by former boss over $13.5m in lost bonuses, ASX rises — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/asx-markets-business-live-news-dec-12/106134504</link><description>Former ANZ chief executive Shayne Elliott is suing the bank for stripping him of $13.5 million in bonuses. Local stocks rallied on Friday after the Dow hit new records in a mixed session for Wall Street overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22dd22fa432152c61a1dc4190fa94df3</guid></item><item><title>Independent wholesaler cautiously welcomes review into outback food subsidy scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/outback-food-subsidy-scheme-review-cautiously-welcomed/106090748</link><description>A wholesaler hopes a review of a controversial outback food subsidy scheme will be independent and transparent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec8ea28f6aa649b62bc6717d5ff7ee0c</guid></item><item><title>After 40 years of plot twists and drama, Neighbours wraps up for the last time — again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/neighbours-finale-recap/106133684</link><description>Relive the highlights, such as they were, in the final episode of Neighbours, which went to air last night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66d77596370f9dcb56e3473c4c20e070</guid></item><item><title>Demersal fishing ban leaves industry 'drowning' as mental health concerns rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/fishing-industry-drowning-in-emotional-toll-of-dermersal-ban/106109302</link><description>WA fishers are raising concerns about a lack of mental health support as the commercial industry comes to terms with a ban on demersal fishing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">780356866a5457fda1599f1fb8e408ed</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says land strikes on Venezuela drug shipments coming soon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/us-ready-to-seize-ships-venezuelan-oil-tankers/106134498</link><description>Donald Trump says the US will soon strike drug shipments making their way from Venezuela on land, amid a large-scale military build-up in the southern Caribbean to increase pressure on Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3988de499dfa17007965f95e974b24e4</guid></item><item><title>FIFA World Cup ticket prices leave fans fuming and claiming 'monumental betrayal'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/football-fifa-world-cup-ticket-prices-fans-monumental-betrayal/106134502</link><description>A fans organisation lashes out at "extortionate" prices for tickets at next year's FIFA World Cup despite claims from the footballing body that the tournament would be affordable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c4f63a7a6a402c846bff82d5660abb8</guid></item><item><title>Record-breaking crocodile Cassius taxidermied for Green Island exhibit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/world-record-crocodile-cassius-taxidermied-new-exhibit/106131178</link><description>The world's largest crocodile in captivity until its death last year is going on display in Far North Queensland, as more findings are revealed about its cause of death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">733169fd9a429b9ff1e0b26e8fc099d4</guid></item><item><title>Hailstorm batters western NSW as homes destroyed in bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/storm-fire-cause-damage-nsw/106134570</link><description>Hailstorms have damaged homes in parts of western NSW as the cost of nearby bushfires continues to mount.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07dafe09ecc5e0e93c29e90d78c2a495</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne's West Gate Tunnel to open on Sunday, Premier Jacinta Allan announces</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/vic-west-gate-tunnel-ready-to-open/106134682</link><description>After being plagued by cost blowouts and delays, Melbourne's West Gate Tunnel will be ready to take motor vehicles from Sunday, say multiple sources.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">892c381d9f9b85832ba1460d984863e3</guid></item><item><title>Community rallies around family of farmer Mark Mudie after bushfire death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/community-support-wa-farmer-family-after-bushfire-death/106130238</link><description>In the wake of the tragic loss of farmer Mark Mudie while fighting a bushfire, the community has rallied to help his family finish harvesting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29225b57eeac8a3e9bddf250890cea9b</guid></item><item><title>Matilda Bay and Applecross ferry terminals approved in Swan River Metronet plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/swan-river-matilda-bay-applecross-ferry-terminals-approved/106130810</link><description>WA's planning authorities approve the construction of two new ferry terminals at Applecross and Matilda Bay as part of the state government's expansion of Swan River ferry services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">263609e9363897531936e450b7d42c1d</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos coach Tony Popovic labelled 'smug' by US great Landon Donovan for reaction at FIFA World Cup draw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/socceroos-popovich-smug-donovan-us-fifa-world-cup-draw/106134712</link><description>America's consensus greatest ever player takes issue with the Socceroos coach's reaction to drawing USA, tipping Australia to finish last in its World Cup group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c5be069dcfd9c226d66257ff65617cd</guid></item><item><title>Eurovision winner Nemo returns trophy in protest over Israel's participation in competition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/nemo-returns-eurovision-trophy-over-israels-participation/106134594</link><description>Swiss singer Nemo says they will return the trophy they won in 2024 over the EBU's decision to let Israel participate in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cb716762728053bb6ac34183a1719bf</guid></item><item><title>Reddit files legal challenge against social media ban for under-16s</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/reddit-social-media-ban-under-16-court-challenge/106134994</link><description>Reddit has filed a High Court challenge alleging that Australia's social media restrictions are being applied to the company inaccurately.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">198bf1486fb398a261f42203fd377f5a</guid></item><item><title>Principal Anita Haley says cancelling the formal was never a thought</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/st-helens-principal-anita-haley/106134694</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">273103e5cf03d68fdf3d6004f153d87e</guid></item><item><title>Career counselling lacking as students try to predict AI impact on jobs of the future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/ai-jobs-student-anxiety-vce-university-atar-employment/106123826</link><description>A Victorian Parliamentary Inquiry report finds youth career support is "severely lacking" as students fear AI is threatening white-collar industries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5781af3b1fbb37853c9b606b2ddad516</guid></item><item><title>Treasurer Jim Chalmers gives green light to Hanwha's double stake in shipbuilder Austal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/hanwha-austal-bid-approve-jim-chalmers/106134860</link><description>Jim Chalmers said there will be "strict conditions" on the South Korean defence conglomerate's stake in the strategic shipbuilder, in a nod to the diplomatic and security sensitivities surrounding the bid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110810108c4d6e185f96e797e7f4a857</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos-containing wind turbine brake pad shipment docked at Geelong port</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/asbestos-wind-turbine-brake-pads-worksafe-cfmeu-vestas/106131948</link><description>A cargo ship containing asbestos products is docked at the port of Geelong in Victoria's south-west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29a5b677e898bfcc7b394bfb1ef0a5e3</guid></item><item><title>French game Clair Obscur breaks records with Game of the Year 2025 win — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/game-awards-2025-live-coverage/106102718</link><description>The biggest night in gaming is getting underway in the heart of downtown Los Angeles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8d73ac44f3cef79d117d2e04e651b49</guid></item><item><title>Hollywood director Carl Rinsch convicted of scamming Netflix out of $16.5m</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/hollywood-director-convicted-of-scamming-16-million-aud-netflix/106135428</link><description>Carl Erik Rinsch is convicted on charges that he scammed Netflix out of $US11 million for a show that never materialised, instead using the cash for purchases including luxury cars and homewares.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e8489bf4a398903633591b2660742f</guid></item><item><title>Perth fires prompt warning of extreme conditions as Kenwick, Bullsbrook blazes downgraded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/extreme-fire-danger-forecast-for-southwest-western-australia/106134884</link><description>A Kenwick resident who lost a shed and thousands of dollars worth of machinery in a bushfire in Perth's south-east says the blaze came within metres of her house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">870a179de0c5ec4dc83ae20ac37cc618</guid></item><item><title>New SA Liberal leader Ashton Hurn unveils 'streamlined' shadow cabinet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/new-sa-liberal-leader-unveils-shadow-cabinet/106135116</link><description>South Australia's new Liberal leader Ashton Hurn unveils a "streamlined" shadow cabinet, just 99 days out from the next state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1951d24f5aa21dc00e9d0d2831cd4cb9</guid></item><item><title>St Helens student arrives for formal in boat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/st-helens-student-arrives-for-formal-in-boat/106135282</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67eec3377bdd7ea97a6f482fd967d041</guid></item><item><title>Stieglitz bushfire not enough to stop students and teachers from holding year 10 formal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/tas-bushfire-affected-year-10-formal-student-arrives-by-boat/106134760</link><description>Tasmanian students and teachers of St Helens District High School defy the Stieglitz bushfire to rescue formal wear, assemble decorations and food and hold their year 10 formal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59c73940bcde61252e688a4a4709011e</guid></item><item><title>How long does it take to fix an underperforming school?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/boonah-high-agriculture-education-turnaround/105983794</link><description>A Queensland high school has re-engaged students by embedding agriculture into the curriculum and building strong local industry ties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b4dcb5993bb0060e638f96fbbe9c04</guid></item><item><title>PM says he has asked independent watchdog for advice on politician entitlement rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/parliamentary-expenses-rules-review/106135370</link><description>Sports and Communications Minister Anika Wells referred her claims to the Independent Parliamentary Expenses Authority for review after a stream of questions over her spending earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bef836fe52d78ae8131a7227fe19a13</guid></item><item><title>What does the US proposal that foreign tourists disclose social media information mean for Australians?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/us-social-media-australia-explainer/106128586</link><description>Mean tweets about US policy might mean no trip to Disneyland, under a new proposal that would see Australians provide their social media history for the past five years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee83874203714c668554e3515de1de1c</guid></item><item><title>Surfers find 'earthquake wave' off Western Australia's remote south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/decade-long-search-for-unique-wa-big-wave/106133082</link><description>A natural phenomenon leaves surfers in awe of the "earthquake" wave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04596bfe87994ec9243bbca950c9b61b</guid></item><item><title>Surfers capture weird wave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/surfers-film-wild-wave/106133580</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a965f9627b6775da38a95dd70e718e7c</guid></item><item><title>Why has Bulgaria's government resigned after anti-corruption protests across the country?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/bulgaria-government-resigns-ahead-of-euro-entry/106135938</link><description>Bulgaria's prime minister announced the decision in a televised address saying "ahead of today's vote of no confidence, the government is resigning".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81068f18e2fd5d41ae777665bee2504c</guid></item><item><title>Dicky Bill salad farm's $10m debt shock as creditors try to claw back millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/dicky-bill-salad-farm-10m-debt-blow/105904126</link><description>Administrators for failed Australian salad farm company Dicky Bill reveal its business debts to hundreds of staff and suppliers could exceed $10 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8e5be403ca29b045c30bc879c4ed016</guid></item><item><title>Brittany Higgins declared bankrupt amid Linda Reynolds court saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/brittany-higgins-declared-bankrupt-linda-reynolds/106136120</link><description>Former senator Linda Reynolds's bid to have Brittany Higgins declared bankrupt has succeeded in a federal court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f9de42f4bde5dc6b81841920cd36d48</guid></item><item><title>Tom Silvagni's victim tells pre-sentence hearing she is haunted by rape 'every single day'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/tom-silvagni-rape-conviction-victim-speaks-in-court/106134992</link><description>The young woman raped by Tom Silvagni, whose father is AFL great Stephen Silvagni, has described the horror of the night it happened and the lasting impact it has had on her life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6a78813bca7c02fedc257b38783e906</guid></item><item><title>Dance teacher locked out from Meta business accounts in under-16s social media ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/social-media-ban-locks-out-30-year-old-mum-dance-teacher/106134692</link><description>A mother of three is urgently trying to regain access to her social media business accounts after being locked out during the blanket under-16s social media ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50d40fc5b419cdfc4fc79cb933af400f</guid></item><item><title>Government deal to ensure Tomago Aluminium smelter remains open beyond 2028</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/tomago-aluminium-secures-government-deal/106135134</link><description>A deal is being finalised between Tomago Aluminium and the state and federal governments to keep the smelter open beyond 2028.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">344a7ea744602f32b11358244f0ec706</guid></item><item><title>UK backpacker Alicia Kemp sentenced over e-scooter death of Thanh Phan in Perth CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/english-backpacker-sentenced-over-escooter-death-/106135496</link><description>Alicia Kemp is sentenced to four years behind bars after the 25-year-old English backpacker hit and killed Thanh Phan as she rode an e-scooter while drunk in Perth's CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db6d181185033240337530be95bca41e</guid></item><item><title>Port Fairy residents demand answers after council abruptly closes only all-abilities pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/belfast-aquatics-community-pool-abruptly-closes/106135078</link><description>The south-west Victorian community of Port Fairy is demanding answers after an abrupt announcement from its council that it has closed the town's only pool.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2475053435283faa9f963d9cc4a5eb3d</guid></item><item><title>Open AI, Microsoft face lawsuit over ChatGPT's alleged role in US murder-suicide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/open-ai-microsoft-face-lawsuit-over-chatgpt-s-alleged-role-in-co/106136406</link><description>The lawsuit is one of a growing number of wrongful death legal actions against AI chatbot makers across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">988a9d56696b75c51c111d1abff5f3a6</guid></item><item><title>Segment of video portrait of the Matildas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/segment-of-video-portrait-of-the-matildas/106136694</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4eae949a8153c9959ffc828bb394b0d0</guid></item><item><title>Courtnee Vine in video portrait of the Matildas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/courtnee-vine-in-video-portrait-of-the-matildas/106136690</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d77dabc04c9ce29fe4d285c0c8e9cc5</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr in video portrait of the Matildas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/sam-kerr-in-video-portrait-of-the-matildas/106136692</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ba0e3fb8833aec3f0b031739ddd2eaf</guid></item><item><title>National Portrait Gallery unveils video portrait of Matildas honouring their contribution to sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/new-video-portrait-of-matildas-pays-tribute-to-their-legacy/106136190</link><description>The 23-minute video portrait of the Matildas 2023 World Cup squad cost $400,000, in what the National Portrait Gallery describes as its most ambitious commission ever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b67ac0ff5d6ccb3e375135e07013ed8</guid></item><item><title>Tsunami warning for northern Japan called off after magnitude 6.9 earthquake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/tsunami-warning-northern-japan-after-magnitude-6-7-earthquake/106136894</link><description>The quake struck off Japan's north-east coast with a depth of 20 kilometres, after a bigger, 7.5-magnitude earthquake hit the same region late on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35b8163982945df48730b4e5423d4d72</guid></item><item><title>Former ANZ chief executive Shayne Elliott sues banking giant after losing $13.5m in bonuses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/former-anz-ceo-shayne-elliott-sues-bank/106136712</link><description>Shayne Elliott says he has been left with "no alternative" but to launch legal action against the bank over its decision to slash $13.5 million from his bonus payments after he retired.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7d863795f4422aa214a07f5703eaf25</guid></item><item><title>Elder abuse 'complex' and 'poorly understood' but new laws not needed, parliamentary inquiry says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/queensland-elder-abuse-report-complex/106135890</link><description>Elder abuse often occurs within families, with a parliamentary inquiry describing the issue as part of a wider systemic problem.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a49e1a005ad62b981f3f49c45f8a5198</guid></item><item><title>New concessional loans for drought-affected farmers and algae-impacted fishers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/government-ric-review-new-loan-program-farmers-fishers-drought/106134810</link><description>The federal government is introducing new low-interest loans for drought-affected farmers and algae-impacted fishers, but some are worried it doesn't go far enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">637d56e286835d468cfe8a39ac049e83</guid></item><item><title>Our 10 best Christmas recipes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/easy-christmas-recipes-mains-desserts/105721782</link><description>Christmas is around the corner and we have plenty of delicious ideas whether you're hosting or bringing dessert.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4744c3fde22d977ef3646b0be11dd87a</guid></item><item><title>The Thai Navy released footage of a Cambodian casino on the Thai border being shelled.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/thai-navy-bombing-building/106135828</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bb0f0a95c492be2839fd96581edb46e</guid></item><item><title>Thailand's bombing of Cambodian casinos could be putting trafficking victims at risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/thailand-bombs-cambodian-casinos-and-scam-centres/106125824</link><description>An expert says the Thai military's strikes on Cambodian casinos and suspected scam centres could be putting the lives of civilians and human trafficking victims at risk and may be considered war crimes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c044830d17205d2026f93fd522896c7a</guid></item><item><title>Celebrity crocodile wrangler Matt Wright sentenced to 10 months in prison, suspended after five months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/crocodile-wrangler-matt-wright-sentencing-nt-supreme-court/106127504</link><description>Celebrity crocodile wrangler Matt Wright has been sentenced to 10 months in prison, suspended after five months, for attempting to interfere with an investigation into a fatal helicopter accident three years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ce1bef24766a0c434377874c4d84c74</guid></item><item><title>Court hears Dreaming story not 'trump card' to halt Regis Resources' McPhillamys Gold Project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/court-told-dreaming-story-not-trump-card-to-stop-gold-mine/106135486</link><description>An elders' group has told a Federal Court in Sydney that the Blue Banded Bee Dreaming story was not being kept "up its sleeve" three years after a protection bid was first made to the Commonwealth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a40abe62a175d5b6f25efd398ee39997</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106137824</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ec17792ba04e87136ec7434373520ed</guid></item><item><title>British porn star Bonnie Blue deported from Bali after 'Bang Bus' case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/bonnie-blue-faces-bali-court-after-studio-raid/106137670</link><description>The controversial adult content creator has faced court for flouting the resort island's road rules.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8222c1e101256089be61bc436435f9d8</guid></item><item><title>Bankstown man charged over alleged death threats against federal MP Anika Wells and family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/nsw-man-charged-over-alleged-threats-to-anika-wells/106138224</link><description>A man accused of sending dozens of emails threatening to kill federal Communications Minister Anika Wells and her family appears in a Sydney court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea748be506fbab6841e22a83e0ac2556</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested over Anika Wells alleged death threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/man-arrested-over-anika-wells-alleged-death-threats/106138216</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c75251c7df71bd19c42225bcf48a770</guid></item><item><title>Horse owners urged to vaccinate animals after bat tests positive to Hendra virus in the NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/hendra-virus-found-in-the-northern-territory-darwin-bat/106135238</link><description>Horse owners in the Northern Territory are being encouraged to vaccinate their animals after a bat tested positive for Hendra virus, in the territory's first confirmed case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47cf55f810d41349e77a2a2323137bb2</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's historic treaty formally commences with cultural celebration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/victorias-historic-treaty-formally-begins/106137848</link><description>Victoria's statewide treaty has officially launched with a day of cultural celebrations in Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9af5d95067bab0db07b1bdad72cf6ac</guid></item><item><title>Americans sceptical of Trump on Epstein, as poll finds just 23pc approve of how he's handled crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/brk-polling-on-trump-handling-epstein-files/106138506</link><description>Most Americans believe Trump's administration is covering up Epstein information, with 62 per cent believing the government is hiding information about Epstein's death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18cc07d2d9e4c3f207ce4eb84ac7f679</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan Nobel laureate María Corina Machado says she's aiming for peaceful transition after Maduro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/maria-corina-machado-says-maduro-will-leave-power/106138770</link><description>Nobel laureate María Corina Machado says she's focused on achieving a peaceful transition of power, adding that she's confident the majority of Venezuela's armed forces and police will follow orders from a duly elected government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a7110091a7e4b0f6a72aa8ff86473ac</guid></item><item><title>US Democrats release more Epstein photos, including some featuring Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/epstein-photos-with-trump-released-by-us-democrats/106138858</link><description>Democrats publish more photos from Jeffrey Epstein's estate as part of their pressure campaign for the full and immediate release of the Epstein files.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3557bb62a3a5066951a17a9b64a72bc</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump fails to secure ceasefire between Thailand and Cambodia as border conflict continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/trump-call-fails-to-secure-peace-between-thailand-and-cambodia/106138772</link><description>The US president spoke with his Thai counterpart on Friday after indicating he would intervene to reinstate peace between the neighbouring countries, who are attacking each other at the border.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce98813723ed159e7eb490bc6defb7e7</guid></item><item><title>Aged care reforms leave elderly Australians and their loved ones in the lurch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/aged-care-package-reform-worse-off-confusion-despair-waitlist/106136364</link><description>The reforms have unleashed a wave of confusion and despair amongst hundreds of thousands of elderly Australians, from those wanting care to those who already have it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bccf44fd0309fdda714dc96ed3d5cde5</guid></item><item><title>Trump's quietly released national security document didn't escape Europe's attention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/donald-trump-foreign-policy-national-security-strategy-europe/106136354</link><description>When the White House quietly released its national security strategy late one night last week, it instead seemed to get lost in other news. Except, perhaps, in Europe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a638ba1f7a2b1556fc4a3782ee5651f1</guid></item><item><title>How a grieving mother's letter helped Australia's world-first social media ban come into being</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/how-australia-developed-social-media-ban-under-16s/106137700</link><description>Key players including Anthony Albanese, Peter Dutton, Peter Malinauskas and Julie Inman-Grant tell the inside story of how an unprecedented ban came to be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a518d11646c795b19b3f686350ae927</guid></item><item><title>Battery subsidy scheme set for 'urgent' overhaul as costs run out of control</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/battery-subsidy-scheme-faces-urgent-overhaul-as-costs-spiral/106138464</link><description>Announced to great fanfare in the run-up to the election, Labor's $2.3 billion battery scheme was supposed to last until 2030. Much of the money is already gone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddcb2c850af156986007371f07ab8125</guid></item><item><title>Warner Bros Discovery battle draws in billionaires, celebrities and Trump's son-in-law</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/warner-bros-discovery-paramount-skydance-netflix-battle/106126968</link><description>The dramatic escalation in the fight for Warner Bros is one of the biggest in recent corporate memory, drawing an unlikely cast of celebrities and business figures including Jared Kushner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1412d0a2b8f61f8e6f279b4a1e8d252c</guid></item><item><title>When can politicians put sport or family trips on the 'company card'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/when-can-sport-be-charged-to-taxpayers/106128390</link><description>A spotlight on sports minister Anika Wells prompts fresh scrutiny of the rules about the expenses politicians can claim, including to attend big-ticket sporting events and concerts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fe77984fac9fd83754193d222751701</guid></item><item><title>Partygoers using walking sticks after ketamine, drug use at music festivals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/partygoers-using-walking-sticks-after-drug-use/106125022</link><description>Australian partygoers are using walking aids to support their ketamine habit at music festivals across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">261b99de3f1a68de6536bd5e8840d45b</guid></item><item><title>Best books of 2025, by Hannah Kent, Arundhati Roy, Charlotte McConaghy and more</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/best-books-2025-hannah-kent-arundhati-roy-charlotte-mcconaghy/106131106</link><description>An exciting Australian debut, a bevvy of award-winning literary fiction and more than one heart-wrenching memoir are among our critics' favourite reads of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a47e37b2c20cf9e65c12b0b5f5610b</guid></item><item><title>Matildas midfielder Tameka Yallop requires surgery, all but ruling her out of home AFC Asian Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/matildas-midfielder-tameka-yallop-out-of-asian-cup/106138960</link><description>Matildas veteran Tameka Yallop will require surgery on a serious hamstring injury, all but ending her hopes of playing at the Women's Asian Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9891e03aaac924ec2a7ebb8aedf1419e</guid></item><item><title>50 years ago, Patti Smith’s Horses fused poetry and punk, rewriting rock's rule book</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/patti-smith-horses-50-years-anniversary-punk-poetry-rock-classic/106125110</link><description>The power and importance of Horses, the seminal debut of punk-poet Patti Smith, still lingers five decades after its release.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb54679b32daf54876ce47e32191e9fa</guid></item><item><title>ABC 50/50 quiz: This week we're testing your knowledge on The Simpsons, Gremlins and fruit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/50-50-quiz-dec-13/106131450</link><description>Every question has only two options: one is right and the other is wrong. You have an even chance of guessing correctly each time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c2f9e5b9fd2382b352819f39dfc9d41</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 13: Box-office hit Sense and Sensibility hits US cinemas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/sense-and-sensibility-released-in-us-cinemas-30-years-ago-today/106127910</link><description>Sense and Sensibility was marketed "chick flick". But this 90s re-imagining of Sense and Sensibility starring British powerhouse Emma Thompson was more than just a bubbly romance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d6d813b6850c55992c00eb46f6b7b0c</guid></item><item><title>How these family-run Christmas shops stay afloat and festive all year long</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/how-these-nsw-christmas-shops-stay-float-all-year-long/106126032</link><description>Christmas store owners say their job is "not a chore", but rather a "fun time" as they reckon with online competition in a seasonal industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f9992e5f74dc105b830c5b0568edc7b</guid></item><item><title>King Charles III gives rare cancer update, says treatment will be reduced in new year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/king-charles-says-cancer-treatment-will-be-reduced-in-new-year/106138940</link><description>King Charles III has revealed his cancer treatment will be reduced in the new year, describing the milestone as a "blessing" and testament to "remarkable" medical advances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45ef49d228f549353388c942617d8184</guid></item><item><title>ODYs_CaveLoop2_0912</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/odys-caveloop2-0912/106122506</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d08a043a8b43629e9764ad0c3d54fe58</guid></item><item><title>Researcher walks through cave on Kangaroo Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/odys-caveloop-0512/106108366</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb002c70a7fec6e6944ddbac68bdeff7</guid></item><item><title>ODYs_FireLoop_0912</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/odys-fireloop-0912/106122526</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4eb4de7d45fd0663e9556ec39faca62</guid></item><item><title>From devastation to wonder as Kangaroo Island bushfires lead to cave discoveries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/more-than-150-caves-discovered-in-ki-after-devastating-bushfires/106095942</link><description>It was an adventure into the unknown. From the surface all that could be seen was a small opening. The ABC has been given exclusive access to newly-discovered caves on South Australia's Kangaroo Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc388cc62031e7ced86dc36fdeb23d3e</guid></item><item><title>Meet the fleet: The helicopters and planes protecting you this bushfire season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/victoria-firefighting-air-fleet-helicopters-aircraft-planes-fire/106130296</link><description>They are an eclectic mix but this diverse fleet of helicopters, water bombers and planes is ready to protect south-eastern Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd08d6e255b4c21288305aa9323d9bbc</guid></item><item><title>West Gate Tunnel project is set to open after delays and cost blow outs pushed onto road users</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/west-gate-tunnel-set-to-open-after-delays-and-cost-blowouts/106137268</link><description>The long-awaited West Gate Tunnel project will open on Sunday, with Labor hoping it's enough to win voters back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf91745cc022d88d7e89031bbf02b1bc</guid></item><item><title>Koolewong resident wins stand-off with insurer Budget Direct over bushfire claim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/bushfire-insurance-claim-rejection-koolewong/106134988</link><description>Gordon Plath thought he was one of the lucky ones when he escaped a bushfire that swept through Koolewong on the New South Wales Central Coast last weekend — but then he found himself in a stand-off with his insurer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c4844facdf469f8e193eeffe0ca0d0f</guid></item><item><title>Exhibition exploring influence of Korean pop culture opens at National Museum of Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/act-korean-pop-culture-exhibition-national-museum-of-australia/106137256</link><description>Whether it's KPop Demon Hunters, Squid Game, or Gangnam Style, Korean pop culture has made its mark in Australia — and the National Museum of Australia's new exhibition explores just that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3656f01bc15cb9c01ba429f169dff2db</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous community feels 'forgotten' in nation's capital after two decades of Labor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/aboriginal-canberrans-feel-forgotten-failure-close-the-gap/106112204</link><description>After 24 years of Labor government, First Nations people in Australia's capital are frustrated and exhausted by a lack of meaningful progress to close the gap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4500ab690127d5eece816a53bb22af25</guid></item><item><title>Illicit vaping, cigarette raids create game of 'whack-a-mole' but health campaign urges patience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/illicit-vaping-cigarette-raids-create-game-of-whack-a-mole/106120236</link><description>Despite a record $15.7 million nicotine seizure, experts say Australia's multi-billion-dollar illicit tobacco and vape market continues to thrive, exposing the limits of raids and crackdowns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26c5c6e9b33a21cf459c67553f43b018</guid></item></channel></rss>