<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 23:18:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Tasmania looks at allowing public hospital midwives to help with homebirths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/tasmania-looks-at-homebirth-model/105899984</link><description>The Tasmanian government is developing a public homebirth model that would allow midwives working in the public system to support women to labour from their homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b288cd9590708ea54ac6e8efd974f327</guid></item><item><title>How a Canberra-based refugee fled the Maduro regime along with millions of other Venezuelans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/act-how-a-venezuelan-fled-the-maduro-regime/106313290</link><description>Josh Madrid was arrested for attending a pro-democracy protest in Venezuela. 24 hours later, he fled his homeland, fearing he would be killed by the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d635939cd740a309d45cc1fc12ccddb7</guid></item><item><title>Coalition reunited after last-minute deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/deal-done-to-bring-coalition-back-together/102760848</link><description>The Liberals and Nationals have reached a breakthrough deal to reunite the Coalition after 11th-hour talks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03d631d89d350d9986b7badfae6006de</guid></item><item><title>Heat and fires expose ancestral remains in Victoria's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/heat-fires-expose-ancestral-remains-in-victorian-mallee/106304308</link><description>Ancestral remains that could be thousands of years old have been uncovered by erosion, dust storms and bushfires in Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49ce14146e6918e7cee89f1e59175fb2</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested after suspicious Maidstone church fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/police-arrest-suspicious-church-fire-melbourne-west/106318732</link><description>A man is due to be questioned by police after a church in Melbourne's west caught fire in the early hours of this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">034a2a23dd8fb891083b3b5a57a23a23</guid></item><item><title>The slow death of Keir Starmer's prime ministership after Peter Mandelson's 'betrayal'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/keir-starmer-leadership-peril-over-mandelson-epstein-scanda/106318588</link><description>Starmer's decision to hand the plum job of UK ambassador in Washington to Lord Peter Mandelson, despite knowing Mandelson had maintained a friendship with Jeffrey Epstein well past Epstein's conviction for soliciting underage prostitution, may simply be too large an error of judgement for the public to accept.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">397ccf8ff9c1e397f0aa8049cd1433d1</guid></item><item><title>Before opening Meg's Bookshop in 1991, the Arnolds were told kids 'didn't read' in Port Pirie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/meg-s-bookshop-port-pirie-closes-after-35-years-south-australia/106277430</link><description>In one of Australia's most disadvantaged regions, more known for its lead than its literature, a couple wanted to open a book store but were told children didn't read books there. They did it anyway, and it went on to become a "world class" institution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">488cbf932021fe26386b52895acbaa59</guid></item><item><title>Valentino Guseli missed out on a bonus 2026 Winter Olympics medal, but won something even more important</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/valentino-guseli-2026-winter-olympics-big-air-snowboard/106318724</link><description>It was 18 months ago that Valentino Guseli blew out his ACL attempting a backside 1800 at the Beijing big air. At the Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics snowboard big air final, he put that ghost to rest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6cb85fcb30e9b60ce1daa388c5f7d61</guid></item><item><title>Train delays in Italy during Winter Olympics opening weekend after damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/winter-olympics-italy-railway-sabotage-allegations/106318876</link><description>Police are investigating three incidents of damage on lines around Bologna, and have not ruled out a potential link to the Milan Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54f40c4b9d300363d1667f309b32f0dd</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers says next federal budget will focus on lifting economy's 'speed limit'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/may-federal-budget-to-focus-on-lifting-speed-limit-on-economy/105435282</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers says the federal government's budget in May will focus on productivity, spending restraint and tax reform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da4b1c57606aca371fd50217191fb699</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 2, Sunday, February 8</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-tess-coady/106307392</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f9218347b9ff96081f5253512a17b47</guid></item><item><title>Why young people say they are not the only ones hooked on screens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/generational-screen-time-brain-rot/106278964</link><description>The focus of discussion around screen time is on teenagers and young adults, but young people say they are noticing older people are in the grips of their devices too.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72ffc41b830d319fbaf67593d8e5438e</guid></item><item><title>Man dead, five others hospitalised after Sydney's Dreamstate music festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/nsw-dreamstate-man-dead-five-hospitalised-sydney/106318948</link><description>Several people suffered "medical episodes" at the trance music festival at Sydney's Olympic Park, according to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb0b81cbc6c892cc70ef52c02bb20db5</guid></item><item><title>Piper James's parents say dingo management reform needed to prevent further deaths on K'gari</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/piper-james-parents-call-for-more-dingo-warnings-on-kgari/106317706</link><description>Piper James's parents are leaving Australia with their daughter's ashes and a determination to ensure she hasn't died in vain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ccf19d954997c8989ad2001fd781236</guid></item><item><title>Palestine Action Group takes court action against extra police powers ahead of protests against Israeli president's Sydney visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/palestine-action-group-to-challenge-police-powers-herzog-visit/106319078</link><description>The Palestine Action Group lodged submissions late on Sunday afternoon, arguing the declaration was "draconian" and imposed rules unsuitable for protest activity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d620aa168abe72abd53aa441463941cb</guid></item><item><title>Payne Haas quits Brisbane to sign three-year deal with South Sydney Rabbitohs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/payne-haas-signs-with-south-sydney-for-2027/106319316</link><description>South Sydney have pulled off one of the biggest recruitment moves in NRL history after signing Brisbane enforcer Payne Haas to a three-year contract from 2027.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4006492fb182ade2ddeeb67451c5ec53</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian government says illegal tobacco sales crackdown will deliver some of the 'toughest' laws in the country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/tasmanian-illegal-tobacco-vapes-crackdown/106318886</link><description>The Tasmanian government announces increased penalties for those caught selling illegal tobacco products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abb1e0b80c97bfdd83a60a814abd6175</guid></item><item><title>In the Australian outback, we're listening for nuclear tests. What we hear matters more than ever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/australian-outback-nuclear-tests-listening-warramunga-facility/106307478</link><description>As the New START treaty curbing the US and Russian nuclear weapons programs expires, the work we do here in the red centre has become more important than ever before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0e5b08cded46dedfceb1992d9d6b4b6</guid></item><item><title>Police recover pilot's body from croc-infested marsh after Normanton plane crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/police-recover-pilot-body-normanton-plane-crash/106319446</link><description>Police officers armed with rifles guarded their colleagues while they recovered the man's body from the crash site in difficult terrain near Normanton, in the Gulf of Carpentaria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6bcdff91b2f00027265cf151c25bc13</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberals promise new stamp duty concessions, Labor tackles aged care bed backlog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/sa-liberal-party-stamp-duty-election-promise/106318938</link><description>Less than six weeks from the South Australian election, the Liberal Party has announced an election promise on stamp duty while the Labor government unveil its plan to create 1,300 new aged care beds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6efd5f5722fbf5b7fcc9dba155108442</guid></item><item><title>Two Australians reach big air final after tense qualifying runs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/winter-olympics-day-two-live-blog-updates/106319558</link><description>Olympic medallist Tess Coady and fellow Australian Meila Stalker reach the snowboard big air final, after a dramatic day where American superstar Lindsey Vonn crashes in women's downhill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eabe2255ae86c9fbbf5b0a4f952c27ac</guid></item><item><title>Danish people using apps to help boycott American goods over Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/greenland-denmark-app-boycott-us-made-goods-donald-trump/106319620</link><description>After Donald Trump's repeated threats to acquire Greenland, many Danish people felt powerless but new apps are helping them make choices to boycott US-made products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2297548a311c1a6d4f30bc1eec67099</guid></item><item><title>Lindsey Vonn's horror crash at the 2026 Winter Olympic Games was always on the cards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/lindsey-vonn-2026-winter-olympic-games-horror-downhill-crash/106319806</link><description>Lindsey Vonn's shocking downhill crash at the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games was always a possibility given the American was competing just nine days after rupturing her ACL. But it was never going to stop her from trying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3298a9e82bd89310260dbbb7b476aef6</guid></item><item><title>Man extradited from Dubai to Moscow over top Russian general's shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/russian-general-shooting-dubai-moscow-extradition/106319910</link><description>Lieutenant General Vladimir Alexeyev is the deputy head of Russia's vast GRU military intelligence service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a718dd9de19d878789e384eddfec8f8</guid></item><item><title>One Nation capitalises on anti-immigration sentiment in a housing crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/one-nation-pauline-hanson-housing-crisis-immigration/106304670</link><description>Pauline Hanson might not have any substantive policies, but her rhetoric about reducing migration is clearly finding an audience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23968ca9459afcd8c2cf60c2582e68d7</guid></item><item><title>Coalition's rushed reunification does not solve their respective branding problems</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/coalition-reunification-liberals-nationals-sussan-ley/106304664</link><description>The Coalition has reunited, but the new agreement does not address underlying party tensions nor the surging fragmentation of the right.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4015c0b9e86f13b0cbf1a5cc8413b8c5</guid></item><item><title>Five simple steps to saving cash (while still having a life)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/finance-tips-saving-money-new-year/106303046</link><description>Saving money is not about beating yourself up. It's also not about depriving yourself of all sources of joy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59b760f5e77d65279a49b68106aa5c6d</guid></item><item><title>Young people could get massive pay boost in 'totemic' wage case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/millions-of-young-people-could-get-massive-pay-boost-in-totemic/106101186</link><description>"I'm paying adult fuel with still a child's wage," says Ben Walker, one of the almost half a million young people who could see a huge boost to their wage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c8ac9ab718a2220257ac5a49545a466</guid></item><item><title>UK prime minister's chief of staff Morgan McSweeney quits amid Epstein fallout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/morgan-mcsweeney-resigns-epstein-mandelson/106320216</link><description>Sir Keir Starmer's leadership is under threat after revelations that one of his former US ambassadors had close ties with Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cee5f2015f6214e64864f3870d049084</guid></item><item><title>Japan PM Sanae Takaichi leads coalition to landslide election victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/japan-election-sanae-takaichi-landslide-victory/106320228</link><description>Sanae Takaichi's Liberal Democratic Party and its coalition partner are expected to hold upwards of two-thirds of the seats in Japan's lower house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fb71b428c5bbf7507c7f3ce7b77658c</guid></item><item><title>$740m veterans plan to fund social 'rehabilitation' and psychedelic treatments for PTSD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/veterans-funding-social-rehabilitation-mdma-ptsd/106309994</link><description>A $740 million program will expand support for veterans and include funding for social activities such as yoga and language classes, with new treatment including MDMA and psilocybin for the worst forms of PTSD also funded for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fae87a317eaabd51c41fe0364bba0f6b</guid></item><item><title>Thailand PM Anutin Charnvirakul confident of forming government after election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/thailand-election-result-anutin-results/106320270</link><description>South-East Asia's second-largest economy went to the polls on Sunday in a tight race between conservatives aligned with the military and the monarchy, and progressive elements represented by the reform-driven People's Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea445c2de3e44242cdf9e5b0f4e49cf0</guid></item><item><title>Why Payne Haas's move from Brisbane to South Sydney changes the game for two NRL giants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/payne-haas-brisbane-broncos-south-sydney-nrl/106319624</link><description>Payne Haas's decision to leave Brisbane for South Sydney in 2027 didn't just shock the rugby league world, it transformed the futures of two of rugby league's most powerful clubs in an instant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3870c2c914c0402e56a618be411dd7e9</guid></item><item><title>Japanese prime minister confirms sweeping election win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/japanese-prime-minister-confirms-sweeping-election-win-/106320386</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">384bb30f1e8e2c1d75e666b3ce5bab10</guid></item><item><title>Businessman and bad gambler Sam Kanjo linked to Australia's biggest illegal tobacco fine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/sam-kanjo-linked-to-australias-biggest-illegal-tobacco-fine/106286014</link><description>He's been declared bankrupt repeatedly, and was a gambling addict. Now he's linked to a $1.5 million fine for illegal tobacco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f50f644637f1f8f64249db0e52537e9</guid></item><item><title>Australia's women beaten by New Zealand in Perth Sevens final, but men claim bronze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/aussie-women-settle-for-perth-sevens-silver-new-zealand/106320454</link><description>The Australian women are forced to settle for silver at the Perth Sevens, while the Aussie men claim bronze in thrilling fashion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23861d2dad88948210d071dce4f97e17</guid></item><item><title>Green turtle released from Taronga Zoo's wildlife hospital after horror injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/green-turtle-released-taronga-zoo-after-fishing-line-injury/106317556</link><description>After surviving one of the worst fishing line injuries vet Rebecca Robey had ever seen, Terry the turtle has been set free.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b197fd3fc2005d27d37f85e98809f573</guid></item><item><title>Bullying surges in ACT public schools as parents, teachers speak out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/bullying-reports-rise-in-act-public-schools/106269450</link><description>Reports of bullying in ACT public schools have risen sharply in four years. Parents and teachers say children are paying the price, and the system is not coping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7cda36cd7ac7cd9196735a6516e4323</guid></item><item><title>Extreme heat returning for south-east Queensland before weekend showers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/queensland-weather-heat-showers/106319132</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology is forecasting "locally severe heatwave conditions" from Tuesday, culminating in a maximum of 35 degrees in Brisbane on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b30ddf4d4ab44e838d7d574f7e1be3ec</guid></item><item><title>ASX jumps 1.9 per cent in $60b rally, another Optus exec sacked — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-january-09/106319466</link><description>The ASX has recouped the losses of last week with a broad-based $60 billion rally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1e7915364d79ad3062ddde2e4b76baa</guid></item><item><title>Israeli President Isaac Herzog tells Sydney event antisemitism has been 'festering' in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nsw-sydney-israeli-president-isaac-herzog-lands-bondi-attack/106320482</link><description>Isaac Herzog was invited by the governor-general and prime minister to join the Jewish community grieving the loss of life in the December 14 massacre of mostly Jewish Australians at a Hanukkah event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8477437267014ce2c5d1873b72d0a6d</guid></item><item><title>Mother claims missed warning signs in NT hospital led to baby's lifelong disabilities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/mother-claims-nt-hospital-missed-warning-signs-during-birth/106273516</link><description>Mia Pilbrow is taking legal action against a Northern Territory hospital and calling for the territory to adopt tailored pre-term labour guidelines, after medical staff sent her home seven times during her pregnancy, repeatedly assuring her the baby was fine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d45744f2a0878ebedd4d9fb2b49e40b6</guid></item><item><title>As AFL prepares to reboot State of Origin, there are hopes it can capture the imagination of a new generation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/afl-state-of-origin-game-does-it-have-place-in-modern-footy/105781418</link><description>The AFL is about to reboot the State of Origin concept, with the clash between Western Australia and Victoria at Perth Stadium next Saturday — on Valentine's Day — set to show if there's any love left for the idea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c46379064496246d0108e4942b1d209</guid></item><item><title>Explain the Internet: Why Wuthering Heights is one of the year's most controversial adaptations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/wuthering-heights-controversy-emerald-fennell-jacob-elordi/106305404</link><description>Days away from the release of Emerald Fennell's highly anticipated adaptation of Emily Brontë's classic novel, critics and fans alike are still fighting about text fidelity in the comments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51691c38c09e7e812fe2f8ae70e9ae0d</guid></item><item><title>The aftermath of the 2019 Cobargo bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/the-aftermath-of-the-2019-cobargo-bushfire/106294344</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22e913e7b6f7929c3a7fe100eb5b6339</guid></item><item><title>Deua River Valley and Cobargo still rebuilding six years after Black Summer bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/cobargo-deua-river-still-rebuilding-after-black-summer-bushfires/106273804</link><description>Residents who lived through the 2019-20 bushfires on the NSW South Coast say this summer's fires triggered traumatic memories, and highlighted the recovery and resilience projects that remain unfinished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75a6395d574e8ce915a53455bd5abe17</guid></item><item><title>Liberals despair at prospect of 'non-existence' and weigh leadership change after catastrophic Newspoll</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/liberals-despair-after-disastrous-poll-weigh-sussan-ley-spill/106320642</link><description>Sussan Ley could face a challenge to her leadership from Angus Taylor this week after a disastrous opinion poll showed the Coalition parties falling further behind One Nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d6794b583bc82ebb66b82a29f4dee89</guid></item><item><title>Aussie stars as Seahawks use ferocious defence to claim Super Bowl win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/super-bowl-lx-live-blog-seahawks-vs-patriots-bad-bunny/106320762</link><description>The Seattle Seahawks overawe the New England Patriots in Super Bowl LX as punter Michael Dickson becomes the second ever Australian NFL champion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fad6557763c143875756ac2daf86b7c</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian minister Nick Duigan to go on medical leave for heart surgery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/minister-nick-duigan-takes-leave-to-undergo-heart-surgery/106320766</link><description>Tasmanian minister Nick Duigan will take extended medical leave to undergo heart surgery, the state government has announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f674506d34ea92eed94098d36ef4d93</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Lindsey Vonn breaks her leg, Breezy Johnson breaks her gold medal — quick hits from day two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/winter-olympics-2026-day-two-quick-hits-lindsey-vonn/106319962</link><description>US great Lindsey Vonn breaks her leg, and her compatriot breaks her gold medal as Tess Coady sneaks through to the final after a nervous wait on the bubble. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">271eb82bfbfbeb3c22aa7602ccb93659</guid></item><item><title>'Punitive' bail law amendments have increased and First Nations people are affected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/bail-law-amendments-resulting-in-more-first-nation-remands/106315210</link><description>A study has found increasing "punitive" bail law amendments are negatively affecting First Nations people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bebd2244ed8d3de1cb17c7226d169513</guid></item><item><title>Darkwaves research allows scientists to measure impact of 'underwater blackouts' on marine life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/darkwaves-research-scientists-measure-impact-on-marine-life/106314712</link><description>For the first time a group of international scientists have measured the impact of what happens to marine life when the lights go out underwater.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70eaaa35d2df02cbcf1d34ac0e2a4c3b</guid></item><item><title>Greens politician Kat McNamara quits NT parliament 18 months after historic Nightcliff win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nt-greens-mla-kat-mcnamara-quits-politics/106320616</link><description>Kat McNamara is leaving the role effectively immediately due to "ongoing health challenges". It comes 18 months after she became the first Greens candidate to win a seat in NT parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce0325863d6027503a10b02026025aa3</guid></item><item><title>Backyard pods won't fix the housing crisis but they signal a shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/backyard-pods-wont-fix-the-housing-crisis/106314472</link><description>Australia's biggest hardware retailer has started selling tiny homes. Are backyard pods the answer to a national housing crisis?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dd2b8a3992ec554b10d8b236bba7c64</guid></item><item><title>Search ends for 'very loved' Gold Coast fisherman Ash Haigh after almost five days lost at sea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/search-ends-loved-gold-coast-fisherman-ash-haigh/106321162</link><description>Queensland Police has suspended the cross-border search for missing Gold Coast fisherman Ash Haigh after an extensive air and sea operation found no signs of life, with his sister describing him as a "very loved" family man.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b728597ddaf78153709b4ea9a825a3a8</guid></item><item><title>Iran sentences Nobel Peace Prize winner Narges Mohammadi to six more years in prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nobel-peace-laureate-narges-mohammadi-sentenced-iran/106314130</link><description>Women's rights activist Narges Mohammadi is sentenced to a further six years in jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a361ee5a20a3e359c2b25fbca523621</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 3, Monday, February 9</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-holly-harris-jason-chan/106307460</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b8f3992831865843a3ea28399b9cf1f</guid></item><item><title>HESTA CEO Debby Blakey resigns after superannuation administration outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/hesta-superannuation-ceo-debby-blakey-resigns/106321478</link><description>HESTA's boss is calling it quits after 11 years in the role. Her exit follows an outage that left members unable to access their accounts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2aa4f7459e81fc5b96c6dfeaeae7d5b</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Lindsey Vonn hailed as 'idol' by downhill rivals after Milano Cortina crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/winter-olympics-rivals-pay-credit-to-lindsey-vonn/106320254</link><description>Lindsey Vonn's 2026 Winter Olympic Games ended in disaster, but her teammates and rivals have heaped praise on the three-time Olympic medallist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d1e30943c1086fc7cce481c2af84273</guid></item><item><title>Jon Kudelka, Walkley-winning Tasmanian cartoonist, dies from brain cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/jon-kudelka-tasmanian-cartoonist-dies/106321714</link><description>Award-winning Tasmanian cartoonist Jon Kudelka dies after being diagnosed with brain cancer in 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b64794da6dd1ff79a97006ebfd7d1f1b</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong media mogul Jimmy Lai sentenced to 20 years in landmark case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/hong-kong-media-mogul-jimmy-lai-sentenced-to-20-years-jail/106321070</link><description>Jimmy Lai, one of Hong Kong's most outspoken critics of China, has learned his fate after being sentenced this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03525059e67690dbcf8a35c0db81456f</guid></item><item><title>Independent inquiry launched into NACC chief's handling of defence ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/independent-inquiry-launched-into-nacc-chief-defence-ties/106320954</link><description>The body responsible for holding the federal integrity watchdog to account will formally investigate it for agency maladministration and its chief, Paul Brereton, for officer misconduct.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9eb72c36c774cffcae6b73bcb70d699</guid></item><item><title>Mitchell Freeway head-on crash in Butler leaves two dead after ute driven on wrong side of road</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/two-people-dead-after-mitchell-freeway-butler-head-on-crash/106321408</link><description>A 56-year-old-woman and a 24-year-old man are dead after a head-on collision involving a utility that was being driven on the wrong side of the Mitchell Freeway in Perth's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366c71a2ba852d44551f4bb42a51335e</guid></item><item><title>Five simple, tasty vegetarian recipes that are perfect for meat-free Mondays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/five-simple-tasty-vegetarian-recipes-for-meat-free-monday/106309846</link><description>Looking to add some more vegetarian dishes to your weekly rotation? We have you covered with these five recipes that are perfect for meat-free Mondays.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8ccc6ae83e7b914cda93001f414be5d</guid></item><item><title>Ben Batterham receives payout from NSW government for wrongful prosecution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/ben-batterham-gets-payout-from-state-for-wrongful-prosecution/106322122</link><description>A Newcastle man will receive a confidential payout from the NSW government for wrongful prosecution by police for an alleged home invasion murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6c1ff78372dd9ba63fb088e5a78ed5e</guid></item><item><title>SpaceX to build 'self-growing city' on Moon, Elon Musk says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/spacex-building-lunar-self-gowing-city-moon-elon-musk/106322472</link><description>Billionaire chief executive says the company will shift its focus from Mars and the project could be achieved within 10 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60090cd3e2417da1cd2217d495e8de23</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos captain Adam Reynolds announces retirement at end of NRL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/brisbane-broncos-captain-adam-reynolds-announces-nrl-retirement/106322932</link><description>Adam Reynolds will finish his stellar career at the end of the season after fulfilling his Broncos mission to perfection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">169322d9299a44e0989b53593be68e74</guid></item><item><title>New gun ownership laws announced by Queensland Premier David Crisafulli</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/queensland-gun-laws-premier-bondi-response/106322868</link><description>The laws aim to crack down on rising gun crime and include tougher penalties for drive-by shootings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9e0505970320f994bd598f7cdc457d3</guid></item><item><title>Inside Minnesotan homes these people are hiding from ICE and living in fear for their children and parents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/inside-minnesota-familes-at-risk-from-ice-arrest-speak-out/106322022</link><description>What was once a hindrance is now "a paranoia like I've never known before", one Minnesotan man says, as his family hides from immigration agents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b02e0fe5c465309c1c3d7f4d3c6850a</guid></item><item><title>Police and protesters clash in Sydney rally against Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/crowds-protest-israeli-president-isaac-herzog-in-australia/106321716</link><description>Thousands of people attend protests across the country against Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit to Australia in the wake of the Bondi terror attack, with demonstrators in Sydney sprayed with pepper spray and led away in handcuffs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf9c9e3b1bab97471914ed882c6b5903</guid></item><item><title>Another Optus tech 'issue' affects hundreds of thousands of customers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/optus-tech-issue-affects-customers-no-service/106323474</link><description>Optus says an issue is affecting mobile services for some customers, who are seeing "no service" or "SOS" on their devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47d7fc7e21afa43e3c80749b4b4950a2</guid></item><item><title>Families of Laos methanol poisoning victims say they've been left in the dark on investigations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/laos-methanol-poisoining-bianca-jones-holly-morton-bowles/106321336</link><description>The families of Bianca Jones and Holly Morton-Bowles say they have been left in the dark following the 2024 poisoning deaths of their daughters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2580145a0bf20f8945a54bc153c8c054</guid></item><item><title>Sanae Takaichi's stomping victory will have profound consequences for Australia and the Asia-Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/japanese-pm-sanae-takaichi-s-election-victory/106323082</link><description>A stomping victory by the ruling coalition government of Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi has opened the way for a major geo-strategic realignment in the Asia-Pacific region, with big implications for Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65ca2c9fe328e0e0981fb58f90e534b5</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106323636</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">968ecebb9b9600345e1566ed32833449</guid></item><item><title>Aussies Coady and Stalker miss the medals in big air final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/winter-olympics-day-two-live-blog-updates/106322542</link><description>Australian's Tess Coady and Mela Stalker miss the podium in the snowboard big air final, while Holly Harris and Jason Chan become the first Aussies in 12 years to represent the country in ice dancing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ab5c808eefcaa38bad83f2aee6e5fb7</guid></item><item><title>Shaun Dunk asks to be 'locked up' 15 days before alleged stabbing murder, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/shaun-dunk-asks-to-be-locked-up-weeks-before-alleged-murder/106323324</link><description>Fifteen days before he allegedly killed a woman and attempted to kill another, Shaun Michael Dunk asked to be taken into custody so he would not be a danger to anyone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">776a71d9c1219b80be2c49f508bed9c7</guid></item><item><title>Living in fear in Minneapolis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/living-in-fear-in-minneapolis/106323408</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc4855840bf345428cddb02eab5bc502</guid></item><item><title>William and Kate 'deeply concerned' about Epstein files as Andrew faces fresh scrutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/prince-william-kate-epstein-deeply-concerned-statement/106323984</link><description>The Prince and Princess of Wales say their thoughts remain focused on the victims of the late sex offender Jeffrey Epstein, in their first statement on the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d612c2a641317f685b27655f77ed980a</guid></item><item><title>Queensland health minister orders review of Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/toowoomba-hospital-maternity-unit-audit/106323798</link><description>Announcement comes after a woman reveals her support person was prevented from entering the birth suite while she was in labour by Toowoomba Hospital security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99b063ed21a492a5f313bd8e1046e624</guid></item><item><title>Maritime safety regulator investigating Carnival cruise ship after whistleblower concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/amsa-investigating-carnival-cruise-ship-exploitation-claims/106323754</link><description>The maritime union says crew members of a major Carnival cruise ship allege they are being made to sleep in crowded rooms, lack access to safe free drinking water, and that some are earning as little as $2.50 an hour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aac8562047e40499a73214ddcb3bb039</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth files defence against Linda Reynolds legal action in federal court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/commonwealth-files-defence-against-linda-reynolds-legal-action/106324034</link><description>The Commonwealth files its defence against former senator Linda Reynolds, who is suing the government and its lawyers over a $2.4 million payout it made to Brittany Higgins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">868917d636420ea166ce9e95e7cd1d3f</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Mitchell expected to batter the Gascoyne region as it moves inland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/tropical-cyclone-mitchell-has-crossed-the-wa-north-west-coast/106322566</link><description>The system is expected to bring strong winds and heavy rain as it moves inland through the Gascoyne region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16fcc5ddef3af39a7f8a479648d4aaa0</guid></item><item><title>Scottish Labour leader calls for UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer to quit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/scottish-labour-leader-calls-for-starmer-to-resign/106324396</link><description>Keir Starmer is facing calls to resign after damaging revelations about the man he picked to represent the UK in Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e65648acd6fbd0990a4a439c0fd4709</guid></item><item><title>US seizes tanker in Indian Ocean that fled Caribbean blockade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/us-seizes-tanker-in-indian-ocean-that-fled-caribbean-blockade/106324658</link><description>The Pentagon says the vessel was operating in breach of Donald Trump's orders on sanctioned ships in the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba8cb7c1e896319cb0ac6e5a847c3d01</guid></item><item><title>King stands ready to help police with Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor investigation, palace says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/king-stands-ready-to-help-police-with-andrew-mountbatten-probe/106324734</link><description>Police have confirmed they are assessing information provided to them that former prince Andrew had passed late sex offender Jeffrey Epstein confidential reports while the former royal was British trade envoy more than a decade ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07f263b143459d3f22dfef261a58e273</guid></item><item><title>What happens when a medal is shared at the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/2026-winter-olympics-shared-silver-alpine-mens-team-combined/106324230</link><description>In the men's team combined Alpine skiing event at the 2026 Winter Olympics, the Swiss and Austrian teams tied for silver. So what happens to the bronze medal? And when there was a tie for bronze in the men's ski jumping, was there a spare bronze?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23ca44a0a4bf6ec3bbf545f329db23e6</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian cartoonist Jon Kudelka and the art of cutting through political spin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/jon-kudelka-tasmanian-cartoonist-illustrator-obituary/106322196</link><description>Hailed as an artist who "knew the power of comedy in holding truth to power", Jon Kudelka once described himself as "like a monkey with an automatic rifle".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57fe9e141789e47e0247d8471e7bb6b6</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos captain Adam Reynolds holds hope of Payne Haas contract backflip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/adam-reynolds-on-payne-haas-contract-broncos-rabbitohs/106324748</link><description>Brisbane prop Payne Haas is set to arrive in England for the World Club Challenge where his teammates will try to convince him not to honour his deal with South Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26ae11679cc83fdf4ab466c033c7a4f6</guid></item><item><title>More people say they'll vote One Nation. What are they voting for?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/one-nation-policy-platforms-pauline-hanson/106296838</link><description>One Nation questions if man-made climate change is real, wants to wind back access to abortion care and plans to pay the HECS debts of doctors working in the regions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed4bdf450e353d8bca00c742667777f</guid></item><item><title>Roblox on notice after 'disturbing' reports of child grooming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/government-puts-roblox-on-notice-reports-of-child-grooming/100020788</link><description>The government puts popular social gaming site Roblox on notice following media reports of children being approached and groomed by predators on the platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17bbfe956fe95675bddb65bf1b70eaed</guid></item><item><title>Painkillers and HRT therapies among drugs not being subsidised under PBS</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/everyday-medicines-not-funded-under-the-pbs/106209526</link><description>Painkillers, HRT therapies and incontinence medicines are among the drugs that will not benefit from the new maximum $25 script price.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0be6f797e20a595543aed32d3067fce7</guid></item><item><title>St Kilda star Max King injured again, Port ruckman Ivan Soldo out for season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/st-kilda-star-max-king-injured-again-port-ruckman-season-over/106324794</link><description>Max King has suffered another injury, further frustrating the St Kilda key forward's bid for an AFL return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43a7cb7b674656d6ef9e220abeeb6274</guid></item><item><title>Shield and First Guardian collapses spur managed investment scheme crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/government-plans-managed-investment-scheme-crackdown/106323450</link><description>The federal government plans a crackdown on managed investment schemes following the collapses of Shield Master Fund and First Guardian.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f3271bc2d46cb8f82e6c8ed402d8f9c</guid></item><item><title>How AI is disrupting the tech boom on global markets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/ai-disrupts-tech-boom-shares-drop/106323844</link><description>Amongst tech investors the penny has finally dropped about just what the future may hold, and many are backing off or at least rethinking their strategy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b13e8934757ed43da4920c192cda5f8e</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan reverses cricket T20 World Cup boycott and will face India in Sri Lanka</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/pakistan-reverses-world-cup-boycott-to-face-india-t20-world-cup/106324864</link><description>Pakistan has ‍agreed to play India ​in the ⁠T20 World Cup match scheduled to take ‌place in Colombo this ‍Sunday, February 15.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d7762f897f18cee09e2bbfe5253973e</guid></item><item><title>Former ATSIC head Geoff Clark was jailed but his community says legal issues persist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/framlingham-aboriginal-trust-shares-court-fallout-geoff-clark/106305592</link><description>Former ATSIC leader Geoff Clark was jailed in 2024, yet some members of his community say legal issues linger on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec0abba8310f5f8dfa22011b1c737b70</guid></item><item><title>First national plan to address violence against Indigenous women and children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/first-nations-national-plan-domestic-violence/106321570</link><description>The first standalone national plan to tackle domestic violence against First Nations women and children was "hard fought for by Aboriginal women", an advocate says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">439229df164e08d1955a3db80571a298</guid></item><item><title>Native title holders take appeal over one of Australia's largest groundwater licences to High Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nt-high-court-singleton-station-aboriginal-groundwater-rights/106322626</link><description>The cultural value of water will be front and centre in the High Court in Canberra today as a group of native title holders from Central Australia fight to assert cultural rights over an aquifer under their lands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d334f651d8d34fed9db2b05f2f04adba</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor faces pressure to challenge for Liberal leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/angus-taylor-pressure-to-challenge-for-liberal-leadership/106324000</link><description>Liberal leadership aspirant Angus Taylor is facing pressure from conservative supporters to challenge Sussan Ley this week and end the damaging speculation paralysing the party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d731de86ca9190f9aeabd2e20ffd4bc0</guid></item><item><title>Ghislaine Maxwell will only talk if Donald Trump grants clemency, lawyer says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/ghislaine-maxwell-will-only-talk-if-trump-grants-clemency/106324720</link><description>The jailed accomplice of sex predator Jeffrey Epstein refuses to answer questions for the US Congress — but her lawyer says she will cooperate if granted clemency by the president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">204920be92b87248239c7364a66b65c0</guid></item><item><title>Margot Robbie and Jacob Elordi sizzle, but Wuthering Heights isn't quite the full Brontë</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/wuthering-heights-movie-review-emerald-fennell-jacob-elordi/106321718</link><description>The two Queensland "bogans" put on a show, but Emerald Fennell's Wuthering Heights is more wish fulfilment than a meaningful adaptation of the classic novel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41b2ef0ef990ef2113fe88e9541e3117</guid></item><item><title>States urged to sign National Water Agreement even though users unaware what's in final version</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/waters-users-in-dark-on-water-policy-ready-for-signing/106314610</link><description>As the country's state governments and territories consider signing a new national water policy that seeks to address climate change and elevate First Nations knowledge, the agriculture industry fears it has been overlooked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f8c01ea5477b908bab868e3c766d92b</guid></item><item><title>Liberal moderates propose petition for Taylor to prove support for spill — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/federal-politics-estimates-ley-albanese-taylor/106323538</link><description>Liberal Party moderates want to force Angus Taylor and his supporters to present a petition to prove he has the numbers if he wants to trigger a spill of Sussan Ley's leadership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b186062dfb8339ab9ee1c04e8b4d675f</guid></item><item><title>A nod to her Olympic legacy as former premier Annastacia Palaszczuk's portrait unveiled in parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/annastacia-palaszczuk-premier-portrait-unveiling/106323608</link><description>Former Queensland premier Annastacia Palaszczuk's parliamentary portrait contains a small nod to her Olympic legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bbc97bd35020ba6aea134be35b993af</guid></item><item><title>Swifts Creek faces tough task of reinventing itself amid job losses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/swifts-creek-future-as-logging-industry-closes/105904130</link><description>Job losses mean Swifts Creek in Victoria's High Country is facing an identity crisis, but it is not the only small town undergoing a transformation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1780877bb9a821ea5202114aac7047b9</guid></item><item><title>Premier fights back at police brutality claims as videos show violent clashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nsw-officer-defends-police-sydney-protest-israeli-herzog/106324050</link><description>Twenty-seven people were arrested, including 10 for assaulting police, on Monday night at a demonstration against Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cfd6b9b1d9072b79b7966ddbb426bc0</guid></item><item><title>ASX loses ground and CSL boss steps down — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/asx-markets-business-live-news-feb-10-2026/106322382</link><description>The ASX 200 closed slightly lower, and the CSL chief executive stepped down abruptly ahead of tomorrow's half-year results. Catch up on the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f211614caa6ae600090f629f1faef5e1</guid></item><item><title>McLaren unveils livery for MCL40 ahead of 2026 F1 season, Piastri and Norris excited about new challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/mclaren-unveil-livery-for-mcl40-ahead-of-2026-f1-season/106324952</link><description>McLaren has unveiled its livery for the 2026 Formula 1 championship season, retaining the design that helped it win championships in the previous two seasons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c712cf8881dedcdae7919ab9fe84ee12</guid></item><item><title>Jake and Chris Waterman relishing prospect of AFL Origin as Perth prepares for Victorian invasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/jake-waterman-chris-waterman-relishing-state-of-origin/106323028</link><description>WA's last State of Origin captain Chris Waterman is relishing the prospect of the concept's reboot — and can't wait to see his son Jake donning the famous black swan for the clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4e7c9262ce711480d0a666d35fb1e5a</guid></item><item><title>Savannah Guthrie makes latest video plea as missing mother's ransom deadline nears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/savannah-guthrie-makes-new-video-plea-over-missing-mother/106325066</link><description>US TV host Savannah Guthrie says her family is at its "hour of desperation" in the search for their kidnapped mother, but makes no mention of a possible ransom in a new video.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d7b80629fdda5092a47af99f45d7a10</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce taps into rural anger as One Nation eyes Coalition seats at the Victorian election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/barnaby-joyce-one-nation-eyeing-victorian-election-seats/106322072</link><description>The right-wing party's prized recruit, Barnaby Joyce, made a key appearance deep in National Party territory as the 2026 Victorian election campaign began to take shape, Richard Willingham writes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a46ca39f0081cb28359ae1fd139fc030</guid></item><item><title>Catherine O'Hara's cause of death revealed as pulmonary embolism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/catherine-ohara-cause-of-death-announced/106324996</link><description>Award-winning actress Catherine O'Hara died from a pulmonary embolism, according to her death certificate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0db2f6d1caf958e134132f56ca8ef189</guid></item><item><title>Lindsey Vonn set for multiple surgeries but denies torn ACL contributed to Winter Olympic crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/lindsey-vonn-tibia-fracture-multiple-surgeries-winter-olympics/106325232</link><description>American ski great Lindsey Vonn will "require multiple surgeries" after sustaining a tibia fracture, but denies that her previously ruptured ACL was the cause of the crash that ended her Winter Olympic Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ab4072a808dc472c68c186a6da6811b</guid></item><item><title>Border Force launches operation targeting illegal foreign fishing off Queensland coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/border-force-operation-targets-foreign-fishing-queensland-waters/106325290</link><description>Authorities announce a special effort to crack down on illegal foreign fishing boats after intercepting 10 boats in Queensland waters since New Year's Day alone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0edfcd2f222c855ac4118702da6f9305</guid></item><item><title>AI-generated social media posts like a 'snake eating its own tail'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/ai-generated-text-predictive-models-formulaic-social-media/106313944</link><description>The age of AI is here and it's going to be infinitely useful, or so they tell us, unless you're the kind of person who, like me, finds computer-generated stories infinitely boring and an insult to humanity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aec83881dfd13d38b83dd462a4442ff3</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Milano Cortina organisers looking into broken medals after at least four incidents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/winter-olympics-medals-breaking-breezy-johnson-alysa-liu/106325112</link><description>Records are meant to be broken at the Olympics, but in the Milano Cortina Games, it is the medals being dismantled, and organisers are giving it "maximum attention".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da0eeb85cc783bf52dfeec17d907e78e</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach terrorist Sajid Akram voiced support for Islamic State in 2019, former ASIO agent says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/sajid-akram-voiced-support-for-islamic-state-in-2019-ex-spy-says/106321482</link><description>Bondi Beach terrorist Sajid Akram voiced support for the Islamic State group (IS) in 2019 and expressed admiration for a leading Al Qaeda propagandist, according to accounts from two men who moved in the same extremist circles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20f66d766145bf26694aec7669da86aa</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill artist exhibits in Japan after brush with J-pop star Fujii Kaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/broken-hill-artist-exhibits-in-japan-fujii-kaze-jpop-star/106304746</link><description>When Broken Hill artist Jason McCarthur started receiving emails from Japan about his tote bags, he assumed they were a scam. But pretty soon he had sold out of the bags and it was all thanks to a J-pop star.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c060dce5346c409f34f513e185619ab</guid></item><item><title>International condemnation of new Israeli settlement measures in West Bank grows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/israeli-west-bank-settlement-draws-growing-global-condemnation/106325522</link><description>The United Nations says it is "gravely concerned" over Israeli plans to expand control over the occupied West Bank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">824876180d95cd859030497885dc8632</guid></item><item><title>Licensed program to kill native animals 'weak' and 'outdated' inquiry told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/licences-to-harm-native-animals-inquiry/106320826</link><description>Animal welfare groups are calling for a major overhaul into the system that allows native animals to be killed in NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93d7971e8816215b902c8e022b64e384</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government dismisses concerns about Fitzroy River as 2032 Brisbane Olympics venue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/rockhampton-hosting-2032-brisbane-olympic-rowing-canoeing/106325194</link><description>The future of rowing and canoeing events being held in a controversial central Queensland venue choice for the 2032 Brisbane Olympic and Paralympic Games is still being assessed by international bodies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dd08f57a7fa1e127f7449d76f3a3d2d</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Steven Bradbury clips Jake Paul as Ukrainian pays tribute — quick hits from Milano Cortina day three</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/sport-winter-olympics-qhs-day-three-jake-paul-steven-bradbury/106324398</link><description>Steven Bradbury hits Jake Paul with a drive-by as he celebrates Jutta Leerdam's Olympic gold, while a Sydney-born Kiwi receives a special celebration. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53c571d98ef2321e4d2f32391d047131</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 4, Tuesday, February 10</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-day-4matt-graham-jakara-anthony/106320694</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c39e879c6be4500d56c80aa209f85717</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast's Mona Wiggins celebrates 105th birthday with game of lawn bowls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/gold-coast-mona-wiggins-105-birthday-lawn-bowls/106325762</link><description>Mona Wiggins is showing no signs of slowing down, celebrating her 105th birthday on the bowling green.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f61dc1821573e2ccc4bbc1023166301b</guid></item><item><title>Ghislaine Maxwell was complicit in Jeffrey Epstein's abuse. Now she's pushing for clemency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/ghislaine-maxwell-fed-jeffrey-epstein-abuse-what-happens-now/105610704</link><description>Powerful socialite Ghislaine Maxwell was able to exploit her connections to recruit, groom, and abuse dozens of young girls. Now, she faces a fresh interrogation over her role in Jeffrey Epstein's abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f26e0500fb7cb1b47ab1e939f24d5ab5</guid></item><item><title>Christchurch attacker was pleased when terrorism charge laid, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/christchurch-attacker-was-pleased-when-terrorism-charge-laid/106325142</link><description>A former lawyer for the Australian who murdered 51 people at two New Zealand mosques in 2019 tells a court the shooter "never wanted to defend the terrorism charge".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8d58eeddf70df9910f81aedefca5bb4</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth asks to meet Roblox following reports of child grooming. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/commonwealth-roblox-reports-of-child-grooming/106323242</link><description>Roblox has been called to an urgent meeting with the federal government in the wake of reports that children are being groomed by predators and exposed to sexually explicit material on the popular online gaming platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8186dce135dbe17f29c38ae0b2e5a4fb</guid></item><item><title>Huon Aquaculture confirms antibiotic use in salmon hatchery on River Derwent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/huon-aquaculture-confirms-antibiotic-use-river-derwent-hatchery/106326652</link><description>There are calls for the public to be made aware of antibiotic use in Tasmania's freshwater hatcheries after Huon Aquaculture recently used oxytetracycline to treat diseased salmon without informing downstream users.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d273d5a7b3627b72a6e5120520d92c4a</guid></item><item><title>Exploitation claims have been levelled against cruise ship company Carnival. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/carnival-cruise-exploitation-claims-what-we-know/106325788</link><description>A major cruise ship has been investigated by the maritime safety regulator for claims around poor working conditions. A spokesperson for The Carnival Cruise Line says it has "nothing to hide" and welcomes AMSA's oversight. Here's what we know so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fb766396c9c7d4da6c405ce6634ae51</guid></item><item><title>Baldivis man Jason William Forbes jailed for planning to abduct and abuse child after buying child sex dolls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/perth-man-jailed-over-planned-child-abduction-and-abuse/106326902</link><description>A Perth man who planned to abduct and abuse a child, having scoped out schools and childcare centres and researched restraint methods, is jailed for seven years. Warning: This story contains details that some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">708aa361649907ffe5a33163651eb958</guid></item><item><title>Sydney man avoids jail over 'abhorrent' social media posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nsw-man-avoids-jail-over-threatening-pm-via-social-media-posts/106326690</link><description>A Sydney man who made "abhorrent" social media posts that promoted sexual violence and threatened the prime minister has been spared time in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17d442d03f2268671f08f95e7ebe2047</guid></item><item><title>Mackay MP Nigel Dalton crosses the floor to oppose LNP ban on abortion debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nigel-dalton-crosses-floor-opposing-lnp-abortion-debate-ban/106327032</link><description>First-term Liberal National Party MP Nigel Dalton votes to overturn a ban on debating abortion — in defiance of his party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c85acc349c94f7e5ef78c2f5a8611f2</guid></item><item><title>Chappell Roan no longer represented by talent agency led by Casey Wasserman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/chappell-roan-no-longer-represented-by-casey-wasserman/106327330</link><description>Pop star Chappell Roan says she is no longer represented by the talent agency led by Los Angeles 2028 Olympics chief Casey Wasserman, who has faced criticism for flirtatious email exchanges with convicted sex trafficker Ghislaine Maxwell more than 20 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfd514ef3d53768e08f6b605a9551524</guid></item><item><title>Grace Tame criticised for leading intifada chants at Sydney protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/grace-tame-criticised-for-sydney-protest-intifada-chant/106326896</link><description>Grace Tame accuses Australia of being "a so-called democracy" that punishes peaceful protesters, before chanting "from Gadigal to Gaza, globalise the intifada!"</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9dc912a9d76603ba103ace6885715f4</guid></item><item><title>Deadline looms for Warren Tredrea to pay Nine's legal costs after failed appeal against unfair dismissal case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/warren-treadrea-deadline-to-pay-legal-costs-to-nine/106326298</link><description>Former footballer Warren Tredrea has an imminent deadline to pay $149,000 to his former employer, Channel Nine, following a failed appeal against an unfair dismissal case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8204048fc3858d5ea8943a955cc6d4ba</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after police allegedly find more than 125,000 files of child abuse material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/child-abuse-material-police-tocumwal-gary-maude/106325362</link><description>A man appears in court after police officers seize a mobile and laptop with allegedly more than 125,000 files of child abuse material.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1937df9d2e4d8ae0dc9b5b60d38a4914</guid></item><item><title>Tocumwal arrest over child abuse material.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/tocumwal-arrest-over-child-abuse-material/106325300</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46969e7cbc1d1f9b85ef170990e9cbe5</guid></item><item><title>At school, I was my brother's protector. But I needed more support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/support-i-wish-i-had-at-school-while-caring-for-my-brother/106279156</link><description>I was my brother's protector at school, but the education system could have done more to support us both.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8737a14dea75637ab0e525bab21121a9</guid></item><item><title>Global Athlete accuses IOC of 'kowtowing' to Russia by including AIN athletes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/russian-winter-olympic-athletes-milan-cortina/106327282</link><description>Advocacy group Global Athlete has accused the IOC of enabling Russia by allowing 13 Russian and seven Belarusian athletes to compete at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c9a39c00f74fc512b507557d2b1ac8f</guid></item><item><title>Craig Goodwin's World Cup hopes cop hammer blow after groin injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/craig-goodwin-s-world-cup-hopes-dashed/106327940</link><description>He was one of the Socceroos best in Qatar but now Craig Goodwin will need a minor miracle to make this year's World Cup after the veteran suffered a groin injury for Adelaide United that will sideline him for some time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">832f24e225d388d7831d181361338c99</guid></item><item><title>Dry conditions, heat and high winds combine for another day of high fire danger in Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/victoria-hot-weather-warning/106326392</link><description>Victoria's parched landscape has authorities concerned amid forecasts of another day of heat and gusty winds across the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5ee5fc4f0573fa9ad8061629a612008</guid></item><item><title>Shark filmed in deep Antarctic waters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/shark-filmed-in-deep-antarctic-waters/106321640</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4eb3f0f8027a13b7cb77a572c9acacff</guid></item><item><title>Elvis Presley 'unguarded' in unseen footage used in new Baz Luhrmann film</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/elvis-presley-unguarded-in-unseen-footage-in-baz-luhrmann-film/106327408</link><description>When director Baz Luhrmann and his team uncovered hours of previously unseen Elvis Presley recordings, Luhrmann abandoned his original plans, deciding to "get out of the way" and let Presley tell his own story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18a8befc1c6399e513d75719298bd33a</guid></item><item><title>Tahmoor Coal placed into administration as court hears creditor winding-up bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/tahmoor-coal-mine-placed-into-voluntary-administration/106326534</link><description>Tahmoor Coal has been placed into voluntary administration just as the Supreme Court was set to hear a creditor's winding-up application.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">953d7d3b73b007feb1525c6e38b10dea</guid></item><item><title>Trucking industry calls out misuse of roadside parking bays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/trucking-industry-calls-out-practice-of-parking-up-in-rest-bays/106325882</link><description>Advocates within the trucking industry are saying misuse of roadside parking bays is putting fatigued drivers at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da55c6eeabd74b3bcad83a6145b28d64</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government appoints tenderers for new oil and gas exploration in Taroom Trough</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/oil-gas-exploration-queensland-taroom-trough/106325922</link><description>The Queensland government approves new oil and gas exploration in a region they believe could become Australia's first new major oil province in 50 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ce99f23603aeb7aa96f732ac4f261b6</guid></item><item><title>Ex-student tells court of pregnancy scare after alleged abuse by Hobart Matriculation College teacher</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/hobart-matriculation-college-former-student-gives-evidence-rape/106326618</link><description>When recounting the first time her former teacher allegedly raped her, the woman told the court he was "like a big monster" on top of her and she "could hardly breathe". The woman is suing both her former teacher and the State of Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffa175ff6b6b2b70b45b9744a5d361fb</guid></item><item><title>Grandparents among those injured in Sydney protest against Israeli President Isaac Herzog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/sydney-protesters-injured-at-isaac-herzog-protest-speak-out/106327578</link><description>A Sydney grandmother says she suffered four broken vertebrae after being "violently" pushed to the ground while trying to leave a protest on Monday night. Warning: This story contains images some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60eb786629ff095fd9a4742e988eaefd</guid></item><item><title>As many as 209 jobs to go from Telstra AI joint venture with Accenture, moving roles to India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/telstra-to-scrap-ai-joint-venture/106328648</link><description>The Telstra joint venture said this move will "bring an enhanced experience" to its customers, but did not make clear how many jobs in the joint venture (JV) are set to be moved to India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7039873facfcd9aa5d3ba0d87b3603de</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106326714</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f1e6a5abe89487f45e90e88fb30e856</guid></item><item><title>Cam Bolton fractures neck as training falls rule two Aussies out of Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/winter-olympics-2026-live-milano-cortina-moguls-ice-hockey/106326694</link><description>Australia's Cam Bolton and Misaki Vaughan are ruled out of the Games after training falls, while reigning Olympic gold medallist Jakara Anthony advances to the women's moguls final at the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf10d0c49b40e45eace54bd9ee12cefa</guid></item><item><title>Australian government puts pressure on Lao authorities over methanol poisoning deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/methanol-poisoning-holly-bowles-bianca-morton-jones-laos/106328530</link><description>The Australian government calls in the Lao ambassador in Canberra, amid criticism of the country's response to a fatal methanol poisoning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc5e186c3bcd06980d9bd00b9b489bd6</guid></item><item><title>Former NT police officer James Kirstenfeldt sentenced on drink driving, weapons offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nt-james-kirstenfeldt-sentenced-drink-driving-weapons-charges/106313314</link><description>A former Northern Territory police officer has been ordered to pay almost $5,000 in fines and undergo supervised treatment for post-traumatic stress disorder after drunkenly crashing his car outside his suburban Darwin home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94f3ae08a6978aeffd227f1b28acd709</guid></item><item><title>Police and protesters clash at Sydney rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/police-and-protesters-clash-at-sydney-rally/106328248</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f55f1c97776896a8ad1d17829bab966</guid></item><item><title>Queensland police commissioner Steve Gollschewski set to retire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/qld-police-commissioner-steve-gollschewski-to-retire/106328730</link><description>Queensland's top cop Steve Gollschewski is set to retire after almost 50 years in the service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed23f80208e7161490469778dd73a42a</guid></item><item><title>Health warnings about ultra-processed foods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/health-warnings-about-ultra-processed-foods/106328288</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52af8963f7db51a368846c06aa60a304</guid></item><item><title>Liberals plot resignations to pave way for leadership challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/liberals-plot-mass-resignation-to-force-leadership-spill-/106328762</link><description>Liberals are bracing for a wave of frontbench resignations as soon as Wednesday to pave the way for Angus Taylor to mount a leadership challenge against Sussan Ley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68227eb101c335608129c57bdf313d7f</guid></item><item><title>WA police investigate possible tobacco wars link to fire at Kelmscott store</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/fire-alleged-linked-to-illicit-tobacco-under-investigation/106325512</link><description>WA Police Commissioner Col Blanch confirms officers from Taskforce Maverick, which investigates crime linked to the illicit tobacco and vape trade, are involved with the investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c193a813072c7da9378b52e50d8e27c3</guid></item><item><title>Celine Cremer search in Arthur River finds more bones and missing backpacker's car key</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/car-key-teeth-found-search-celine-cremer-tasmania/106323260</link><description>Tasmania Police say a car key found in the Arthur River has been "formally verified" as belonging to missing backpacker Celine Cremer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f44f7b3c1d64c6fe98c04e84cabd033d</guid></item><item><title>Three key moments in police clashes with Sydney protesters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nsw-police-israel-herzog-protest-town-hall-key-moments/106325680</link><description>Competing narratives have emerged from NSW Police and protesters who were at Monday night's demonstration near Sydney's Town Hall. ABC NEWS Verify has gathered footage and spoken to witnesses in an early attempt to examine what happened in detail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55bfcaef3544b431846d0937470d213b</guid></item><item><title>Waterfalls on Uluru, Daly River flooding peaks as rain soaks Central Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nt-weather-rainfall-uluru-daly-river-flooding/106326436</link><description>Heavy rain in Central Australia has sent water cascading down the face of Uluru and filled the usually parched Todd River, while cutting off a number of remote communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">154698806a27d58e8b258474e05ea7dd</guid></item><item><title>Bulk-billing rates rebound on back of government's multi-billion-dollar policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/bulk-billing-rates-rebound-after-multi-billion-dollar-investment/106327456</link><description>Bulk-billing rates have rebounded in the first clear measure of the impact of the government's multi-billion-dollar pledge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d77c00d7ce459a8883fdcf39108f49f</guid></item><item><title>Rental affordability hits record low as rents rise 2.5 times faster than wages, analysis shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/rental-affordability-rents-rise-faster-than-wages-cotality/106327364</link><description>Tenants now pay an average of 33.4 per cent of their pre-tax income on rent, which is the highest level on record, according to a property research firm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6fc06f379d9dabc4c56af45e59d226cc</guid></item><item><title>ASIO ordered independent review into Bondi terror case, stands by 2019 assessment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/asio-ordered-independent-review-into-bondi-terror-case/106329140</link><description>The nation's top spy has welcomed a royal commission into the Bondi terror attack, vowing to "own any mistakes" uncovered by the probe as his agency comes under pressure over whether the tragedy could have been prevented.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29ab83ff049297eda1f7acea4b877675</guid></item><item><title>The desperate toll of Australia's 2026 Winter Olympic Games injury chaos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/australian-injury-hell-at-2026-winter-olympic-games/106329260</link><description>Games-ending injuries to Cam Bolton and Misaki Vaughan have emphasised the dangers of winter sport as the Australian team copes with issues early in the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f1a5314017e313b221ef7737afe9b23</guid></item><item><title>Israel tightens grip over West Bank while Herzog visits Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/isaac-herzog-visit-protest-police-west-bank-annexation/106325902</link><description>While Israeli President Isaac Herzog visited Sydney, his government was taking concrete actions in the West Bank designed to "continue to kill the idea of a Palestinian state".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">728001663fca5f0a0371d55a7b3d1249</guid></item><item><title>FBI releases surveillance pictures of masked man at Nancy Guthrie's home on morning she disappeared</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/fbi-release-pictures-of-masked-man-at-nancy-guthries-home/106329322</link><description>FBI director Kash Patel has posted the images on social media, saying they had been recovered after days of work by investigators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">728b1ecdd6098f978fa86fe8a55eede2</guid></item><item><title>Protesters were punched, pushed, and arrested but were NSW Police actions excessive?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/verify-police-use-of-force-town-hall-protest/106328358</link><description>What is reasonable? It's a question being asked by some after footage of clashes in Sydney's CBD, during a rally against Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc032833c827cf116d697c6b10faca22</guid></item><item><title>The Epstein files are shaking Britain, but Donald Trump could still have 3 million reasons to worry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/epstein-files-shake-uk-but-white-house-could-still-be-worried/106324788</link><description>Donald Trump's enemies made no secret of their hopes the documents would contain something explosive enough to bring the president down, but right now the Epstein spotlight is on Britain's politicians and palaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd62bb34a29f437c14df3ee1992e6c76</guid></item><item><title>Uber quietly agrees to external review after woman sues over guide dog refusals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/uber-agrees-to-review-after-guide-dog-refusal-case/106307858</link><description>Uber quietly agrees to an external review of its Australian operations after settling a Federal Court case brought by a woman refused more than 30 rides while travelling with a guide dog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7dae27423705f7913b0c26f0c1f43a5</guid></item><item><title>Iran's rulers face 'defections and disobedience', but will it be enough to topple the regime?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/amid-us-iran-nuclear-talks-will-defections-spark-regime-change/106323120</link><description>As talks between Washington and Tehran over a nuclear deal continue, fractures within the regime are starting to emerge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec8f5a39abe057d153a273869091cc1d</guid></item><item><title>Jaraka Anthony picture perfect, Matt Graham with room to improve at 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games moguls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/jakara-anthony-matt-graham-pressure-moguls-qualifiers/106324214</link><description>Jakara Anthony will do anything aside from thinking about moguls skiing after qualifying number one for Wednesday's 2026 Winter Olympics final, taking to Lego, a puzzle and Grey's Anatomy instead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c5b1f5d3da4862fb201d76474dc2318</guid></item><item><title>High-rise apartments at remaining activity centres mapped across Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/activity-centre-building-heights-map-melbourne-housing/106327152</link><description>The state government releases draft maps of the remaining activity centres around Melbourne that show apartments of up to 20 storeys could be built in the south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9ef5299484ca6bffb9bd43f18cad423</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberals face wipeout not seen since state bank election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/sa-liberals-face-wipeout-not-seen-since-state-bank-election/106325582</link><description>Labor faced a humiliating election loss following the state bank collapse in the early 90s. Now, recent polling shows a collapse of another kind could be brewing for the Liberal Party with One Nation hot on its heels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d37b7dfeb9d62359f82edf2221b3e29</guid></item><item><title>How 'capacity constraints' are linked to inflation and your hip pocket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/what-are-capacity-constraints-economic-growth-inflation-rba/106322390</link><description>It may sound boring, but "capacity constraints" are to blame for your higher mortgage repayments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">945ab804992cc48ca6c41e4f4a2a3d57</guid></item><item><title>Food ministers move closer to mandating Health Star Ratings on packaged food</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/move-to-mandate-health-star-ratings-on-food-and-drink/106231700</link><description>The nation's food ministers will this week take a crucial step towards mandating the Health Star Rating scheme on packaged food products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d49aa89b821cfcbaa27037bef0288134</guid></item><item><title>How to reduce loneliness while working remotely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/how-to-reduce-loneliness-while-working-remotely/106286338</link><description>Working remotely can be a lonely experience. Here's what you can do about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07ee38b05fb1af72edee6be374ac35ed</guid></item><item><title>Hume City Council wants action over thousands of tyres dumped in Melbourne's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/illegal-tyre-dumping-and-hume-council-action/106328912</link><description>A council in Melbourne's north wants the federal government to establish a free tyre recycling scheme to stop thousands of tyres being dumped, causing a potential environmental hazard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1abf383c1d01a41e7eb877b26adf62af</guid></item><item><title>Developers desert plans for new apartments in Sydney's west due to construction costs and interest rates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/developers-desert-plans-for-new-apartments-in-western-sydney/106326624</link><description>Industry peak bodies and economists blame mounting construction costs and rising interest rates for the stalling of new apartment projects in Western Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08c76145b471efc377a5aa92fa2ed07e</guid></item><item><title>Loved ones left behind after voluntary assisted dying say more support is needed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/loved-ones-left-behind-after-vad-say-more-support-needed/106273606</link><description>A voluntary assisted dying legislation review considers feedback from families of people who ended their life through the program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6a434c3f961ccbd4ea9c5d373a28ee2</guid></item><item><title>Travel quiz, February 11: Which Spanish city hosts a tomato-throwing festival?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/travel-quiz/106251040</link><description>Which European country has no McDonalds? And where's Australia's most western point?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47821408bf3d55cc98b44a62c5659000</guid></item><item><title>Buoyed by global culture juggernauts, the Australian K-pop community has 'exploded' in popularity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/kpop-community-grows-thanks-to-bts-demon-hunters/106325884</link><description>Members of the Australian K-pop community say pop acts and blockbuster films are contributing to the local scene "soaring".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d04497a71176e54746c0307a2d07bd48</guid></item><item><title>Aging stormwater infrastructure could cause issues building more medium-density housing in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/act-stormwater-infrastructure-pressing-question-housing-plan/106328498</link><description>The government wants to build more medium-density housing in Canberra to accommodate a growing population — but with a changing climate some worry the city's infrastructure, including stormwater systems, does not have the capacity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">242deb9fb5a37e9e9cc297fc6b807649</guid></item><item><title>Cricket umpire numbers rise since COVID, but regions still in 'dire' need</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/victorian-cricket-umpires-referee-shortage/106313892</link><description>Cricket umpire numbers increase significantly in Victoria, but some regions remain in desperate need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c25e208a1280b6ca42f95914eb0b617</guid></item><item><title>E-bike seller uses fake compliance stickers to skirt crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/e-bike-sellers-fake-compliance-stickers-crackdown/106285924</link><description>An e-bike seller agrees to help a buyer avoid police detection by putting fake compliance stickers on high-powered bikes to make them look road legal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31811725e3a6430e79fad369e543aa70</guid></item><item><title>Live: Police presence beefed up as Herzog arrives in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/federal-politics-estimates-albanese-ley-herzog/106328310</link><description>ACT police say a "significant police presence" will be ready in Canberra for Israeli President Isaac Herzog's arrival. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9652a4c3a8e2cd737e83d0b30398df6</guid></item><item><title>Australian T20 World Cup squad looks different but do not count it out, Mitch Marsh says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/injury-hit-australia-open-t20-world-cup-campaign-against-ireland/106329438</link><description>Despite a slew of key injuries leaving the Australian team unrecognisable, captain Mitch Marsh is confident about the experience left in the side.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e7e79b7afbfde0a033b919098cc0b12</guid></item><item><title>Limestone Coast hospital's staff shortage in spotlight after former administrator's fall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/limestone-coast-hospital-staff-shortage/106318896</link><description>David Walshaw spent 20 years looking after the Limestone Coast's hospitals, but a fall made him realise the system was failing patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63b01408b05a077885b47352dd28bbdc</guid></item><item><title>Live: Commonwealth Bank profit beats expectations, rising to $5.4b</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/asx-markets-business-live-news-february-11/106322798</link><description>The Australian share market is likely to rise ahead of the first big day of reporting season. Some of the nation's largest companies, such as Commonwealth Bank, CSL and AGL Energy, are reporting. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81edd0aee0be4606cfe44b95d5c351fb</guid></item><item><title>Surgeon Kelvin Kong's life growing up Chinese and Indigenous in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/kelvin-kong-s-growing-up-chinese-and-indigenous-australia/106326388</link><description>Australia's first identified First Nations surgeon, Dr Kelvin Kong spoke about his Malaysian Chinese heritage during the annual Wang Gungwu lecture at Parliament House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3366e9b48200b228bb48ce12f315720</guid></item><item><title>Citizen scientists work on 100-million-year-old ichthyosaur fossil in Winton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/ichthyosaur-winton-australian-age-of-dinosaurs-fossil/106310754</link><description>Participants from across Australia and the world travelled to outback Queensland to clean up the near-complete ichthyosaur fossil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af8a6ea34ab1f32371b167c057d77dd9</guid></item><item><title>Images of alleged tobacco wars kingpin Kazem Hamad released in Iraq</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/images-of-kazem-hamad-released-by-afp/106329460</link><description>Hamad was deported from Australia in 2023 and has been a key person of interest relating to firebombings at Victorian tobacco shops and businesses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e824b5d9e2cfb1c10502ba2cb1ccb7d</guid></item><item><title>US immigration bosses questioned over Donald Trump's ICE crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/ice-customs-border-patrol-heads-questioned-by-congress/106329244</link><description>Democrats level a litany of complaints against the heads of America's immigration agencies during a rare hearing in Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e5254a2eb076a02d850dc833ae45c0c</guid></item><item><title>Trump told police chief 'everyone' knew about Epstein, FBI document says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/trump-commerce-chief-claims-no-relationship-with-epstein/106329468</link><description>Donald Trump allegedly told police in 2006 that people in New York knew about Epstein, a newly uncovered FBI interview shows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3c205dcd4860dd580cc592880560660</guid></item><item><title>Five-year-old girl killed in ATV rollover on Queensland’s Western Downs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/girl-5-killed-atv-rollover-queensland-property/106329550</link><description>A young girl has died and a boy has been injured after an ATV rolled on a rural property near Chinchilla on Tuesday evening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdda000adf2d614bb5aca14a04fad009</guid></item><item><title>Volunteers say neglect by state's wildlife department caused bushfires on WA's south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/fitzgerald-river-bushfire-dbca-mismanagement/106321810</link><description>Farmers and volunteer firefighters say decades of neglect by WA's Department of Biodiversity, Conservation and Attractions is at the heart of fires that ripped through more than 200,000 hectares of state-managed land.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40f45582a4045e521119758ac54edc75</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Stunning cheating admission overshadows medal win as Naumov brings tears with tribute — quick hits from day four</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/sport-quick-hits-winter-olympics-day-four-cheating-nauov-tribute/106329142</link><description>A Norwegian's first-ever medal is overshadowed by a stunning admission to reporters as Maxim Naumov pays tribute to his parents in the most beautiful way. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4ddae6dcef41de86448ed66a84d4881</guid></item><item><title>Western quoll joey born in outback NSW likely to be first in a century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/western-quoll-thrive-outback-nsw-after-taronga-program/106304882</link><description>Once thought to be extinct in NSW, the small, spotted, and highly photogenic western quoll is making a hard-fought comeback to the wild.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1127d8b0dfa1ad403186fda2e24d1f68</guid></item><item><title>Fateful wrong turn, quiet cancer battle possible factors in missing prospector's suspected death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/barry-podmore-inquest-potential-wrong-turn/106328254</link><description>An inquest into Barry Podmore's disappearance in WA's remote Midwest hears the 73-year-old faced significant health challenges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70fd4d4de62cfa6ad418be560e1027f2</guid></item><item><title>Queensland hospital data shows e-scooter injuries escalate to five per day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/queensland-e-scooter-injuries-escalate-hospital-data-shows/106329602</link><description>New state hospital data shows more than five Queenslanders per day end up in the emergency department with injuries like bone fractures due to e-scooters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">471f0aff695e4a49c8bf9bc9c4fc44b6</guid></item></channel></rss>