<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 21:30:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The Agent Inside</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/the-agent-inside/105198860</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe5267caa680beaa0cc4c1c6c2a8a4fc</guid></item><item><title>Vulnerable youth non-for-profit Allambi Care agrees to end 'unacceptable' housing scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-19/allambi-care-investment-property-scheme-to-end-nsw-mp-says/105670898</link><description>Not-for-profit Allambi Care was named during a budget estimates hearing on Tuesday as the subject of a redacted forensic auditor's report tabled in parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70bb988bd6c0bcd21407f5efa058a67d</guid></item><item><title>Victorian bushfire evacuees buoyed by community kindness amid Grampians bushfires</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-12-28/victoria-grampians-bushfire-community-kindness-christmas/104766794</link><description>Amid the turmoil of evacuations, residents in western Victoria have provided shelter, food and Christmas cheer to those in need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e84f98d6e3d3883f3a25d66bc846690</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu earthquake to 'stretch thin' country's recovery from cascading disasters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-12-22/vanuatu-earthquake-recovery-effort/104747600</link><description>People in Vanuatu applaud its latest show of resilience following a deadly magnitude-7.3 earthquake, but they say it can't respond to its cascading natural disasters alone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f11abae1624043e7770a8e9aa158d217</guid></item><item><title>Mother of asthmatic son calls for more transparency from SA Health regarding algal bloom advice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/sa-mum-calls-for-stronger-algal-bloom-health-advice/105759034</link><description>A South Australian mother of a teenager with asthma says it was "irresponsible" of health authorities not to communicate updated advice more widely, amid the state's harmful algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f10573b27e0d244d55214357458c046c</guid></item><item><title>Speech therapy books reach regional kids one laminated sticker at a time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2022-01-01/tamworth-therapist-labels-books-to-improve-kids-speech/100702932</link><description>Speech pathologist Kelly Makepeace is labelling books at her local library with an important purpose for kids.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db2d958cc3b88ca72e1de3414a6ad13d</guid></item><item><title>MP Gareth Ward resigns ahead of NSW parliament vote to expel convicted sex offender</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-08/mp-gareth-ward-resigns-ahead-of-parliament-expulsion-vote/105627050</link><description>After the convicted sex offender lost his bid on Thursday to stop the NSW parliament expulsion, Gareth Ward resigned from his position as minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b6b624dfa26c54f1a52c6aa4c1c2ca</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle childcare centre failed to promptly report serious fall, regulator says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-27/busy-bees-newcastle-childcare-centre-claims-budget-estimates/105702756</link><description>Busy Bees New Lambton failed to report a serious fall until a child presented to hospital nearly a month later with a fractured skull, budget estimates has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">384ffbfcc051ede3b8bbae7d138297fe</guid></item><item><title>Whales and dolphins at play</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-12/whales-and-dolphins-at-play/105642668</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3268fbcc54df345b040d9142f65d8c42</guid></item><item><title>ENT surgeon speaks out on World Hearing Day on lifelong impact of COVID surgical delays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2022-03-03/fear-for-childhood-deafness-amid-covid-surgery-halt/100872122</link><description>It's World Hearing Day, but concerns remain about a spate of avoidable childhood deafness due to delays in non-urgent surgery in response to the pandemic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c02f9e11099c6143db92e988cffe991d</guid></item><item><title>Ancient Dreamtime stories kept alive in colourful Wyndham puppet show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-05/a-river-is-born-puppet-show-tells-dreamtime-stories-wyndham/105105470</link><description>An entire community helps bring to life a giant puppet show, telling ancient stories of creation, in Western Australia's northernmost town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f7c88da8a720ee67f8a1ef7c1d71009</guid></item><item><title>Inquest hears NT police repeatedly overlooked warnings before Kumanjayi Emitja's DV-related death in Alice Springs</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-30/kumanjayi-emitja-nt-coronial-inquest-finishes-in-alice-springs/105711364</link><description>A 24-year-old Indigenous woman who died after being hit by a car following a violent attack by her partner was failed by police multiple times in the lead-up to her death, the Northern Territory coroner has heard during a week-long inquest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f621fb233e92edc1121ca36e29885f55</guid></item><item><title>NT government exempts US military fuel tanks built unlawfully on Darwin Harbour from certification</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-05/nt-us-military-fuel-tanks-darwin-government-exemption-foi/105736876</link><description>The Northern Territory government has exempted 11 massive US military fuel tanks built unlawfully on Darwin Harbour from needing occupancy certification.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">281cf1a6cd78c0d9604e9924c954ffed</guid></item><item><title>How to prepare your pet for their first in-cabin flight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-23/how-to-prepare-small-pets-for-in-cabin-flights-virgin/105677280</link><description>Some pet owners will soon be able to fly with their cat or dog on some domestic routes. Here's how to prepare your pet for busy airports and in-cabin flights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f91107702911fca5d19b5b6409a6f199</guid></item><item><title>The submerged world under the old Rapid Bay Jetty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-24/submerged-world-under-rapid-bay-jetty/105680578</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e2607d34670f20a87ccca75c06b6a1f</guid></item><item><title>What it means to have your song 'KPopped': Kylie Minogue, the Spice Girls and Boy George find out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-21/kylie-minogue-spice-girls-boy-george-among-stars-kpopped/105680836</link><description>A new music show, in which global icons team up with K-pop idols to have their songs "KPopped", features Australian pop princess Kylie Minogue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7779b09eec1b622d057f92f584dd34f9</guid></item><item><title>Liberal says no moves to replace Ley as leader after Nampijinpa Price sacking — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/federal-politics-september-11/105759138</link><description>Shadow Home Affairs Minister Andrew Hastie says there are no moves in the Liberal Party to replace Opposition Leader Sussan Ley after Jacinta Nampijinpa Price's sacking yesterday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc8ed10ec1b1dfbeebae906c2a866d07</guid></item><item><title>Man shot by police outside Wynnum West house fire charged with attempted murder and arson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/qld-wynnum-west-police-shooting-attempted-murder-arson/105760374</link><description>Emergency services were called to Cabanda Street in Wynnum West on Tuesday morning where they found the two-storey house on fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1557a15e2a01d9f2d96686d71c3fa593</guid></item><item><title>Fight against fire ants at tipping point</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-21/fire-ants/105556792</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7d801d508ee9a59d2482272a10e6512</guid></item><item><title>NRLW wrap: Brisbane Broncos thrash the Cowboys 50-4, Gold Coast grab last finals spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/upton-hat-trick-leads-broncos-to-big-nrlw-win-over-cowboys/105770416</link><description>It's a big day for Queensland sides in the NRLW, as the Broncos — led by skipper Tamika Upton — are far too good for the third-placed Cowboys, while the Titans clinch the last finals spot with a win over Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0af6a0f9bdb8ae75a28c6c7e963ce856</guid></item><item><title>Former Queensland police officer Ross Kouimanis behind bars for child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-12/former-police-officer-ross-kouimanis-jailed-for-child-sex-abuse/105274736</link><description>Ex-Queensland police officer Ross Kouimanis is now behind bars for the rape and assault of a child in the 1990s. The survivor of the abuse says he carried a silent burden for decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8990b41a69f24e028e338cc05fd93be1</guid></item><item><title>Australian Border Force officers find drugs, cash, animal products, weapons at Queensland airports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-11-14/australian-border-force-seized-drugs-cash-animal-products-weapon/104541676</link><description>The ABC was granted rare access to official operations at Gold Coast Airport, where passengers are searched for illegal weapons, drugs and animal products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">280d16dc13bb3b45ef1a7ed5164ab860</guid></item><item><title>Athlete Claudia Hollingsworth prepares for World Championships in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/athlete-claudia-hollingsworth-prepares-for-world/105755400</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88fe79472cae00da34c77b3394352050</guid></item><item><title>Your coronavirus COVID-19 questions. Tell us what you want to know and we'll find the answers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2021-06-11/coronavirus-questions-page/100200936</link><description>Do you have a question about coronavirus? Tell us what you want to know and we'll try to provide you with answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc7ddb9767df9271d02ba416a6d1516c</guid></item><item><title>Police search for weapon allegedly used in Gold Coast shooting</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-01-09/police-search-for-shotgun-allegedly-used-in-gold-coast-shooting/104799514</link><description>Police are still searching for the weapon allegedly used to shoot a woman in the back at a Gold Coast property on Wednesday. The 33-year-old remains in hospital in a critical condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d49ae134098c6e4ec275b29da47f2ccc</guid></item><item><title>Australia on alert to shot-hole borer threat as WA pivots to tree canopy rehabilitation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/shot-hole-borer-tree-threat-australia/105740250</link><description>It's barely the size of a sesame seed, but the shot-hole borer has quickly devastated Western Australia's tree canopy. Experts are warning other states and territories to take action now to avoid a similar fate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aea657a36513f410d730aac2a0066292</guid></item><item><title>Graduates in 'debt vortex' as HECS front and centre for first time in an election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-16/federal-election-2025-hecs-student-debt-policies/105177248</link><description>New research shows a sharp rise in HECS debts, despite graduate earning power declining, as student loans become a potent election issue for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48707ffafbe02c400b1200e6269fd40e</guid></item><item><title>Mobile coverage is an election issue in regional areas. What's been promised?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-23/telecommunications-mobile-coverage-federal-election-promises/105080674</link><description>For many regional and remote Australians, reliable mobile coverage can be life-saving. They are desperate for both sides of politics to take meaningful action towards eliminating black spots.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ceda72e552d98e5f293d3c037efeefa</guid></item><item><title>Artists and users boycotting Spotify over AI use and CEO's military tech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/spotify-boycott-daniel-ek-ai-music-military-tech-fenn-wilson/105765846</link><description>A growing number of artists and users are leaving Spotify. What's changed with the streaming giant? And what comes next?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dce4c940b969890ecfdfb4e37ad98c9</guid></item><item><title>Lord Howe Island detection dog Sebbi retires to Brisbane after years of 'hard work'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/lord-howe-island-sniffer-dog-sebbi-retires-to-brisbane/105762486</link><description>It might be hard to leave the one of the most idyllic places in Australia, but it is not a case of paradise lost for this retiring pest-hunting pooch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee308da8fc9e5d16b127301e912ff08d</guid></item><item><title>The simple system I use for composting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/simple-system-use-for-composting/105648580</link><description>Koren Helbig has devised an easy and effective method of turning her food waste and plant trimmings into a nutrient-rich compost for her Adelaide/Tarntanya food gardens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79967d2cf242f317c83d0a075a76ca87</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government pours $12 billion into expanding AUKUS defence facility near Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/albanese-announces-aukus-12-billion-dollar-defence-spend-perth/105770188</link><description>The Albanese government will spend $12 billion on building a submarine and naval shipbuilding facility south of Perth under AUKUS, as doubts linger over the agreement's future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">420e959c71ffce19abd7eac4b8f6483e</guid></item><item><title>Who was Charlie Kirk, the MAGA podcaster and Trump ally shot dead in Utah?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/charlie-kirk-who-helped-build-support-for-donald-trump-dies/105760300</link><description>Charlie Kirk rose from a teenage conservative campus activist to a top podcaster, culture warrior and ally of US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cb5074e50db73965f4aeed9b76eb196</guid></item><item><title>Evidence points to remains found in Vietnam cave being South-East Asia's earliest known homicide victim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/vietnam-remains-earliest-known-homicide-victim-cold-case/105741956</link><description>It was on a sweltering morning in 2018 in a cave in northern Vietnam when Chris Stimpson and his team uncovered what may be the oldest cold case murder in South-East Asia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34f92776d6167c167af22a4b170f6648</guid></item><item><title>Right-wing activist and Trump ally Charlie Kirk shot dead at Utah university</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/charlie-kirk-shot-utah-university-event/105418226</link><description>Donald Trump confirms Charlie Kirk has been shot dead in front of a crowd of horrified students, with the US president describing the conservative activist as a "tremendous person" and a "very good friend".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ea200333d2037582fb4799f0fc34d4d</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou begins Nottingham Forest tenure with 3-0 loss to Arsenal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/premier-league-ange-postecoglou-nottingham-forest-arsenal/105771400</link><description>Ange Postecoglou promises a quick response after a brutal re-introduction to the Premier League, with Nottingham Forest defeated by Arsenal 3-0.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47dc173ed01cdc7fdedea1bd2ba5acdc</guid></item><item><title>Advocates call for action on brain health as AIHW reveals dementia is leading cause of death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/australians-dying-from-dementia-more-than-any-other-cause/105768682</link><description>Advocates warn the number of people with the condition could exceed 1 million without government intervention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b35bf8bb29f6390428b007c4fc10877</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump and his 'good man' Anthony Albanese share some common ground</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/donald-trump-anthony-albanese-common/105756898</link><description>The MAGA president's grip on the Republican party is near total while Albanese holds a sway over his left-leaning caucus like few of his Labor predecessors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88bb570d5f115243764edac358fd6925</guid></item><item><title>Labor win Kiama by-election as voters replace disgraced MP Gareth Ward</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/kiama-byelection-polls-close-votes-counting/105770414</link><description>The NSW Premier said Kiama now has the ear of the government after it claimed victory in the by-election triggered by the resignation of convicted rapist Gareth Ward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f8148eb8e329e6cf74190c6118a0a8f</guid></item><item><title>From Formula One to creating the 'world's best' croissant, how baking saved Lune founder Kate Reid's life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/cars-to-croissants-kate-reid-and-the-lune-empire/105750472</link><description>Kate Reid's Lune croissants have been called the world's best. But how did a young woman struggling with a near-fatal eating disorder end up perfecting pastry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d09b350f758690100795053d1425df1</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane far too good for Gold Coast in QClash semifinal, setting up Collingwood prelim date</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/afl-finals-brisbane-lions-gold-coast-suns-live-blog/105768034</link><description>Brisbane's finals experience has come to the fore in a commanding and comfortable 53-point semifinal win over the Suns at the Gabba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35fd90e486aa2532889961cd9ae474b8</guid></item><item><title>Parramatta Road could get up to 8,000 new homes close to Sydney CBD in rezoning plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/thousands-new-homes-could-be-built-sections-parramatta-rd-sydney/105768070</link><description>The NSW government strikes a deal with Inner West Council to move forward with a plan to rezone sections of busy Parramatta Road that could see up the construction of up to 8,000 new homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f91bfdf2fe77baed9a8e3ab75b5e6d8d</guid></item><item><title>What's next for the far-right political movement in Australia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/what-next-for-far-right-john-macgowan/105735032</link><description>Australia's far-right movement has been buoyed by a wave of recent protests against mass immigration, with some saying the rallies were the "biggest thing that's happened in conservative and nationalist politics for a hundred years".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07e149ee4aff2602783cd21b0afe8328</guid></item><item><title>'Bubble curtain' ready to protect cuttlefish as algal bloom persists in SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/algal-bloom-bubble-curtain-ready-as-asthma-advice-defended/105761978</link><description>A "bubble curtain" is set for activation as part of South Australia's fight against the ongoing algal bloom, as the state government defends its handling of health advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c99d09af36c76bdbcccd8ef52874b9da</guid></item><item><title>Australian-funded PALM scheme liaison workers say they went months without pay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/country-liaison-officers-allege-underpayment-pacific/105694912</link><description>Pacific Islanders supporting PALM workers say they have had to go to great lengths — including flying to their home countries — to chase money owed to them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8170a75dc62bc775f286f334b5115dc4</guid></item><item><title>Construction workers are at higher risk of suicide. Here's how to look out for them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/supporting-loved-ones-who-work-in-construction/105724124</link><description>Construction workers are nearly twice as likely to take their own lives as other employed Australian men of the same age. Understanding the risks can help us better support those we know in the industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d30f05b9ecbefa716057acb813bf159</guid></item><item><title>Nourishing and easy sweet potato and lentil bowls - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/easy-roasted-sweet-potato-and-lentil-bowl/105643934</link><description>This jazzy little bowl is made from simple ingredients. The sweet potato is roasted gently with spices and tinned lentils are roasted until crisp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f14ee49334cef10b8f95233d1889d9e</guid></item><item><title>World-famous bee sanctuary on Kangaroo Island under threat from Varroa mite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/world-famous-bee-sanctuary-under-threat-from-parasite/105766650</link><description>Beekeepers on Kangaroo Island are demanding that biosecurity measures be boosted to prevent a deadly parasite from wiping out the island's world-famous bee sanctuary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dc81d0494e04695ce39dafec86cab57</guid></item><item><title>WA Health issues measles warning as two more cases linked to Bali travel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/two-more-measles-cases-in-wa-linked-to-bali-travel/105770492</link><description>West Australians planning to visit South-East Asia are being urged to get vaccinated against measles, with two more cases linked with travel to Bali.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1897bbaf4493022b86af465fcc949ac6</guid></item><item><title>The Pacific won a stunning climate victory at the International Court of Justice. What's next?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/whats-next-after-pacific-icj-climate-victory/105747794</link><description>Pacific Island nations are weighing up how to use a historic international court ruling in their fight to bring about stronger emissions reductions and climate justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4d5352fd2872714b73915e90a078b57</guid></item><item><title>Who is Larry Ellison and how did he overtake Elon Musk to briefly become the richest person in the world?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/larry-ellison-overtakes-elon-musk-world-richest-person/105761394</link><description>The switch in the ranking comes after a blockbuster earnings report from Oracle, powered by multi-billion-dollar orders from customers as the AI race heats up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0730b98607c60787120f4e7ae4674d8</guid></item><item><title>Australia and Papua New Guinea to 'totally integrate' military in defence treaty, minister says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/australia-and-png-defence-treaty-to-integrate-military-forces/105770088</link><description>Australia is set to "totally integrate" its military with Papua New Guinea's forces, PNG's defence minister has said, as the two countries prepare to sign a landmark treaty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20e8d04fdc68355dd6bb0bcbd76a253c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's health chief, RFK Jr, is dividing Republicans on vaccines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/trump-health-chief-rfk-jr-divides-republicans-on-vaccines/105763060</link><description>US Health Secretary Robert F Kennedy Jr's anti-vaccination agenda is gaining ground, but resistance is coming from all sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">550382bc4a2dad860c2ebd332ba5da22</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk's accused killer Tyler Robinson awaits formal charges in Utah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/tyler-robinson-awaits-formal-charges-over-charlie-kirk-murder/105771364</link><description>Tyler Robinson, jailed on suspicion of fatally shooting right-wing activist Charlie Kirk, faces formal charges in Utah early next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">388d30366d16f1bf3aebb0058cc923e8</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fall to 28-26 defeat against Argentina in The Rugby Championship in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/live-updates-wallabies-vs-argentina-the-rugby-championship/105753320</link><description>The Wallabies have fallen just short of a magical comeback against Argentina, losing 28-26 in a thrilling Rugby Championship Test in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac9963693b81c061d5a7137f7874121c</guid></item><item><title>Update your ABC News homepage for more local stories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2020-09-03/update-to-abc-news-homepage/12579988</link><description>We've got an ABC News homepage for you. Adjust your settings for the right mix of local and national news.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">146f1699ce6b1b7420a91b6bb80d0309</guid></item><item><title>Porepunkah community stuck in limbo as police search for alleged gunman Dezi Freeman continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/porepunkah-shooting-police-operation-community-limbo/105769036</link><description>As a police operation to find alleged gunman Dezi Freeman continues with no end in sight, Porepunkah residents share their anxiety about being left in limbo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3130a72fcb7e4cc9051d3a24bcf3ce34</guid></item><item><title>Australia and Fiji to press ahead with security treaty talks as Vanuatu deal goes unsigned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/pacific-islands-forum-australia-fiji-security-treaty-talks/105757640</link><description>The government is still racing to expand ties with Pacific nations — particularly the current governments in Fiji and Papua New Guinea — despite a diplomatic setback with Vanuatu.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df82cbc9032e24ef1b1739da332a6e21</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu warns Australia that expanding Woodside's North West Shelf gas project could breach international ruling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/vanuatu-warns-australia-about-expansion-of-woodside-gas-project/105759934</link><description>Australia's move to expand Woodside's North West Shelf gas project has not been welcomed in the Pacific, which is fighting the most dramatic effects of climate change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">112f08872918df84094b125b428478cd</guid></item><item><title>'Low levels of satisfaction' with healthcare in Canberra for endometriosis, menopause, identified in Women's Health Matters survey</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/women-health-canberra-survey-access-affordability-not-serious/105748894</link><description>A survey of women in Canberra about the state of their wellbeing and health reveals large gaps in access and affordability, as well as the staggering statistic that almost half of respondents felt doctors weren't taking them seriously.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">124301288b396763dfdb1ac672cdfeb3</guid></item><item><title>What happens to your data when you trade or recycle your device?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/what-happens-to-data-when-disposing-of-old-devices-in-ewaste/105681804</link><description>A cybercrime expert says trading or recycling electronics may not completely erase personal data and users should adopt a "risk-adjusted strategy" when disposing of devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a43950c96dbc6efda59bd57a5459809</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne seat of Calwell highlights Labor woes as Gaza pain galvanises Muslim voters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-20/calwell-labor-backlash-over-gaza-islamophobia/104850500</link><description>Dissatisfaction with the Albanese government's stance on Israel-Palestine among many Arab and Muslim voters threatens to unseat Labor MPs, in some places for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63e7f9854fee5bc20e54ee2f5bd136f4</guid></item><item><title>The US election is about style more than substance. It's why Kamala Harris needs to nail her DNC speech in about eight seconds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/us-election-kamala-harris-dnc-speech-style-substance/104256162</link><description>When the Democrat presidential candidate Kamala Harris delivers her speech to the Democratic National Convention today, style will be almost everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bddf8093759d999153dfd749b90e144a</guid></item><item><title>Migrants from Dubai, Philippines breathe new life into Edenhope</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/edenhope-home-to-new-migrants-from-philippines-dubai/105562718</link><description>When Nausheen Hashmi moved to a south-west Victorian farming town, she wondered how the locals would greet her and her children. She need not have worried.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a9fc72b4e6305c0db77bafe91a1bedf</guid></item><item><title>In their Melbourne Fringe Show, First Trimester, performer Krishna Istha is seeking a sperm donor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/first-trimester-melbourne-fringe-krisha-istha-sperm-donor/105650028</link><description>Krishna Istha has made a habit of turning to performance to solve a problem. So when they needed help to find a sperm donor, the solution was obvious.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cca559ebaead97189e3624cdb196df95</guid></item><item><title>Perth had its wettest winter in 30 years. Why aren't its dams full?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/perth-dam-remains-low-despite-the-wettest-winter-in-30-years/105767386</link><description>The last time it rained that much in winter, Perth's drinking water dam overflowed. Now it's barely half full. It's telling the story of a water crisis that's not only affecting Australia, but the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">520afffe8e8f2b9614549ec3a2399a4d</guid></item><item><title>Toni Jordan spent her childhood at the greyhound track, inspiring her new novel Tenderfoot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/toni-jordan-books-tenderfoot-interview/105754310</link><description>The acclaimed author's father was a greyhound trainer and her mother ran a TAB. Her unconventional childhood inspired her eighth book, Tenderfoot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19370cb777b009a92f1855e8361e9d09</guid></item><item><title>An Ozzy Osbourne tribute, a Mayhem Ball and a Mariah Carey medley delight fans at the 2025 MTV VMAs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/key-moments-from-the-2025-vmas/105746958</link><description>Ariana Grande and Lady Gaga took home the biggest awards at this year's MTV VMAs with several nineties stars honoured for their musical legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7aac3df4ab0753ac617e05bcf866036a</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Think you're contestant material? Prove it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/105746846</link><description>It's time to show me your exceptional trivia knowledge. Ha!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03f61e05a2d928ef5dd5a855914f188a</guid></item><item><title>Is the pink soap scum in my bathroom mould, or something else?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/why-is-the-soap-scum-in-my-bathroom-pink-and-orange-/105721212</link><description>Have you ever noticed a pink or orange-coloured substance in the tile grout or around taps in your bathroom? In most cases, it's one of two things.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9deb3308036c00d500826ba08d50f062</guid></item><item><title>Penrith Panthers, Cronulla Sharks win NRL elimination finals against Warriors, Sydney Roosters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/nrl-finals-live-warriors-panthers-sharks-roosters/105770330</link><description>The Sharks end the Roosters' NRL season in the second NRL elimination final after Penrith took down the Warriors 24-8 in Auckland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8453f95a136416a45ec4efe167c5d81f</guid></item><item><title>Call for button battery redesign after new study reveals horrific injuries and fatalities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/button-battery-warning-danger-deaths-lithium-swallow/103986966</link><description>A new study reveals the horrific injuries suffered after swallowing or inserting button batteries but manufacturers aren't prioritising their redesign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46ab5f96ade65908ecf6b7be8673e61f</guid></item><item><title>Armani drama beyond the grave as will instructs heirs to sell or list on stock market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/giorgio-armani-will-sell-company-or-list-on-stock-market/105768872</link><description>Giorgio Armani's will has surprised fashion watchers as it contains instructions to gradually sell off his company to a luxury brand or seek a listing on the stock market, in seeming contrast to his fiercely independent stance throughout his career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53e94498a98d7b4b3828f43dae15498d</guid></item><item><title>Islamophobia has been 'persistent' and 'ignored', envoy says — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/federal-politics-live-sept-12/105765250</link><description>A long-awaited report into Islamophobia in Australia has been handed down, with the special envoy finding it has been "persistent" and "ignored".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2ef5426aa13af6f04a2b80bf14d5cab</guid></item><item><title>Heavy police presence monitors thousands of protesters across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/protesters-across-political-spectrum-rally-across-australia/105769960</link><description>Rallies against racism and in support of Indigenous sovereignty coincide with mixed anti-government protests in major cities around the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">114f96de2b5f61b5df11c8299f73fdb6</guid></item><item><title>Have Your Say: What was the issue, policy or event that decided your vote?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-02-26/federal-election-your-say/104788518</link><description>After a five-week campaign, the results are in with Labor returned to government. Is there a policy or issue that swayed your vote? Have Your Say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">320dfcbec9cd8fe02e449407ce78e618</guid></item><item><title>Childcare giant G8 cut unorthodox $26 million deal with Darren Misquitta's Genius despite warnings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/g8-childcare-genius-darren-misquitta-adrian-portelli/105757230</link><description>Despite G8 knowing about problems, an ABC investigation can reveal how the childcare giant downplayed concerns and maintained it had conducted checks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f62db8a3d68477b74164c7287c364e9</guid></item><item><title>Air strikes kill at least 32 in Gaza City as Israel ramps up its offensive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/israeli-strikes-kill-at-least-32-across-gaza-city/105770758</link><description>Israel in recent days has intensified strikes across Gaza City, destroying multiple high-rise buildings and accusing Hamas of putting surveillance equipment in them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a19cccd4d36d16c4736f44ec0be6998</guid></item><item><title>Reserve Bank restructure closer to reality after Treasurer Jim Chalmers offers olive branch to Angus Taylor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/reserve-bank-restructure-closer-to-reality/104260250</link><description>The Reserve Bank of Australia is a step closer to its biggest restructure in three decades after the treasurer offers an assurance to his Coalition counterpart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e920ec5b24583b8f74962ecc7f9c2585</guid></item><item><title>Housing advocates seek federal funding election promise for co-op model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-17/housing-cooperative-solution-proposed-for-rental-crisis/105108816</link><description>Advocates admit co-operative housing models are not for everyone but say for the right residents, they offer more security and affordable pricing than traditional rentals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3608b0c1ae56f5a5b36968898f65df5e</guid></item><item><title>Inside the world of Jeffrey Epstein's friends, associates and alleged co-conspirators</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/jeffrey-epstein-friends-associates-over-the-years/105593832</link><description>Convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein intentionally sought out some of the world's most powerful people. Here's how they have responded to his disgraced reputation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d86bdfe45629edff6870e5bdbfae31a</guid></item><item><title>Understanding the literal bin fires in Europe's 'magical mystery summer' of inaction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/drone-attack-on-poland-shows-europe-is-not-equiped-for-war/105769208</link><description>Moscow's drone incursion into Polish airspace this week may have just laid bare how fruitless Europe's summer of talkfests has been.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad36c5f8aa76037acc9c47d200ab7bb</guid></item><item><title>How fear of being 'cringe' is holding young people back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/fear-of-being-cringe-is-holding-young-people-back/105762928</link><description>A psychologist says the growing online phenomenon of "cringe" is making young people avoid doing things they fear are embarrassing, sometimes to their detriment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c01b8347dc75fad5ead443afbb25ef2</guid></item><item><title>Push for seniors' dental scheme grows ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-13/aged-care-dental-scheme-australia-federal-election/105149782</link><description>Imagine living in aged care and not having your teeth or dentures properly cleaned and checked each day. That's a risk faced by elderly Australians, prompting calls for the next federal government to boost oral health training and services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36d312d336a36247fd1c01e78814112b</guid></item><item><title>Sushila Karki sworn in as Nepal's new prime minister after gen Z protests prompt political change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/sushila-karki-nepals-new-prime-minister-after-gen-z-protests/105769388</link><description>Sushila Karki garnered widespread support from many young Nepalese people who took to the streets in anger over government corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b14068c37ad26302453e199b0b0960b7</guid></item><item><title>Next-generation voters call for better engagement ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-18/federal-election-rural-next-generation-voters/105173450</link><description>Young people in Albury say issues that directly affect them and their communities are not being addressed by major parties for the 2025 election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ae182892b8c9591cd9ec35e6e57fcb9</guid></item><item><title>Israel's air strike campaign levelling Gaza City's remaining buildings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/israel-idf-destroys-apartment-blocks-in-gaza-city/105748728</link><description>Israel has dramatically ramped up its attacks in Gaza City in the past week with a targeted campaign to strike its high-rises. Hundreds of structures have been destroyed, forcing thousands of already displaced Palestinians to flee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50cf5012172274f369cca0a629feb384</guid></item><item><title>Former minister Greg Hunt works for Brethren company whose owners made millions on COVID contracts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/greg-hunt-plymouth-brethren-liberal-party-four-corners/105767402</link><description>The Sydney-based church has been described by former members and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese as a "cult".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4328a557e1520bd5030668231cb9ac20</guid></item><item><title>Torrie Lewis makes semifinals at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo, Day 1</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-in-tokyo-day-1/105770190</link><description>Torrie Lewis broke the national record to claim a spot in the women's 100m semifinal, as Lauren Ryan recorded Australia's best finish in a 10,000m final since 2003 on day one of the World Athletics Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1fd0acc71517e138058f6992507918f</guid></item><item><title>Australia's growing cohort of tenants fear they will rent forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-16/australias-growing-tenant-cohort-fear-forever-renting/105127148</link><description>Home ownership rates in Australia have been falling for decades, and with rental vacancies at record lows and prices at historic highs, many fear their dream of owning a home may be out of reach. Some experts say rental caps could help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f35fe439f533ac9522c679c7e37187</guid></item><item><title>US golfer John Daly takes a record 19 shots to play a par-5 on the PGA Tour Champions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/john-daly-makes-wrong-kind-of-golfing-history-with-19-on-a-par-5/105770020</link><description>John Daly is known as "Wild Thing" for his big-hitting, swashbuckling play, but the US golfer's round went right off the rails on the PGA Tour Champions, hitting the water seven times on a par-5.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b97b8101604fb31617977361f0fd2839</guid></item><item><title>Growing group of Labor MPs urge 2035 emissions target above Climate Authority's floor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/labor-mps-urge-2035-target-within-climate-authority-advice/105762592</link><description>A growing cross-factional group within Labor is privately urging for Australia's next major climate target to respect the advice of the Climate Change Authority, which will hand its opinion on a 2035 target to government any day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366f414d754ce8a4269105ca01955ee0</guid></item><item><title>A journey through 35 years of Canberra's history since the Raiders last won a minor premiership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/the-35-years-since-canberra-raiders-last-won-a-minor-premiership/105768944</link><description>Two weeks ago, the Canberra Raiders won the NRL's 2025 minor premiership by beating the Wests Tigers. It is their first minor premiership since 1990, and a lot has changed since then.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6c07216269a150c362150bb1c36ed05</guid></item><item><title>'Clone' websites catch out Australian customers as online shopping scams become 'alarmingly' common</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/clone-websites-retailers-catch-out-online-shoppers-scam/105736854</link><description>Online shopping scams are now one of the most frequently reported scam types and experts say they are alarmingly common, impersonating well-known brands and being promoted in search engine advertisements.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d6cf1bf94f1b9a65d30881e571ce779</guid></item><item><title>Voters tell ABC's Your Say they want politicians with a vision, not bickering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-13/abc-your-say-federal-election-politicians-with-vision/105164874</link><description>Voters tell ABC's Your Say campaign they want courage and vision from politicians, not bickering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">033ddce5ad54070fbce620dc6760d9ba</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand fugitive Tom Phillips killed in shootout with police after four years on the run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-08/nz-fugitive-tom-phillips-shot-dead/105746874</link><description>Tom Phillips is killed during a shootout with police during a burglary in New Zealand's Waikato region, his sister says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e302078e2d9bb555278551a94b40cfd3</guid></item><item><title>London anti-immigration protesters scuffle with police, who promise 'many more' arrests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/uk-anti-immigration-rally-and-counter-protests/105770802</link><description>The march was organised by far-right activist Tommy Robinson while a counter protest by anti-racism campaigners also took place as the country continues to be dogged by the issue of immigration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">400ded37a12d6921e0e758dc480fc33d</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi Islanders eager to have their say as remote voting for the federal election begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-22/early-voting-starts-in-remote-communities-tiwi-islands-aec/105201318</link><description>Voters in the small remote community of Pirlangimpi on the Tiwi Islands, north of Darwin, have become some of the first to cast their votes for the federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0c419fe3ae44debe7edf27241c0e5c1</guid></item><item><title>Health, climate and community sport: What older voters in the Tasmanian seat of Bass are talking about this election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-29/health-climate-sport-election-older-voters-bass-tasmania/105224138</link><description>The federal seat of Bass is held by a margin of just 1.4 per cent. For these older voters who live in the electorate, health, climate and community sport are the issues that will decide their vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3579db910b5a7ee8e11d2618bf798f</guid></item><item><title>Cost of living, housing among key concerns in SA marginal seat of Boothby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/boothby-cost-of-living-federal-election-2025/105190262</link><description>At this year’s federal election, the South Australian seat of Boothby is one of the state’s two marginal seats. As part of the ABC’s “Your Say” campaign, we spoke to residents in the electorate about their biggest concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dfd66b0605d29b960082ff52f18c170</guid></item><item><title>More than a dozen women complain about Brisbane doctor accused of performing 'sexually motivated' checks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/complaints-against-brisbane-doctor-accused-unnecessary-checks/105761406</link><description>Dr Stan Theodoros is facing disciplinary proceedings, lodged by Queensland's health ombudsman, in the Queensland Civil and Administrative Tribunal (QCAT).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">741e87aaa3667ced3bea58af9748de48</guid></item><item><title>Children missing out on early intervention for language delays due to shortage of speech pathologists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/australias-speech-pathology-therapy-language-delay/105658306</link><description>One in four children starting school now has a speech or language delay. It can hold back their learning, affect their friendships and harm their mental health. Speech therapists are struggling to find ways to support them all, but one school is leading the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fd8643f474de3cb897a95d95769fb75</guid></item><item><title>Adrianne Lenker on Big Thief's evolution and the making of Double Infinity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/big-thief-double-infinity-adrianne-lenker-new-album-interview/105754728</link><description>At the peak of their success, Big Thief faced a major emotional rupture that reshaped the group from the inside out. Now, they've returned with their sixth album, shaped by deep creative trust and a renewed commitment to collaboration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c838f7561646302e00adf2a4fa4ff7b4</guid></item><item><title>Australians tell ABC's Your Say they are struggling more than ever with housing costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-15/abc-your-say-federal-election-2025-housing-policies/105175180</link><description>Voters tell ABC's Your Say campaign they are struggling more than ever with housing costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54451646ec8e9f100cc2fe59fc9c08c5</guid></item><item><title>Black Diamond Cup, the oldest trophy still in use in Australian sport, up for grabs in Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/black-diamond-cup-oldest-trophy-still-in-use/105757792</link><description>Teams in the Hunter Central Coast AFL play for a trophy that was first contested in 1888 and holds plenty of memories for grand final winners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a44aa5fba65df5067d085c7c531b0f1</guid></item><item><title>Regulator with oversight of gas leak 'scandal' had paid role with industry lobbyist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/nt-regulator-oversight-gas-leak-scandal-paid-role-lobbyist/105752490</link><description>The man in charge of the Northern Territory government's handling of a major methane leak at a Santos gas plant was working with a lobbyist for the project's co-owner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b8811b14516374a1aa847b275d1f80a</guid></item><item><title>Who is Tyler Robinson, the accused killer of Charlie Kirk?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/tyler-robinson-charlie-kirks-alleged-killer/105769710</link><description>After his father encouraged Tyler Robinson to turn himself in, people close to the 22-year-old provided investigators with crucial insights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeb2177456349534e747aeb65ed554d9</guid></item><item><title>Homebuyers turn to shared ownership in expensive Wollongong market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/homebuyers-turn-to-shared-ownership-in-property-market/105719548</link><description>Friends Gem and Renata have saved money buying a home together with their respective families in Wollongong, and say the pay-off goes much further.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12de675050396e817010850d0aa22cf0</guid></item><item><title>Nepal's gen Z protesters are continuing the fight for their future even after picking a new prime minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/nepal-gen-z-protesters-on-fight-for-future/105765704</link><description>A calm has fallen on Nepal's streets after days of violence and chaos. But leaders of the gen Z protest movement say the work's not done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b37bb71a46bc744a9f38b66a4eed75af</guid></item><item><title>Supreme Court gives Queensland hospital permission to terminate 12yo girl's pregnancy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/qld-hospital-gets-court-permission-for-abortion-on-12yo-girl/105770196</link><description>A 12-year-old girl in residential care in Queensland should be allowed to have an abortion, a court rules, after a judge found she was not capable of making the decision herself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86cd5589ba9855a3f68a146a74e238ad</guid></item><item><title>AFLW wrap: Collingwood ends Sydney's unbeaten run, Carlton thumps Gold Coast, the Power beats the Demons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/swans-perfect-start-ends-as-magpies-stun-at-home/105770154</link><description>Collingwood, wooden spooners last season, keep Sydney goalless for more than three quarters at home on Saturday for an upset win, as Port Adelaide beat another unbeaten side in Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">112f93d3f5b081beaf0d54247ad5c93a</guid></item><item><title>'Bone lady' who helped find Daniel Morcombe still unearthing stories of the dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/life-of-qld-police-forensic-anthropologist-donna-macgregor/105757258</link><description>From the search for Daniel Morcombe to a flaming roadside torso, Queensland's top forensics cop deals with some of the state's worst crimes — when she's not identifying fallen Australians on WWI battlefields.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">756451363a24944c71314b39d4ee9da4</guid></item><item><title>Nepal authorities lift curfew for Kathmandu and surrounding areas after gen Z protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/nepal-authorities-lift-curfew-for-residents-in-kathmandu/105770846</link><description>The curfew was lifted after Nepal swore in its first female prime minister, following deadly protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5956808eef8ce43215031876e7a2806</guid></item><item><title>ASX higher on US rate cut expectations, but markets underestimating inflation risk — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/asx-markets-business-live-news-sept-12/105765376</link><description>The ASX rises, as do Virgin shares, as the airline reveals the exit pay of its former CEO. Westpac's economics team, led by former RBA assistant governor Luci Ellis, say they think markets are underpricing the risk of a renewed inflation breakout in the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9e5b59041ffdcd6b6304cf4b5301d79</guid></item><item><title>Islamophobia envoy calls for religious discrimination laws, review of approach to counter-terrorism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/islamophobia-envoy-wants-religious-discrimination-laws/105767918</link><description>In a landmark report, newly-appointed Aftab Malik also calls for counter-terrorism laws and approaches to be reviewed, and for national inquiries into Islamophobia and anti-Palestinian racism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc9a9f371e9e7f0d19902747f4cfb1dd</guid></item><item><title>How the Jeffrey Epstein saga spread to British politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/mandelson-how-epstein-scandal-spread-to-the-uk-starmer/105764932</link><description>After dogging the US president for months, evidence of a connection to Jeffrey Epstein has claimed a senior scalp within the British government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b90733943995ade4f20f3bb500f68ab</guid></item><item><title>Wallaroos' Rugby World Cup hopes dashed by dominant Canada in 46-5 loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/rugby-world-cup-wallaroos-canada-quarterfinal/105771382</link><description>The Wallaroos miss the chance to reach the Rugby World Cup semifinals, losing heavily 46-5 to Canada in Bristol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eeea51af32489f3175d1f115a728a37</guid></item><item><title>Energy projects in South West WA threaten votes for major federal parties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/energy-projects-south-west-wa-federal-election-labor-liberals/105152524</link><description>Australia's two major parties have tied their federal election fates to controversial energy projects in WA's South West where the issues have polarised voters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8962a53de05f0293b3a104690022111a</guid></item><item><title>Murdochs resolve succession saga but family's hold on empire is vulnerable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-10/murdoch-money-trust/105753004</link><description>Rupert Murdoch's family has always been close. But if you really want to trace the extent of filial and sibling affection, you need to follow the money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05772215b7594bca0b62e72680c673b5</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal artist Emily Kam Kngwarray becomes first Australian with solo exhibition at London's Tate Modern</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/emily-kam-kngwarray-nt-artist-solo-exhibition-tate-modern/105748722</link><description>Emily Kam Kngwarray has been recognised as "one of the world's leading artists" after becoming the first Australian whose work is the subject of a solo exhibition at the Tate Modern Gallery in London.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80742075f005deb3851d847eafa37b21</guid></item></channel></rss>