<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 16:56:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Ferrari crash reportedly kills Call of Duty co-founder Vince Zampella in California</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/vince-zampella-dies-car-crash/106173016</link><description>Vince Zampella has died after a crash on a scenic road north of Los Angeles, according to local broadcaster NBC4.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1b47f1713b30f9a5548511d9072e9c6</guid></item><item><title>Newmont's Cadia Gold Mine to spend $300,000 on monitors after dust incidents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/newmont-cadia-gold-mine-buys-dust-monitoring-stations-epa/106170892</link><description>One of the country's largest gold mines in the NSW Central West will buy five new dust monitors after incidents at its tailings dam.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8b16aa24b0110d31f9b6c0be2269d84</guid></item><item><title>Historic giant sequoia tree in Hobart's St David's Park 'very, very sick' after fires and vandalism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/historic-giant-sequoia-tree-in-hobart-park-is-sick/106171168</link><description>An 88-year-young giant sequoia tree is "declining rapidly" in St David's Park in central Hobart due to a range of disturbances, including vandalism and fire, the council says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6948c23add1761505282eddcc4c6ca92</guid></item><item><title>Rain-hit orchards still producing 'best quality' lychees in time for Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/weather-impacted-christmas-lychees-are-best-quality-in-decades/106162250</link><description>After season constraints and rain-delayed harvests, this summer is producing exceptional Queensland lychees, according to the wholesalers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16e5cb33ab2fdee1026c2a58720857da</guid></item><item><title>Woman appears in court after failing to 'keep the King's Peace' and allegedly biting ACT police officer's leg</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/woman-fails-keep-king-peace-biting-police-officer/106173712</link><description>A failure to 'keep the King's Peace' and biting a police officer has almost landed a Canberra woman in jail for Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2531d9cd74672f55bbc06e81b72969cf</guid></item><item><title>Latest 'Battle of the sexes' commodifies and risks mocking historic event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/nick-kyrgios-aryna-sabalenka-battle-of-the-sexes-lose-lose/106174192</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka and Nick Kygrios' match marketed under the "Battle of the Sexes" banner makes a mockery of first era-defining match between Billie Jean King and Bobby Riggs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f9df8171a4c08b8311e5a2c2fe729eb</guid></item><item><title>Boy rescued after falling from cliff at Sorrento on the Mornington Peninsula</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/boy-rescued-after-falling-from-cliff-at-sorrento/106173774</link><description>The teenager suffered leg injuries after falling three metres from a clifftop on the Mornington Peninsula.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df17af030e0247561b4ef3ce4468e567</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese recommends changes to parliamentarians' travel rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/anthony-albanese-recommends-changes-parliamentary-travel-rules/106174182</link><description>Under the recommendations, family of parliamentarians would be restricted to economy class flights and an allowance for three annual "Australia-wide" return trips would be scrapped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dffd23670c5c0a70913dbe382d609bc</guid></item><item><title>Koala protection in south-east Queensland to be shaped by new strategy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/qld-koala-strategy/106173284</link><description>The Queensland government is inviting the public to have their say on a new strategy to protect the south-east's koala population.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">515cc2988cc82186aa02db050a98c33a</guid></item><item><title>Gregory John Walker jailed over Arthur Haines' death after 1998 Sydney firebombing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/nsw-gregory-walker-sentencing-arthur-haines-firebombing/106173498</link><description>Gregory John Walker is sentenced to at least six-and-a-half years in prison for unlawfully killing a teenager by firebombing a Sydney home in 1998 during an escalating neighbourhood dispute.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09dc039ee5b005aa683345d6db3c87cc</guid></item><item><title>Best podcasts of 2025, from Forged to Fela Kuti: Fear No Man</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/best-podcasts-2025-forged-fela-kuti-fear-no-man/106138476</link><description>Our favourite podcasts of the year include tales of art forgery, a documentary about the life of Fela Kútì and a true-crime thriller about a dead body in the ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ccd2f33573cb77c395b8b3bf699ea6c</guid></item><item><title>As a newly single mum, I am redefining Christmas with my kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/spending-christmas-without-my-child-perspective/106129654</link><description>This is my first Christmas as a single mum where I will wake up without my son in the home. I won't be watching him excitedly tear into presents. It's not easy, but there's also some relief, writes Catherine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d5a38448fa2d7d2e1fb3e4cab6272b3</guid></item><item><title>No air conditioning in Shellharbour Hospital ward during heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/hospital-patients-swelter-without-air-con-during-heatwave/106173174</link><description>Patients swelter in an Illawarra hospital ward after an air conditioning unit fails during a heatwave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0799f44f22f84a2e18d9dabd6186cff</guid></item><item><title>Therapeutic Goods Administration issues warnings over heavy metals in Ayurvedic tablets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/complementary-ayurvedic-medicines-heavy-metals-safety-alert/106156510</link><description>Australia's medicine watchdog has issued another safety alert for contaminated Ayurvedic medicines. So what do consumers need to know about this multi-million-dollar industry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f839cfc4577b67765d53fe3970548e3</guid></item><item><title>NSW oyster growers face contrasting holiday seasons as Christmas Eve rush looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/holiday-season-oyster-farms-christmas/106150290</link><description>The Christmas oyster harvest is flourishing on the NSW south coast, but further north it is a very different story as growers face the fallout of this year's record-breaking floods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f8cb8dd51a20c0fcd6787563277d3e2</guid></item><item><title>Severe Christmas heatwave scorches WA as Tropical Cyclone Grant strengthens offshore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/perth-wa-severe-christmas-heatwave-tropical-cyclone-grant/106174278</link><description>Perth, and much of WA, is enduring a severe Christmas heatwave with extreme fire danger, while Tropical Cyclone Grant intensifies offshore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2b1297740e2718b68e3eea718278a7f</guid></item><item><title>ECB managing director Rob Key to investigate England's Noosa break following Ashes failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/england-rob-key-ashes-noosa-drinking/106175002</link><description>ECB managing director Rob Key will investigate reports England's recent break in Noosa resembled a "stag do" as the tourists pick up the pieces from their Ashes defeat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12762fcf89066cd205121cc1842d1263</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins could miss T20 World Cup to manage back injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/pat-cummins-no-certainty-for-t20-world-cup/106175190</link><description>Pat Cummins could be held back from the upcoming T20 World Cup as Australia look to manage his workload following his recent back injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b31b570afd3d68bce0cd5d9eea32e598</guid></item><item><title>NSW police officer Jack Hibbert released from hospital after being shot in Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/nsw-police-constable-jack-hibbert-out-of-hospital-after-bondi/106165734</link><description>A young police officer who was rendered blind in one eye after being shot during the Bondi terror attack is released from hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">863fae5e27a1267508c77e7e0ee8c79e</guid></item><item><title>Delta Electricity found guilty over 2022 fish kill near its Vales Point Power Station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/delta-electricity-guilty-for-fish-kill-near-power-station/106173120</link><description>A court rules a maintenance failure caused hundreds of fish to die near Delta Electricity's Vales Point coal-fired power station in September 2022, a month after another kill triggered by natural causes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6a3a4a71e4f4e25cab04a2f450b4dd7</guid></item><item><title>Up to 1,700 jobs axed days out from Christmas as security firm MA Services collapses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/ma-services-security-cleaning-company-enters-administration/106175160</link><description>A "significant number" of employees have been made immediately redundant as MA Security — which provides security and maintenance services to major retailers like Coles, Kmart and Amazon — enters administration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f44180052c8f395d11dc624bad4134da</guid></item><item><title>CommBank reverses refusal to refund $68m in excessive fees for low-income earners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/commbank-reverses-bank-fee-refusal/106174050</link><description>The Commonwealth Bank of Australia will refund low-income earners receiving Centrelink payments approximately $68 million in unfair fees — just over a quarter of what was charged.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36c96e32b41f5ea3d1c941877dab0efa</guid></item><item><title>Woman treated for suspected bite after eastern brown snake became trapped in her shoe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/woman-finds-eastern-brown-snake-trapped-in-shoe/106174484</link><description>A woman has been rushed to hospital after a brown snake curled around her leg, becoming trapped in her shoe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96f7252ca6f2c8da2e9e7248ba2f775a</guid></item><item><title>Robert Donald Blackberry jailed after hay bale scam targeting Tasmanian farmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/hay-bale-scammer-robert-donald-blackberry-jailed/106173248</link><description>A judge blasts a man's "complete and utter disregard for the law" and jails him for scamming farmers desperate for feed out of money for hay bales he never delivered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae49e3a22372ec0d044afd7fcd498144</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal legal aid lawyers launch High Court challenge to NT bail laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/northern-territory-bail-laws-to-be-challenged-in-high-court/106175228</link><description>The North Australian Aboriginal Justice Agency says hundreds of people are likely being held on remand in Northern Territory jails "unlawfully and unconstitutionally".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e49a5a405e445c1c3aa1b16b1159033</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese and Sussan Ley release Christmas messages in wake of Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-christmas-messages/106175306</link><description>Anthony Albanese and Opposition Leader Sussan Ley are urging Australians to "stand together" this Christmas in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5161d332a202792544fa6606a0dcdd23</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide academic accused of attempting to kill her ex searched methods to kill, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/lisa-lines-bail-application/106173090</link><description>A woman accused of trying to murder her ex-husband before fleeing to Palau has made a bid in South Australia's Supreme Court for release on bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2d2b9c476702795542e404d1c34872b</guid></item><item><title>US approves Wegovy pill, giving Novo Nordisk an edge in obesity drug competition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/wegovy-pill-approved-in-us-new-obesity-treatment/106175652</link><description>A daily weight-loss pill will soon be available in the US, after the regulator gave approval to Danish drug company Novo Nordisk's oral version of the popular injectable, Wegovy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2a5ee3d3b6d8085cb49ee03f61d25e8</guid></item><item><title>Cooler spring blamed for Tasmania's later Christmas berry, cherry harvest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/cooler-spring-blamed-tas-late-berry-cherry-harvest/106173424</link><description>Christmas is usually a boom time for Tasmanian berry producers, but this year's cold spring has slowed crops and hurt profits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">705a5995417dbc7739b8e638b75d975b</guid></item><item><title>Do you know how to make the gravy? Test your Christmas song knowledge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/christmas-songs-quiz/106133752</link><description>Which Christmas hits didn't do as well on the charts as you'd think? Test your knowledge of festive cheer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a6f069aa41b131375949561d682b968</guid></item><item><title>Christmas festivities return to Bethlehem after two years as Palestinians hope for 'better future'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/christmas-festivities-return-to-bethlehem-after-two-years/106156060</link><description>For the first time in two years, Bethlehem has restarted its Christmas festivities to "reignite the spirit that everybody needs" while Palestinians continue to live under restrictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">959bab0c472d2bc907e8df47cab050cb</guid></item><item><title>Boxing Day sales set to be biggest on record as interest rate relief drives retail rebound</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/boxing-day-sales-australia-2025/106171474</link><description>Boxing Day spending is expected to hit a record high, supported by revived household spending after three interest rate cuts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad1a713797696e8327e634ed101ddcf6</guid></item><item><title>Australian businessman Ranjit Thambyrajah languishes in Vietnam jail after string of failed loan deals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/australian-businessman-ranjit-thambyrajah-jailed-in-vietnam/106174026</link><description>A high-flying Australian financier accused of swindling a struggling Vietnamese petroleum trading company has been languishing in a Ho Chi Minh City cell for two months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32afb45f1768c514427193990162ebc0</guid></item><item><title>A $7m unpaid tobacco fine and online sales emerge amid government crack down on illegal trade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/qld-illicit-tobacco-unpaid-fines-health-smoking/106170904</link><description>Illicit tobacco retailers have racked up millions in unpaid fines since the introduction of stronger penalties, with one owing more than $7 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">787337ed5dcf9686f03d4e519b1e3e37</guid></item><item><title>Rain on Queensland's Christmas forecast, north-west on flood watch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/rain-forecast-christmas-qld-north-west-flood-watch/106173584</link><description>It may not be the most welcome weather at the beach, but out in the west, rain is the best Christmas gift.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b341d575edef8b6616b4176339c1bf1a</guid></item><item><title>Runner Nancy Dickman, 83, prepares for her next marathon at 90</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/83yo-runner-nancy-dickman-preparing-for-her-next-marathon/106027164</link><description>Nancy Dickman has run marathons in London, New York, Rome and Sydney, and at 83 shows no signs of slowing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ce23e10ca9dfe12fea5638e3ceed667</guid></item><item><title>Australian dollar jumps to 14-month high, ASX falls as gold and silver hit record highs — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/asx-markets-business-live-news/106176162</link><description>The Australian share market is down on Christmas Eve, despite the value of US stocks, gold and silver climbing to their most expensive levels ever, while the Australian dollar has jumped to its highest level since October 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c78068110747ab7aaa5444e314acc337</guid></item><item><title>Woman's miraculous Arnhem Land survival story after ankle 'snapped in half'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/arnhem-land-survival-story-woman-crawled-for-help-ankle-snapped/106166278</link><description>Lying on the ground with her ankle snapped in half in the remote bushland of western Arnhem Land, her mind racing, and with no help or phone reception, Margie Moroney began to crawl.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2b76790497fb883ac74f29812ef09e4</guid></item><item><title>Mohamed Salah claims Africa Cup of Nations record as Egypt beat Zimbabwe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/mohamed-salah-claims-africa-cup-of-nations-record/106176216</link><description>Mohamed Salah scored at his fifth Africa Cup of Nations tournament in a row, becoming the first Egyptian player to do so.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f8aa2987bb15d6e3b13ebf9afa6596c</guid></item><item><title>Double-lung transplant recipient Johnnie Tumai's plea for Christmas organ donors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/double-lung-transplant-recipient-johnnie-tumai/106033118</link><description>Johnnie Tumai is preparing to spend his first Christmas at home since receiving a new set of lungs. He's urging others to register as donors this festive season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46e9d57e567decf05cbc39dff061528e</guid></item><item><title>A US bone marrow donor is reunited with the Perth man she saved.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/us-bone-marrow-donor-reunites-with-perth-man-she-saved/106175644</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f6a78b0d2dd8bb934d9d8359a026d5</guid></item><item><title>Father of three meets bone marrow donor who saved his life for 'most special Christmas'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/wa-bone-marrow-recipient-meets-donor-special-christmas/106172104</link><description>Battling acute myeloid leukaemia, Gennaro Rapinese finally found a suitable bone marrow donor on the other side of the world in the US. And, after making a full recovery, he got to thank her in person in the lead-up to Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff6481214c7dc01941ff0685683c806d</guid></item><item><title>Tarina Warren has been legally blind since she was 16, now a seeing eye dog is helping her navigate life on Moolooloo Station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/seeing-eye-dog-helping-on-outback-south-australian-sheep-station/106119816</link><description>Moolooloo station, nestled in South Australia's Flinders Ranges, might look like your typical outback farm, but the workforce at this station has one unique addition — a black labrador called Mika.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b31e319b326ff413922ba6b31841ec3e</guid></item><item><title>Convenience over tradition as gen Z and millennials favour pre-peeled prawns over the Christmas period</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/young-australians-not-peeling-christmas-prawns/106173238</link><description>New research shows younger Aussies prefer to save time and mess by buying pre-peeled prawns over the festive season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c26bc33a33387bfea269786da7f0eeed</guid></item><item><title>Home affairs minister cancels visa of British national charged with displaying Nazi symbols</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/british-national-visa-cancelled-for-displaying-nazi-symbol/106176308</link><description>The Australian government has promised changes to make it easier to deport people who spread hateful views.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80cd728ce8c38812bdbd79de1a54c110</guid></item><item><title>Bondi terror attack heroes to be recognised in new honours list</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/bondi-heroes-to-be-recognised-in-new-honours-list/106176488</link><description>The prime minister announces those who showed "extraordinary" bravery during the Bondi terror attack will be recognised in a new honours list.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51c14b2bdf7a6685f0595618026787e0</guid></item><item><title>WA farming community loses 500 sheep, thousands of hectares of crops in fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/western-australian-farming-community-loses-500-sheep-in-fires/106153256</link><description>A bushfire emergency in Warradarge is over, but farmers say the work to recover what was lost has only just begun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80cdd9268fb9fd905e22ffb4920dd350</guid></item><item><title>Through my eyes: Jean Mitchell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/through-my-eyes-jean-mitchell/106162552</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f91acbae2647822d58a176ffd0a9be5</guid></item><item><title>Brooks Koepka leaves LIV Golf in major blow to breakaway league</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/brooks-koepka-leaves-liv-golf/106176562</link><description>Golf superstar Brooks Koepka has cited family priorities as he announces he is leaving the breakaway LIV Golf league.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">810822568c249759fa95a72196633a8c</guid></item><item><title>Kate Winslet makes her directorial debut with family Christmas movie Goodbye June</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/goodbye-june-kate-winslet-directorial-debut-movie/106150390</link><description>The actor talks about why she felt compelled to make the Christmas-themed film and why she was lucky to get Helen Mirren to play the titular role.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e87fd55db98fa5d4e281f9f4594d605</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Grant approaches Cocos (Keeling) Islands as severe Christmas heatwave scorches WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/tropical-cyclone-grant-nears-islands-amid-wa-christmas-heatwave/106176456</link><description>Preparations are underway far off Western Australia's north-west coast for the impact of a category one cyclone as Perth and much of the state continues to swelter in heatwave conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9eb942cdf56564b96e8cfcbca5123d93</guid></item><item><title>Sydney to Hobart yacht race not expecting repeat of last year's horrific conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/sydney-to-hobart-conditions-set-to-be-ok/106176678</link><description>The Sydney to Hobart fleet is in for milder conditions this year than in 2024, when two people died on the first night of racing, although sailors have been warned to expect strong winds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">997b2e54e1de0f06c49f224650477ac0</guid></item><item><title>'Fake' letter and 'false claims' among latest Epstein files, US Justice Department says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/epstein-files-contain-fake-documents-us-justice-department-says/106173212</link><description>The US government says newly released documents from the Epstein files contain "untrue and sensationalist" claims about Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bef3e57d6bc4b93383de3f48852bb8d</guid></item><item><title>Video purported to show Ben Duckett drunk in Noosa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/video-purported-to-show-ben-duckett-drunk-in-noosa/106176806</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4eada5fc8d18466db504c6096920074</guid></item><item><title>England investigates Ben Duckett Noosa video as disastrous Ashes tour takes another turn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/england-investigates-ben-duckett-noosa-video/106176788</link><description>A video said to feature Ben Duckett is under ECB investigation in another problem for England's disastrous Ashes tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a005c9dfc957b64f8748c248130e1b6</guid></item><item><title>Sewage leak prompts Broadwater swimming warning ahead of Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/sewage-spill-broadwater-swimming-warning-gold-coast/106176726</link><description>Swimmers and boaties are being warned to avoid part of the Gold Coast Broadwater at Biggera Waters after a sewage leak just days out from Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2552642669cb5df34e8d569632c6cb66</guid></item><item><title>'$10,000 worth of Louis Vuitton' stolen in alleged home invasion at Old Beach, Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/10k-worth-of-louis-vuitton-stolen-old-beach-home-invasion/106176766</link><description>Two armed offenders allegedly forced the occupant of a house north of Hobart to open a safe, escaping with about $10,000 worth of Louis Vuitton items, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fe38a5f969582d221e1a535ed43e97a</guid></item><item><title>Girl, 12, critical after being pulled from water at Trigg Beach in Perth's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/girl-critical-after-being-pulled-from-water-at-trigg-beach-perth/106176930</link><description>A 12-year-old girl is in a critical condition after a surfer pulled her unresponsive from the water at Trigg Beach on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dc476927fc0183985b0e8c682a29246</guid></item><item><title>Young motorcyclist warns others after surviving high-speed crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/young-motorcyclist-warns-others-after-surviving-high-speed-crash/106174926</link><description>Liam Ganter does not remember the crash that nearly killed him, but he is living with the consequences, and hopes his story will stop others making the same mistake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75be536dbd463232b2f3e35ef40ba731</guid></item><item><title>Woman accused of 'repeatedly encouraging' partner to suicide granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/jacinta-drust-accused-encourage-suicide-granted-bail/106176852</link><description>An Adelaide woman accused of repeatedly encouraging her partner to take his own life has been granted home detention bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2aecc20ffe4f6337bc27a2b2f886f23</guid></item><item><title>WA Police charge man over alleged antisemitic comments on social media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/wa-man-charged-over-alleged-antisemitic-comments-social-media/106177056</link><description>A WA man's eligibility to hold a gun license will be reviewed after police charged him with allegedly posting antisemitic comments on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98352c8c09ced2a521975680289691f9</guid></item><item><title>Man in his 30s dies in e-scooter accident in Geraldton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/geraldton-e-scooter-death/106176946</link><description>Police say a man has died after losing control of an e-scooter in Geraldton overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6e22dae3326e39867c80d88af856799</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged over fatal stabbing of Zac McRae at Western Sydney bus station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/nsw-zac-mcrae-stabbing-charges-laid-mount-druitt/106177144</link><description>Emergency services were called to a bus station at Mount Druitt in August to find two 19-year-old men with stab wounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67fb83b44626811fc8915990df3c02da</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after weapons, detonators allegedly found at Dublin property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/sa-man-charged-after-weapons-allegedly-found-at-dublin/106177098</link><description>A man has been charged after police allegedly seized explosive detonators and three unregistered firearms among other weapons from his property in Adelaide's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29bedf5020f9f578b2bc51f0e8088d88</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach gunmen's phone pinged near Philippine region known for Islamic extremism: police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/bondi-beach-shooter-pinged-near-philippines-extremist-region/106176954</link><description>Mobile phone data suggests the Bondi Beach gunmen may have travelled near a region in the Philippines where Islamic State-aligned militants could still be operating, a police source has told the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d612ea3d7aa44793790596fd88c30a31</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate alleged attack of Norwegian tourist on Melbourne's St Kilda Pier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/norwegian-tourist-attacked-st-kilda-pier/106177528</link><description>Police are searching for at least seven more people allegedly involved in an assault last Thursday, which left a Norwegian tourist with a broken arm and facial injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96f28abd7068699d673afb06c3d1af5f</guid></item><item><title>$1.2 billion Hamilton Island deal sets precedent for Australian island resorts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/hamilton-island-sale-1-2-billion-dollars-blackstone/106176628</link><description>An American equity firm plans to purchase the jewel of the Whitsundays.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d244394aadb0e31bc11f4fe034c1983b</guid></item><item><title>Concerns over abortion, vasectomies, IVF, gender-affirming care access as Catholic organisation Calvary buys Hobart Private</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/hobart-private-hospital-sale-calvary-abortion-concerns/106177108</link><description>The operator of the Hobart Private Hospital has agreed to sell the facility to Catholic healthcare provider Calvary, leading to concerns about access to surgical abortions, vasectomies and some other legal procedures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5430d43a7cde42fec16d598dafd02f8d</guid></item><item><title>England skipper Ben Stokes defends his team as Jofra Archer ruled out of Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/england-boxing-day-ben-stokes-noosa/106177474</link><description>England's disastrous Ashes tour has received another blow with Jofra Archer ruled out of the remaining two Tests while skipper Ben Stokes has dug in to defend his beleaguered team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d30958882c35c298deebc595e0fbf384</guid></item><item><title>Duress alarms given to councillors amid violent threats from public</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/panic-buttons-for-bendigo-councillors-amid-public-threats/106174996</link><description>Duress alarms, often used by healthcare workers in high-risk settings, are being handed out by a regional Victorian council to boost elected representatives' safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">196582eef60cd6a7875f223de11cb3fe</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs veteran Geoffrey Shaw remembered as tireless advocate for Aboriginal rights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/vietnam-veteran-land-rights-champion-geoffrey-shaw-remembered/106177422</link><description>Alice Springs war veteran Geoffrey Shaw OAM has been remembered as a tireless advocate for Indigenous rights in Central Australia, who leaves a legacy of courage and service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9eadafd0e8f634cc10d6af15eb22c34</guid></item><item><title>Bomb-making list, firearms, extremist flags seized from Perth man accused of backing Bondi attackers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/bondi-attack-supporter-charged-in-perth-raid/106177710</link><description>Police found a bomb-making shopping list when they searched the home of a man who allegedly posted on social media that he supported the gunmen behind the Bondi terror attack, a Perth court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36521dccd8b218e73f0e8c2c3deeac09</guid></item><item><title>Even in the markets, it's beginning to look like Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/finance-report-241225/106177792</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b4f9300c7f3d9aad335a7ab323c356c</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds attend Christmas event at Syrian church that suffered terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/syria-church-celebration-after-june-terror-attack/106177942</link><description>People have flocked to a Christmas celebration at the Mar Elias church in Damascus, which was the site of a suicide bombing in June.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6da43d9f6ca287d1e0455318851aec43</guid></item><item><title>US and Ukraine reach consensus on key issues to end war with Russia but territorial disputes remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/us-ukraine-reach-consensus-on-key-issues-to-end-war/106178118</link><description>President Volodymyr Zelenskyy has said that Ukraine has reached consensus with the US on key issues to end the war with Russia but sensitive issues around territorial control, along with the management of a nuclear power plant, still remain unresolved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05c4eb8bd99fe5b814901714a1641ea9</guid></item><item><title>US sanctions five Europeans involved in regulating tech companies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/european-countries-slam-us-visa-bans/106178152</link><description>Leaders in Germany, France, Spain and the European Union slam the move as "intimidation and coercion".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64e74175013c5e059816621ae0498780</guid></item><item><title>Christmas quiz: How well do you know traditional Christmas carols?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/christmas-songs-quiz-traditional-carols/106133808</link><description>Do you know your Merry Gentlemen from you Three Kings? Your Dancers from your Prancers?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">824d802373eed7060a62552b3ca0c026</guid></item><item><title>Rental Family offers connection in an increasingly polarised world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/brendan-fraser-rental-family-hikari/106156660</link><description>Academy Award-winner Brendan Fraser speaks to ABC News about his new film and why human connection is the antidote to an increasingly polarised world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64796142ed39b4c48912a9c0e0b1a59d</guid></item><item><title>These young men fled Ukraine, but found a Europe far less welcoming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/young-men-fleeing-ukraine-russia-war-find-europe-less-welcoming/106164084</link><description>Since Russia launched its full-scale invasion in 2022 thousands of men have fled Ukraine. Once welcomed, they are increasingly finding a Europe that is running out of patience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d905f9e1324bb3c59e9004f0528c536</guid></item><item><title>Daniyl's journey through the Carpathian mountains to escape Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/daniyl-s-journey-through-the-carpathian-mountains/106165118</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d7ab5a934f950abe14d683115d0e5b6</guid></item><item><title>Gaza's remaining Christians mark Christmas with subdued celebrations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/gaza-remaining-christians-mark-christmas-subdued-celebrations/106177982</link><description>The small number of Christians remaining in Gaza have marked Christmas early with subdued celebrations in the shadow of ongoing conflict and occupation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eda5898dfa737111276df19f9aee72c4</guid></item><item><title>How political divides are putting more pressure on Australian couples</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/political-differences-pressure-australian-couples/106048876</link><description>More Australian relationships are struggling because of political divides. But experts say this does not have to be the end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfdae25d8b39d3f18ef6996ee10d6146</guid></item><item><title>What you need to know before you buy lab-grown versus natural diamonds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/what-to-know-about-laboratory-grown-and-natural-diamonds/106167962</link><description>Diamonds are generally considered a luxury asset that holds its value, but the emergence of laboratory-grown diamonds in the jewellery industry over recent years could challenge that belief.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24202eae3fcc5aaa1137df26f99527c9</guid></item><item><title>Second-hand shopping is a sustainable alternative, but could it be fuelling consumption?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/qld-second-hand-shopping-thrifting-consumption-apps/106173026</link><description>The rising popularity of second-hand and vintage fashion has been viewed as an opportunity to reduce fast fashion consumption; however, Australia remains one of the world's highest waste producers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71947152529f5c6dfc7368acdb22a6f8</guid></item><item><title>She readies for a 23rd Sydney to Hobart as the crew honours late owner Peter Rodgers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/sydney-to-hobart-she-peter-rodgers-memorial-race/106056430</link><description>A fellowship of sailors will embark on She's 23rd Sydney to Hobart campaign. As they do they will honour one of the most resilient boats in the race's history and remember late owner Peter Rodgers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e98f67c47d1cb8aba16c38df8cad139f</guid></item><item><title>What athletes mean when they talk about 'flow state' or being 'in the zone'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/the-science-and-art-behind-flow-state-sport-music-maths/106172880</link><description>There is a state of mind athletes talk about when they are totally absorbed in the moment and the actions of their sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3dd60dd0ec9a1fb90c71aed61ccdaf6</guid></item><item><title>Aged care centre confronts racism, improves staff retention with cultural celebrations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/aged-care-centre-starts-cultural-celebrations-to-address-racism/106085844</link><description>In 2024 a nurse reported racist abuse from some residents and family members. A year later, instances of abuse have plummeted and staff say it is because of a new program promoting respect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">106bbaf745444b130937df055a3765c6</guid></item><item><title>A million more Epstein files found, US Justice Department says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/more-epstein-files-found-by-us-department-of-justice/106178284</link><description>The Department of Justice says the release of the Epstein files will take "a few more weeks" after a million additional documents were uncovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">864b6e61dd0c9445d283aae091533e8b</guid></item><item><title>White House orders US forces to focus on 'quarantine' of Venezuelan oil, official says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/us-forces-to-quarantine-venezuelan-oil-as-un-condemns-aggression/106178276</link><description>The White House has ordered US military forces to focus almost exclusively on enforcing the "quarantine" of Venezuelan oil, a US official says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29c3a7ae3d0bfc2c7ac85c07e2b281fc</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Grant expected to remain category one system as it passes Cocos (Keeling) Islands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/tropical-cyclone-grant-impacts-cocos-islands-christmas-day/106178056</link><description>Tropical Cyclone Grant is expected to remain a category one system as it passes just to the north of the Cocos (Keeling) Islands off the West Australian coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ee3c8641c0d4437378e06a43346d1a2</guid></item><item><title>Australia's 'outback fashion capital' promotes healing through fashion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/fitzroy-crossing-fashion-event-helps-to-heal-community/106037952</link><description>Almost three years ago, a region in Western Australia's far north was devastated by once-in-a-century floods. Now fashion is stepping in, to heal scars and promote confidence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e3fc90c6543ea536adf803f980f1417</guid></item><item><title>Christmas morning snow in Tasmania, amid Western Australian heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/christmas-day-weather-snow-in-tasmania-heat-across-australia/106178338</link><description>Snow has arrived in the island state on Christmas morning, but hotter conditions are expected around the country, including a scorcher in the west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fb3eda7326f3e7bb000780545f48802</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate fire attack on 'Happy Chanukah' car in St Kilda East</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/happy-chanukah-car-firebombing-on-christmas-day-in-st-kilda-east/106178444</link><description>Authorities were called to a St Kilda East residence about 3am, where a car with a sign celebrating the Jewish holiday had been set alight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25fe8d829748789520bc501f02af6f27</guid></item><item><title>Analogue camera technicians with decades of experience retiring amid boom in film photography</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/future-of-film-as-camera-repairers-retire/106012478</link><description>As film photography surges in popularity among younger generations, technicians who repair analogue cameras are retiring, raising concerns it will become a dying art.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f2260136cba1cb406538e0cd51e9a96</guid></item><item><title>Why is there a massive camera in this tiny outback town?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/why-is-there-a-massive-camera-in-this-tiny-outback-town-/106178014</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad7e44111139ee42ee84852115b69d6</guid></item><item><title>Nick Bolkus, long-time Labor senator and Hawke-Keating-era minister, dies aged 75</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/nick-bolkus-obituary/106178484</link><description>Nick Bolkus, the long-time Labor senator who played an influential role in shaping Australia's migration policy under prime minister Paul Keating, has died aged 75.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2580267b3575e4e215ac342a2ffa5f6a</guid></item><item><title>Public assemblies banned for 14 days across Sydney as police enforce new powers under protest laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/public-assemblies-banned-14-days-in-sydney-under-new-protest-law/106178406</link><description>The NSW Police Commissioner, Mal Lanyon, has activated new powers prescribed under changes to NSW protest laws sparked by the terrorist attack at Bondi Beach on December 14.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0ffae786ed4d39fb5070328bf4f1a2a</guid></item><item><title>Man dies after Christmas Eve stabbing in Perth suburb of Aubin Grove</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/fatal-christmas-eve-stabbing-aubin-grove-perth/106178672</link><description>Homicide squad detectives are investigating the fatal stabbing of a man near a shopping complex in Perth's southern suburbs late on Christmas Eve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c638a04f15a13913bbe52f2f05fe4a5d</guid></item><item><title>'Scandinavian sleep method' could help your bad sleep</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/scandinavian-sleep-method-hot-cold-doona-temperature/106171152</link><description>This arrangement allows couples to continue sleeping together while meeting each person's individual needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd2b759a8a0d6dd541f517639ef58108</guid></item><item><title>Multiple bushfires threaten homes north and south of Perth, triggering power outages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/christmas-day-boddington-bushfire-emergency/106178756</link><description>Several bushfires burning north and south of Perth have caused major power blackouts, including the entire town of Margaret River.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02cd42472ece8c0d5742158fbddf1ee2</guid></item><item><title>Police make emergency declaration after partial crane collapse on the Gold Coast on Christmas Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/qld-crane-collapse-gold-coast-christmas-day/106178834</link><description>Storms hit south-east Queensland on Christmas Day afternoon, knocking out power to thousands of homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">554a17c52ea5b34c83e1e5244c87a2a7</guid></item><item><title>Pope Leo decries conditions in Gaza during Christmas Day speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/pope-leo-decries-conditions-in-gaza-christmas-speech/106178920</link><description>During his Urbi et Orbi (city and world) speech on Christmas Day, Pope Leo XIV has called for an end to all wars and for people to think about the conditions in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1023451f4ca1f78f346c0e2c228d714b</guid></item><item><title>The marathon mums competing in the Olympics and breaking records postpartum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/marathon-mums-competing-olympics-breaking-records-postpartum/106158638</link><description>For decades, pregnancy was seen as an "injury" that could end a career. But now, determination and growing industry support are seeing marathon-running mothers reach new heights after giving birth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">911ad6e201fbaac1ec3430b377f3fe12</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 26: Babe Ruth is sold to the Yankees to start the 'Curse of the Bambino'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/today-in-history-babe-ruth-is-sold-from-red-sox-to-the-yankees/106135072</link><description>It was the deal that changed the face of baseball for good, and set in motion the most infamous sporting curse of all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e5ab3496ff758523bc2b53626c7ae12</guid></item><item><title>From Spongebob to Orwell: Here's your guide to Boxing Day movies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/what-to-watch-boxing-day-cinemas/106170510</link><description>The soaring mercury has you craving the cool, dark sanctuary of the cinema. But what to see? The art-house awards-season hopeful? The psychological book adaptation? The one with the big snake?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0067604e8d12d4c660cec1c700395679</guid></item><item><title>Gamba grass risks star attractions in NT's beloved Litchfield National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/nt-national-park-under-threat-from-invasive-gamba-grass-weed/106167898</link><description>Much-loved by locals and bringing in more than 250,000 visitors a year, Litchfield National Park has become one of the Northern Territory's star attractions. But it's under threat from a near-invisible invader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b403c062bde0be6fd104443d00f5983e</guid></item><item><title>Shield and First Guardian raise the question, who pays when super funds collapse?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/first-guardian-investors-dealt-another-devastating-blow/106145496</link><description>Thousands of First Guardian investors were dealt another devastating blow when it was revealed just $1.6 million had been recovered from the almost $450 million invested in the collapsed fund. Who will end up paying investors back their lost retirement savings?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61ee5120fe363a2c94729fb05ef29323</guid></item><item><title>King Charles delivers annual Christmas message</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/king-charles-delivers-annual-christmas-message-/106179278</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39d40c75c736870f8c155790eac970df</guid></item><item><title>Monitoring cameras help determine Adélie penguin colony size</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/adelie-penguins-timelapse/106157940</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87708cd86d3a08507b2e7ec75b9abd83</guid></item><item><title>Scientists on 'high alert' as bird flu threat looms over Australian Antarctic Territory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/bird-flu-threat-looms-over-australian-antarctic-territory/106171164</link><description>Preparations are underway for the arrival of the deadly H5 strain of bird flu in the Australian Antarctic Territory, as scientists gather baseline population data so they can measure potential deaths among wildlife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e7609304214a3894f11e91309f5811f</guid></item><item><title>Social media can help save lives during cyclone season, but also has a tendency to spread misinformation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/qld-cyclones-social-media-pros-and-cons-misinformation/106159684</link><description>State government reports have found that while social media plays a vital role in warning communities during tropical cyclones, some posts can lack context and spread misinformation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27e545f26b68033e05466ed4d78a058d</guid></item><item><title>Entertainer Kamahl, now 91, reflects on life, career spanning 70 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/kamahl-entertainer-reflects-on-life-70-year-career-racism/106132732</link><description>At 91, Malaysian-born Australian entertainment legend Kamahl reflects on his life and career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b946d4eaecacc1a82baa773ab3a7fab2</guid></item><item><title>The best classical music and jazz stories of 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/best-classical-music-and-jazz-stories-2025/106176460</link><description>From homegrown heroes to visiting legends, here are Australia's favourite classical music and jazz stories this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e20a46b15fc67a0c56dc741372cd716d</guid></item><item><title>Boxing Day Test more than just cricket for descendant of Australia's First XI Aboriginal team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/boxing-day-test-medal-presenter-honours-aboriginal-cricket-team/106137822</link><description>They travelled on horse and cart and were smuggled on a boat for three months to England, the story of the First XI Aboriginal cricket team is being remembered as a descendant presents the Boxing Day medal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b50808a74cf8fa3304dee6cab90223c8</guid></item><item><title>Bells and bonfires — Christmas celebrations around the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/christmas-celebrations-around-the-world/106179306</link><description>From Bethlehem to Beijing, people around the world have been celebrating Christmas in their own traditional way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9b0565c226191e73c1d21e704691bc1</guid></item><item><title>Hoop dreams come true as first Indigenous basketball team heads to USA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/indigenous-basketball-team-heads-to-usa/106158408</link><description>School attendance was just as important as a jump shot for the scouts picking a First Nations team to take part in a prestigious US basketball competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d34d1da0da81d4b5ea855db9d5a3d0b9</guid></item><item><title>Why Australian Open organisers will be torn on offering Nick Kyrgios a wildcard berth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/nick-kyrgios-australian-open-wildcard-update/106179426</link><description>Nick Kyrgios remains one of Australian tennis' biggest names, but, according to Mark Philippoussis, there are clear pros and cons to offering him a wildcard berth for the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db1b5fc77ce0878c8ec246e2f1b02586</guid></item><item><title>New virtual fencing laws could promise safer bushfire response by allowing farmers to move stock remotely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/virtual-fencing-could-help-in-bushfire-response/106170506</link><description>New technology allowing livestock to be remotely moved via electronic collars has been legalised in SA. Industry says virtual fencing has the potential to save animals and even human lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">192897585527f4b7df9b5fd155d53c37</guid></item><item><title>Endangered malleefowl chick saved from fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/endangered-malleefowl-chick-saved-from-fire/106177074</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b90ce9d521644bc3b0b15c52ef61269</guid></item><item><title>Endangered malleefowl chick saved in 2,000-hectare fire at Wyperfeld National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/malleefowl-chick-saved-wyperfeld-national-park-bushfire/106176370</link><description>An endangered malleefowl chick has been saved from a 2,000-hectare bushfire in a regional Victorian national park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddefccd7a2b1c56365c12e2baad72bb7</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Australia all out for 152 on Boxing Day Test, England bowled out for 110 in reply on day one at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/live-updates-ashes-boxing-day-test-australia-vs-england-day-one/106179504</link><description>Australia lead England by 42 runs on a wild Boxing Day after 20 wickets fall on the first day at the MCG. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c303409339583878a217bf5cfe4bcd88</guid></item><item><title>Skippering school kids along Magela Creek system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/skippering-school-kids-along-magela-creek-system/105848148</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">086f23f55822e022cf4fbfd0a56d6f3f</guid></item><item><title>Drone shot above Kakadu sandstone country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/drone-shot-above-kakadu-sandstone-country/105848288</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7abfe75eded55e4d3e718a23038566e</guid></item><item><title>Driving near Kakadu wetlands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/driving-near-kakadu-wetlands/105848610</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44a6b4f95afbb0fa7eee54fb5a7f017c</guid></item><item><title>King tide at Nightcliff beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/king-tide-at-nightcliff-beach/105848020</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18f6764d3b52708bd856985f15fa3f13</guid></item><item><title>Dead trees in Tommy Cutt creek</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/dead-trees-in-tommy-cutt-creek/105848200</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a02e7b174f7540e1f7c00b2fcb96175</guid></item><item><title>Panning shot over Kakadu National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/panning-shot-over-kakadu-national-park/106179456</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eeb462767c44fbab555df86f304749f4</guid></item><item><title>When can you get a refund or exchange under Australian law?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/what-are-the-return-and-exchange-rights-in-australia/106078512</link><description>It can feel awkward asking for a refund or to exchange an item if you’re not sure what you’re entitled to. We’ve broken it down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2723be7871092c53be9590ed79e4005</guid></item><item><title>Pedestrian struck in hit-and-run during Christmas Day Tasmania breath test evasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/pedestrian-tasmanian-hit-and-run-after-police-breath-test/106179584</link><description>A 23-year-old driver in a hit-and-run on Christmas Day following a roadside breath-test evasion in Tasmania's north west has been charged by police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">056c2be17ffd6886c7f1fa385294adb8</guid></item><item><title>Vladimir Putin critic and pro-war activist sentenced to six years in prison by Russian court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/russian-court-sentences-war-activist-and-putin-critic-to-prison/106179590</link><description>Sergei Udaltsov, the leader of the Left Front movement that opposes President Vladimir Putin, was arrested last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f46694fd12b3eb7d27f87246e14db092</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump launches US strikes against Islamic State militants in Nigeria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/donald-trump-ordered-strikes-against-islamic-state-nigeria/106179626</link><description>Donald Trump says he ordered a "powerful and deadly strike against ISIS terrorist scum" for targeting Christians at levels not seen for years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e78e946ebf1f357d5108534304674ddc</guid></item><item><title>Tim Wilson desires to one day lead the federal Liberal Party</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/tim-wilson-liberal-party-politics-now-the-interview/106162420</link><description>In a broad ranging interview for the Politics Now podcast, Liberal MP Tim Wilson speaks about what the Liberal Party should be fighting for and why he would one day like to be its leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0109c7585acd76bdfd34229961e7858a</guid></item><item><title>Fishing facilities lacking despite high boat ownership in Karratha</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/karratha-boating-fishing-lack-of-toilets-filleting-facilities/106093260</link><description>Female fishers say the lack of toilet facilities at Karratha boat ramps does not cater for the increasing number of women on the water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef18396e1b505919d63f589ce903e197</guid></item><item><title>Boddington gold mine infrastructure damaged by bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/boddington-fire-western-australia-christmas-fires/106179544</link><description>The bushfire has burnt through more than 4,000 hectares.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e98a4c122f6d614247d735cd5c74867d</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast exclusion zone displacing tourists will continue until Tuesday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/damaged-crane-gold-coast-80-tourists-evacuated/106179414</link><description>Holiday-makers spent Christmas night in temporary accommodation after a crane damaged in a Gold Coast storm caused authorities to evacuate several streets around Southport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0e6df85ea6ebde13f9f577d928f21f5</guid></item><item><title>Police name person of interest in arson attack on 'Happy Chanukah' car in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/police-name-person-of-interest-hanukkah-vehicle-arson/106179668</link><description>Officers in Melbourne's south continue to investigate an arson attack on a car with a Hanukkah decoration in the early hours of Christmas morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8296de41305e534266d705e1ae6c66e</guid></item><item><title>2025 Sydney to Hobart Yacht Race: Day one of the 80th edition of the blue water classic, as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/sydney-to-hobart-yacht-race-live-blog/106179718</link><description>Master Lock Comanche takes over from LawConnect late on day one of the Sydney to Hobart, as tough conditions take their toll on the fleet, forcing a number of retirements. Look back at the action in our blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a51b09c950062dc669c8df81130ac30e</guid></item><item><title>US judge blocks deportation of British anti-disinformation activist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/us-barred-from-deporting-campaigner-imran-ahmed/106179794</link><description>A US judge temporarily blocks the Trump administration from detaining a British man over his work combating online hate and disinformation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a392805d99ee3699f0176ec99c0501a</guid></item><item><title>Poland intercepts Russian plane over Baltic, reports airspace breaches from Belarus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/poland-intercepts-russian-plane-over-baltic/106179994</link><description>Poland has warned several incidents regarding airspace during the holiday season may signal a provocation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e6bb0e0fce20217418dbbc6e3e3d1dd</guid></item><item><title>US Department of Defense releases missile launch video after northwest Nigeria operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/us-missile-launch-video-nigeria/106180096</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05859f74ae3122414840f1530da6383c</guid></item><item><title>Paddleboarders rescued after drifting from Portarlington to Wyndham Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/victoria-family-rescued-christmas-day-paddelboard-mishap/106179858</link><description>Police say two holidaymakers are lucky to be alive after being rescued from the cold waters of Port Phillip, south-west of Melbourne, on Christmas Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50da2ebb51bc40fb017ee61ba1c7f634</guid></item><item><title>Japan okays record defence budget amid rising tensions with China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/japan-approves-record-defence-spending-china-tensions/106180112</link><description>Japan's cabinet approves a record defence budget plan aiming to fortify its strike-back capability and coastal defence amid rising regional tensions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">226514049ef3fb20b15245e7b63db459</guid></item><item><title>Sydney to Hobart pays tribute to Bondi victims with petals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/sydney-to-hobart-boat-tributes-bondi-victims-with-petals-/106180276</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1eb26c06a311d6aa9fafe2681d251de5</guid></item><item><title>Kazuaki Ono's photo exhibition Southern Crust melds Australian scenery with our bakery culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/southern-crust-bakery-photography-exhibition/106169972</link><description>Kazuaki Ono wanted to entice people from Japan to visit Australia by showing we have as much to offer with our food culture as we do with our iconic scenery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92d7b7dca9079219e2846df04f166a65</guid></item><item><title>Police seeking to identify offender after man stabbed to death north of Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/laramba-stabbing-death-police-seek-to-identify-offender/106180286</link><description>Northern Territory police are investigating after a 35-year-old man was stabbed to death in a small town north-west of Alice Springs on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f71bf95fa0cc7db88b498dde4d7d7fb</guid></item><item><title>The best documentaries to binge in the weird week after Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/best-docos-to-binge-over-christmas-summer/106022170</link><description>Summer is here and so are those long leisurely days of nothing following Christmas. Here are five documentaries that will help you while away the time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e551aa5c5e8b609e0c5d9d9e10e9bab2</guid></item><item><title>Paddleboarders rescued from waters near Wyndham Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/paddleboarders-rescued/106180450</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">683af46d6bfa4d80eb1a675b273d2153</guid></item><item><title>Harry Brook's on the attack, Cameron Green runs himself out and Josh Tongue cashes in — quick hits from Boxing Day at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/ashes-test-england-australia-quick-hits-harry-brook-cam-green/106179806</link><description>A record crowd for cricket at the MCG saw another fast-forward day of Ashes action as calamitous run outs and wild Bazball batting took centre stage. Here are the quick hits from the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75bc2f7fccf9d4a6d699188d9e20e531</guid></item><item><title>England's cowardly batting response spares Australian blushes on farcical Ashes Boxing Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/cowardly-english-batting-spares-australia-s-boxing-day-blushes/106180182</link><description>Australia's batting order is unsettled, unbalanced and out of form, but it matters little as England throws in the towel and considers the challenge of a Boxing Day Ashes Test all too hard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">187ff36f0baab20891ef104286fac289</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy plans to meet with Trump as peace plan with Russia inches closer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/volodymyr-zelenskyy-donald-trump-meeting-peace-plan-russia/106180632</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy says he is planning to meet with US President Donald Trump on Sunday to search for ways to end the war with Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c94842f6bc240f2c1f589fba07963d6d</guid></item><item><title>At least 14 injured in a knife and chemical attack at factory in Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/at-least-14-injured-in-japan-knife-and-chemical-attack/106180698</link><description>A man has been arrested after stabbing eight people at a factory in the Japanese city of Mishima.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f722fd9947b691159d1707229f25d577</guid></item><item><title>Family unearths story of Australian cricket's 'girl Bradman' Hazel Pritchard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/cricket-hazel-pritchard-girl-bradman-women-cricket-test-1937/106100096</link><description>There was no central catalogue for the scattered histories of women's cricket. That may be about to change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75fa9e9dfca84c469dc8ce1a5f7d1c67</guid></item><item><title>ABC 50/50 Megaquiz: This week we're testing your knowledge on Die Hard, pizza and princesses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/abc-50-50-quiz-december-27/106157446</link><description>Every question has only two options: one is right and the other is wrong. You have an even chance of guessing correctly each time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33b6e6f179eac330d4007f957f77b475</guid></item><item><title>Today in history, December 27: Benazir Bhutto assasinated at election rally by teenage militant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/today-history-december-27-benazir-bhutto-assasination-pakistan/106165790</link><description>During the tense campaign for her third term as prime minister of Pakistan, Benazir Bhutto survived one attempt on her life before she was shot dead by a teenage suicide bomber on December 27, 2007. She helped to build a political dynasty that continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">493a29be57b003ed7d2fcd17f5ab5bf9</guid></item><item><title>The 'Epstein Files' reveal how Ghislaine Maxwell helped pull young girls into a paedophile's web</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/epstein-files-victim-grooming/106179662</link><description>The arts camp was prestigious, and "Jane" had travelled almost 2,500 kilometres to attend. As she sat by herself on a bench between classes, a man and a woman approached her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a45298537181d5d1a679e98cdd53ae08</guid></item><item><title>England's soft underbelly exposed again as 20 Boxing Day wickets put MCG pitch in firing line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/england-batting-criticised-mcg-pitch-20-wickets-boxing-day/106180560</link><description>England's batters once again fall flat on their faces in the face of tricky conditions at the MCG for the Boxing Day Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8066d2349a2bd017297819914f562f0f</guid></item><item><title>A quick guide to the best fabrics and fibres for summer and their sustainability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/what-fibres-and-fabrics-to-wear-in-summer/105981546</link><description>What our clothes are made of can make a big difference when it comes to keeping cool, but not all fabrics are created equal. Here is what to look for — and avoid — during the warmer months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dc31cbc8f4af5932b93e4fb5b030ee6</guid></item><item><title>25 years on, the search continues for stars of the Sydney Olympics' closing ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/sydney-olympics-kewpie-doll-search/106169888</link><description>For Trevor Harvey, honouring a departed mate meant one thing — finding a 6-metre-tall Kewpie doll from the Sydney Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2db87d7aa3f1086c01d0693d98b03505</guid></item><item><title>Sydney to Hobart race crews doing it tough in challenging conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/sydney-to-hobart-yacht-race-day-two/106180992</link><description>Crews are battling sea sickness and tough conditions as teams head for the finish in the 2025 Sydney to Hobart yacht race.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0256d5474c3476a9c0ba3461c1ee630d</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal community tension in Victoria's north amid health board division</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/aboriginal-community-tension-mallee-board-division/106170928</link><description>An annual meeting to elect a new board at Mallee District Aboriginal Services has led to divisions among members and incoming board members as the chair announces elections will be re-run.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f068d39e8567f078e563191fa53cb96</guid></item><item><title>When green energy threatens what it is meant to save</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/nelson-wetlands-green-energy-boom-planning-protections/106097868</link><description>In a tiny town near the Victoria–South Australia border, a proposed wind farm near a protected wetland is posing a big question for Australia's planning regulators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cce00efa3282f14d1cb581e60a16068</guid></item><item><title>BBL title-holders Hobart Hurricanes beat Perth Scorchers but lose Tim David to hamstring injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/tim-david-injures-hamstring-as-hurricanes-beat-scorchers/106181008</link><description>Hobart's title defence suffers a huge blow after star batter Tim David injures his hamstring in his team's four-wicket win over the Scorchers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83ac28695423a38f74cc26978038bce4</guid></item><item><title>The best vantage points and everything else you need to know about Sydney's New Year's Eve fireworks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/where-to-watch-the-new-years-eve-fireworks-in-sydney-2025/106175504</link><description>Sydney's New Year's Eve celebrations will this year pay tribute to the victims of the Bondi terror attack, with events to feature a heavy police presence. Here is everything you need to know to plan your night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf93969efada38d9bce589ed6247600b</guid></item><item><title>South Australian playwright pays tribute to late partner in new production</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/anthony-nocera-log-boy-play/106095628</link><description>An upcoming South Australian playwright was writing a horror, comedy show about the prospect of losing a much older partner, then it happened to him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">459b7018fcf05da5cd1894814562d377</guid></item><item><title>Ice sport broomball faces extinction as player numbers fall and rinks shut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/townsville-broomball-club-sees-fewer-players/106158068</link><description>North Queenslanders have been playing the ice-based sport broomball for decades, but dwindling numbers and rising costs have players fearing it may be dying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01e19be057cc1ac4a2b9ec8aa216b425</guid></item><item><title>Australian medical history – the heart donor who still walks the earth 20 years later</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/qld-domino-transplant-lucinda-simpson-cystic-fibrosis/106127132</link><description>Lucinda is a member of an exclusive club — living heart donors, and is the only woman to have a baby after a heart-lung-liver transplant</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fdc746668c7434580fe039bc48bbe9f</guid></item><item><title>13 long reads to catch up on for your summer holiday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/long-reads-2025-virginia-trioli/106175224</link><description>Here we've gathered a bunch of other things to read while you're relaxing over summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96a03c3f95f56c5d4532a4ecf3388352</guid></item><item><title>Ladybugs set loose at Australian Parliament House in Canberra over summer to take out pests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/ladybugs-released-at-canberra-parliament-house/106160100</link><description>When politicians and most staff are away for the summer holidays, a ravenous group of fly-in workers descend on Parliament House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d0fc288cf443c20ee792420a6420b93</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with string of offences after burglaries that began on Christmas Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/melbourne-christmas-burglaries-arrest-victoria-police/106181074</link><description>A man is arrested following a Melbourne crime spree that allegedly began about 7pm on Christmas Day and ended with burglaries of two restaurants about 6:30am on Boxing Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">586d0a6317c6e08768b05fa34fd680d3</guid></item><item><title>Northern parts of Queensland bracing for heavy rainfall, potential flooding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/queensland-weather-rain-and-flood-weekend-forecast/106180424</link><description>Holiday travellers are being urged to check road closures before setting off on their journey, with parts of the state expecting rain into the middle of next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72cfc7364a99693d7110bd5756144916</guid></item><item><title>Former football manager Harry Redknapp wins King George VI Chase with The Jukebox Man</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/harry-redknapps-horse-the-jukebox-man-wins-king-george-vi-chase/106181036</link><description>Harry Redknapp is known for his long career as a football manager, but on Boxing Day his horse The Jukebox Man wins famous jumps race the King George VI Chase in one of the all-time great finishes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">749bc9565b9fe8fe0e0bb8645e5dac96</guid></item><item><title>175-year-old Nor' West Bend Station reopened to public after decades of restoration work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/175-year-old-nor-west-bend-station-reopened-to-public/106028646</link><description>History is being brought back to life at a former pastoral station that has seen drought, boom and bust over the course of its 175 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8940f35a06954e50ec7e7c189ecb994a</guid></item><item><title>Somalia, Arab nations denounce Israeli recognition of Somaliland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/somalia-arab-nations-denounce-israeli-recognition-of-somaliland/106181060</link><description>Matters of strategy are behind Israel's drive to recognise Somaliland, analysts say, as Arab nations worry about instability in the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90cd83b662f7981d74e54e2b1206eef6</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar's first election in five years begins – but experts warn it's a sham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/myanmar-first-elections-in-five-years/106180094</link><description>Five years after the military toppled a democratically elected government and imprisoned its leaders, the country is preparing to hold national elections beginning on December 28.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7076d82ea1efed8789a7b4ce43e02d86</guid></item><item><title>NT government says release of State Square plans not in 'public interest'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/nt-plans-for-darwin-landmark-state-square-building/106171494</link><description>Plans for Darwin's new State Square Art Gallery remain unclear, with the Northern Territory arts minister saying he is "eagerly awaiting" an outcome of who will move into the $145 million building.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f39d173d357f2943120ac017a52ff613</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: England wins first Test in Australia in 5,468 days after two-day MCG match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/ashes-boxing-day-test-live-australia-england-day-two/106181180</link><description>England survives a nervy run chase to win its first Test match on Australian soil since 2011 in a manic two-day encounter in Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bf833f810194620176aaebe677ed1b4</guid></item><item><title>Mosque blast during Friday noon prayers kills eight in Syria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/mosque-blast-during-friday-noon-prayers-kills-eight-in-syria/106181170</link><description>The attack has been claimed by the ultra-conservative Sunni group Saraya Ansar al-Sunnah, which was also responsible for a Damascus church bombing in June.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4f4106013b1c8b4b610fbfa10b3cbb7</guid></item><item><title>The Cure guitarist and keyboard player Perry Bamonte dies aged 65</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/cure-guitarist-perry-bamonte-dies-aged-65/106181152</link><description>The Cure guitarist and keyboard player Perry Bamonte has died aged 65, the legendary British dark rock band announced on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adccf50b70e56c31ea93a366da4404f1</guid></item><item><title>Trio of retirees from Dongara win award for community rubbish collection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/dongara-roadside-relics-group-collecting-litter-wins-award/106154988</link><description>Armed with gloves, bags, buckets and tongs, a trio of passionate rubbish removalists have picked up an award in this regional Western Australia town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfadfe96068151ef0ee3f0fa86954cde</guid></item><item><title>Storm Hunter returns for the Australian summer targeting a top doubles ranking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/storm-warning-aussie-wants-to-regain-world-number-one-status/106181154</link><description>Popular Australian Storm Hunter is back from injury and adamant she can return to the form that made her the world's top-ranked doubles player.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd5d5e8783ea370e7a17bcad44a8bacc</guid></item><item><title>Australians are drinking less, but one cohort won't give up the booze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/australians-drinking-less-older-taking-bigger-health-risks/105371018</link><description>Health-conscious Australians may be thinking twice about having that first or second beer, but not all of us are getting the message when it comes to alcohol and risky drinking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fd92f06e70a0c7e12bc8de8191b8249</guid></item><item><title>These volunteer firefighters keep communities safe. Here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/volunteer-firefighters-risk-their-lives-to-keep-communities-safe/106139496</link><description>Volunteer firefighters put their lives on the line for their community, despite facing extreme situations, heightened health risks and constant exposure to traumatic events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e5df5e52758b691d4ab28b9ed0d45a1</guid></item><item><title>China hits US defence firms with sanctions over arms sales to Taiwan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/china-sanctions-us-defence-firms-over-arms-sales-taiwan/106181220</link><description>China urged the US to "stop the dangerous moves of arming Taiwan" after its multi-billion-dollar sale of weapons last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33227ba851bab9d9f659aabc61e30a14</guid></item><item><title>Ukrainian capital Kyiv under Russian attack, officials say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/ukrainian-capital-kyiv-under-russian-attack-officials-say/106181284</link><description>Explosions have been heard, air defences are in operation and the military is on alert for impending missile attacks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4965b085c5fd94c37f6cd1db355ea66f</guid></item><item><title>How a tsunami in Sri Lanka sparked a push to prevent drowning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/sri-lanka-tsunami-solutions-to-drownings-waterways/106173020</link><description>What began as tsunami relief, has become something more powerful — teaching children not to fear the water that surrounds them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e4eb5c147fe58006ee735956f6a75f7</guid></item><item><title>Labor party identity Tim Picton in critical condition following alleged assault in Northbridge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/man-critical-following-serious-assault-northbridge/106181328</link><description>Tim Picton, who spearheaded the campaign behind WA Labor's landslide 2021 victory, is in a critical condition in hospital after he was allegedly assaulted in Northbridge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4ffd4440fc8f15d5c3d0db777d2115c</guid></item><item><title>Thailand and Cambodia agree to ceasefire, ending weeks of clashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/thailand-and-cambodia-agree-to-ceasefire-/106181650</link><description>The ceasefire will take effect on Saturday at noon local time, in a conflict which has displaced more than half a million people on both sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3865afc2e60cb84e441f304589306cc</guid></item><item><title>Urban water restrictions likely across Victoria as dam levels drop and dry summer predicted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/urban-water-restrictions-likely-across-victoria-dam-levels-drop/106181336</link><description>Victoria's water storage levels have dropped to 61 per cent capacity after most of the state recorded below average rainfall in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">802ede04d18fcccb9d3a0a58674a6485</guid></item><item><title>Robots, AI and 'smart tourism' will change how we travel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/tourist-new-technology-ai-travel-smart-tourism/105956560</link><description>Will new technology lead to streamlined service and stress-free travel, or will it fundamentally change tourism and tourist destinations?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6265082f5c6968dacc7e1d1fd35c0efb</guid></item><item><title>Residents return home as threat level downgraded for Boddington fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/residents-return-home-after-boddington-fire/106181310</link><description>Residents have begun returning to their homes after a bushfire burning south-east of Perth forced them to flee on Christmas Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38d7667979dbb4c735e54fcc93462d7a</guid></item><item><title>Police overseeing Bondi terror response investigate tattooed man at Newcastle beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/police-investigate-tattooed-man-at-newcastle-beach/106180310</link><description>Police overseeing the response to the Bondi terror attack are investigating after a man was seen at a NSW beach allegedly showing a tattoo of a banned Nazi symbol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8294c2c1aef91af579261a260d4c364b</guid></item><item><title>Austrian tourist rescued after falling from rocks near Cape Schanck on southern tip of the Mornington Peninsula</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/vic-cape-schanck-rescue/106181672</link><description>A 25-year-old woman has been winched into an ambulance helicopter after falling onto rocks at Cape Schanck.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dd8be8b5fd0b8803a0958b9181fd076</guid></item><item><title>Hobart family reunited with dog nearly four years after it disappeared from home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/tasmanian-family-reunited-with-missing-dog-found-living-wild/106181610</link><description>A blurry photo on social media has led to a Hobart family reuniting with their missing dog nearly four years after it vanished from their home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a92c519decdd8e65e93256421933dd9b</guid></item><item><title>Gus Atkinson injured and Marnus Labuschagne struggles again as Bazball pays off for England — five quick hits from day two of the Boxing Day Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/ashes-boxing-day-two-quick-hits-atkinson-bazball-wins/106181258</link><description>Bazball finally has its day in the Aussie sun as England's audacious tactics pay off despite another hit to its pace stocks. Here are the quick hits from day two at the MCG.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ea1ecf2308c1e2b3b75e519e61af7b8</guid></item><item><title>Australia belted, England vindicated and Test cricket wounded in MCG Ashes Test farce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/australia-belted-england-vindicated-test-cricket-wounded-mcg/106181362</link><description>As England deservedly celebrates a long-awaited Test win in Australia, everyone else involved counts the cost of a farcical and damaging two-day disaster at the MCG.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b8c1e011213e214665690d118a882bc</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after fatal Christmas Eve stabbing in Perth suburb of Aubin Grove</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/man-charged-over-aubin-grove-fatal-stabbing/106181894</link><description>A man has been charged over the fatal stabbing of a 19-year-old in the Perth southern suburb of Aubin Grove on Christmas Eve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67bc1a7da4fbcccdb1c31069871b1133</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Calls for MCG Boxing Day Test pitch to be rated 'poor' as England and Australia batting criticised</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/boxing-day-ashes-test-ends-inside-two-days/106181452</link><description>After the first Test of the Ashes series sensationally ended in just two days, Cricket Australia hoped it wouldn't see that again for a century. It's happened again five weeks later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bef5f9857484c314cb5ce8fecde9597f</guid></item><item><title>Jewish security group warned of violent antisemitism during Hanukkah event weeks before Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/security-risks-bondi-hanukkah-raised-weeks-before-terror-attack/106181812</link><description>A document by the Jewish Community Security Group NSW raised the alarm about the threat of Islamic extremism and Jihadist-inspired lone-actor attacks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4955cd185417b83f3edc94fc532e03cc</guid></item><item><title>Woman dies in custody at police watch house in Tennant Creek</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/woman-aged-44-dies-in-custody-as-nt-police-investigate/106181994</link><description>Authorities say the cause of death is unknown, and further updates will be provided.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79c818bee979e9738d84593296ec831a</guid></item><item><title>Russian drones, missiles pound Ukraine ahead of Zelenskyy-Trump meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-27/russian-strikes-pound-ukraine-ahead-of-zelenskyy-trump-meeting/106181990</link><description>Russia has attacked Ukraine with hundreds of missiles and drones ahead of what President Volodymyr Zelenskyy said would be a crucial meeting with Donald Trump to work out a deal to end nearly four years of war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0ac272b1e62ea83e94bba00d6fc8eee</guid></item></channel></rss>