<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:32:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Call for button battery redesign after new study reveals horrific injuries and fatalities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/button-battery-warning-danger-deaths-lithium-swallow/103986966</link><description>A new study reveals the horrific injuries suffered after swallowing or inserting button batteries but manufacturers aren't prioritising their redesign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46ab5f96ade65908ecf6b7be8673e61f</guid></item><item><title>The US election is about style more than substance. It's why Kamala Harris needs to nail her DNC speech in about eight seconds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/us-election-kamala-harris-dnc-speech-style-substance/104256162</link><description>When the Democrat presidential candidate Kamala Harris delivers her speech to the Democratic National Convention today, style will be almost everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bddf8093759d999153dfd749b90e144a</guid></item><item><title>Reserve Bank restructure closer to reality after Treasurer Jim Chalmers offers olive branch to Angus Taylor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/reserve-bank-restructure-closer-to-reality/104260250</link><description>The Reserve Bank of Australia is a step closer to its biggest restructure in three decades after the treasurer offers an assurance to his Coalition counterpart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e920ec5b24583b8f74962ecc7f9c2585</guid></item><item><title>Have Your Say: What was the issue, policy or event that decided your vote?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-02-26/federal-election-your-say/104788518</link><description>After a five-week campaign, the results are in with Labor returned to government. Is there a policy or issue that swayed your vote? Have Your Say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">320dfcbec9cd8fe02e449407ce78e618</guid></item><item><title>Global gas lobby tries to hamper Victoria's electrification efforts by stoking fear, researchers say</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-02-28/global-gas-lobby-push-against-victoria-electrification/104966938</link><description>Analysis by international think tank InfluenceMap has looked at how the gas industry has pushed back against efforts in Victoria to transition away from gas as part of a global campaign to keep households hooked on the fuel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">351bf16f6e74e31517f62e4f39bfc850</guid></item><item><title>Voters tell ABC's Your Say they want politicians with a vision, not bickering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-13/abc-your-say-federal-election-politicians-with-vision/105164874</link><description>Voters tell ABC's Your Say campaign they want courage and vision from politicians, not bickering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">033ddce5ad54070fbce620dc6760d9ba</guid></item><item><title>Push for seniors' dental scheme grows ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-13/aged-care-dental-scheme-australia-federal-election/105149782</link><description>Imagine living in aged care and not having your teeth or dentures properly cleaned and checked each day. That's a risk faced by elderly Australians, prompting calls for the next federal government to boost oral health training and services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36d312d336a36247fd1c01e78814112b</guid></item><item><title>Australians tell ABC's Your Say they are struggling more than ever with housing costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-15/abc-your-say-federal-election-2025-housing-policies/105175180</link><description>Voters tell ABC's Your Say campaign they are struggling more than ever with housing costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54451646ec8e9f100cc2fe59fc9c08c5</guid></item><item><title>Australia's growing cohort of tenants fear they will rent forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-16/australias-growing-tenant-cohort-fear-forever-renting/105127148</link><description>Home ownership rates in Australia have been falling for decades, and with rental vacancies at record lows and prices at historic highs, many fear their dream of owning a home may be out of reach. Some experts say rental caps could help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f35fe439f533ac9522c679c7e37187</guid></item><item><title>Graduates in 'debt vortex' as HECS front and centre for first time in an election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-16/federal-election-2025-hecs-student-debt-policies/105177248</link><description>New research shows a sharp rise in HECS debts, despite graduate earning power declining, as student loans become a potent election issue for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48707ffafbe02c400b1200e6269fd40e</guid></item><item><title>Housing advocates seek federal funding election promise for co-op model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-17/housing-cooperative-solution-proposed-for-rental-crisis/105108816</link><description>Advocates admit co-operative housing models are not for everyone but say for the right residents, they offer more security and affordable pricing than traditional rentals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3608b0c1ae56f5a5b36968898f65df5e</guid></item><item><title>Next-generation voters call for better engagement ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-18/federal-election-rural-next-generation-voters/105173450</link><description>Young people in Albury say issues that directly affect them and their communities are not being addressed by major parties for the 2025 election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ae182892b8c9591cd9ec35e6e57fcb9</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne seat of Calwell highlights Labor woes as Gaza pain galvanises Muslim voters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-20/calwell-labor-backlash-over-gaza-islamophobia/104850500</link><description>Dissatisfaction with the Albanese government's stance on Israel-Palestine among many Arab and Muslim voters threatens to unseat Labor MPs, in some places for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63e7f9854fee5bc20e54ee2f5bd136f4</guid></item><item><title>Cost of living, housing among key concerns in SA marginal seat of Boothby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/boothby-cost-of-living-federal-election-2025/105190262</link><description>At this year’s federal election, the South Australian seat of Boothby is one of the state’s two marginal seats. As part of the ABC’s “Your Say” campaign, we spoke to residents in the electorate about their biggest concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dfd66b0605d29b960082ff52f18c170</guid></item><item><title>Energy projects in South West WA threaten votes for major federal parties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/energy-projects-south-west-wa-federal-election-labor-liberals/105152524</link><description>Australia's two major parties have tied their federal election fates to controversial energy projects in WA's South West where the issues have polarised voters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8962a53de05f0293b3a104690022111a</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi Islanders eager to have their say as remote voting for the federal election begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-22/early-voting-starts-in-remote-communities-tiwi-islands-aec/105201318</link><description>Voters in the small remote community of Pirlangimpi on the Tiwi Islands, north of Darwin, have become some of the first to cast their votes for the federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0c419fe3ae44debe7edf27241c0e5c1</guid></item><item><title>Mobile coverage is an election issue in regional areas. What's been promised?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-23/telecommunications-mobile-coverage-federal-election-promises/105080674</link><description>For many regional and remote Australians, reliable mobile coverage can be life-saving. They are desperate for both sides of politics to take meaningful action towards eliminating black spots.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ceda72e552d98e5f293d3c037efeefa</guid></item><item><title>Health, climate and community sport: What older voters in the Tasmanian seat of Bass are talking about this election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-29/health-climate-sport-election-older-voters-bass-tasmania/105224138</link><description>The federal seat of Bass is held by a margin of just 1.4 per cent. For these older voters who live in the electorate, health, climate and community sport are the issues that will decide their vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3579db910b5a7ee8e11d2618bf798f</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Vixens farewell long-time coach with Super Netball grand final victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-02/2025-super-netball-grand-final-live-blog-vixens-fever/105605562</link><description>After a lacklustre start to the 2025 season, the Melbourne Vixens upset minor premiers West Coast Fever in the Super Netball grand final, 59-58.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b07c48ab0858c012a87637576c3f186b</guid></item><item><title>Tributes flow for David Stratton, 'Gandalf' of Australian cinema</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-15/tributes-flow-for-gandalf-of-australian-cinema-david-stratton/105659128</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6af79b9ae5472f314e7e5eea9b50993</guid></item><item><title>As Iran-Australia relations plunge to a new low, Tehran faces another diplomatic setback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-29/europe-countries-to-reimpose-sanctions-on-iran/105710530</link><description>Tehran's nuclear ambitions are no secret, and that could lead it to another round of crippling sanctions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7c1faeaf77fb287c2cd597894822c64</guid></item><item><title>Nauru's unorthodox money-making schemes are a 'riches to rags to riches' story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-02/nauru-economy-wealth-sources-of-revenue/105720686</link><description>Experts say Nauru's new deal with Australia to take non-citizens is the latest episode in an unconventional economic story — one featuring phenomenal growth, a mining bust, and a failed musical about a Renaissance genius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">125ec37f2f067f41ec08a1d988d2e1a3</guid></item><item><title>The age assurance technologies under-16s could face amid social media bans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-04/how-age-verification-tools-work-australia-social-media-ban/105720526</link><description>Handing over identification documents or biometric screening — these are the barriers teens could face under the social media ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d0a5e9213c6955b3dd7747ef043b3a8</guid></item><item><title>Jai Hindley targeting podium in 'crucial' Vuelta a España final week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-09/jai-hindley-targeting-podium-in-vuelta-a-espana-final-week/105751220</link><description>Jai Hindley is in prime position to land his third career grand tour podium ahead of a crucial final week at the Vuelta a España.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">982f54c99cf509d403f056d09e4d7a61</guid></item><item><title>Sushila Karki sworn in as Nepal's new prime minister after gen Z protests prompt political change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/sushila-karki-nepals-new-prime-minister-after-gen-z-protests/105769388</link><description>Sushila Karki garnered widespread support from many young Nepalese people who took to the streets in anger over government corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b14068c37ad26302453e199b0b0960b7</guid></item><item><title>Evidence points to remains found in Vietnam cave being South-East Asia's earliest known homicide victim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/vietnam-remains-earliest-known-homicide-victim-cold-case/105741956</link><description>It was on a sweltering morning in 2018 in a cave in northern Vietnam when Chris Stimpson and his team uncovered what may be the oldest cold case murder in South-East Asia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34f92776d6167c167af22a4b170f6648</guid></item><item><title>Who is Tyler Robinson, the accused killer of Charlie Kirk?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/tyler-robinson-charlie-kirks-alleged-killer/105769710</link><description>After his father encouraged Tyler Robinson to turn himself in, people close to the 22-year-old provided investigators with crucial insights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeb2177456349534e747aeb65ed554d9</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fall to 28-26 defeat against Argentina in The Rugby Championship in Sydney</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/live-updates-wallabies-vs-argentina-the-rugby-championship/105753320</link><description>The Wallabies have fallen just short of a magical comeback against Argentina, losing 28-26 in a thrilling Rugby Championship Test in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5469c7b464e3dc361d956d14cd5a474c</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fall to 28-26 defeat against Argentina in The Rugby Championship in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/live-updates-wallabies-vs-argentina-the-rugby-championship/105753320</link><description>The Wallabies have fallen just short of a magical comeback against Argentina, losing 28-26 in a thrilling Rugby Championship Test in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac9963693b81c061d5a7137f7874121c</guid></item><item><title>Erika Kirk makes first public statement after assassination of husband Charlie Kirk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/erika-kirk-pays-tribute-to-late-husband-charlie-kirk/105770008</link><description>Charlie Kirk's widow, Erika, delivers her first public remarks since the fatal shooting of her influencer husband.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a3e797f573f130d4cdaa37fc918652a</guid></item><item><title>The Pacific won a stunning climate victory at the International Court of Justice. What's next?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/whats-next-after-pacific-icj-climate-victory/105747794</link><description>Pacific Island nations are weighing up how to use a historic international court ruling in their fight to bring about stronger emissions reductions and climate justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4d5352fd2872714b73915e90a078b57</guid></item><item><title>FBI director Kash Patel to face congressional hearing amid missteps on Charlie Kirk assassination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/kash-patel-faces-congressional-hearing/105771606</link><description>Kash Patel faces a clear test of whether he can convince the country that the FBI, under his watch, can avoid compounding its mistakes in a time of political violence and deepening distrust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff3edf3e8615beb76880722256515f03</guid></item><item><title>Family violence survivors waiting years for social housing as demand surges in Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/social-public-housing-wait-times-victoria-family-violence/105655044</link><description>As family violence survivor and mother-of-two, Maya was assessed as a high priority for social housing. Eight years later, she's finally moved into a suitable home in outer-suburban Melbourne, with vulnerable Victorians left waiting for years as the social housing waitlist soars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e74302190404e5284428c6e45ccbce8a</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr scores 100th goal for Chelsea in long-awaited WSL return from knee injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sam-kerr-makes-wsl-chelsea-return-from-torn-acl/105772878</link><description>Matildas star Sam Kerr scores her 100th goal for Chelsea just minutes after returning to the pitch for the Blues for her first game since 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bae5f25a567be7986ec4489f569f5f25</guid></item><item><title>Nepalese migrants in Australia turning to parents to help with childcare and culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/canberra-nepalese-community-family-tradition-and-culture/105772020</link><description>For many Nepalese families living in Canberra, the arrival of parents from overseas is both a helping hand with raising children and a connection to their homeland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83d7bb8c245d2e5d11433eda0c9b3fd1</guid></item><item><title>Nepal's Gen Z demands reform as country begins new political path</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/nepal-generation-z-anti-corruption-protests-kathmandu/105773042</link><description>Protesters in Nepal say their Gen Z-led movement was not just about removing one leader, but about reforming the system to ensure accountability and protect Nepal’s future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">836ee3f4801e6cf8e546d51627e6e4b8</guid></item><item><title>2025 Emmys key moments: From Hacks star Hannah Einbinder's acceptance speech to chants for Stephen Colbert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/emmys-2025-key-moments-from-hannah-einbinder-to-stephen-colbert/105773412</link><description>From a rallying political cry from Hacks star Hannah Einbinder to standing ovations for Stephen Colbert, here are your Emmys 2025 key moments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5949a0290fa0abaf999a6b633f1291cd</guid></item><item><title>How much fish is in tinned tuna, and how to shop for your needs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/packaged-foods-content-supermarkets/105707244</link><description>When you're at the supermarket, do you wonder how much much tuna you're getting in a can? A series of popular social media has been comparing how much food there is in some packaged items.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c07e1af76a9ce085f39b2e2924bc18d</guid></item><item><title>How is Australia affected by climate change? The National Climate Risk Assessment models the future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/national-climate-risk-assessment-and-why-it-matters-explained/105773936</link><description>For the first time, the government has modelled the threats from climate change on Australia's future. What's the point of a document like this, and can it help us avoid the worst-case scenarios?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ad84229da5de3e8a79b28e4eacc8cab</guid></item><item><title>Shadow minister Andrew Hastie says he will be 'without a job' if Liberals don't abandon net zero</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/andrew-hastie-flags-resignation-or-sacking-over-liberal-net-zero/105776432</link><description>Liberal frontbencher Andrew Hastie indicates he will quit or be dumped from the shadow cabinet if the Coalition does not abandon the target of achieving net zero greenhouse gas emissions by 2050.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d65a81fca15feb36d2a53c3d3bdd85a3</guid></item><item><title>All the latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/all-the-latest-financial-news/105776480</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f073c7f7020949078deb2eb0c7a85c</guid></item><item><title>Final rules for social media ban revealed, with no legally enforceable effectiveness standard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/social-media-ban-final-rules-announced/105776730</link><description>While substantial fines would apply to social media platforms that make no effort to ban under-16s, they would not need to test the age of every user.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bf25735e4356b3846b028a3101595a6</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste students protest government plan to buy new cars for parliamentarians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/timor-leste-protesters-demand-repeal-of-plan-to-buy-cars-for-mps/105776898</link><description>About 1,000 students hit the streets of the capital to rally against the plan, before police clashed with some protesters who reportedly threw rocks and damaged properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ce414e161409b0fcdd72ce826062fbc</guid></item><item><title>US and China agree to TikTok 'framework' ownership agreement at trade talks in Spain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/us-and-china-agree-to-framework-for-tiktok-sale/105776964</link><description>US Treasury Secretary Scott Bessent says the framework would see the platform switch to US ownership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5792446bfea9843c09b316ffd472ee8e</guid></item><item><title>Australia-PNG defence treaty will require countries to 'act' if either one is attacked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/australia-and-png-defence-treaty-could-oblige-military-action/105776214</link><description>Australia and Papua New Guinea will be legally obliged to defend each other from a military attack on either territory under a landmark defence treaty, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a01cbea51a11c9d04e1bcff45aa8aa5</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers urge Australians to ensure valid will in place as house prices rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/lawyers-urge-australians-to-ensure-valid-will-in-place/105767604</link><description>Lawyers urge Australians to ensure they leave behind a valid will to avoid legal disputes as surging house prices and superannuation balances increase the size of inheritances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a89e25f073724834a4daf823bb8d4cd</guid></item><item><title>Climate Risk Assessment's 'high risk' warning for 1 million Australian homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/climate-risk-assessment-million-homes-insurance-gdp-costs/105774418</link><description>One in 10 homes could be effectively uninsurable by 2050, while lost labour productivity to extreme weather could wipe $211 billion in household wealth, the Climate Risk Assessment warns, with tourism, trade, and property values forecasted to take a dive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">801dfb5f2bac8394e795c9893975dce2</guid></item><item><title>ANZ commits bank errors in its favour. Is there any other kind?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/anz-slammed-for-bank-errors-in-its-favour/105775702</link><description>ASIC has lived by that aphorism in its decision to strike a settlement deal with ANZ over a raft of wrongdoing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eab85143099e30eb989aba207539b011</guid></item><item><title>WWII-era bombs are killing and injuring thousands in PNG. Now trainees will learn how to remove them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/png-world-war-2-unexploded-ordnance-removal/105774308</link><description>Trainees in Papua New Guinea will learn to remove unexploded ordnance, as fading memories of World War II expose more people to the conflict's dangerous legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8bf240cd5378047327fc404a9e7f897</guid></item><item><title>Western Sydney is set to dramatically heat up, this is how communities are preparing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/western-sydney-plans-to-address-climate-change-warming/105775030</link><description>A "shocking" warning that heatwave deaths could skyrocket brings the issue of urban heat back into sharp focus, particularly in the city's west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8587e0ed7880e781adeb84da2b9f99da</guid></item><item><title>Jacinta Nampijinpa Price and Kerrynne Liddle a 'unity ticket' on Indigenous affairs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/kerrynne-liddle-backs-jacinta-nampijinpa-price/105776102</link><description>Kerrynne Liddle speaks for the first time since Jacinta Nampijinpa Price was dumped from the frontbench, saying the pair are "on a unity ticket" when it comes to Indigenous affairs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">baf6de4a9c0796b996abab3ba46e1810</guid></item><item><title>How to determine if your kid is well enough for child care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/the-advice-around-sending-a-sick-kid-to-child-care/105734762</link><description>Work demands and a lack of village mean keeping a child at home from care every time they have a sniffle can be a dilemma for many parents. So when it it OK to send them?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3431c0d66326982196374e9a6c348b5f</guid></item><item><title>Does washing your fruit and veggies remove chemicals?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/best-way-to-wash-fresh-produce-fruits-veggies-remove-chemcials-/105773664</link><description>This is what experts have to say about washing fruit and veggies, with removing chemicals and reducing the amount we consume in mind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57b4d4864180c3c11eed8be0eca03f20</guid></item><item><title>Concurrent disasters will overwhelm responders, stress ADF, risk report warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/defence-forces-disaster-response-climate-risk-assessment/105778304</link><description>A dedicated disaster recovery force is needed, or else responders and defence forces could be "overwhelmed" by multiple concurrent natural disasters, the National Climate Risk Assessment warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79a82e7988ce64cb47e2aea9d939b300</guid></item><item><title>Israel is committing genocide in Gaza, major United Nations report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/israel-committing-genocide-in-gaza-un-report-says/105780230</link><description>Israel has committed and is continuing to commit genocide in Gaza, according to the "most authoritative assessment" to date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e547fcd275b42fb12bbaa7d9028fd7aa</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105781402</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e2b5a3b30f5fdf1b8c8739f00047ca8</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump takes aim at ABC journalist as he suggests he'll meet Albanese 'very soon'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/donald-trump-john-lyons-exchange-before-anthony-albanese-meeting/105781624</link><description>Donald Trump takes aim at the ABC's Americas editor during an extraordinary exchange at the White House, as the president suggests he will meet Prime Minister Anthony Albanese "very soon".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">156db315a11501aa8fbeaf35550e4091</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste protesters vow to continue rallying until plan to buy MPs 65 cars is overturned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/timor-leste-protests-over-mp-car-plan-grow/105781726</link><description>The protests nearly doubled in size on Tuesday as people continued to vent their frustrations at a plan to buy MPs 65 new SUVs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">feeb6a6ab4a2322ebf2709358b8c2353</guid></item><item><title>Australians too dependent on government, says Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/australians-too-dependent-on-government-says-sussan-ley/105781276</link><description>In her first major economic speech, the opposition leader hits out at universal subsidies and says "dependency" has affected Australia's "national character".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">651c319b8e005af88f9f36c064e26d9e</guid></item><item><title>Threat of stagflation bears down on world's largest economy as Federal Reserve decision looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/threat-of-stagflation-bears-down-on-world-s-largest-economy/105781264</link><description>The world's largest central bank is less than 24 hours from announcing one of the most anticipated interest rate decisions of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">317d2acf44c6b55d5cef638469f7338f</guid></item><item><title>The Federal Home Guarantee Scheme is expanding, but just how many will be able to afford to buy in?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/home-loan-guarantee-scheme-cost-first-home-buyers/105772918</link><description>The expansion of the scheme, which allows first home buyers to purchase a property with as little as a 5 per cent deposit, has some warning it will also inflate the market. Here's what you'll need to be earning to get a foot in the door.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4fd4e5c6040f2d8b9de5c0800458317</guid></item><item><title>SA's ongoing harmful algal bloom labelled 'cultural emergency' by First Nations groups</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sa-algal-bloom-cultural-emergency/105631230</link><description>First Nations South Australians say the harmful algal bloom impacting the state's coastline is a cultural emergency, as it continues to devastate beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ed15cf74630a813b331beecfe638cdf</guid></item><item><title>Cashrewards's abrupt closure leaves shoppers many unanswered questions. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/cashrewards-abrupt-shutdown-stuns-many-australians/105765936</link><description>Two and a half million Australians have signed up for this cashback app, which leaves them wondering what's next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74d5aaf89ebaad05dd5c26265b442d23</guid></item><item><title>New doco Signorinella: Little Miss celebrates the Italian women who shaped modern Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/signorinella-little-miss-documentary-italian-film-festival/105774428</link><description>Signorinella: Little Miss, the new documentary from the filmmakers behind Lygon St — Si Parla Italiano, celebrates the tenacity of Italian Australian women in business and beyond.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc3ea23b27aab754a73fa0319a25aee</guid></item><item><title>Australia and PNG fail to clinch defence agreement, resorting to communique</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/australia-png-fail-defence-agreement-communique/105782424</link><description>A major defence treaty between Australia and Papua New Guinea has failed to get over the line today, with the countries resorting to signing a communique in lieu of the actual document.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d5916f8d88a6bb049ef9ef389165d8e</guid></item><item><title>Why 'everything feels easier' for Chloe Rykers since her breast reduction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/breast-reduction-changed-my-quality-of-life-chloe-rykers/105763294</link><description>Chloe Rykers says her "big boobs" had, in various ways, made her career harder and left her feeling uncomfortable and in pain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfb6d7d9d5d29c944f231ddddf5980dc</guid></item><item><title>Does the damning planning report mean the end for Hobart's Macquarie Point stadium?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/is-hobart-stadium-now-dead-explainer/105780834</link><description>The Tasmanian Planning Commission described the Hobart stadium as a "singular, large, bulky monolith" with "optimism bias" in the government's cost-benefit figures. What does this mean for the stadium?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6d2b782c8ad36854242ff8269a71dd8</guid></item><item><title>UTS to axe 1,100 subjects across education and public health, cuts 134 full-time jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/uts-cuts-subjects-job-cuts-restructure/105783978</link><description>The University of Technology Sydney will close its schools of education and public health under a multi-million-dollar restructure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">745b450ac59dd82dd2a07962aa9b5e5c</guid></item><item><title>Albanese has found out nailing down Pacific agreements is harder than expected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/papua-new-guinea-defence-treaty-delays/105783902</link><description>Anthony Albanese was meant to emerge from his recent flurry of Pacific diplomacy holding no fewer than two major agreements — instead he's returning home conspicuously empty-handed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef894cba91b42943ab469518f13e2d11</guid></item><item><title>Australia refusing to panic over Pat Cummins's injury ahead of Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/ashes-cricket-australia-england-pat-cummins-injury/105785808</link><description>Australia coach Andrew McDonald is confident injured captain Pat Cummins will be fit to play a major role in the men's Ashes, even if he does not feature in all five matches of the series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3764f86fe491f37a58f6d749d3f0b446</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105786068</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4fdf32035483c97cc8e3b3c2ceb960b</guid></item><item><title>Alexei Navalny's wife says new tests show former Russian opposition leader was poisoned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/alexei-nalvalny-poisoned-says-wife-yulia-navalnaya/105786116</link><description>Yulia Navalnaya says that laboratory analysis of smuggled biological samples had found he was killed by poisoning while incarcerated in prison in February 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fe9f91d93abaeaa861fc8cb19ecd191</guid></item><item><title>Ben &amp; Jerry's co-founder Jerry Greenfield quits over Gaza dispute with parent company Unilever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/ben-jerrys-co-founder-resigns/105785958</link><description>Ben &amp; Jerry's co-founder Jerry Greenfield resigns after a feud with parent company Unilever over the war in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e788c44c33e590bcd5f58e11d005c9b9</guid></item><item><title>King Charles hails 'vital' AUKUS relationship during state banquet for Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/donald-trump-second-state-visit-uk-met-with-protests/105786186</link><description>King Charles praises the AUKUS defence pact between the US, UK and Australia during a state banquet for Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">576545f23dd21127388a3bd3042f9430</guid></item><item><title>European Commission lays out new tariffs and sanctions on Israel over war in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/eu-lays-out-new-tariffs-and-sanctions-on-israel/105786322</link><description>The European Union's executive arm has made a series of proposals aimed at forcing an end to the Israel–Hamas conflict.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcf8968b74aefc70146386449173685e</guid></item><item><title>Australia's 2035 climate target will strike a middle path. Will it be enough?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/2035-climate-emissions-target-middle-path/105782220</link><description>Australia's next major climate commitment will be more ambitious than New Zealand's and Canada's, but less than the United Kingdom's, as the government strikes a middle path in pursuit of an "achievable" 2035 target.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09490579740954d02af7a3ac935593e5</guid></item><item><title>NT regulator takes new side job with miner amid calls to quit over gas leak 'scandal'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nt-regulator-takes-new-side-job-with-miner-amid-calls-he-quit/105783120</link><description>The chair of the Northern Territory's Environment Protection Authority has become a "strategic adviser" to a miner but denies he has a conflict of interest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80fb3748f8891eb305aaaffb96c7fc55</guid></item><item><title>Fears human rights activist Aung San Suu Kyi could 'die' in a 'hellhole' prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/aung-san-suu-kyi-needs-urgent-medical-care-son-says/105779816</link><description>One of the world's most recognised pro-democracy activists needs urgent medical care as she serves a 27-year sentence in a "hellhole" prison, her son has claimed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c3c46168a5e4d40865d7addf1355e38</guid></item><item><title>Coal miner Anglo American confirms job cuts in Brisbane, Bowen Basin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/anglo-american-confirms-more-qld-coal-job-losses/105784432</link><description>Mining giant Anglo American confirms job cuts in Brisbane and the Bowen Basin in the wake of BHP Mitsubishi Alliance axing 750 workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2c2ffd3fcd4ff63bb350e73f18ebbc1</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout shows class to reach 200m semifinal at World Athletics Championships</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/gout-gout-indication-of-his-class-in-200m-heats-world/105786404</link><description>Gout Gout could have been rattled competing against some of the world's best in the 200m at the World Athletics Championships, but powered through with an assured display beyond his years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70b755a573bebadc192be4e09363af06</guid></item><item><title>Gaming history goes on display with Australian titles Hollow Knight Silksong and Team Fortress chronicled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/acmi-game-worlds-hollow-knight-silksong-neopets-team-fortress/105754152</link><description>An exhibition at Melbourne's ACMI will pull back the curtain on how iconic games like Hollow Knight Silksong, Team Fortress, Neopets and Sim City were made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fccda39e18804bf9590546dadaed39f</guid></item><item><title>Abu Dhabi consortium drops bid to take over Santos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/abu-dhabi-consortium-drops-bid-to-take-over-santos/105786656</link><description>The investment arm of Abu Dhabi's state-owned oil company has dropped its $30 billion takeover bid for Santos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7942c024f80918f5b4df2c29ac2fa3e1</guid></item><item><title>ASX slips amid Santos sell-off, weak jobs data and 2035 emissions target — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/asx-markets-business-live-news-sep18-2025/105786834</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate remains steady at 4.2 per cent in August with a decline in full-time employment that drove the overall drop in employment numbers, according to ABS.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c9b52757d4c8bed330dd9676c5f85da</guid></item><item><title>How youth orchestras foster lifelong friendships and open career pathways for musicians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/youth-orchestra-lifelong-friendships-career-pathways-musicians/105775992</link><description>With youth orchestras set to busk on the streets of Sydney and Melbourne this weekend, Australian musicians share how those orchestras helped shape their careers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39cc489e47ad597a9a2e2610c3bf0e4a</guid></item><item><title>Kmart broke privacy laws by using facial recognition technology, commissioner finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/kmart-facial-recognition-technology-privacy-commissioner/105785802</link><description>The privacy commissioner has found Kmart broke the Privacy Act with its use of facial recognition technology, ordering the retail giant not to repeat the practice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">951624fe912cfaedd0c6e7cac0bca47d</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's royal banquet dinner in pictures during historic state visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/donald-trump-state-banquet-dinner-in-pictures/105786672</link><description>Surrounded by high-level politicians, a media mogul, tech giants and athletes, the grandeur-loving US president was treated to a glowing spectacle at Windsor Castle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bc4938e2b936e932176490989e7d215</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel Live pulled from air by US broadcaster ABC over 'insensitive' Charlie Kirk comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/jimmy-kimmel-live-cancelled-indefinitely/105787192</link><description>The late-night talk show's host suggested during a monologue earlier this week that Charlie Kirk's alleged killer may have been a pro-Trump Republican.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42b62491994f952ca23ef1806fafc33b</guid></item><item><title>How the Collingwood Magpies are righting the ship this AFLW season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/aflw-collingwood-magpies-round-six-hawthorn/105785982</link><description>A year after finishing dead last in the AFLW, the Magpies have started making moves up the ladder thanks to a new approach at both ends of the field.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09dcd2a4338fbef6fc6396c784fa2fe5</guid></item><item><title>Charges against veteran broadcaster Alan Jones 'downgraded', some withdrawn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nsw-sydney-alan-jones-charges-downgraded-dropped/105787356</link><description>Eleven counts of aggravated indecent assault against the veteran broadcaster have been dropped in what the magistrate described as a "reformation" of the case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c138a3782bc62a82275efd716973097</guid></item><item><title>Australian cow market at record high as US demand hits 'scary times'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/us-cattle-prices-soar-increasing-demand-for-aussie-beef/105776020</link><description>Australian cow prices are at record highs, but are still way below the United States where beef demand is going "crazy".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56f2d0555cc98f7f69e717a8162ea988</guid></item><item><title>Unemployment rate steady despite jobs losses in August</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/unemployment-steady-august-2025-abs-labour-force-data/105788046</link><description>Australia's unemployment rate remains steady at 4.2 per cent in August, despite more than 5,000 jobs being lost last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c87774100b3dc545eb48b806aa5e9216</guid></item><item><title>Airline receives mixed reaction to pets on planes pilot program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/major-australian-airline-set-to-trial-pets-on-planes/105783886</link><description>Virgin Australia has finally announced the start date of a trial of pets on flights, beginning next month between Melbourne and the Gold and Sunshine coasts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">602c0c6b2973931cfecd6e3d3b448806</guid></item><item><title>Australia vows to cut emissions 62 to 70 per cent by 2035</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/australia-vows-to-cut-emissions-62-to-70-per-cent-by-2035/105786880</link><description>Australia will vow to cut its emissions by 62 to 70 per cent by 2035, lifting its sights further as the world strives to reach net zero emissions by 2050.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2e21efb7e74be7accc0d01defc0839f</guid></item><item><title>Brittany Higgins files last-day appeal over ex-senator Linda Reynolds's defamation win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/brittany-higgins-appeal-over-linda-reynolds-defamation-ruling/105787774</link><description>Brittany Higgins lodges an appeal against a WA Supreme Court judgement that she defamed her former boss and ex-Liberal senator Linda Reynolds in social media posts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48e1405575ae54fb34788f0c57fd4e45</guid></item><item><title>The AFL is in danger of becoming a 'two-tier competition' as multiple club captains search for the exit door</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/afl-player-movement-merrett-curnow-simpkin-paul-roos-analysis/105784732</link><description>Three captains from the AFL's four worst-performing clubs are searching for the exit door. It is the symptom of a player movement era that has left the gap between the AFL's strongest and weakest larger than ever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fe6fc38b706e2d5bb69fdebfcdad181</guid></item><item><title>What are the best ways to clean windows and fly screens?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/what-are-the-best-ways-to-clean-windows-and-fly-screens/105757576</link><description>Windows and fly screens are often the first things we see when we walk into a home, but rarely at the top of the spring-cleaning to-do list. Experts share their tips on the easiest and most effective ways to clean them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7541abd5471ba63f11dace84578558cf</guid></item><item><title>Australia's 2035 climate targets on path to net zero judged by the experts</title><link>http://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/climate-targets-australia-2035-on-path-to-net-zero/105719910</link><description>After much anticipation, Australia has its new climate targets. Now that the dice have fallen, we consult experts on their assessment of how these targets stack up with what’s at stake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b90d42c5d85aad6e6c0f33bc868f19ac</guid></item><item><title>Australia's 2035 climate targets on path to net zero judged by the experts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/climate-targets-australia-2035-on-path-to-net-zero/105719910</link><description>After much anticipation, Australia has its new climate targets. Now that the dice have fallen, we consult experts on their assessment of how these targets stack up with what’s at stake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dabb8156d4044b51ff0dc8bd8feb97a4</guid></item><item><title>Amid Trump's biggest, best state visit ever, the king delivers a pointed message</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/trump-state-visit-king-charles-message/105788584</link><description>Amid the diamonds, whisky sours and flattery of a royal banquet for Donald Trump's state visit, tiara diplomacy was on full display.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55c7f64974504498042a988379cc1542</guid></item><item><title>Cats coach Chris Scott regrets run-in with AFL staffer after qualifying final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/geelong-cats-chris-scott-afl-staff-qualifying-final/105789664</link><description>Geelong coach Chris Scott says long-held frustration with the AFL was behind his regrettable post-qualifying final win outburst at a junior league employee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64f8afe41599735121373a93d14d1aff</guid></item><item><title>Hobart stadium proponent dismisses planning commission key issues as 'matters of opinion'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/tasmania-hobart-macquarie-point-stadium-tpc-report-opinions/105787276</link><description>The agency behind Hobart's Macquarie Point stadium build says it is undeterred by the three key issues raised by the recent planning commission's final report, arguing it comes down to "priorities".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95214532bc602d9fbcd7742ff8b727a4</guid></item><item><title>Qantas to review staff bases in Mildura, Canberra and Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/qantas-to-review-staff-bases-in-mildura-canberra-and-hobart/105787036</link><description>There are concerns the decision could impact regional flights, as staff would have to travel from Sydney, Melbourne or Brisbane to get to work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b12683d82bbcee89c77a3511592fb58</guid></item><item><title>'Just a joy': Margot Robbie and Colin Farrell on their movie A Big Bold Beautiful Journey</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/-just-a-joy-margot-robbie-and-colin-farrell-on-their-movie-a-big/105788870</link><description>Margot Robbie and Colin Farrell tell News Breakfast that 'the best part' of working on their new movie A Big Bold Beautiful Journey was each other.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17f06a763068abdf061f97892bdb3970</guid></item><item><title>Disability employment provider Bedford's financial situation concerns SA, federal government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/disability-employment-provider-bedford-financial-concerns/105787712</link><description>The federal disability minister says his concerns about Australia's second-largest disability employment provider, Bedford, have grown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26088ccc4b0d7adc561a4f0cb51bf652</guid></item><item><title>Family of Aboriginal man killed in Darwin hit-and-run speak out over driver's sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/family-of-man-killed-in-darwin-hit-and-run-speak-out/105787700</link><description>The family of an Aboriginal man killed in a hit-and-run in Darwin have spoken out about the sentence handed to the man who killed him, and the "racist, dehumanising" messages he sent afterwards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc87964fabc0227fe5c48880a62ad60b</guid></item><item><title>Domestic violence comments on fishing show breached classification rules: ACMA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/domestic-violence-comments-on-channel-seven-in-breach-says-acma/105789254</link><description>An exchange about domestic violence between 'Bush Cook Ranger Nick' and the host of Step Outside with Paul Burt, broadcast on 7mate, was in breach of classification rules, the watchdog has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0793754492a6a1f2c4bb7b9112a6cb41</guid></item><item><title>Albanese to meet with Trump after returning from Pacific empty-handed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/anthony-albanese-png-coalition-climate/105767026</link><description>This week in politics, the prime minister returned home from the Pacific empty-handed and the climate debate continued to unsettle the Coalition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e48586b5fbd1829a80e680eae1c55719</guid></item><item><title>Queenslander Sean Bell appointed as a senator representing NSW after parliament vote</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/one-nation-queenslander-sean-bell-nsw-senator/105790262</link><description>An attempt to stop a Queenslander being parachuted into a NSW seat in the Senate vacated by a One Nation senator has failed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbd2bc360684dd44f7b418ea7fb284f1</guid></item><item><title>National Gathering backs plans for new First Nations body, but tensions remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/national-indigenous-gathering-post-voice-referendum/105787906</link><description>First Nations leaders have endorsed plans for a new national representative body to be established. Here’s what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31e9e3c6ecd0c09297f677025d57e6b6</guid></item><item><title>Albury Wodonga Regional Cancer Centre to become public hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/albury-wodonga-cancer-centre-hospital-ramsay-health-public/105786700</link><description>A major cancer centre on the Victorian-New South Wales border will become a fully public hospital in a move that has caught a healthcare provider by surprise and sparked community concern.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6af03fa22837640d34b69f4c529cc60f</guid></item><item><title>WA coal phase-out uncertainty amid Bluewaters power station closure backflip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/wa-coal-phaseout-uncertain-amid-energy-grid-upgrade-plan/105788864</link><description>Efforts by WA's government to force the premature closure of a privately owned coal plant appear to be unravelling after the market operator backed the power station to keep running towards the end of the decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4f55f2cbe6604ced891de18ea6af73a</guid></item><item><title>Educator resigns from Melbourne school over inappropriate descriptions of students</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/st-michaels-grammar-school-staff-member-resigns/105790000</link><description>St Michael's Grammar School in St Kilda says the staff member responsible for an annotated cast list for the Year 6 musical has resigned from their position.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">911816f0c2a8a2522cd3af2f6d6f0802</guid></item><item><title>Henley residents advised to keep windows, doors closed amid algal bloom crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/sa-beach-residents-algal-bloom-advice/105790474</link><description>Authorities have told a group of residents living near a metropolitan Adelaide beach to close their doors and windows to prevent symptoms related to South Australia's ongoing algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">094835ce530689c0fec54c85ace98853</guid></item><item><title>The Albanese government has learned from the last major climate commitment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/2035-target-energy-debate-power-prices/105787072</link><description>The government is keenly aware that the cost of the transition is a sensitive issue, which is why the prime minister was flanked not just by his climate minister but also his treasurer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb04f44e27c2583896465cd35dce2ecb</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel is the latest to be put on pause. How Trump is influencing the world of late-night TV</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/jimmy-kimmel-stephen-colbert-late-night-in-trump-america/105788394</link><description>Emmys watchers could assume there's never been a better time in Hollywood to hold its most powerful to account, but Jimmy Kimmel's axing proves otherwise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aebb28d38d1022146481b424b8a62c82</guid></item><item><title>Roosters hand Victor Radley 10-match ban for bringing NRL club into disrepute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nrl-sydney-roosters-victor-radley-10-match-ban/105790722</link><description>The Sydney Roosters suspend Victor Radley for 10 matches without pay following media revelations he allegedly requested an illegal substance from former teammate Brandon Smith.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0476c9486f857e18734c6e0056795098</guid></item><item><title>Ry Jacob Nairn charged with murder after body found in Northampton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/man-charged-with-murder-after-body-found-northampton/105790222</link><description>Ry Jacob Nairn has faced Geraldton Magistrates Court over the death of a 69-year-old man in Northampton earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d19fe3c819e5c9d92d18ba663c9e26f8</guid></item><item><title>Former Roebuck Bay Hotel manager found guilty of raping staff member</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/roebuck-bay-hotel-stewart-burchell-guilty-rape/105788218</link><description>A District Court jury has found Stewart Patrick Burchell raped a former staff member and indecently assaulted several others during his time managing the Roebuck Bay Hotel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4bf9d8271f4c0aafb3b2aaefa1e5200</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with threatening to kill pro-Palestinian rally organiser Remah Naji</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/qld-man-charged-threatening-to-kill-pro-palestinian-organiser/105790946</link><description>Queensland counter-terrorism detectives charge a man with making verbal threats via a carriage service to Remah Naji, a spokesperson for a Brisbane-based pro-Palestinian action group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79fb27d7a9037f6916ba69472b653da7</guid></item><item><title>Police lay murder charge after Indigenous woman's alleged domestic violence death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/man-charged-with-murder-after-alleged-dv-death-palmerston-nt/105790976</link><description>Northern Territory police have charged a 32-year-old man with the murder of his 31-year-old partner, who died hours after she was found unresponsive in the front yard of a Palmerston home earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ef129cc6970d350f41596426a01f694</guid></item><item><title>ANU chancellor Julie Bishop 'categorically' denies allegations of bullying in formal response to Senate inquiry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/anu-julie-bishop-categorically-denies-allegations-of-bullying/105791110</link><description>ANU chancellor Julie Bishop provides a formal written response "categorically" denying allegations of bullying, harassment and hostile behaviour, levelled against her during a Senate committee hearing last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28ca0a65693ae07e89d0cf01b3a69f21</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout, Torrie Lewis miss finals in brilliant 200m semifinal displays at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/live-updates-gout-gout-200m-world-athletics-championships-2025/105789710</link><description>Gout Gout and Torrie Lewis have missed the final of the 200m, both running to a hugely respectable fourth place in their semifinals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d91eed956c7bb07dd7aa6825e1414ea3</guid></item><item><title>NT sports star and school staffer committed to stand trial on student sex charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nt-sports-star-school-staffer-supreme-court-student-sex-charges/105785686</link><description>A Northern Territory sports star and school staffer will face the Supreme Court on charges of having sex with a student at the school where he worked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5f49a3ef6f1d44a25f8a5ff1e12d5ea</guid></item><item><title>Man jailed for punching boy, 8, threatening to use baby as human shield at WA school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/west-australian-man-jailed-for-punching-child-at-school/105790898</link><description>Details of the 49-year-old's violent outburst at a WA school were revealed during his sentencing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0395a22d78d1606ffa08ed488c473629</guid></item><item><title>Police officer found not guilty of assault during shopping centre scuffle at Batemans Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/police-officer-not-guilty-assault-batemans-bay-shopping-centre/105775816</link><description>A New South Wales police officer is found not guilty of using unreasonable force while removing three girls and a woman from a scuffle at a shopping centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c14d987edba1b9dfa103c7bd81c6de2</guid></item><item><title>All the latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/all-the-latest-financial-news/105791258</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01b895719353cf122016325431e84219</guid></item><item><title>Pope Leo talks Trump, sex abuse scandals, welcoming the LGBTQ+ community and China in his first interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/pope-leo-first-interview-discusses-trump-and/105791360</link><description>Pope Leo says he recognises the influence of the United States on world affairs but makes clear he is not a supporter of US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23b4b5afac2ea78ffe86d81dd9c478ea</guid></item><item><title>Two people killed in a shooting at West Bank-Jordan border crossing, ambulance service says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/reported-shooting-israel-jordan-border/105791580</link><description>In a statement, the IDF said a person "arrived in a truck transporting humanitarian aid from Jordan, and opened fire".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">703258d1b55da8993ac80b29b6bc1f8b</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Jimmy Kimmel off-air for 'bad ratings' as Democrats slam regulator for 'bullying' ABC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/trump-kimmel-bad-ratings-democrats-fcc-bullying/105791856</link><description>Prominent leaders in the Democratic Party are accusing the US's communications regulator of "bullying" a network to take the long-running late night show off air.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a35d01ad79ff21536357113faa2da610</guid></item><item><title>AI-generated minister addresses Albanian parliament for first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/ai-generated-minister-addresses-albanian-parliament/105791708</link><description>The world's first AI government minister was appointed last week by Albania's prime minister to oversee decisions on public tenders and to ease voter concerns about corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6ebff04dd13bb994197a62feb3160b9</guid></item><item><title>Clashes and disruption in France amid nationwide protests over Emmanuel Macron's austerity policies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/france-protests-austerity-macron/105791966</link><description>The CGT trade union claims more than a million people took part in demonstrations, while police say more than 90 people have been detained.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8e5b19f23415522807b4f1cf83b7b63</guid></item><item><title>What Donald Trump and Keir Starmer had to say after the US president's historic second UK state visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/what-did-donald-trumps-second-uk-state-visit-achieve/105791450</link><description>The US and UK leaders held a wide-ranging press conference after nearly two days of carefully crafted pomp and ceremony. Here's what they had to say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec99933b10d971a98ad93c4964a4e4dc</guid></item><item><title>UK prime minister urges Trump to pressure Putin amid escalating 'recklessness'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/trump-starmer-russia-ukraine-oil-drone-strikes/105792022</link><description>Keir Starmer says recent incidents, including the incursion of Russian drones into Poland, showed the Russian president were "not the actions of someone who wants peace".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7d6fb04c7bb765a5f84193a917ae9bc</guid></item><item><title>Independent advice spells out mammoth task ahead for government to reach 2035 target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/the-task-ahead-to-reach-2035-emissions-target/105789538</link><description>Getting to even the bottom end of the government's 62 to 70 per cent emissions reduction target by 2035 will require drastic increases to solar and wind power capacity, electric vehicle take-up and an extension of the safeguard mechanism, according to the Climate Change Authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">112c61869ecf0e96b28c94212500d843</guid></item><item><title>After deadly floods in Bali, its people want answers. Many are blaming overtourism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bali-overtourism-blamed-in-wake-of-deadly-floods/105785674</link><description>Unexpected and deadly flooding rocked Bali last week, at a scale many had never experienced before. In the wake of this disaster, the search has begun for answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">744d51865bef7cb34f9b946d580e8498</guid></item><item><title>The climate conversation is stuck in a loop, but out in the world things are changing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/climate-conversation-is-stuck-but-things-are-changing/105787796</link><description>We don't have to wait for moonshot technologies to reach our climate targets. Most of the solutions to the climate crisis are already around us.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36fccec4cd29f75e6be2134b94cacc07</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine could face waves of 2,000 drones as Russia ramps up mass production</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/russia-record-drone-missile-mass-strikes-ukraine-conflict/105753634</link><description>Ukraine is struggling to defend against growing drone attacks, and with Russia's mass production factories in full-swing there are fears thousands will soon be launched in a single night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e9f9a29907d82d98effe7c010edc04a</guid></item><item><title>First Guardian, Shield superannuation disasters expose deep flaws in Australia's $4.3 trillion retirement system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/first-guardian-shield-collapse-asic-and-superannuation-flaws/105783328</link><description>The failed First Guardian and Shield schemes have cost about 12,000 Australians more than $1 billion in retirement savings and exposed deep flaws in how Australia's $4.3 trillion superannuation sector is regulated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b80687a0c984dcbca73fbbe0b5a3dbb7</guid></item><item><title>Therapists, patients raise concerns over The Hobart Clinic closure with fears it could be 'dangerous' for some</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/hobart-clinic-therapists-patients-raise-concern-over-closure/105788162</link><description>For more than four decades, The Hobart Clinic has provided private mental health services to clients. Since the announcement of its October closure, clinic staff, therapists and patients have warned of the negative impact on those reliant on the service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fbc511d8b370e60dea926bbab98c0ab</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout's understanding of patience shows World Athletics Championships performance in 200m semifinal won't be one off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/when-does-gout-gout-run-200m-at-world-athletics-championships/105779054</link><description>Gout Gout's promise and progress are on full display at the 2025 World Athletics Championships. But by showing patience, he could get even better.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f32fc8f98bc12721121d3bf5f2046d2</guid></item></channel></rss>