<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Nov 2025 17:45:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dutch centrist Rob Jetten 'confident' as Geert Wilders' far-right party suffers setback in election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/dutch-election-results-d66-pvv/105955042</link><description>Geert Wilders' Freedom Party lost ground in elections which had been seen as a potential test of the far-right's staying power in European politics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5fc08e7649fc4cd7a689ec6fe14c478</guid></item><item><title>Dictionary.com's surprising choice for word of the year — 'six-seven'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/dictorary-dot-com-word-of-the-year-is-67/105955222</link><description>Unveiling its choice for word of the year, Dictionary.com explained that it was not quite sure what six-seven meant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a63bf5ae503873c2b1688ad6fba8bcda</guid></item><item><title>US politicians call for Trump to act on 'unspeakable atrocities' in Sudan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/sudan-violence-calls-for-trump-to-act/105955336</link><description>The UN and others are condemning paramilitary Rapid Support Forces, which reportedly attacked civilians as it moved to seize new territory in the North African country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4647407e6690012cff6270e64ddda409</guid></item><item><title>Questions from ratepayers group over $20m redevelopment to historic Albert Hall in Launceston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/questions-over-20m-reno-to-launceston-albert-hall/105953582</link><description>A ratepayers' group is calling for an audit of the $20 million redevelopment of Launceston's heritage-listed Albert Hall for what it says are design flaws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70abdd6a0c4d4b668b92e2fd6fe21469</guid></item><item><title>Leaked emails show NBN Co fast-tracked upgrade for Sky News host Andrew Bolt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/nbn-co-fast-tracked-upgrade-for-sky-news-host-news-corp-pundit/105953892</link><description>Senior managers at the National Broadband Network intervened to accelerate a home internet upgrade for News Corp pundit Andrew Bolt and resolve a technical problem for a top executive's friend during the final stages of the infrastructure project's rollout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92d6ce6e334e5bfc610ac7d88cdbd5ad</guid></item><item><title>Bulk-billing changes are coming into effect — what does it mean for you?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/bulk-billing-changes-medicare-gp-incentives/105953126</link><description>The government is pouring billions into Medicare so you have a better chance of being bulk-billed but the decision to charge or not charge still rests completely with your doctor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cccbaed84752a4d9473f3630eeec4a5</guid></item><item><title>Dangerous anti-renewables rhetoric, bullying and intimidation creates growing chasm in rural communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/anti-renewables-campaigns-fuel-community-division-in-regions/105938440</link><description>There are grave concerns that dangerous language and bullying of farmers who are hosting renewable energy projects on their properties could turn into violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94ae62deffe3f1f0a779fa3cb29f51ef</guid></item><item><title>No plans to change Tim Tam recipe after rival UK biscuit can no longer be called chocolate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/tim-tams-vs-penguins-cocoa-price-challenges/105931332</link><description>Food manufacturers are responding to high cocoa prices, and a change to the UK's Penguin biscuit may have all but cemented Australia's Tim Tam as the better of the two.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7790956298a772ceb7f53385e4f57c9f</guid></item><item><title>Girl, 5, dies after being hit by car outside school in north-west Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/nsw-girl-dies-after-being-hit-by-car-at-rouse-hill-school/105954142</link><description>A girl has died after being struck by a car outside a school in Sydney's north-west on Thursday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd38f07f6ae8a9396265c8ee6374faa6</guid></item><item><title>Family of Frank Coleman say death in custody findings show prison system failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/nsw-frank-coleman-coronial-inquest-death-in-custody/105952756</link><description>Just three months into 2021, Frank Coleman was the ninth Indigenous death in custody in New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32d6e0b1f3429b2e25aa52ab6cf6a9cf</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: History exams, an unusual gift and the 'storm of the century'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/weekly-news-quiz-october-31/105951152</link><description>It is time to see if you have been paying attention — test your memory of this week's news cycle here.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8dc50fb8d4336e3f586566741fe5f43</guid></item><item><title>Australian-first treaty legislation passes in Victorian parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/victorian-first-nations-treaty-legislation-passes/105954864</link><description>Historic legislation has passed that will see the creation of an Indigenous council that will be consulted on laws and policies affecting Indigenous communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">094f68669c519d3627b4518f411e27dd</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump sets US refugee cap at 7,500, white South Africans given priority</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/donald-trump-asylum-cap-white-south-africans-priority/105955480</link><description>The US president paused all refugee admissions when he took office in January, saying they could only be restarted if established to be in the best interest of the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ec2688779308bc0ea4e1b06e6a5d8c3</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew stripped of title by King Charles and told to leave Royal Lodge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/prince-andrew-to-leave-royal-lodge-lose-title/105955534</link><description>Prince Andrew will have his royal titles removed and surrender the lease of the Royal Lodge on the grounds of Windsor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95dc5197db309c553f2c48e9b30c09b9</guid></item><item><title>Award-winning youth advocate Cody Schaeffer charged over alleged assaults on teenagers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/award-winning-advocate-charged-alleged-assault/105953562</link><description>The radio host and youth mental health charity founder has been charged with assaulting several teenagers, according to Queensland authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89678fbe79c70982746ee521bf01731d</guid></item><item><title>Canberra is a step closer to getting its first dementia care village</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/canberra-dementia-care-village-on-site-of-sold-school/105942542</link><description>Specialised accommodation will be built in Curtin to house those living with the nation's deadliest disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">109e5e3f66c2731acc1db56469f50fba</guid></item><item><title>New-found love of running takes SA man all the way to New York Marathon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/indigenous-marathon-foundation-squad-prepare-for-new-york/105950978</link><description>Six months ago, Jack Atkinson had little running experience. But this weekend he will tackle the world's largest marathon alongside NRL great Johnathan Thurston and AFL giant Lance 'Buddy' Franklin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7467324170fc51e789bcdb91a79dbeb8</guid></item><item><title>Heartbroken dad wants Senate inquiry into doctor suicides</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/calls-for-senate-inquiry-into-doctor-suicide-deaths/105885252</link><description>There are calls for a Senate inquiry into the suicide deaths of Australian doctors amid allegations of untenable rosters and payback for whistleblowers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cb120622fea746f458abf16cfc11b4e</guid></item><item><title>Australia rues batting and fielding mishaps in Women's World Cup semifinal loss to India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/cricket-world-cup-semifinal-australia-loses-to-india/105955560</link><description>Australia captain Alyssa Healy says her side only have themselves to blame as the defence of their World Cup crown comes to an end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">551400f1ea68e61d7c2004c80df270f7</guid></item><item><title>Tame Impala, Lily Allen, Dave lead October's best new albums</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/10-best-albums-october-lily-allen-tame-impala-dave-baker-boy/105952214</link><description>From Lily Allen's devastating divorce record to Tame Impala's polarising return, here are October's best new music releases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f72053d7b5ec4a8e348657728b9cce1</guid></item><item><title>Emma Stone reunites with director Yorgos Lanthimos for fourth time in Bugonia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/bugonia-film-review-yorgos-lanthimos-emma-stone-jesse-plemons/105941636</link><description>Yorgos Lanthimos continues his journey as the king of absurdist dark comedies with this latest offering, which delves into conspiracy theories in the most bizarre way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbc0f9ae9ce94e731361cd72b3bca372</guid></item><item><title>Women paid thousands less per year than men in Victoria's forest firefighting ranks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/deeca-pay-inequality-gender-gap-ffmv-firefighters/105941598</link><description>The Australian Workers' Union says Victorian female forest firefighters have been short-changed by an average of more than $4,000 in pay growth since 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0024a9616b7afb244d67da54e5511a2</guid></item><item><title>Doctors say Chinese Australians should get checked for breast cancer earlier. Here's why they don't</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/chinese-women-get-breast-cancer-younger-than-in-the-west/105927052</link><description>As Breast Cancer Awareness Month draws to a close, support groups urge Chinese women to get screened for breast cancer, as doctors highlight how the disease impacts this cohort differently.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6c6f672d3fe7b2a88fbdf8accb2e6cc</guid></item><item><title>Democrats are 'fighting fire with fire' in California. Is a political inferno coming for American democracy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/california-gerrymandering-election-map-november-4/105944438</link><description>A debate is underway about American democracy, as California's governor campaigns for voters to approve a set of gerrymandered maps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5988d8b075ecfb55c7e7600d64328b68</guid></item><item><title>Tech stocks weigh on Wall Street but Apple and Amazon rally, ASX rises after Trump-Xi meeting — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/asx-markets-business-live-news-31-oct/105955602</link><description>The Australian share market is higher on Friday but still on track for a weekly loss. ANZ has flagged a $1.1 billion profit hit due to redundancy costs and fines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37144f5a29a306a3825703a3902c8956</guid></item><item><title>Olympic Leisure Centre swimmers left high and dry as historic aquatic venue closes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/olympic-leisure-centre-heidelberg-west-pool-closure/105953220</link><description>The closure of the Olympic Leisure Centre public pool in Melbourne's north-east today has left local swimmers adrift, with many saying there are no other options for them to swim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bfd54566fce4635de0595faa7676d1a</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies forced to play by World Rugby's rules in England Test at Twickenham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/rugby-union-australia-wallabies-england-twickenham-test/105955734</link><description>Wallabies coach Joe Schmidt is not concerned about rules prohibiting some of his key overseas-based players from lining up against England at Twickenham this weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d53a4b0a677e6666d19d4b6c9c34eb26</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government has not walked its talk about accountability and integrity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/labor-transparency-david-pocock-jobs-for-mates/105938080</link><description>Labor came to power in 2022 promising a new form of transparent, accountable politics. As recent incidents have shown, there is little sign of it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8fc78e5f2229acc225d8f3826a21c3c</guid></item><item><title>Dozens of shoppers report experiencing static shocks at Sunshine Coast supermarket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/dozens-of-shoppers-experience-static-shocks-at-supermarket/105943202</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaf22f7cc0cd77576a651d7cd1645712</guid></item><item><title>Aldi shoppers report static electricity shocks at Nambour supermarket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/aldi-investigates-static-shocks-nambour-store/105942226</link><description>Something is giving shoppers a shock at this Queensland store — and it is not the grocery bill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4352a60254432b657cbc85242bd1a54f</guid></item><item><title>How ancient knowledge is making modern science sit up and pay attention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/how-ancient-science-is-driving-modern-science/104872844</link><description>From dinosaur footprints to volcanic eruptions, First Nations knowledge is helping to drive modern science.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50095967b7a3c44455a6763a4dcc6e41</guid></item><item><title>Decades after the 'final' seance, hundreds still hope to contact Harry Houdini</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/harry-houdini-seance-halloween/105899090</link><description>On Halloween night in 1936, the tiny, white-haired widow of Harry Houdini made her final attempt to contact him from beyond the grave. Today, the tradition continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fa0dd9dced651720e47d86f4f127aa5</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with murder of baby in Baldivis in Perth's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/woman-charged-with-murder-of-baby-in-baldivis-in-southern-perth/105956052</link><description>Police investigating the death of an eight-month-old baby at a Baldivis home charge a 28-year-old woman with murder and say she will face court at a later date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43f9d07e3d08873f7b0ca8eaab05b549</guid></item><item><title>SA coastal tourism struggling, even in areas outside the algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/coastal-accommodation-down-amid-sa-algal-bloom/105938456</link><description>Coastal towns in parts of SA's south-east have seen significant drops in visitation, despite being free of harmful algae.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29fdc88051c2f790be6cbd769bad13a0</guid></item><item><title>Andrew's last appearance as a prince on September 16, 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/andrew-s-last-appearance-as-a-prince-in-september-16-2025/105956352</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7a387f306eb76ba32cc66ba8e782aa1</guid></item><item><title>Black bearded irises bloom just in time for Halloween</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/black-bearded-irises-bloom-on-flower-farm-in-time-for-halloween/105942068</link><description>While red roses have their moment on Valentine's Day, these "black suited" irises come into bloom close to Halloween.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0300dc3c24cf3c0c6c94e637f12407c3</guid></item><item><title>Darling Downs 'inundated' with reports of snakes, bites and near misses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/snakes-becoming-more-prevalent-on-the-darling-downs/105953444</link><description>Gunter Glasser has been catching snakes for almost 30 years across Southern Queensland, but October has been an especially busy month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2100cbd5d77935766d6b6ffb955cbc42</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Jillaroos lose Tamika Upton for Pacific Championships Test against New Zealand's Kiwi Ferns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/pacific-championships-australia-jillaroos-new-zealand-kiwi-ferns/105956360</link><description>The Jillaroos will have to cope without one of their stars in Sunday's Pacific Championships Test against New Zealand in Auckland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8990b682f325b3db20d4e2be39f5884d</guid></item><item><title>Strong prices, good conditions encourage Queensland farmers to trial canola</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/queensland-growers-trial-canola-with-strong-prices/105948370</link><description>While they are a long way off from rivalling the plantings in Western Australia or New South Wales, growers in Queensland are experimenting with canola and reaping the rewards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94383f29d34d12c50fd4da46186ddeb2</guid></item><item><title>Yacht salvage team innovates with geotextile to protect Lady Elliot Island reef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/yacht-salvage-team-protects-lady-elliot-island-reef/105952960</link><description>After a fibreglass yacht ran aground on Lady Elliot Island's pristine reef, a bespoke salvage team worked tirelessly to save the environment from irreparable harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9467c32a312dd00ab73dcf2d4f4984ce</guid></item><item><title>The storm which killed a 21-year-old woman in Cooroy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/the-storm-which-killed-a-21-year-old-woman-in-cooroy/105956456</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7c366a64a75860b7251615b55bca0d9</guid></item><item><title>Man removes 18km of barbed wire fencing from Victorian property to save wildlife</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/man-removes-18km-of-barbed-wire-fencing-to-help-wildlife/105890356</link><description>Wongarra man Doug Gimesy removes more than 18 kilometres of barbed wire from his property to create a wildlife haven.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c0bf85e258a086971d52698dadb06eb</guid></item><item><title>Opposition implies Labor scuttled Sussan Ley's planned visit to Tomago smelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/ley-visit-to-tomago-cancelled/105956788</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley has revealed her scheduled tour of the plant was cancelled at the last minute but she was given a meeting with its chief executive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">820a2b867c39bbf6525d378e4f6c1551</guid></item><item><title>GWS Giants player Katherine Smith on playing AFLW through pain of endometriosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/endometriosis-elite-athlete-katherine-smith-aflw-gws-giants/105952810</link><description>Endometriosis remains a silent struggle for many women and elite athletes alike. GWS Giants leader Katherine Smith spent years playing through the pain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06acb9ae31170ef7ae2f73da7ee838ed</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Health confirms homemade food products as source of rat poisoning cluster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/qld-health-rat-poisoning-cluster-homemade-food/105956778</link><description>Queensland Health says the three products were made in a home kitchen and were either gifted or purchased in the local area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c97948fdc15caee9a8849ba2ed48a6bc</guid></item><item><title>Perth men charged over seizure of more than five tonnes of illicit cigarettes, vapes and loose tobacco</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/perth-men-charged-illicit-tobacco-seizure/105957130</link><description>Two Perth brothers are charged after the seizure of more than four million cigarettes, around 50,500 vapes and almost 900 kilograms of loose-leaf tobacco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49eee83c8197cb719016445cd2eb17ca</guid></item><item><title>How 5 Seconds of Summer stayed together after all these years together</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/how-5-seconds-of-summer-stayed-together/105950350</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad363607af4109b7fd0698bd4684f26f</guid></item><item><title>Perth brothers charged over massive seizure of imported cigarettes, vapes.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/perth-men-charged-illicit-tobacco-seizure/105957498</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7de76233e13ab1e21658cb0c12971e9c</guid></item><item><title>What are the origins of Andrew Mountbatten Windsor's name?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/why-prince-andrew-will-go-by-andrew-mountbatten-windsor-/105956622</link><description>Buckingham Palace has announced Prince Andrew will lose his royal titles and honours. But where does his surname Mountbatten Windsor come from?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75b3f50397aff310430b7706b45da405</guid></item><item><title>Waroona Shire suggests blowing up rotting whale carcass to save money</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/waroona-shire-suggests-blowing-up-dead-whale-to-save-money/105954240</link><description>A coastal shire in WA suggests towing a rotting whale carcass out to sea and blowing it up, saying it cannot afford to dispose of the whale itself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc10ef67425429fffc19d164c6b3c365</guid></item><item><title>Will Hayward and Ollie Florent left hurt by brutal conversation with Sydney before Carlton trades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/afl-hayward-florent-hurt-by-swans-trade-with-carlton/105957592</link><description>Will Hayward and Ollie Florent were both locked into long-term deals with Sydney before being told they needed to leave while holidaying in South America.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d162ed07f21a01a0b3a8570205c0a6b1</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal Community Controlled Health Service clinics in remote NT desperately need additional resources</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/nt-remote-aboriginal-community-controlled-health-service-funding/105953720</link><description>Imagine visiting a health clinic where you may be exposed to asbestos, leaking roofs and lead in the water pipes. That's the reality for remote NT, according to a new report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa8f587b08c0afef95e1f20ba455024e</guid></item><item><title>Stripped of his titles and his home, Andrew's humiliation is complete</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/prince-andrew-loses-titles-royal-lodge-and-dignity/105955874</link><description>Once considered the darling of the royal family and the "favourite" son of Queen Elizabeth II, the King's brother will now be known only as Andrew Mountbatten Windsor. It's a humiliation for the history books.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e0ae4adf6d8a924fed09f5ab76eea08</guid></item><item><title>Rescuers scramble to recover bodies after landslide in Papua New Guinea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/papua-new-guinea-landslide-kukas-enga-province/105957220</link><description>Police say 21 people have been killed in a landslide in Papua New Guinea's highlands overnight, with bodies still being recovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a16fc758622edfecffc8a0cf8bad37cf</guid></item><item><title>Queensland mayors to lead local disaster recovery after long-running dispute at Ipswich City Council</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/ipswich-dispute-forces-ldmg-mayor-change-across-queensland/105953990</link><description>The changes form part of a larger Empowering Councils Bill set to be introduced by the Queensland government later this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b378d6900dd497b8d7a9943df7b37de6</guid></item><item><title>Port Adelaide dismisses Warren Tredrea from board of directors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/warren-tredrea-dismissed-from-port-adelaide-board/105958182</link><description>AFL great Warren Tredrea has been dismissed from the board of the Port Adelaide Football Club, the Power has confirmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00a1f95f5595f68b1322b46d966bb1c6</guid></item><item><title>Broncos legend Corey Parker fears Reece Walsh's stardom may mean eventual code switch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/corey-parker-fears-reece-walsh-could-join-rugby-union-all-blacks/105958064</link><description>After setting the NRL and international rugby league alight in recent months, Reece Walsh's next move could be one that leads him to global stardom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9306a06732f9206cf10fe969dd0e50d1</guid></item><item><title>Queensland premier promises change after boy dies in e-bike crash on Sunshine Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/fatal-ebike-crash-sunshine-coast-premier-new-laws/105956500</link><description>David Crisafulli says laws will be changed following a string of fatal accidents involving electric bikes and scooters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">997336b58af56fe0220659e93ee85ecd</guid></item><item><title>What happens to Prince Andrew's children? Princess Beatrice and Eugenie to keep their titles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/future-of-princess-beatrice-and-eugenie-in-royal-family-/105957580</link><description>What to know about the future of Andrew Mountbatten Windsor's daughters and their role in the royal family going forward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d60de38bc3440b6a030db534d2c3ed3d</guid></item><item><title>Jury finds man guilty of rape of woman he found unconscious on Shepparton nature strip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/dexley-bule-meme-found-guilty-in-shepparton-rape-abduction-trial/105938504</link><description>A jury has found a 29-year-old Vanuatu national guilty of the rape and abduction of a woman in Shepparton in August last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ee7f6ddf2dd631515b0c843bc7f1eda</guid></item><item><title>2025 Bournda Bird Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/2025-bournda-bird-olympics/105958854</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc85e6f5e6c57a03f79a8367b36280ce</guid></item><item><title>What moving overseas for love and work looked like for Alex</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/what-moving-overseas-for-love-and-work-looked-like-for-alex/105884670</link><description>Having recently ended a seven-year long-distance relationship, Alex Bowyer wasn't keen on repeating history when he met his now-boyfriend Tony in Japan. So he packed up his life and moved overseas — but not without a safety net.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">caec662cdc4fc573eada2d7389b3da29</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of jobs to go as AGL speeds up energy transition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/hundreds-of-agl-power-station-workers-warned-of-job-losses/105958582</link><description>AGL is preparing to shed hundreds jobs as part of a massive restructure aimed at freeing up capital to accelerate its transition away from coal and towards renewables.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">045a93aaafc9d62c988ce78be54f5abf</guid></item><item><title>Liberals hope for climate consensus but fear Nationals will dump net zero first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/liberals-hope-for-climate-consensus-fear-nationals-net-zero/105958676</link><description>After most federal Liberal MPs attended a net zero meeting in Canberra, there is cautious optimism a consensus position can be found, but the junior Coalition partner could be poised to strike first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c06019f6d84d6edfa042cd70bde80a35</guid></item><item><title>Miners asked to reconsider using industrial explosives involved in underground explosion which killed two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/cobar-explosion-investigation-unearths-new-details/105958148</link><description>Regulator may ban the type of explosive used in fatal mining accident which claimed the lives of two workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8440ef045985b51177cebf0f6e2bf398</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne happy to open in Australia's Test side for upcoming Ashes series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/cricket-marnus-labuschagne-ready-to-open-australia-ashes/105959688</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne is prepared to do whatever it takes to get back into Australia's Test side, even if that means batting in a non-preferred opening slot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aaceba17d7858f2de1a829904e732ca9</guid></item><item><title>Canberra will get its first dementia care village</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/canberra-will-get-its-first-dementia-care-village/105959468</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fb4bf48a55298218731fa4663c10083</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/friday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/105959882</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42a32d74df89994c443a844112fee9dd</guid></item><item><title>Australia vs India second T20: Hazlewood and Marsh dominate in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/cricket-australia-india-second-t20i-melbourne-live-scorecentre/105959222</link><description>A lethal spell from Josh Hazlewood has propelled Australia to an emphatic four-wicket Twenty20 win over India in front of 82,438 fans at the MCG.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c924fd75cf27f00160799d33b1310dce</guid></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa death toll continues rising as Caribbean nations embark on clean-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/hurricane-melissa-death-toll-continues-rising/105960218</link><description>The death toll in the wake of Hurricane Melissa has climbed to at least 49, according to official reports, after wreaking destruction across much of the northern Caribbean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">843dc0cbb292fbf6e9889e26b4c70374</guid></item><item><title>Dutch centrist leader Rob Jetten claims election victory and is set to become country's youngest PM</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/dutch-centrist-d66-party-confirmed-as-election-winner-anp-says/105960122</link><description>Dutch centrist party D66 is now expected to take the lead in a first round of talks to form a coalition government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837e28c07f59e4f52cf2bada907deebe</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's salad days are stalked by the spectres of stagflation and soaring bills</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/albanese-trump-rba-interest-rates-jim-chalmers/105956176</link><description>The PM and his government are sitting in the often-fleeting sweet spot that comes early in the second term under our Westminster system of government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dc79fc50f5fd23410b6265f04496499</guid></item><item><title>What does the average house price get you in regional Victoria?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/what-does-the-average-house-price-get-you-in-regional-victoria/105947516</link><description>The median house price in regional Victoria is $636,500. But what that will get you can look very different from place to place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b1f9e66e750a2e3439cf8f1491d2ba9</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew's downfall is Virginia Giuffre's justice, but can it save the monarchy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-virginia-guiffre-charles-jury-out/105959842</link><description>Prince Andrew has been exiled to a kind royal house arrest but the jury is still out on whether it's enough to stem damage to the monarchy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3a2ba1ff4cef4efc1e36e9eae1cde57</guid></item><item><title>Conjoined twins in PNG could be sent to Germany for surgery after Australia hopes fall through</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/png-conjoined-twins-not-getting-treatment-in-sydney-australia/105952802</link><description>The parents of conjoined twins in PNG who were hoping to send their babies to Sydney for an operation are now trying to go to Germany instead because Australia is too expensive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ebb82535b2f5b422a620c992c9c6562</guid></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani's pledge to arrest Benjamin Netanyahu in NYC 'unenforceable campaign promise'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/zohran-mamdani-pledge-to-arrest-netanyahu-impossible-say-experts/105955338</link><description>Zohran Mamdani, the man many predict will become New York City's next mayor, has made plenty of promises — his one to arrest Israel's PM is causing a particular stir ahead of Tuesday's election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c9b853f87c7a320d38dd90f5df5463d</guid></item><item><title>Nurse among patients calling for better access to long COVID treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/calls-for-more-specialist-treatment-into-long-covid/105836026</link><description>Patients are calling for better access to long COVID care after the closure of one of the country's last public clinics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5638d2425e01e1612dee5ffec366fbe4</guid></item><item><title>Virginia Giuffre's brother demands Prince Andrew investigation, wants King to pressure Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/virginia-giuffre-s-brother-wants-andrew-investigated/105960436</link><description>Sky Roberts also appealed to King Charles to pressure Donald Trump into putting "big boy pants on" over the release of the Epstein files.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">510d4de91745e3e2adeaeeea4ac1ca84</guid></item><item><title>Survey reveals nine out of 10 NSW farmers are victims of crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/farm-crime-survey-rural-theft-nsw-farmers/105953178</link><description>Widespread farm crime is frustrating rural communities, with almost 90 per cent of farmers in New South Wales reporting they have been victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca3685010c044834d674786d3fcc67b0</guid></item><item><title>Alcohol industry explores smaller packaging as consumers seek convenience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/alcohol-industry-looks-towards-smaller-packaging/105898004</link><description>From wine in 187ml bottles to spirits in sleek aluminium cans, producers are downsizing to meet a growing demand for convenience and variety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06918ace93ca9c6d4266e307b0e5a7d1</guid></item><item><title>David McCormack on Bluey, Custard, and the power of popular music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/david-mccormack-custard-bluey-polaroids-interview-bandit/105957448</link><description>From indie rock to children's TV icon, David McCormack has done it all — and now he's back with a new album and zero expectations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e656df70aaecbde8d98aa2dcaa094b9</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers move to block Nauru deportations over lack of adequate healthcare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/lawyers-launch-fresh-bid-to-block-nauru-deportations/105956438</link><description>Human rights lawyers have applied to intervene in the High Court case of a man facing deportation to Nauru, arguing the government should be barred from deporting people to places where they face death or serious harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">925338d4024bf4344d379d1c6ca05899</guid></item><item><title>Why Australia's spring housing market this year is set to go into overdrive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/is-the-spring-real-estate-selling-season-boom-accurate-australia/105910630</link><description>NSW sees a 16.8 per cent increase in new property listings during spring — ringing true to the age-old saying this time of year is the best time to jump into the housing market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">701696510367692d1ffd5716678135dc</guid></item><item><title>North makes history with 24th consecutive AFLW win, Carlton finals-bound after win in the west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/north-melbourne-makes-history-with-24th-consecutive-aflw-win/105960520</link><description>North Melbourne becomes the first male or female VFL/AFL team to win 24 consecutive games after prevailing over Hawthorn by 49 points.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8853825ea0c5e574c574d6747f015958</guid></item><item><title>Wastewater from a metal and critical mineral refinery in Baotou, China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/wastewater-from-metal-critical-mineral-refinery-baotou-china/105957548</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92d209e2752baae60fe47a0c5913a2ad</guid></item><item><title>Pursuing critical minerals could come at a cost.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/cost-of-critical-minerals/105960076</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6823e2dd3050307231d76257855fb44</guid></item><item><title>Australia's pursuit of critical minerals holy grail could come at great cost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/will-critical-minerals-cost-australia-too-much/105954636</link><description>Researchers warn Australia's pursuit of a critical minerals industry could come at a significant cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cf1f06e0c623e2822f22f0ac0d1c4d5</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur upset by Alexander Bublik again in Paris in repeat of Roland Garros heartbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/alex-de-minaur-upset-by-familiar-foe-again-in-paris/105960540</link><description>Alex de Minaur suffers another nightmarish defeat in Paris at the hands of his old tormentor Alexander Bublik.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa59a406bdfa767d6298d015b3d7a047</guid></item><item><title>Trump wants to resume US nuclear weapons testing. This is what it could look like</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/what-donald-trump-us-nuclear-weapons-testing-would-mean/105955836</link><description>The US has not conducted nuclear weapons testing for 33 years. Now Donald Trump is calling for a resumption, raising concerns about what that may involve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">592dbf744580aa6b4dc97f32018e4581</guid></item><item><title>Interest rates will fall again when inflation returns to target but that could require a painful adjustment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/interest-rates-will-fall-again-when-inflation-returns-to-target/105959070</link><description>And until someone — redundant workers, big business, the RBA or government — foots the bill, interest rates are unlikely to budge from here.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1366f2c16234ffbc86520a1225eddb9d</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja has seen politicians 'all over cricket', now he's joining other athletes to get action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/usman-khawaja-players-coalition-end-game-sport-politics/105956976</link><description>Cricketer Usman Khawaja is one of the highest-profile Australian athletes who regularly wades into political issues. Now, Khawaja and other athletes have agreed to form a Players' Coalition to influence policy change on issues ranging from racism and human rights to social media abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4244b2427f7b8691e7f1ec870cd90b45</guid></item><item><title>Trans people push to make healthcare more inclusive in the regions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/healthcare-for-trans-people-in-regional-australia/105951286</link><description>A Queensland trans man says healthcare workers did not fully understand his needs when he sought fertility treatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c50eae967b4c2f86c1115dbff28cbcb</guid></item><item><title>Australia's childcare crisis forces us to reconsider how we organise care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/childcare-revelations-denmark-parenting-community-safety/105947096</link><description>This is not the first revelation about how we treat the most vulnerable in our society but such reports persistently reveal a deeper, and more distressing malaise about Australian society.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">562a18df36c8df40c1668f02d6ffb748</guid></item><item><title>Is the AI bubble too big to burst?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/if-youre-listening-ai-bubble-too-big/105960072</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6c58216143f41625b58dc75818bde30</guid></item><item><title>How the Lions conquered their growing pains to reach AFLW top four</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/aflw-how-brisbane-lions-reached-top-four/105951226</link><description>After a shaky start to the season the Brisbane Lions showed faith in a shift in game style to climb up the ladder and guarantee themselves a top-four finish.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89b1abd2fd62d24a392eafb8dd58b8f9</guid></item><item><title>Queenslanders urged to prepare as severe storms, giant hail and flash floods forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/severe-storms-supercell-risk-queensland/105957138</link><description>South-east Queensland faces a dangerous supercell outbreak on Saturday, with forecasters warning of giant hail, flash flooding and possible tornadoes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9a58aa6102be807e92e94da7740e8df</guid></item><item><title>Emergency doctors say RAH admitted more patients than bed limit, SA Health denies claim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/ed-doctors-under-pressure-at-royal-adelaide-hospital/105952042</link><description>The Australasian College of Emergency Medicine says on a day in September there were 70 admitted inpatients in the Royal Adelaide Hospital's emergency department that has 68 beds — a claim disputed by SA Health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dffcfe5d9444278730f4f2b4c51d1fd</guid></item><item><title>Holiday workers propping up key sectors exposed to serious workplace injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/working-holiday-makers-face-higher-risk-of-injury/105876542</link><description>Many young people on the Working and Holiday Visa programs come to Australia to fill labour shortages in industries like meat processing and farming, but there are concerns around their health and safety in dangerous workplaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4d109f50ed67b18b9f731588e56f11a</guid></item><item><title>ABC Quote Quiz: Brutal weather, a prince evicted, gen alpha slang and nature being weird … again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/abc-quote-quiz-november-1/105956502</link><description>They said it, we published it. Can you decipher it? See if you can work out who said what, and why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0c8c2e8d3c89b2c88a891ef14847b5b</guid></item><item><title>The Canberra Liberals need to put their internal feud behind them. It's hard to see how they'll do that</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/canberra-liberals-internal-feud-distracting-from-job-opposition/105959904</link><description>After suspending two backbenchers from her party room this week, Canberra Liberals leader Leanne Castley has been silent. And it's hard to see how staying silent is helping Canberrans build trust in her party and her as the ACT's alternative chief minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6092a469630022aa6e000888ae487a5c</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate electric dirt bike crash as 15yo dies on the Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/gold-coast-teenager-dies-electric-dirt-bike-crash/105960602</link><description>A teenage boy has died overnight after falling from an electric dirt bike in Broadbeach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc5d59d80676974c2eebc6d9359f1507</guid></item><item><title>Who made the 2025 Booker Prize shortlist, who missed out and who will win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/booker-prize-shortlist-2025-reading-guide/105938154</link><description>'Spiky characters' and 'luminous writing': Here's what we thought of the prestigious literary award's 2025 shortlist, the first with Sarah Jessica Parker as judge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e56d5d64ebed92baa37fc7bef87c9e1</guid></item><item><title>Pen pals enjoy 60-year friendship from opposite sides of the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/pen-pals-for-60-years-joy-doevendans-diane-hatt-friendship/105893420</link><description>Sixty years ago in Canada, 12-year-old Diane Hatt went searching for a pen pal in Australia. She found one in South Australian Joy Doevendans and they've become best friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">804dd3e41d88618206c0d9211f0d6ef9</guid></item><item><title>What are you going to pay for your aged care? Here are all the details</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/what-aged-care-recipients-will-pay-under-government-proposal/105958056</link><description>A new fee structure for aged care takes effect today. Find out what it will mean for you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf85089e4290931f295656e23d71fb2a</guid></item><item><title>Quick and easy tomato and halloumi bake for busy weeknights - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/quick-easy-tomato-and-halloumi-bake/105929094</link><description>This tomato and halloumi bake requires only a handful of ingredients, sliced and seasoned and popped in a baking dish.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">789c5895d72e095e35c552b7d464aacf</guid></item><item><title>She accused him of rape, but Prince Andrew's downfall is too late for Virginia Roberts Giuffre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/virginia-giuffre-voice-finally-heard-prince-andrew-epstein-fight/105957478</link><description>In many ways, justice has been robbed from Epstein survivor Virginia Roberts Giuffre. Prince Andrew's stripped titles are a posthumous victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a998edbe78ca9949991b2d99999cc68</guid></item><item><title>Nhulunbuy Tennis Club faces final serve as Rio Tinto mine closure looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/future-of-gove-tennis-centre-in-doubt-as-mining-winds-down/105917060</link><description>The impending departure of Rio Tinto raises concerns about the future of sporting clubs in Nhulunbuy. But there are hopes increased investment in regional sports can help sustain the community's active lifestyle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36e3a7519ef27e93f34f9e7dd926b7d3</guid></item><item><title>Tanzania election protests leave hundreds dead, main opposition party says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/tanzania-election-protests-hundreds-killed/105960546</link><description>President Samia Suluhu Hassan this week held an election in which her main challengers were either jailed or barred from standing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f85f9f5ab328bb8cb1f4493b83c85059</guid></item><item><title>Buy Australian campaign aims to save dwindling domestic food manufacturing industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/federal-government-buy-local-campaign-food-shoppers/105947768</link><description>Experts warn that Australian food manufacturing is under threat as shoppers turn to cheaper imported items, but the federal government is trying to promote locally grown produce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">456a65f4e2f0a77a89ea886399f89dfc</guid></item><item><title>Fathers and daughters, international rowing champions and wartime love feature in our top WA October photos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/wa-photo-wrap-october/105944870</link><description>Our photographers this month illustrate a significant day for WA's history, a woman's struggle with her tiny home and a group of rowers competing on the world stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6387b2ce70b14afd3782e7b709897cc4</guid></item><item><title>UN calls for end to US strikes on alleged drug boats in the Caribbean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/us-strikes-on-alleged-drug-boats-must-stop-human-rights-chief/105960644</link><description>US President Donald Trump has justified his attacks on boats in the Caribbean as a necessary anti-drug campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa3ba78c8d03559b2d652c82b79bad60</guid></item><item><title>Nationals ditch net zero support in party platform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/nationals-ditch-net-zero-support-in-party-platform/105959532</link><description>The decision by the party's Federal Council does not bind federal parliamentarians but could pave the way for them to make a similar move as early as this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b81d174da3188fa2eec1d3a9d141af4</guid></item><item><title>Liam Gallagher incensed by flare let off at Melbourne Oasis concert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/oasis-concert-flare-melbourne-concert-liam-gallagher/105960702</link><description>A flare let off by a crowd member at the first of three Melbourne Oasis concerts has angered the band's co-founder Liam Gallagher, sparking an expletive-laden post.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d900445763b5a4b59252cb54dd16bdb6</guid></item><item><title>WHO confirms militia attack on hospital that killed 460 people in Sudan's Darfur region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/militia-attack-on-darfur-hospital-in-sudan/105960730</link><description>The World Health Organization says the attack this week involved gunmen striking in several waves, abducting doctors and nurses, gunning down staff, patients and people sheltering there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ef73c7b109ac426168e354b49a55049</guid></item><item><title>South African government criticises Trump's refugee policy prioritising white Afrikaner minority</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/south-african-criticises-us-refugee-policy-afrikaner-minority/105960720</link><description>On Thursday, the Trump administration announced its refugee policy would prioritise admitting Afrikaners, South Africa's white minority group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48d3584318e36a5458bc9b29af0f18d4</guid></item><item><title>Warren Tredrea was the Power's premiership captain, but has now been booted from its board</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/how-port-adelaide-great-warren-tredrea-lost-a-board-position/105467820</link><description>The Port Adelaide Football Club continues to describe Warren Tredrea as one of its greatest-ever players — but on Friday it dismissed him from its board of directors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a28d3f1051b04fcdcdfb0195c975542c</guid></item><item><title>Japan wants to hire more bear hunters after record number of people attacked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/japan-hires-bear-hunters-after-record-number-of-attacks/105960706</link><description>In the past six months, there have been four times the number of people killed by bears compared with last year, and the Japanese government wants to hire hunters to help cull the animals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b94b0d493eff834ff8f63809da300887</guid></item><item><title>Monkey escape in Mississippi gives a glimpse into the secretive world of animal research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/monkey-search-us-animal-research-questions/105960876</link><description>A truck carrying 21 research monkeys overturned in Mississippi, spilling wooden crates labelled "live monkeys" into the tall grass near the highway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837b49eea6678d18176e391ed60579b7</guid></item><item><title>Australia criticises 'lost opportunity' for strengthened Antarctic conservation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/antarctic-conservation-krill-fishing-ccamlr/105958414</link><description>The Australian government says it's "disappointed" after an international conservation meeting in Hobart failed to reach agreement on improved protection measures in Antarctica.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b8e997fb574570c44cb438a1c4ea1b6</guid></item><item><title>Giant hail causes injuries and damage to cars, homes across south-east Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/qld-thunderstorms-hit-south-east-saturday/105961034</link><description>Giant hailstones, lightning and rain have lashed parts of the state's south-east with supercell storm activity reported.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ef92d591d3415099ac0e409c057269a</guid></item><item><title>NSW mental health nurse disqualified after intimate relationship with patient</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/mental-health-nurse-disqualified-intimate-patient-relationship/105960708</link><description>The NSW Civil and Administrative Tribunal has found a mental health nurse guilty of professional misconduct after she was observed hugging and kissing a patient.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24944a801043e0de150b7f3c3a619f28</guid></item><item><title>Eagles to make historic AFLW finals appearance after Swans fall to Bombers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/aflw-power-giants-tigers-suns-swans-bombers-cats-demons/105961268</link><description>Daisy Pearce's West Coast Eagles have reached the AFLW finals for the first time after the Sydney Swans blew their chance in a shock three-point loss to struggling Essendon at Coffs Harbour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8352fdea61b61a74d7d71d411279529b</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after woman's body found in home near Cessnock</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/police-make-arrest-after-womans-death-cessnnock/105960920</link><description>Police have charged a man in connection with the violent death of a 39-year-old woman in a home near Cessnock.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da28036e83cf08345f69ac738cde7e04</guid></item><item><title>APEC world leaders meeting highlights idea of 'free and fair' global trade is severely wounded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/apec-highlights-idea-of-free-and-fair-global-trade-is-wounded/105961066</link><description>While Donald Trump skipped the APEC conference, Xi Jinping was positioning China as a believer in free and fair trade, and multilateralism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0566f6102894ef7c78bf89e77059156</guid></item><item><title>Police charge teen after officers allegedly assaulted at Byford Halloween party</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/two-arrested-over-police-assault-at-byford-halloween-party/105961178</link><description>Two police officers were allegedly assaulted while shutting down an out-of-control Halloween party attended by hundreds of people in Perth's southern suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97de9b08824a32ec2c7df8196e8c47af</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Cup 2025 field, horses, form guide and betting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/melbourne-cup-2025-field-horses-form-guide-and-betting/105895400</link><description>Supporters of the favourite Half Yours are smiling after the barrier draw, but the forecast for heavy rain in the coming days could reshape the chances of the 24 contenders. Explore our interactive form guide to all the horses set to line up in Tuesday's great race.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5c14042d610687b63933e018c602f35</guid></item><item><title>US House Democrats call on Prince Andrew to answer questions about Epstein links</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/democrats-call-on-prince-andrew-to-answer-questions-on-epstein/105961492</link><description>Democratic members of a US congressional committee investigating the Jeffrey Epstein case are calling on Andrew Mountbatten Windsor, the former prince, to answer questions about the convicted sex offender.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f57c675ccc781fe736d2f04a9a94931f</guid></item><item><title>Tanzanian president Samia Suluhu Hassan wins disputed election with more than 97pc of vote, results show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/samia-suluhu-hassan-tanzania-election-results-disputed-win/105961496</link><description>The result is likely to amplify the concerns of critics, opposition groups and others who said the election was not a contest but a coronation, after the president's two main rivals were barred or prevented from running.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f882ddb778d8b55165f699bcfb9ca3f7</guid></item><item><title>Three players sin-binned as Australia win torrid second Test 14-4 over England to retain Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/rugby-league-ashes-live-updates-australia-england-second-test/105961660</link><description>Australia have won a tough physical battle in Liverpool to claim the second Test against England and ensure they will retain the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00cefecb9b09081da42f3e08f2474f9e</guid></item><item><title>England power past Wallabies 25-7 at Twickenham as Matt Dawson slams Australians as being 'woeful'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/live-updates-england-vs-wallabies-rugby-union-international/105950672</link><description>The Wallabies were overpowered by a disciplined and ruthless England team, who won their eighth-straight international to claim victory at Twickenham.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a65e895909c012bbf81dead627b70dc</guid></item><item><title>Two more people charged over Louvre heist in Paris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/louvre-heist-suspect-released-without-charge/105961712</link><description>The man and woman deny any involvement in the heist as investigations continue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b684b03bddb0c65cf3adf01f8e0f665d</guid></item><item><title>Share your experience with the housing market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/audience-callout-housing-experiences/105958352</link><description>What's your experience looking to buy your first home, or find an affordable, stable rental? We want to hear from you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d2af351a2853732a55f711d6a86bdde</guid></item><item><title>Trump and Xi prove they aren't just great rivals but politicians fighting for survival back home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/donald-trump-xi-jinping-meeting-busan-trade-taiwan/105957454</link><description>Donald Trump's gains are immediate and personal while Xi Jinping's are quiet, reversible, and strategic</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39b4047e9d75d88c7897c44769cd5431</guid></item><item><title>As US government shutdown drags on, 42 million people could be affected by food program cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/us-government-shutdown-millions-could-be-affected-by-snap-cuts/105960412</link><description>Isaac Stein should be at his day job as a lawyer for the Internal Revenue Service, but instead, he's making hot dogs as the US government shutdown drags on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dac092401c80b6e2437d59356589ccd8</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew is leaving Windsor Estate. Why wasn't he given another property on the grounds?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/prince-andrew-windsor-estate-who-lives-where/105961082</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten Windsor's eviction from his mansion in Windsor Castle is the latest part of a reshuffle of royals around the estate's grounds. Here's where everyone lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40999d5b8081f180d9837a54afab649e</guid></item><item><title>Australians are being priced out of the property market and first home buyers schemes might not be helping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/real-estate-property-market-first-home-buyers-schemes/105941822</link><description>A recent auction for a three-bedroom townhouse in Brisbane has captured just how much property prices have skyrocketed in recent years, highlighting the nation’s fast-growing housing affordability crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b516c705020e5d11eef2fa6ae1e76d3</guid></item><item><title>When is the RBA meeting next? When will interest rates go down?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/reserve-bank-australia-rba-meeing-interest-rates-october/105942272</link><description>Many people paying off mortgages were hoping for a cash rate cut, but recent inflation data means that is highly unlikely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f329c2691a88d508e7837d35f646745</guid></item><item><title>Labor takes fight to Greens in key seats over environment laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/labor-takes-fight-to-greens-on-environmental-laws/105959854</link><description>As it negotiates with the Greens and the Coalition over its proposed overhaul of environment laws, Labor is preparing a campaign accusing the minor party of obstructing its agenda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e24fd6f4bdadc2cf53792201d360334c</guid></item><item><title>New York's underbelly is thriving — this FBI case pulled back the curtain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/new-york-mafia-families-caught-running-complex-gambling-ring/105958744</link><description>The New York mafia is alive and an "historic" FBI bust has shown that underworld crime is still kicking across the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">262122226118c0158e14d96cee51a5d0</guid></item><item><title>Strong filial responsibilities can make discussing aged care a sensitive topic among multicultural families.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/aged-care-conversations-multicultural-family/105948108</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2afcc38a3b4d9427c398bee80a81e0f</guid></item><item><title>Talking about aged care in multicultural families can be hard but these tips may help</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/talking-about-aged-care-in-multicultural-families/105938294</link><description>Discussing aged care in culturally diverse families can be a sensitive subject. Here's how some approached the conversation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2ac3beed4221115a2488574253ef35c</guid></item><item><title>Horse racing replays edited to remove falls and deaths as industry grapples with social licence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/horse-racing-disappearing-video-replay-ethical-concerns/105812252</link><description>For years, the racing industry has been quietly removing falls and deaths from its replays. Now, industry insiders are speaking out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60509cf475521db2072628c3e8b45285</guid></item><item><title>I tried to outsmart the social media algorithm. Here's how it outsmarted me</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/social-media-ban-algorithm-phone-addiction-instagram-x-tiktok-/105844066</link><description>Armed with a burner phone and a fake name, I set out to learn how Instagram’s algorithm really works. This is what happened next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9906f6c214afd6cbbd8ed6bce1a755cb</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian couple buys the Eulo Queen Hotel in outback Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/from-marine-engingeers-to-outback-publicans/105793722</link><description>Adam and Prue Brancher had no experience running a pub when they decided to uproot their lives in Tasmania and move to outback Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8793b0d6ae4644caf2809d1c691b5e4</guid></item><item><title>A game for the ages: Nan and teen granddaughter line up together in country netball</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/newstead-netball-game-for-the-ages-nan-and-teen/105944908</link><description>A grandmother and granddaughter played for their regional Victorian netball team, turning a secret plan into a moment of country sport history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95920eb90f08d84fbc57ca7f8a5ec5ad</guid></item><item><title>Copper theft costing Queensland taxpayers millions of dollars every year, as rate of crime increases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/copper-theft-costing-queensland-millions-crime-rates-increase/105943088</link><description>Experts say cost of living pressures, and the ability to make money quickly, is behind a surge in copper thefts which are leaving highways and sporting fields in the dark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0f0ec08f1204c4a7360840a2b521d86</guid></item><item><title>Do the Queensland government’s claims about the surgical waiting list stack up?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/queensland-goverment-claims-surgicial-wait-times/105958488</link><description>Queensland's government declared victory on elective surgery wait times but thousands of patients are waiting longer than recommended — and specialists warn the fix is short-term at best.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1addc634e85cc415f058a6f711c9770</guid></item><item><title>From death masks to selfies: The history of our love-affair with portraits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/history-of-the-portrait/105915764</link><description>Whether it's an ancient death mask found on an Egyptian sarcophagus or the selfie you have just cropped on your phone, we have been creating portraits for centuries. So why do we love them so much?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e709c70c97458c7783289aaa7bc0da4</guid></item><item><title>How taxidermists are 'honouring the life' of extraordinary creatures through art and science</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/inside-the-role-of-taxidermists-and-nsw-rules-around-taxidermy/105858594</link><description>From a taxidermied mynah bird perched on a teacup to a mammoth leatherback turtle, here are the "extraordinary creatures" these taxidermists are preserving.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0ffe9b37d678fe031e628d33e163a35</guid></item><item><title>House prices have been climbing for a generation. Undoing the damage could take even longer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/house-prices-climbing-for-generation/105954416</link><description>It's an inconvenient truth that a housing crisis that took a generation to create cannot be fixed easily. The damage will likely take another generation to undo, unless the solution comes at the expense of those who already own their homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">029813aa2a3bd32b3760400b372935b2</guid></item><item><title>Australian number one Maya Joint loses in Hong Kong Open semis, Kim Birrell through to Chennai final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/hong-kong-open-semifinals-maya-joint-kim-birrell/105962042</link><description>Australian number one Maya Joint falls short of reaching the Hong Kong Open final, but compatriot Kimberly Birrell wins through to the tournament decider in Chennai.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88b411666705cb40a6cf868fe350d23a</guid></item><item><title>Israel says three bodies returned from Gaza are not those of hostages held by Hamas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/israel-gaza-not-hostage-bodies/105962050</link><description>Hamas says it offered to hand over samples of the unidentified bodies, but Israel refused and asked for the remains for examination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b0189f43f7bdcf69f0f9f8748d3a438</guid></item><item><title>Think you've got what it takes to top this quiz? It's time to play ... HARD!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia-tom-gleeson/105938854</link><description>Let's get it straight: you'll probably do badly on this quiz, and I'll judge you. It's time to play … HARD!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">466367d1bfc6da25874b17e1169c00f1</guid></item><item><title>Pitch invader stands with Kangaroos during national anthems before Ashes Test against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/pitch-invader-stands-with-kangaroos-at-ashes-test/105962104</link><description>A man is arrested by police after he lined up next to Cameron Munster before the Kangaroos' victory over England in the second Ashes Test in England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">659b8535fd83d29f6d57607dbfa2d552</guid></item><item><title>Rock climbers' defiance grows over Mount Arapiles cultural site requests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/arapiles-dyurrite-rock-climbers-defy-parks-victoria-requests/105950420</link><description>Rock climbers are publicly urging others to ignore Parks Victoria's requests to avoid culturally significant routes at Mount Arapiles Dyurrite in western Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f94931f9679aa559cb31740079bcf6c6</guid></item><item><title>Kirsha Kaechele banned men from MONA's Ladies Lounge — and won</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/mona-kirsha-kaechele-artist-curator-ladies-lounge-court-tasmania/105950618</link><description>No men are allowed at Kirsha Kaechele's Ladies Lounge and the Supreme Court agrees. The artist, curator and "missus" of MONA's owner knows how to cross boundaries, but can she solve Tasmania's thorniest dispute?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9eb89d5990fedbf1ad146e5a325a75f4</guid></item><item><title>South-east Queensland struck by second night of storms as residents assess hail damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/qld-storm-clean-up-begins-after-giant-hail/105962090</link><description>Queensland residents still counting the cost of giant hailstones that fell on Saturday afternoon were struck by a second round of storms on Sunday, with hailstones up to eight centimetres in diameter reported at Googa Creek.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23efc9862c6dff75838e933eace7c5cd</guid></item><item><title>Fishers and researchers are working together to create a 'transformational' data set</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/fishsoop-to-changes-ocean-knowledge/105946294</link><description>An international program in which researchers collaborate with the fishing industry is generating a dataset that will change global weather forecasting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d0be8dd19db857d8bebdf3c09e48455</guid></item><item><title>Sting linked to AN0M encrypted app which brought down criminals around the world enters new phase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/operation-ironside-an0m-arrests-messages-new-phase-explained/105950980</link><description>An international covert sting linked to the encrypted AN0M platform which brought down hundreds of alleged criminals and netted cash, drugs and weapons has reached a new phase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c81f46b90927df3ed2f640543f7ceadd</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump warns Nigerian government of US military action over alleged killings of Christians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/trump-warns-nigeria-of-action-over-killings-of-christians/105962120</link><description>Donald Trump is threatening to pull US aid and going "guns-a-blazing" as he accuses the Nigerian government of allowing the killing of Christians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6b030638add2962b6739a5eecb5bc55</guid></item><item><title>UK train stabbing leaves 10 in hospital, nine with life-threatening injuries, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/multiple-people-stabbed-on-uk-train-two-arrested/105962212</link><description>British police declare a "major incident", with counter-terrorism officers investigating a mass stabbing attack on a London-bound train.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a06b26a629b9fb1767a6f889a22afab</guid></item><item><title>Women's crisis shelter waits years to sub-lease vacant NT building</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/nt-galiwinku-womens-space-waits-years-to-lease-vacant-building/105947400</link><description>An Aboriginal-led domestic violence support service is demanding answers over stalled progress in establishing a women's shelter in remote Northern Territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c5519c7e21bec78ba2608589fe13d55</guid></item><item><title>Jockey Ethan Brown makes rise from from near-fatal fall to Melbourne Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/fall-and-rise-of-alice-springs-jockey-ethan-brown-melbourne-cup/105959830</link><description>Two years after a near-fatal fall, 25-year-old Alice Springs-born jockey has had a bumper season with 32 wins. Now he is riding in the Melbourne Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">119e82e58075acf4c274d207a8b07167</guid></item><item><title>Calls for road map for disability employment providers after Bedford's troubles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/advocates-call-for-road-map-for-disability-employment-sector/105952760</link><description>Some in the disability employment sector say they are operating in an increasingly complex and changing environment, and that there is a need for a clear way forward for organisations supporting people with complex needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1c23b56d2930c0a42e75b55696ab779</guid></item><item><title>There was a large police presence after reports of stabbings on a train in Cambridgeshire.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/large-police-presence-after-reports-of-stabbings-on-uk-train/105962274</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23f5eefc621d4af1bbe941ed925aee86</guid></item><item><title>Coalition won't back environment reforms without changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/coalition-wont-back-environment-reforms-without-change/105962194</link><description>The Coalition says it cannot support major reforms to Australia's environment laws in their current reform, setting a bar as they enter deep negotiations with the federal government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2234622f8159395c0c50b31e8b6a5e92</guid></item><item><title>Australian-first domestic violence digital notification service for victim-survivors to launch in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/dv-digital-notification-service-for-survivors-to-launch-in-nsw/105962116</link><description>DV Notify, a joint federal and NSW government led initiative, will provide real-time text and email updates from the time a violent offender is arrested through to their final sentencing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb79487fb28c9ae54f44abdbdeb72fa7</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island shrew declared extinct after decades without a sighting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/christmas-island-shrew-declared-extinct/105949448</link><description>A researcher says the long-suspected extinction of the mouse-sized mammal is "another stain" on Australia's environmental record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5881e83cdbfcb4b8a03bf21dcfcc021</guid></item><item><title>Did a former Perth bikie order the public assassination of his one-time gang leader?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/david-pye-nick-martin-assassination-supreme-court-murder-trial/105946084</link><description>With all the hallmarks of a Hollywood blockbuster, the high-profile murder trial of ex-bikie David Pye in WA's Supreme Court was never going to be a pedestrian affair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dbdcfef0061b6ca8b57bb1f0884bfe5</guid></item><item><title>Southern NSW summer crops shrink amid water shortages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/nsw-rice-and-cotton-plantings-slashed-amid-water-shortage/105899914</link><description>Southern NSW rice and cotton growers are heading into one of their smallest summer cropping seasons in years, with tight water allocations forcing many to halve their plantings or sit the season out altogether.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb84268cc4e631402cd4bcac564e8480</guid></item><item><title>Spotlight on youth justice after dozens arrested in WA's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/community-government-split-on-how-to-manage-youth-crime/105960744</link><description>The political spotlight has once again turned to preventing and managing youth crime in Western Australia, but decision-makers are split on how best to tackle the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e66797b37f7b947c54d8cfd5aefe6249</guid></item><item><title>What is the difference between an e-bike and an e-motorbike? What are the laws around them?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/e-bike-electronic-bicycle-e-motorbike-state-laws-speed/105580790</link><description>Noticing a lot of e-bikes around lately? Here's a state-by-state breakdown of the laws about them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78ae976ce50c968a6f2276556b5fa4af</guid></item><item><title>Veteran credits his local RSL with helping to pull him out of darkness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/regional-rsl-helps-veteran-during-time-of-darkness/105945666</link><description>A veteran in Victoria says he found hope and solace in his local RSL that "had his back" when he felt overwhelmed by his wife's early onset dementia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e62e59e10ad6400b36d4782f5d0997a</guid></item><item><title>High demand for ambulances in Melbourne and Geelong as weather warms up on Cup weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/vic-ambulance-victoria-high-demand-in-melbourne-and-geelong/105962168</link><description>Victorians are being urged to only call triple-0 for critical cases as demand for an ambulance soars on the quasi-Melbourne Cup long weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ccec54418d7485d71cf4d6c80c677ec</guid></item><item><title>Australian world champion Matthew Hauser wins Noosa Triathlon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/noosa-triathlon-world-champion-matthew-hauser-wins/105962372</link><description>Only a fortnight after being crowned men's world champion, Australia's Matthew Hauser tops the podium at the revered Noosa Triathlon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45f864e06e2aa13bbdab053093011aeb</guid></item><item><title>Critically endangered shrub on NSW Northern Tablelands could have prosperous future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/endangered-plant-grows-only-on-nsw-northern-tablelands/105924048</link><description>There are signs a critically endangered plant that grows on a rural property near Armidale could have a prosperous future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65eed854defe58937336b9a998c6ad1a</guid></item><item><title>The tensions inherent in Australia's housing crisis laid bare at Perth gallery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/need-for-housing-inspires-artist/105939626</link><description>In an exhibition exploring the fraught issue of finding a home, artist Alana Hunt is directly inviting owners of multiple properties to solve her own, personal housing crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1ede08335cf42653d92cae8ec5a73da</guid></item><item><title>Koalas found at Avonside in the NSW Snowy Mountains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/koalas-found-in-nsw-snowy-mountains/105951296</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fa344b8bed5c5e2a2839eba39c799c2</guid></item><item><title>Drones spot hidden koala population in NSW Snowy Mountains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/drones-spot-hidden-koala-population-in-nsw-snowy-mountains/105938022</link><description>A hidden group of koalas is found for the first time in a remote area of the New South Wales Snowy Mountains.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75fc1668ffcc40181a0b318a70f9f929</guid></item><item><title>Canadian PM Mark Carney apologises to Donald Trump over anti-tariff Reagan ad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/carney-apologises-to-trump-over-reagan-tariff-advertisement/105962422</link><description>Canadian PM Mark Carney says he apologised to an "offended" US President Donald Trump over the ad, which led to trade talks being suspended and an additional 10 per cent tariff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89ce7bb7bb3d2290248dbce8ffdd2505</guid></item><item><title>Police ask for help after body found in burnt-out ute in NSW Riverina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/nsw-police-body-found-in-ute-in-riverina/105962364</link><description>Two people have been killed in fatal crashes across the Riverina just hours apart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d013409edafb25df99ecee9c1553298d</guid></item><item><title>Nationals formally abandon commitment to reach net zero emissions by 2050</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/nationals-formally-abandon-net-zero-by-2050/105962162</link><description>The Nationals have formally abandoned a commitment to reach net zero emissions by 2050, setting a challenge for Opposition leader Sussan Ley whether to follow or risk splitting the Coalition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46eb3da651430f25d065e42b19a4b4ec</guid></item><item><title>Female jockey Jamie Melham discusses riding Melbourne Cup favourite Half Yours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/jamie-melham-half-yours-melbourne-cup-2025/105962620</link><description>Jockey Jamie Melham says she will be doing a "rain dance" on Monday, ahead of riding Melbourne Cup favourite Half Yours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c470aa33d7806c624d07e1920957cc8</guid></item><item><title>Three generations tackle 12th annual Variety Postie Bike Dash at Nabiac</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/family-gathers-for-charity-postie-bike-dash/105951144</link><description>Brian leads three generations of his family in the annual Variety Postie Bike Dash, raising money for sick and disadvantaged kids.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4db43038f1692bc5604a07fbdae21032</guid></item><item><title>Christopher James McLoughney refused bail over alleged murder of Rhukaya Lake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/court-hearing-for-man-accused-of-murder-of-rhukaya-lake/105962286</link><description>A man charged with the domestic violence murder of 39-year-old Hunter woman Rhukaya Lake is remanded in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e02a89e9350dc3c1d31c5a2c1ded6326</guid></item><item><title>Police stop train at Huntingdon Station after mass stabbing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/police-stop-train-at-huntingdon-station-after-mass-stabbing/105962658</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fe2514f2e3fe196c8c30a4c2f2604f6</guid></item><item><title>Orla O'Dwyer of the Brisbane Lions celebrates a goal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/proxy-orla-o-dwyer-of-the-brisbane-lions-celebrates-a-goal/105962734</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14c4627d45581f5534621552b494ba76</guid></item><item><title>AFLW round 12: Crows hold on to eliminate Dockers from finals contention, Lions finish third after beating Magpies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/aflw-round-12-collingwood-lions-st-kilda-bulldogs-crows-dockers/105962532</link><description>Adelaide has hung on for a thrilling 12-point win over Fremantle that secures its AFLW finals spot and ends the Dockers' season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e10849f6e5a398d9f4c6195ad557c31</guid></item><item><title>Car park closure leaves parts of Canberra's city centre inaccessible for people with disability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/act-inacessible-carparks/105962780</link><description>Patients with mobility issues are struggling to visit medical professionals after the Theatre Lane car park closed for the construction of the Lyric Theatre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8eaa76e36eda8a5f143c1528cc560957</guid></item><item><title>Easy low-alcohol cocktails and non-alcoholic drinks for summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/low-alcohol-cocktails-and-non-alcoholic-drinks-mocktails/105763344</link><description>Having a range of drinks on offer can help everyone feel included, especially at end-of-year gatherings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf0b38dd980309d44e125e1fc03ddb6b</guid></item><item><title>LA Dodgers win 2025 World Series game seven over Toronto Blue Jays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/la-dodgers-win-2025-world-series-game-seven-toronto-blue-jays/105962748</link><description>The Los Angeles Dodgers rallied to beat the Toronto Blue Jays 5-4 in extra innings of a decisive seventh game of the World Series to become Major League Baseball's first repeat champion in 25 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95accbcdae9dcf99be52ea2e9e79b9f2</guid></item><item><title>Eliesa Katoa fitted with oxygen mask during Tonga vs New Zealand Test match, Jillaroos defeat Kiwi Ferns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/australia-jillaroos-defeat-new-zealand-kiwi-ferns-10-4/105962804</link><description>Tongan forward Eliesa Katoa has been fitted with an oxygen mask during the Pacific Championship Test match against New Zealand, after copping multiple blows to the head.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c73a30eb3d2eb448a458821f369b445</guid></item><item><title>Man dies after worksite incident in South Kalgoorlie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/man-dies-after-worksite-incident-in-south-kalgoorlie/105962784</link><description>A worker in his 60s has died after sustaining critical injuries on a property in South Kalgoorlie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">772663df06f1f16aa5e7753b14d40773</guid></item><item><title>Inmate taken to hospital after alleged assault at SA's Yatala Labour Prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/inmate-taken-to-hospital-after-alleged-prison-assault/105962732</link><description>A prisoner has been taken to the hospital after the second alleged violent assault in two weeks in the South Australian prison system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2f67da22d83a326dc19f70b0a9d48bf</guid></item><item><title>Australia's scandal-ridden childcare sector is a legacy of the 'golden age' of reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/australia-childcare-sector-scandal-golden-age-of-reform/105952006</link><description>The decision by past governments to push Australia's childcare industry in the direction of marketisation and corporatisation has left a lasting legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1d56cc77ce2fe08cd4f6170ffaaaeeb</guid></item><item><title>India levels T20 series against Australia with impressive run chase in Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/cricket-australia-india-third-t20i-hobart-live-scorecentre/105962480</link><description>India levels the Twenty20 series against Australia, sharing the blows with the bat for a five wicket win with nine balls to spare in Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bd43953a9d2e34ceba1672873e920ea</guid></item><item><title>India vs South Africa, ICC Women's ODI Cricket World Cup final, live updates from Navi Mumbai</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/india-vs-south-africa-odi-world-cup-final-live-blog/105962972</link><description>South Africa must score 299 runs to win the first Women's ODI World Cup final not to feature Australia or England. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">491dce6762cbeeff4645783266a86c2c</guid></item><item><title>'Nothing to suggest' stabbing attack on train was a terrorist incident, UK police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/nothing-to-suggest-terrorist-attack-on-train-say-uk-police-/105963010</link><description>Police investigating a mass stabbing on a train bound for London on Saturday say there is nothing to suggest it was a terrorist attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9ecfd2362c9a76384f5e506470829e9</guid></item><item><title>Wedding guests shelter under tables as storm tears roof from historic Camboon Campdraft Hall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-02/camboon-campdraft-hall-collapses-storms-banana-shire/105963160</link><description>Dozens of wedding guests rushed to shelter children under tables and hold up the walls of a reception hall during an intense storm in Queensland's Banana Shire over the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e88d4113b10240d3aa742828e1fac9ec</guid></item><item><title>Investors and first home buyers flock to property market, driving up prices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-03/investors-versus-first-home-buyers-flock-back-to-property-market/105943356</link><description>Australia's property market is seeing rising demand, with record auctions over spring and a rise in both first home buyers and investors pushing up house prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0dc7ecf241d905d6c06b9d0a12ff2f49</guid></item></channel></rss>