<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 08:56:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Alleged gunman charged with murder over 'execution-style killing' of John Versace in Condell Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/alleged-gunman-charged-over-john-versace-shooting-murder-sydney/105996584</link><description>John Versace, 23, died in the driveway of a Sydney property in what police at the time described as "extremely brutal".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">703a546b4cfbf8c0015800bc35675c67</guid></item><item><title>AI could be the ultimate test of Australia's democracy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/ai-could-ultimate-test-australia-democracy-boyer-lectures/105991022</link><description>Developing safe AI is not just an opportunity for a democracy like ours; ever since our superpower ally checked out of its responsibilities on this front, it's an obligation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd3ecd4227d5985d0919b3e195d819eb</guid></item><item><title>Nauruan president makes secretive trip to parliament amid claims bikies won lucrative contract</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/nauru-president-parliament-contract-allegations/105996920</link><description>Nauru's president has made a secretive visit to Parliament House in Canberra amid allegations that bikie gangs won a lucrative contract to provide security for former immigration detainees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1747005400dd69005694c57223e459c9</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian parliament to apologise for body parts kept in pathology museum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/tasmania-apologies-for-body-parts-kept-in-pathology-museum/105996256</link><description>The Tasmanian government will apologise for the past practice of retaining body parts after autopsies without the knowledge or consent of family members.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb72c9939fd3cc88e7bb24fb79bd6007</guid></item><item><title>Torres Strait Islanders appeal federal court decision on landmark climate case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/climate-case-appeal/105990864</link><description>Two Torres Strait Islander uncles are appealing a federal court ruling that the Commonwealth does not owe a duty of care to protect their people from the impacts of climate change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca7d7ab8673ce37ad206b8bac32fb1ec</guid></item><item><title>Nauru's president makes secretive Parliament House visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/nauru-s-president-makes-secretive-parliament-house-visit/105997172</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76731f57cedd23b1f435aeca4b1d3266</guid></item><item><title>I thought I hated basketball. Now it's given me an amazing life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/how-para-sport-has-changed-my-life/105952646</link><description>After breaking her back at 19 Katherine's community made sure she knew how special she was. Wheelchair basketball brought her back to earth and made her life "truly amazing".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7670f4c828bd61b3087694a64e71ad4d</guid></item><item><title>'No legislative fix' for rise of neo-Nazis, counter-extremism expert warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/nsw-neo-nazi-groups-expert-warns-no-legislative-fix/105996626</link><description>Professor of Global Islamic Politics at Deakin University Greg Barton says while elements of public expressions of Nazism should be banned, there is no "quick fix".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c53c1b5f87d1ce197d792f1ead1bffa</guid></item><item><title>Trio arrested in regional SA for alleged scam targeting innocent motorists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/south-australia-arrests-alleged-scam/105996586</link><description>Three people have been arrested in relation to an alleged scam targeting motorists along the state's Eyre Peninsula.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d4235882f54cfead88b17b3280e70f9</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump pardons multiple lawyers, aides for their role in 2020 'fake electors' scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/trump-fake-electors-pardoned/105996140</link><description>Lawyers, campaign aides and a former publicist for Kanye West — here's who Donald Trump has pardoned for allegedly trying to overturn the 2020 election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d13d857d71287f4d9ea1f731fe558621</guid></item><item><title>Grounds revealed for State of Western Australia's appeal against abuse survivor Dion Barber's $2.8 million payout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/appeal-grounds-revealed-for-state-case-against-dion-barber/105996250</link><description>The State of Western Australia is appealing the entire basis of a judgement which awarded a Perth man nearly $3 million in compensation for abuse he suffered while he was in state care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2d43cef6475a460e1e93aff9c4e74ae</guid></item><item><title>England cricket great Ian Botham concerned by lack of warm-up matches prior to first Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/cricket-ian-botham-questions-england-ashes-preparation/105997704</link><description>England's only warm-up game prior to the first Ashes Test will be an internal match, a fact that is greatly concerning legendary all-rounder Ian Botham.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d377c420ec9badac5102acc497e2fe6d</guid></item><item><title>West Australian man Patrick Joseph Hunter stands trial over alleged rape of girl under 10</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/patrick-joseph-hunter-broome-district-court-trial/105996402</link><description>Patrick Joseph Hunter, 46, is facing a charge of sexual penetration of a child under 13 and four counts of indecent dealing with a child under 13.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f780d2e4c5a33126cb013ec0cd0c2da8</guid></item><item><title>Where Trump's lawsuits against news outlets stand as he threatens to add BBC to the list</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/trump-media-lawsuits-explained-bbc/105996302</link><description>The BBC could be the next media organisation to be sued by US President Donald Trump. So where do the president's other lawsuits stand?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fe0c29e9a92412a94b10325741a5108</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/tuesday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/105997428</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">882a5edd6dc3108a75e41a81b2203ca6</guid></item><item><title>Government announces increased police powers around masks, bans on certain items and symbols in protest crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/police-victoria-protest-mask-laws-violence/105997712</link><description>Stronger police powers tackling masks and face coverings, a ban on attachment devices and bans on certain flags and symbols are part of a suite of government reforms to be taken to parliament on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d3072a60360e673e56af2b702927e58</guid></item><item><title>Algal bloom exposes 'limitations' in government monitoring programs, Senate inquiry finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/algal-bloom-inquiry-limitations-monitoring-program/105996478</link><description>A Senate inquiry into South Australia's toxic algal bloom has been tabled highlighting "limitations" in how the government has handled the crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23f3187adba78b7e182fc4e1874b2d21</guid></item><item><title>When can a strip search be conducted?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/mint-730s-stripsearchesol-1111/105997878</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96891ae666f39b2e378cb9c2c272c3fb</guid></item><item><title>Bombing near Islamabad court kills 12, Pakistani Taliban claims responsibility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/explosion-pakistan-kills-12-dozens-more-injured/105998546</link><description>Pakistan's interior minister says a suicide bomber detonated explosives near a police vehicle outside the gate of a district court in Islamabad on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">406305dc3f6e3ef400c5a1481756a163</guid></item><item><title>Several ancient statues stolen from Syria's national museum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/ancient-roman-statues-stolen-from-national-museum-in-syria/105998652</link><description>Officials say at least six marble statues were stolen from the museum in Damascus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c380f16f7afa47c15713f758a154e83</guid></item><item><title>Turkish military cargo plane crashes in Georgia with 20 soldiers killed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/turkish-military-plane-crashes-in-georgia/105998794</link><description>Türkiye's defence ministry confirms 20 Turkish soldiers on board were killed in the crash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b80fe31380c4c6c9630c2ae485b7396</guid></item><item><title>Chinese 'cryptoqueen' fraud jailed in UK over $9b Bitcoin laundering scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/uk-crypto-queen-jailed-over-9b-bitcoin-laundering-scheme/105998844</link><description>British authorities say Zhimin Qian was the mastermind behind a Ponzi scheme into which around 128,000 people invested billions of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a90ea29d3a1517bfb56ab225e533758</guid></item><item><title>Princess Anne welcomed with open arms during Australian tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/princess-anne-australia-visit-signals-andrew/105996452</link><description>Whether Princess Anne's visit has been enough to repair the damage to the monarchy's brand wrought by Andrew Mountbatten Windsor remains to be seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bf56bc4aab3d7b926ae9082b8823f2d</guid></item><item><title>Future of three Victorian community hospitals up in the air as references wiped from government website</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/community-hospitals-torquay-emerald-hill-eltham-government/105985488</link><description>The Victorian government is refusing to say whether it will build three community hospitals that were originally meant to be completed more than a year ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99250cab819469edd23c4a1bee9da20b</guid></item><item><title>Spike in dolphin deaths at Huon Aquaculture pens prompts questions from Tasmanian regulator</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/huon-aquaculture-response-to-dolphin-deaths-salmon-pens/105991470</link><description>Tasmanian regulators question major salmon farm operator Huon Aquaculture about the effectiveness of its "predator" nets after a spate of dolphin deaths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d859cad498ca0936341476fc5e0e6629</guid></item><item><title>Nationals nominate hardliner for net zero talks as Liberals meet to settle position</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/canavan-to-join-net-zero-talks-with-liberals/105998148</link><description>One of the Nationals' most strident opponents of net zero will attend talks on a final Coalition policy position. Before then, the Liberals must decide their own stance — but conservatives are now confident net zero will be dropped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f0bdac6bb6fbfbdfaf0113e1e1a4b77</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley sees the Coalition's young voter problem but may not survive to offer solutions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/liberal-party-woes-attracting-younger-voters/105996134</link><description>The Coalition risks political extinction unless it can reconnect with younger voters who have abandoned it in droves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">766ce17d19ab5c6a20e7bab56577eccf</guid></item><item><title>Are 5 per cent deposits the leg-up first home buyers need, or are they pouring fuel on the fire?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/are-five-per-cent-first-home-deposits-pushing-up-prices/105979708</link><description>It will be some time before the full effects of the government's expanded first home buyer support scheme become clear, but young Australians across the country say it is still a tough market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">375eac2b3eaea97759c707a877b2e479</guid></item><item><title>Children aged 14 and above to face adult sentences under Victorian reforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/victoria-youth-crime-laws-adult-sentencing-court/105998434</link><description>Children aged 14 and above will face adult sentences in adult courts if caught committing violent crimes such as home invasions, in sweeping new reforms by the Allan government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50dd3183157b955adca6d8fe38bd5d96</guid></item><item><title>Michelle Foster's family feels let down by mental health and justice systems</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/family-of-young-mother-calls-for-systemic-change/105994636</link><description>Andrea Foster and her son Peter Spiniello continue to feel let down by a system they believe caused the death of their daughter, and sister, who was killed seven years ago by a mentally unwell man.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd09e4700083bec6a8037752230c598b</guid></item><item><title>Doctors defend emergency department triage policy as 'closing the gap in action'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/closing-the-gap-doctors-defend-melbourne-ed-triage-policy/105991086</link><description>Doctors and medical associations have backed a Melbourne hospital's emergency department triage policy to improve care for First Nations patients, describing criticisms of the closing the gap measure as 'opportunistic, uninformed'.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05bc8583091c7f58e798281d0cc3526c</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia accused of 'twisting facts' as former dictator Suharto named national hero</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/prabowo-gives-suharto-indonesian-national-hero-honour/105995984</link><description>Indonesian President Prabowo Subianto courts controversy by granting his former father-in-law, the authoritarian dictator Suharto, "national hero" status.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3f0855a41e8b8776e35d3da66453bdd</guid></item><item><title>Black Friday sales set to be biggest on record with shoppers spending billions on deals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/black-friday-sales-to-be-biggest-on-record-shoppers-hunt-deals/105997054</link><description>About 6 million Australians are expected to take part in Black Friday sales this year and on average they will fork out $804 each.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfe0cd9b1fca6eaa57b202b0c7c8f21a</guid></item><item><title>Leo relies on exercise physiology to keep him moving but that could change under NDIS review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/advocates-fear-ndis-review-cuts-to-exercise-physiology/105970108</link><description>Leo depends on exercise physiology to keep him moving, but there are fears that his progress could be halted under an NDIS review.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd9e61829bcc6512de4de29f5c895fea</guid></item><item><title>Farmers angry as Woolworths imports US butter in green and gold packaging</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/farmer-anger-over-woolworths-importing-american-butter/105738806</link><description>Australia's dairy industry is concerned a US brand, packaged in green and gold with a white colouring and bland flavour, looks as if it's locally made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddc50cf1dd93b51945b7377cafb0fe5d</guid></item><item><title>Genea patients want IVF giant held to account as cybersecurity expert raises ongoing concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/genea-ivf-data-breach-fallout-ongoing-cyber-concerns-raised/105984716</link><description>Patients of fertility giant Genea want the company held to account for a data breach earlier this year, amid concerns that some of its IT systems continue to fall short of best practice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc9c751eefe8d69c13408c4e8508ed58</guid></item><item><title>Joe Root a new player under Bazball despite previous Ashes struggles in Australia, says batting coach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/roots-pre-bazball-struggles-in-australia-irrelevant-says-coach/105998934</link><description>England insists Joe Root's lack of centuries in Australia is not an issue, pointing to the fact he has thrived around the world under Brendon McCullum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27fb0128ec0861a70973dde3e443797f</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Liberals have met to decide fate of net zero policy in closed-door meeting — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/federal-politics-live-blog-nov-12/105997816</link><description>The Liberals have met at Parliament House in Canberra after a marathon meeting to decide on the future of the party's net zero policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2b6368454f2fd5b5ca2d2c770957084</guid></item><item><title>Coral larvae released as part of research project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/coral-larvae-released-lizard-island-research-project/105998566</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fca6132ddf14eee56e1e9f2bf5ca3efb</guid></item><item><title>Scientists work to improve health of Great Barrier Reef during annual coral spawning event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/great-barrier-reef-coral-spawning-csiro-restoration-work/105997942</link><description>A thick cloud of coral spawn has blanketed parts of the Great Barrier Reef this week, signalling a key window for restoration work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f192d486efdd91769b29e8342201d593</guid></item><item><title>Outback graziers hope approach to tackle mesquite weed infestation is effective</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/mesquite-tree-weed-infestation-far-west-nsw-mark-facer/105983024</link><description>For the past 25 years the "king of weeds", Mark Facer, has been chasing and eradicating weeds. Now he has been called in to help graziers in far west NSW with the worst mesquite infestation he has seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">382661cbaa20f01d1cba3ae7edd725ea</guid></item><item><title>CASA warns of 'zero tolerance' for helicopter safety breaches in wake of Matt Wright trial evidence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/casa-warns-zero-tolerance-on-helicopter-rule-breaking-in-north/105996760</link><description>Australia's aviation watchdog has issued a warning to the sector, after accounts of widespread chopper rule-breaking were aired during the trial of Northern Territory croc wrangler Matt Wright.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e50510e27b904f589b88a6d38b93aee9</guid></item><item><title>Key independent Tasmanian MLCs concerned over Macquarie Point stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/tas-independent-mps-concern-over-stadium-before-vote/105998500</link><description>Two independent MLCs whose votes are crucial for the proposed Macquarie Point stadium have outlined their concerns about the project in budget reply speeches to parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c3c74b48c04e3ece282384bbb7a2e6e</guid></item><item><title>Beau Webster, Matt Renshaw shine in Sheffield Shield ahead of Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/webster-renshaw-send-timely-shield-reminders-on-eve-of-ashes/105999066</link><description>Beau Webster and Matt Renshaw remind selectors of their talents with stand-out performances in the Sheffield Shield on the eve of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bef79d3557c1983503e3488ea0eeab7d</guid></item><item><title>How WA's outgoing Chief Health Officer Andy Robertson once hunted anthrax in Iraq</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/andy-robertson-retires-after-extraordinary-career/105993126</link><description>For WA's retiring Chief Health Officer Andy Robertson, the 2020 spread of the "novel coronavirus" was not the first time he had been part of a story of global significance — and he also fears the next pandemic could be worse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcc8f28685ef0f3d9f1604a692a9f476</guid></item><item><title>SA Police search for driver in fatal alleged hit-run crash at Hillier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/sa-police-search-for-driver-in-fatal-hit-run-crash-at-hillier/105999118</link><description>Police said a 25-year-old man was struck by a car on Hillier Road at Hillier just before 8pm on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f11f5481c59fe5222544d1b0559515a1</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal team wins national award for suicide prevention work in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/alice-springs-team-wins-award-for-suicide-prevention/105996996</link><description>The Alice Springs team has been rewarded for its culture of listening to reduce high suicide rates in the Northern Territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a427e7c5370748aae1d3da18a9a965ad</guid></item><item><title>Macedon Ranges community honours Eleanor Bryant a year after fatal kindergarten truck crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/riddells-creek-eleanor-bryant-memorial-truck-crash/105998552</link><description>A foundation called The Eleanor Bryant Memorial Fund will provide scholarships to the next generation of allied health professionals from regional areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">816fe7422604d8ec37df4db66769c5b0</guid></item><item><title>Vapes reaching country towns across WA despite strengthened laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/vapes-reaching-country-towns-across-wa-despite-strengthened-laws/105997660</link><description>Despite a federal crackdown, shops selling vapes are popping up in regional areas prompting increased calls for education programs in schools.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ea41a7f4e962558255aaae5f284576d</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump asks Supreme Court to throw out E Jean Carroll abuse finding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/trump-asks-supreme-court-to-overturn-e-jean-carroll-verdict/105998988</link><description>US President Donald Trump asks the Supreme Court to overturn a civil jury's finding that he sexually abused writer E Jean Carroll at a Manhattan department store in the mid 1990s and later defamed her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be2d602724981032b016b8c696b38d0b</guid></item><item><title>Bunbury family distraught over Main Roads WA plan to remove 120-year-old tree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/bunbury-family-fights-jeffery-road-tree-removal/105991610</link><description>A 120-year-old tree is set to be removed to make way for a new intersection in the Bunbury suburb of Glen Iris, but a great-grandmother says she will be devastated to see it go.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">884022dbdc0ce197d965c5ec56c07aca</guid></item><item><title>Cristiano Ronaldo confirms 2026 World Cup will be his last with retirement looming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/cristiano-ronaldo-confirms-2026-world-cup-will-be-his-last/105999234</link><description>Cristiano Ronaldo says the 2026 World Cup will be his last as he plots retirement in the next two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccb538d2a83774a351e9fbb24b89df44</guid></item><item><title>Abuse lawyer slams WA government's decision to appeal Dion Barber's compensation for historical sexual abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/abuse-lawyer-slams-wa-government-for-appeal-dion-barber/105998046</link><description>A lawyer accuses the WA government of hijacking Dion Barber's $2.85 million compensation case for historical sexual abuse in a bid to "clarify law", instead of legislating it through parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f2bec6a802b90cb61a31e8360ed8683</guid></item><item><title>Jacinta Nampijinpa Price in 'urgent' pre-Christmas 2028 campaign fundraising drive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/jacinta-nampijinpa-price-family-community-nation-fundraiser/105997648</link><description>Northern Territory senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price is asking supporters to dig deep ahead of the festive season and help bankroll a $125,000 campaign fund three years out from the 2028 federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1151776cda33a1199e347578728413c0</guid></item><item><title>Russia loses High Court battle with Commonwealth over Canberra embassy site, but will be compensated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/russia-loses-high-court-battle-over-canberra-embassy-site/105999328</link><description>The lease was granted to Russia in 2008, but was withdrawn when parliament passed a new law citing ASIO advice that the planned embassy could pose a threat to national security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fa33004123ea22e28c6e843a3e8d33a</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur beaten by Lorenzo Musetti but still alive at ATP Finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/alex-de-minaur-down-but-not-out-at-atp-finals/105999526</link><description>Alex de Minaur's hopes of reaching the ATP Finals semis hang by a thread after a heartbreaking three-set loss to Lorenzo Musetti.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbcc2720ce1d32476c6e82e6baa4af76</guid></item><item><title>Spy chief warns of China espionage threat to business, critical infrastructure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/spy-chief-warns-of-china-espionage-threat-to-business/105999522</link><description>ASIO director-general Mike Burgess urges businesses to protect their data to prepare for possible attacks from hostile states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a8f55dd714b7b0654c89de15865c122</guid></item><item><title>Ruby Gold mango variety to hit Australian supermarket shelves this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/new-mango-variety-ruby-gold-hits-the-supermarkets/105996270</link><description>The Ruby Gold mango has been produced in commercial quantities for the first time and sellers say they are sure it will be a winner with consumers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">374acf8eaf43a8008c7f14a6aa0a7c25</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr scores twice in first club start in 692 days as Chelsea defeat St. Pölten 6-0 in the Women's Champions League</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/sam-kerr-two-goals-chelsea-womens-champions-league/105999572</link><description>Sam Kerr celebrates her first Chelsea start in almost two years by scoring a double, then declaring herself 100 per cent fit and "ready to go" for more game time and goals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d16cd916e7e3b464b6ee2321c26c4d4</guid></item><item><title>Thermal camera drone footage of fur seals at Seal Rocks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/thermal-camera-drone-footage-of-fur-seals-at-seal-rocks/105985896</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c96b13b35bb0384835ca80eb4330b16a</guid></item><item><title>Drones assist researchers in studying hard-to-reach wildlife</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/scientists-turning-to-drones-to-study-hard-to-reach-wildlife/105976234</link><description>Researchers are turning to drones to help them discover the health and habits of large marine mammals and other wildlife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d229a4295539442d7212dcac3c1c3318</guid></item><item><title>Hongqi Bridge partially collapses in southwest China just months after opening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/bridge-partially-collapses-in-china-months-after-opening/105999564</link><description>Video has been captured of the moment a bridge in China partially collapses with the structure becoming engulfed in plumes of dust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">010ae511948ec7689a22d4ad647ff3ad</guid></item><item><title>Good chance of aurora tonight, as two-year peak solar activity nears its end</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/chance-of-aurora-as-peak-solar-activity-winds-down/105983750</link><description>One of nature's most magnificent shows, the southern lights, could be on display for large parts of southern Australia tonight with a severe solar storm event impacting on Earth. But the boom in aurora activity will not last forever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3cddc2fcf384406017962a9570fa6ba</guid></item><item><title>Plane wing transformed into Sydney Airport memorial for young pilot Jake Anastas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/sydney-airport-memorial-for-young-pilot-jake-anastas/105995730</link><description>Jake Anastas, 29, died along with two others in a light plane collision last year. Now his memory is being honoured at Sydney Airport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4888eb8fc33eab1206fb66d11655c10a</guid></item><item><title>Coonawarra wine association apologises for 'disappointing' T-shirts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/coonawarra-wine-sorry-for-t-shirts-drink-more-die-younger-sa/105991132</link><description>The Coonawarra Vignerons, in South Australia's South East, has deleted a post which attracted controversy for celebrating binge drinking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">798a9d5ffba33ad340a755e3c6a23280</guid></item><item><title>Manjimup avocado growers celebrate abundance of 'unusual' avocados</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/south-west-wa-growers-of-quirky-avocados/105962558</link><description>Avocado growers in WA's South West say the oddly shaped fruit popping up on their trees may cause a few chuckles, but that does not affect the taste.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7c093a6d204f9fcb46e48b98dac6fa6</guid></item><item><title>Anthropologist under fire in Andrew Forrest's Ashburton River hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/andrew-forrest-ashburton-river-anthropologist-questioned/105995574</link><description>A lawyer for billionaire Andrew Forrest questions an anthropologist's credibility over his opposition to plans to change a sacred Pilbara waterway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e0f19680f582157c7a90bb348d5c75a</guid></item><item><title>Can we tackle climate change without net zero? Here's what it really means</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/what-does-net-zero-mean-and-why-we-need-it-to-act-on-climate/105996502</link><description>The Liberal shadow ministry has agreed to dump net zero by 2050 from the party’s platform. Here's what that term actually means.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a95411f87dca676fc98f698afe4a9102</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's Hellyer Gold Mine shut down over unpaid royalties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/tas-hellyer-gold-mine-closes-over-unpaid-debts/105999334</link><description>The state government has directed Hellyer Gold Mines to cease operations at its mine in north-west Tasmania. It says the company has significantly fallen behind on its debts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb08a561638cff454cc54663093f9deb</guid></item><item><title>Former construction union boss John Setka charged with threatening CFMEU administrator</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/former-cfmeu-boss-john-setka-accused-threatening-administrator/105999766</link><description>Police allege the 61-year-old sent threatening emails to the administrator of the construction union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e406427431c25bfa4c8b19582243f02d</guid></item><item><title>Toyah Cordingley's father gives evidence in trial of Rajwinder Singh, who is charged with murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/qld-toyah-cordingley-father-gives-evidence-murder-trial/105999862</link><description>Toyah Cordingley's father has told a jury he paused to rest under a tree during the search for his daughter when he noticed an "odd-shaped mound" at his feet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec68445b75038348bfc06e8533172052</guid></item><item><title>BHP ordered to pay miners $84,000 following Christmas holiday pay dispute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/bhp-labour-company-ordered-to-pay-for-employees-working/105999642</link><description>The Mining and Energy Union wins an appeal, arguing the mine operated for the pure purpose of profit over the public holiday period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c546ed4e403df01019e66ccf7d3a6f49</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast to host AACTA awards, festival through to 2028</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/gold-coast-locks-in-aacta-awards-festival-next-two-years/105996182</link><description>An Australian film and television awards ceremony that has attracted Hollywood heavyweights, including Margot Robbie, will be held in Queensland until 2028.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7910fab0c15d014386123b7dd273184c</guid></item><item><title>Wollongong council seeks $44,000 for removing whale drowned by shark net</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/whale-cost-cleanup-wollongong/105999632</link><description>Wollongong City Council wants the NSW government to cover the $44,000 cost of recovering a humpback whale that drowned in a Coledale shark net.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c544e2e166a1d444f213d0bf9723941a</guid></item><item><title>Claims secret gas decarbonisation report 'doctored' by WA government to support net zero narrative</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/claims-wa-government-doctored-secret-gas-report-for-net-zero/106000070</link><description>Last year the WA government commissioned a report on whether LNG exports to Asia were helping decarbonisation efforts — but the final report is vastly different to the draft, and analysts and activists say it has been doctored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d389da15c6ef2023f9a268d88c8acf9</guid></item><item><title>Australia suffers Ashes scare with Josh Hazlewood and Sean Abbott having scans on hamstrings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/ashes-josh-hazlewood-sean-abbott-assessed-injury-nsw-victoria/106000740</link><description>Josh Hazlewood's hamstring scare is not serious, but the news was less promising for fellow Ashes squad member Sean Abbott.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f9ad8466ec7dff59fb09c1166ac7968</guid></item><item><title>Seven people arrested after alleged police assault in Bega Vinnies carpark</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/seven-arrests-bega-alleged-police-assault/105999676</link><description>Three police officers have been injured after they were allegedly assaulted during a drug bust on the New South Wales south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c34faf2ff0c65be106c4e95703e25c81</guid></item><item><title>Two taken to hospital after collision at Nambrok in Victoria's Gippsland region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/princes-highway-crash-nambrok/105999934</link><description>A woman in her 20s suffered lower body injuries when her vehicle and a prime mover collided in Victoria's east this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28c9fb46192a610b43072c3ab2f0417d</guid></item><item><title>Japanese ambassador calls for security 'triangle' with Australia, US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/japanese-ambassador-calls-for-security-triangle/105999344</link><description>Japan's ambassador to Australia calls for the two countries to form an "equilateral" security triangle with the United States, while championing the role of gas in the clean energy transition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61c9831e8dc05dc32020f438b4dab3bd</guid></item><item><title>Not introverted or extroverted? You could be an otrovert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/what-is-the-personality-type-otrovert/105953010</link><description>Unlike extroverts or introverts, otroverts don't look outward or retreat inward to be energised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ce6d0bc0cf0337634cbe8abef79aaad</guid></item><item><title>Ben Stokes calls out 'has-beens' after criticism of England's Ashes preparations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/ben-stokes-hits-out-at-has-beens-over-england-ashes-prep/106000958</link><description>Critics of England's truncated preparation for this summer's Ashes Test series are off the mark, according to touring captain Ben Stokes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97714b0f46625e3bf5122080687a9d5d</guid></item><item><title>Three men to stand trial over Sterling Group's failed retiree housing scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/three-to-stand-trial-over-failed-sterling-group-retiree-scheme/106000456</link><description>Three men linked to a failed housing scheme which left retirees across the country with huge financial losses deny criminal charges levelled against them in a WA court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">144421202a6ecb0094ae051b9301c072</guid></item><item><title>National mental health agreement failing, Productivity Commission finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/productivity-commission-review-mental-health-agreement-failing/106000508</link><description>A scathing Productivity Commission review concludes that Australia's mental health system is failing and needs a rewrite, while warning that 500,000 Australians are unable to access the care that they need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c479d50ab0bbcffba7aa1d64120ea2bc</guid></item><item><title>Report reveals concerns about restraint techniques used in Adelaide youth detention centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/youth-in-detention-restrained-south-australia-report/106000630</link><description>Children and young people at Adelaide's only youth detention centre are being held to the floor in a restraint technique that "may constitute a breach of human rights and clinical best practice", according to a report tabled in parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b868a79e86a3b308b62ec9996c4d5bf</guid></item><item><title>Protesters clash with security at COP30 climate summit in Brazil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/protesters-force-cop30-summit-venue-clash-with-security/106001066</link><description>The incident caused "minor injuries to two security staff, and minor damage to the venue," according to a spokesperson for the United Nations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7548bde38b24b7272ea0063a5d5fb661</guid></item><item><title>Louvre heist 'detective' Pedro reveals inspirations behind viral look</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/louvre-heist-detective-pedro-talks-about-the-inspirations/105999952</link><description>Louvre heist "fedora man" Pedro Elias Garzon Delvaux says the inspiration behind his vintage look includes Agatha Christie's famed detective Hercule Poirot and James Bond.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afd8922057322a461605840adbe9591c</guid></item><item><title>Australia and Indonesia strike landmark security treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/australia-and-indonesia-strike-landmark-security-treat/106001570</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese declares a "new era" in the relationship between the neighbours in a joint appearance with Indonesian President Prabowo Subianto in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2864a5f23743e45c34f543b8a8d5a092</guid></item><item><title>Teenager faces sentencing hearing after pleading guilty to murder of Vyleen White at Ipswich shopping centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/qld-vyleen-white-sentencing-hearing-murder-ipswich/106000756</link><description>A young girl who watched on as a teenager killed her grandmother in an act of "indiscriminate violence" at an Queensland shopping centre says the 70-year-old was not "just a nanny".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e03a827c685e9ec3cb5ff42443fd1ed9</guid></item><item><title>Regulator suspends use of dimethoate insecticide on berries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/apvma-suspends-dimethoate-use-on-berries/106001530</link><description>Australians' surging appetite for berries has prompted the national farm chemical watchdog to suspend a popular insecticide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e3d695e8472d544953e7552938ce25a</guid></item><item><title>NSW Reconstruction Authority sells flood buyback homes for as little as $1</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/house-sells-for-one-dollar-at-flood-buyback-auction-in-nsw/106000336</link><description>Eleven flood buyback homes sell without a reserve price in the NSW Northern Rivers, with more to hit the market before the end of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b22530605e34112dada10d4f544c7a76</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Cup-winning jockey Jamie Melham suspended for 30 race meetings for careless riding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/melbourne-cup-winner-jamie-melham-banned-blake-shinn-race-fall/106002084</link><description>History-making jockey Jamie Melham has hit the headlines for the wrong reasons, with the Melbourne Cup winner banned for 30 race meetings for careless riding that resulted in a race fall for Blake Shinn.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">644ce65cc2a5c8a1124d4b53a8c736c0</guid></item><item><title>Recruitment data shows unemployment rate worse than official figures suggest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/data-shows-unemployment-rate-worse-than-official-figures/106001550</link><description>The October unemployment rate is crucial because it will either cement the RBA's decision to keep interest rates on hold, or cause more confusion about monetary policy. Early evidence points to a weakening jobs market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62be7b55d9d06400db4aefe6cea1c82a</guid></item><item><title>Two-thirds of A-League Women players experience 'psychological distress', PFA report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/a-league-women-players-pfa-survey-full-time-pay-mental-health/106002146</link><description>More than two-thirds of A-League Women players were in psychological distress last season, including experiencing disordered eating, alcohol misuse or disturbed sleep, according to football's players' union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2e34ce8099bb810027402ea83cd081d</guid></item><item><title>Inquest into death of Stanley Obi, allegedly set alight by former partner in murder-suicide, concludes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/stanley-obi-and-sarah-mudge-fire-deaths-inquest-evidence-ends/106001084</link><description>Stanley Obi, 33, died after his former partner Sarah Mudge set him and his then-partner alight. A coronial inquest hears he should have been asked if he was the victim of abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c391d2e3ae4427030142eb5c44cc9d47</guid></item><item><title>Man found not criminally responsible for murder of Ray McCormack in Wollongong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/aaron-lord-not-criminally-responsible-homeless-murder/105999992</link><description>Train station rough sleeper Aaron Michael Lord has been found not criminally responsible for the murder of Ray McCormack in a Wollongong stairwell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">899be91438af9062ffdddc98839fd468</guid></item><item><title>WA parliamentary committee recommends changes to state's proposed 'post and boast' laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/post-and-boast-law-parliamentary-committee-recommends-changes/106002498</link><description>Freedom of speech and peaceful protest could be under threat if WA laws to deter people from boasting about crimes are passed, a parliamentary committee finds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00f567d742b724c0d2618be18e9c3bba</guid></item><item><title>Queensland prisons watchdog report lays bare state of separation rooms at youth detention centres</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/queensland-prisons-watchdog-report-separation-rooms-dirty/106000548</link><description>The Inspector of Detention Services suggests separation rooms at youth detention centres — which have sometimes been found to lack basic amenities — are inhumane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48e6ec01c139238ef17658342c86f492</guid></item><item><title>Kyle and Jackie O escape prosecution over controversial comments during Erin Patterson trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/kyle-and-jackie-o-avoid-charges-erin-patterson-mushroom/106002620</link><description>Victoria's Office of Public Prosecutions says it will not lay contempt of court charges against the controversial radio hosts, who made comments about the Erin Patterson case in the middle of her trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea40b05b02d4da824edce7057d792e74</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Health issues alert after three measles cases attend Jelly Roll concert at Brisbane Entertainment Centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/qld-measles-cases-traced-to-jelly-roll-concert-at-brisbane/106002746</link><description>Queensland Health says the three infected people were at last month's concert of American singer Jelly Roll at the Brisbane Entertainment Centre and is warning others who attended to be alert for symptoms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44286258231058e48bdb396a170a4b83</guid></item><item><title>Four key takeaways from the Eddie Murphy documentary Being Eddie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/eddie-murphy-documentary-being-eddie-takeaways/106002068</link><description>Eddie Murphy has taken on many characters throughout his career, sometimes even within the same film. But a new documentary explores the "real Eddie Murphy" — someone the actor and comedian says few people actually know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">280b5b989c3c5928b1fa2cf85750ced7</guid></item><item><title>Bagpipers play tribute to AC/DC in world record attempt in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/world-bagpipe-record-melbourne/106002186</link><description>The biggest ever ensemble of bagpipers gathered in Melbourne's Fed Square to play tribute to AC/DC, smashing a world record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c13dd51f200037361951192672d0ed1c</guid></item><item><title>Macedon Ranges Mayor Dominic Bonanno caught drink driving in mayoral vehicle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/macedon-mayor-caught-drink-driving-speeding/106002772</link><description>Macedon Ranges Mayor Dominic Bonanno says he has been caught speeding and drink driving in his mayoral vehicle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72ddb623432a41e637e1a531a2fc2596</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Health warns hospitals to strengthen procedures around medical imaging results</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/queensland-health-checking-hospital-procedures-for-medical-scans/106002578</link><description>Authorities fear some patients involved in a medical imaging bungle have suffered long-term or permanent harm due to delays in receiving scan results and follow-up care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8554b8ea0f2e27bfe22e131d46b14b32</guid></item><item><title>Liberals still deciding fate of net zero policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/liberals-still-deciding-fate-of-net-zero-policy/106002484</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">432a33031d91fa96c510d8ee10bc831c</guid></item><item><title>Sawfish found with rostrum cut off on Port Hedland beach sparks anger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/sawfish-found-dead-with-rostrum-cut-off-port-hedland/105999948</link><description>A video showing a critically endangered sawfish lying dead on a beach with its saw removed is described as "cruel" and "trophy hunting".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a259fc62cf0dd402513d2b8847bf442f</guid></item><item><title>Ley to announce final position on net zero after Liberals clear path to dump target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/liberals-pave-way-to-ditch-net-zero-and-settle-infighting/106002684</link><description>Months of bitter infighting between Liberals over the party's climate policy could be drawing to a close, with MPs paving the way for net zero to be formally abandoned at a shadow ministry meeting on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf7a9bdcc4334fa3c2700e1dd53fc1a6</guid></item><item><title>WA Environmental Protection Authority gives expanded ferry network tick of approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/expanded-perth-ferry-network-gets-environmental-tick-of-approval/106003118</link><description>Western Australia's environmental regulator decides not to formally assess plans to expand Perth's ferry services on the Swan River, despite pressure from the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">808896e13c5ccf35512222056d2c1382</guid></item><item><title>Allegations against ex-Attorney-General Mark Dreyfus removed from Linda Reynolds action against Commonwealth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/-mark-dreyfus-allegations-removed-from-linda-reynolds-lawsuit/106001236</link><description>Linda Reynolds is suing the Commonwealth and its lawyers over the handling of Brittany Higgins' $2.4 million compensation settlement, yet has removed specific allegations against the former Attorney-General Mark Dreyfus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d9f795fe54bc791daae29b9ff315b0a</guid></item><item><title>Abortion legislation voted down in South Australian Parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/sa-abortion-voted-down/106001338</link><description>A new push to change South Australia's abortion laws to limit terminations after 23 weeks has been voted down in state parliament's Upper House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">978de31879380953a492acefc663c992</guid></item><item><title>Woolworths executive was hospitalised by 100-hour-a-week workload, lawsuit claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/woolworths-executive-ceo-lawsuit/106002948</link><description>The executive had a suspected stroke, went temporarily blind and was hospitalised five times after regularly clocking more than 100 hours a week on the job, according to documents filed with the Federal Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b293695cfdd1514f13196a402d3af58</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump writes to Israel's president requesting pardon of Benjamin Netanyahu from corruption charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/donald-trump-letter-israel-president-pardon-benjamin-netanyahu/106003278</link><description>Donald Trump has taken the extraordinary step of writing to Israel's President Isaac Herzog calling on him to pardon Benjamin Netanyahu of long-standing corruption charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ceb36373172580322103e399a3c88d8</guid></item><item><title>Alleged Myanmar scam kingpin She Zhijiang extradited to China from Thailand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/alleged-myanmar-scam-kingpin-she-zhijang-extradited/106003306</link><description>The US has accused She Zhijiang of turning a village on the Thailand-Myanmar border into a resort city "custom-built for gambling, drug trafficking, prostitution, and scams targeting people around the world".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61cf6cf07ee4b043917d2352b925b98b</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine suspends justice minister amid corruption probe involving top figures close to Zelenskyy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/ukraine-suspends-justice-minister-in-corruption-probe/106003334</link><description>After his suspension from the post of justice minister, German Galushchenko said in a Facebook post that he would defend himself in court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5442830c3b5c7dce32794ec00efca7d</guid></item><item><title>Jeffrey Epstein emails suggest Donald Trump knew about his sexual abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/epstein-email-says-trump-knew-of-his-conduct/106003452</link><description>Donald Trump has denied any involvement in or knowledge of the sex-trafficking activities of his former friend, and the White House has accused Democrats of peddling a "fake narrative".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d930d29d62ea58ef5d65e2c91b0a593f</guid></item><item><title>Cambodia and Thailand accuse each other of border violence amid reports of civilian casualties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/cambodia-accuses-thai-troops-of-killing-civilian-at-border/106003444</link><description>Phnom Penh has accused Thai troops of killing a civilian at the border, just days after a peace deal between the two countries was paused by Thailand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14fbbd46edd46f7e61d8a68fe19b7dac</guid></item><item><title>UK prime minister Keir Starmer insists team 'united' as rumours swirl of leadership challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/uk-prime-minister-starmer-under-pressure-leadership/106003496</link><description>Sir Keir Starmer is denying he authorised unnamed allies to brief the media about a possible leadership challenge, in a move that forced his health minister to publicly deny he was plotting against him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d22be23cab8c10eb22f47cf290abf531</guid></item><item><title>Australia's first treaty with Aboriginal people signed in Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/australia-first-treaty-agreement-signed-law-victoria/106002730</link><description>Leaders and activists say they are feeling the gravity of Australia's first treaty with Aboriginal people being signed and formalised as law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7daefd99fdc04d90d4b526ef0eac3025</guid></item><item><title>Liberals want to ditch net zero but IEA report says it's cheaper and cleaner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/net-zero-iea-world-energy-report-emissions-cheaper-electricity/106000244</link><description>The most authoritative snapshot of where the global energy transition is going has just been released at a most opportune moment for any politician weighing which direction Australia should pursue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6b2909ab35be7ff781035537a66173a</guid></item><item><title>Macquarie Point stadium goal at risk on eve of crucial AFL team vote</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/macquarie-point-stadium-angered-mlc-ahead-of-vote/106000534</link><description>While Tasmania's MPs will pass the proposed AFL stadium through the lower house on Thursday, it's become a much tougher task ahead to win over the parliament's key upper house decision-makers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b763cccba7f59652474450e31e89fda0</guid></item><item><title>Almost half a million households could be eligible for federal government's co-purchasing scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/tough-competition-likely-for-co-ownership-scheme/105996244</link><description>The Help to Buy scheme will open to applicants soon. However, new research finds almost half a million households could be eligible for just 10,000 places in the co-ownership scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">315f4b8009bd2f478631a36588c092c1</guid></item><item><title>Regulator raises alarm over insecticide use on blueberries, suspends products</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/dimethoate-insecticide-use-on-berries-not-safe-for-children/105997524</link><description>The federal pesticide authority has updated how the chemical dimethoate can be used on berries after new data confirmed skyrocketing consumption has been putting young children over the safety limit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfc2f5be1a339469b3ab32209e185163</guid></item><item><title>Prabowo Subianto's foreign policy hints at what Indonesia gains from treaty with Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/what-treaty-with-australia-means-for-indonesia/106002126</link><description>Details of an upgraded security treaty between Indonesia and Australia are yet to be made public, and the practical impact it will have on relations between the two countries depends on who you ask.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a720cabec95aaa3e76ef338c1093469c</guid></item><item><title>Sanjeev Gupta accused of deliberately losing phones in $US30m unpaid bonuses court case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/sanjeev-gupta-unpaid-wages-court-case-in-dubai/105995626</link><description>Sanjeev Gupta is gone from the Whyalla steelworks but his troubles are far from over, with a former high-level international executive who oversaw the South Australian operation now suing for US $30 million in unpaid wages and bonuses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96b7c840277d8886ce34ec230b43461e</guid></item><item><title>Some regional Victorian train platforms too short for six-carriage VLocity trains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/public-transport-association-calls-for-extensions-for-platforms/105862146</link><description>There is a problem with regional Victoria's top-of-the-line, six-carriage trains — they do not fit at more than a third of the state's train stations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca059bb3cdb06c10a8bc6dc7fed1fa23</guid></item><item><title>Army veteran walking around Australia for charity reported to police over assistance dog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/pub-calls-police-on-army-veteran-assistance-dog-disabilities-sa/106001482</link><description>Despite assistance dog Max wearing a vest and Garth Murray carrying his accreditation, they still faced illegal discrimination on a round-Australia charity walk, with one publican even calling the police on them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d84261b880f5ed152a3da9496ce4879</guid></item><item><title>Australians suffering 'irreversible complications' waiting years to see medical specialists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/australians-waiting-years-to-see-specialists/105991158</link><description>Some Australians are waiting more than six years to see health specialists, prompting doctors to warn that people are risking death while languishing on public waiting lists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ebb30e2d75c0e8d49fc24d09e4ecee9</guid></item><item><title>Scientists concerned for wellbeing of rare albino humpback whale that should be migrating south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/scientists-worried-for-rare-albino-baby-whale/105999974</link><description>A white humpback calf known as Siale is seen heading north along the NSW coast when most whales are searching for food in the Antarctic Ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cafb6ff24793357592eac04e2fe479d4</guid></item><item><title>Cody Schaeffer, youth advocate and radio host, charged with assaulting five people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/qld-cody-schaeffer-radio-host-youth-advocate-extra-charge/106000898</link><description>Cody Schaeffer is accused of assaulting five teenagers after police added a fresh charge during his first court appearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a81723abc2768904080193cfb952633</guid></item><item><title>Menulog is closing down in Australia later this month. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/menulog-is-closing-down-in-australia-here-s-what-we-know/106002740</link><description>The food delivery company is set to shut down on November 26. Here's what we know about the closure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba27820e3fe7fbdefec685f3d5482dd5</guid></item><item><title>Sri Lankan cricketers forced to stay in Pakistan despite Islamabad bombing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/sri-lankan-cricketers-forced-to-stay-in-pakistan-after-bombing/106003630</link><description>Sri Lanka's cricket board has told concerned players they must stay in Pakistan to complete a white-ball tour despite 12 people dying in a bombing in Islamabad earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c48edd60a86623631d60438c055dd11</guid></item><item><title>Photos: Aurora Australis puts on dazzling display</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/aurora-australis-in-photos-november-2025/106003620</link><description>One of nature's most dazzling shows was on display last night. Take a look at some of the photos taken across southern Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15274d4e3bdac9e182ee0a037593dbfa</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Liberals to dump net zero by 2050, shadow ministers decide — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/federal-politics-live-blog-nov-13/106002896</link><description>A meeting of Liberal shadow ministers ends with a decision to dump the net zero by 2050 target, following a party room meeting yesterday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bf9aa96e34f46bc22420cc01e0b792c</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn faces another AFLW finals exit in straight-sets as they struggle to recapture 2024 magic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/hawthorn-hawks-aflw-finals-struggles-by-numbers/106001276</link><description>Despite finishing the home-and-away season in fourth spot on the ladder — earning the double chance — Hawthorn has struggled to recapture the magic of its rapid 2024 rise and faces another straight-sets exit out of finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c06a7081a9012e58eff54b934560b7c</guid></item><item><title>Financial pinch leaves Winter Olympic hopefuls struggling to afford skis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/winter-olympics-paralympics-financial-reality-milano-cortina/105992034</link><description>A ski mountaineering athlete and trail runner by day and a DJ by night, Lara Hamilton scrapes for every dollar to finance her dream of becoming a Winter Olympian.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3543ef84fe5971a4692ebe4883f0dd47</guid></item><item><title>'Fortune teller' allegedly defrauds Sydney's Vietnamese community out of $70 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/sydney-fortune-teller-allegedly-defrauds-70-million-nsw-police/106003554</link><description>The 53-year-old told clients a "billionaire" was in their future, allegedly persuading them to take out financial loans before keeping a share for herself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95b6104999390bc6bf7564db9ee747a8</guid></item><item><title>ASX tumbles, Aussie dollar jumps as stronger jobs figures quash rate cut prospects — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/asx-markets-business-live-news-month-nov-13/106002198</link><description>The local share market takes another leg lower as labour force figures pour cold water on rate cut expectations. Look back on the day's financial news and insights from our specialist business reporters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b704e388b3a47972ec112b4444433dbc</guid></item><item><title>Taiwan evacuates 8,300 ahead of tropical storm Fung-wong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/taiwan-evacuates-8300-shuts-schools-tropical-storm-fung-wong/106003596</link><description>Soldiers rescue people in neck-deep floodwaters as heavy rains lash Taiwan, where thousands have been evacuated ahead of tropical storm Fung-wong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d0f332a45a3301c8019380ab13bc3f9</guid></item><item><title>Teen arrested after woman sleeping rough allegedly sexually assaulted near Mitcham Memorial Library</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/sa-woman-allegedly-assaulted-in-serious-attack-at-hawthorn/106003720</link><description>A teenage boy has been arrested after a woman was seriously injured in an alleged rape and assault in Adelaide's southern suburbs overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea3127e09612b6e7e59f37d15dcdd429</guid></item><item><title>Giant hail in Queensland prompts questions about national standards for solar panels</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/solar-power-panel-damage-giant-hail-queensland/105992850</link><description>Prue and Jamie Rogers were in the path of a savage pair of storms that wreaked havoc in south-east Queensland this month. They are wholly reliant on their solar system, but massive hailstones have left it in ruins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36c4742f3191450ed1ef4b5799af16ec</guid></item><item><title>Two eight-year-old girls with nowhere to go highlight Kununurra's social issues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/kununurra-youth-issues-community-wa/105975842</link><description>With young people in Kununurra making news for the wrong reasons over the last month, a police patrol shows the stark reality for children on the streets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2bf32446ba416f021a87b6542fd3305</guid></item><item><title>Missed last night's aurora australis? Here's when and where it's likely to put on a show tonight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/where-to-see-aurora-australis-lights-on-thursday-night/106002728</link><description>The skies lit up overnight with a spectacular light show by the aurora australis. But as the two-year solar peak period ends, tonight may be your last chance to see the southern lights for a while.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">903b457e19c1b2448ec328606f6959dc</guid></item><item><title>PR campaign to relocate Melbourne sculpture to Mildura 'profoundly silly' says artist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/vault-artist-says-mildura-council-pr-stunt-is-silly/106000354</link><description>The artist whose sculpture headlines a regional Victorian tourism campaign says it's a "beat up to get publicity".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f90494ebdbd8891dd2eb889a7b79f29</guid></item><item><title>Jeffrey Epstein mentioned Donald Trump in several newly released emails. This is what he said</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/donald-trump-epstein-emails-released-by-democrats-explainer/106003494</link><description>Donald Trump's relationship with Jeffrey Epstein is pushed back into the spotlight after he was named in several years-old emails unearthed by a congressional committee investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adf7c707f5828a38f2f8072a42fad25d</guid></item><item><title>Driver charged after fatal alleged hit-run crash at Hillier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/driver-charged-after-fatal-alleged-hit-run-crash-at-hillier/106003846</link><description>Police said a man was struck by a car on Hillier Road, Hillier, just before 8pm on Tuesday before he was rushed to the hospital where he later died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eef897127455db478b3e118ae2e7b2b</guid></item><item><title>'Nothing was being done': Inpex workers raise fears over toxic chemical emissions and oil spills</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/nt-inpex-worker-speaks-out-toxic-chemical-emissions-oil-spills/105965424</link><description>In the wake of a federal government investigation, a worker at major oil and gas company Inpex has spoken out, raising fears of exposure to dangerous air pollutants and claims of a toxic workplace where staff concerns are brushed aside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72d7516d4eb7404da59547d49860a406</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast police officer's pull-up world record marred by online abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/gold-coast-officers-pull-up-world-record-marred-online-abuse/106002472</link><description>Jade Henderson says she has been the victim of online abuse since breaking the Guinness World Record for the most pull-ups in an hour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4149567fb04d810b8380cfdb205ab657</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police raid 'fortune teller' who allegedly committed $70m fraud</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/nsw-police-raid-fortune-teller-/106003998</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b718cb3e4d6850079e3f3cbbad108fa7</guid></item><item><title>Drone footage shows parts of Taiwan's Yilan already flooded ahead of Fung-wong.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/drone-vision-shows-flooding-in-taiwan-s-yilan-ahead-of-typhoon/106004048</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00994921a0b63e010fc03af12670382d</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri set for test of 'character' as Formula 1 championship chase unravels</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/piastri-set-for-test-of-character-as-f1-season-unravels/106004050</link><description>Oscar Piastri will have to show "character" after his recent F1 disappointments says his manager, former Australian ace Mark Webber.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">185bc86379f1c98950b87c149ecd1e53</guid></item><item><title>More players involved in Shield, First Guardian collapses face ASIC legal action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/asic-action-financial-planners-shield-first-guardian/106004042</link><description>Corporate watchdog ASIC is suing several players involved in the collapses of Shield and/or First Guardian, which led to Australians losing more than $1 billion of their retirement savings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e02e958a47532c11d99bae21c39b572a</guid></item><item><title>Hervey Bay community comes together to protect Torquay caravan park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/hervey-bay-residents-protest-to-retain-popular-caravan-park/105999958</link><description>Fraser Coast council is weighing whether to transform a popular tourism site into a public green space, prompting a backlash from thousands of locals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4524b5fb886314058145b8e8e6b8272b</guid></item><item><title>Emails reveal former prince Andrew talked to Jeffrey Epstein long after claiming he cut contact</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/ex-prince-andrew-mountbatten-windsor-epstein-email-revealed/106004024</link><description>Newly released emails reveal former prince Andrew begged Jeffrey Epstein to ensure a strong denial of his involvement with alleged crimes was sent to a tabloid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59a9d24373bc9ddc67df36f09ae7e7db</guid></item><item><title>Country SA heavy metal band KNAW travels 800km for 40-minute gig</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/ceduna-heavy-metal-band-knaw-live-music-regional-sa/105948704</link><description>Heavy metal band KNAW dream of playing festivals one day. The problem is they are the only band of their kind around for hundreds of kilometres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf47b30f725e0d322c565fb9266fa729</guid></item><item><title>Century-old Hereward shipwreck re-emerges at Sydney's Maroubra Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/hereward-shipwreck-re-emerges-at-sydney-maroubra-beach/105999218</link><description>Shifting sands have re-exposed the Hereward shipwreck just metres from a swimming beach in Sydney's east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">912af1c55f23fe798f0335e596465215</guid></item><item><title>Australia's unemployment rate slips to 4.3 per cent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/australia-unemployment-rate-october-2025/106004258</link><description>The unemployment rate fell to 4.3 per cent in October, down from 4.5 per cent in September, as the number of people in employment increased by 42,200.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ea95ad4601ccbd38a4221fea181d289</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri says McLaren team orders in Monza part of 'perfect storm' for horror Azerbaijan Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/oscar-piastri-f1-beyond-the-grid-mclaren-team-orders-buku-gp/106004458</link><description>Oscar Piastri says the Azerbaijan Grand Prix weekend was the worst of his racing career and has hinted McLaren team orders may have played a part in it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e755fd4ddc8e03a3f390d739131d210e</guid></item><item><title>Teenager sentenced to 16 years behind bars for murder of grandmother Vyleen White at Ipswich shopping centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/teenager-sentenced-over-murder-vyleen-white-shopping-centre/106004406</link><description>The then-16-year-old stabbed the Queensland grandmother at a shopping centre in February last year as her granddaughter watched on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f8695cb4b7de4a727d6c70bc37546b</guid></item><item><title>Renowned lawyer returns to Wittenoom asbestos case that changed his life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/peter-gordon-returns-to-wittenoom-for-banjima-asbestos-case/105985052</link><description>Forty years ago, the Wittenoom asbestos disaster changed Peter Gordon's life. Now he has come back to finish what he started.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">719af9872fa6b48bf290168ce35cddbe</guid></item><item><title>Trump signs bill to end longest government shutdown in US history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/us-house-votes-to-reopen-federal-government-shutdown/106004314</link><description>President Donald Trump has signed a bill ending the longest government shutdown in US history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1debc3e842461de86313db9b26078fb0</guid></item><item><title>Neo-Nazi Thomas Sewell granted bail on charges relating to attack on Camp Sovereignty in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/neo-nazi-thomas-sewell-released-from-prison/106005212</link><description>Neo Nazi Thomas Sewell had been granted bail after a Supreme Court judge found he would not pose an unacceptable risk to the community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06cb887c41d15f58bf012990b94be701</guid></item><item><title>Stephen Fleming sentenced to 10 years in jail for manslaughter of Melbourne teacher Annette Brennan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/vic-stephen-fleming-jail-manslaughter-annette-brennan/106005066</link><description>Stephen Fleming has been sentenced to 10 years in jail for killing teacher Annette Brennan and placing her body in a wheelie bin in Melbourne's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcb5cf67a00140d99f42a43866bc9a9d</guid></item><item><title>Contact tracing underway in Queensland as health authorities brace for further measles cases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/qld-measles-cases-contact-tracing-underway-brisbane-outbreak/106003732</link><description>Health authorities expect to see more confirmed cases of measles in the next 48 hours as contact tracing into a Brisbane outbreak begins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5415b4e19b3e486e76faf7238f708ae</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of Qantas jobs to come to new innovation centre in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/sa-government-and-qantas-enter-new-innovation-centre-agreement/106005388</link><description>The South Australian government has entered into an agreement with Qantas for a Product Innovation Centre that is expected to create more than 420 technology jobs by the end of 2028.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25532d372d075308c19f9f1a51f1fe9e</guid></item><item><title>King of the Mountains trailer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/king-of-the-mountains-trailer/106005192</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f412b3ac7860dcbbe567a8d5cc6cd50</guid></item><item><title>Documentary follows William Corlett's week-long 500km Blue Mountains run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/king-of-the-mountains-william-corlett-film-award-nominations/106003624</link><description>A documentary following a young man's epic 500-kilometre run over seven days is nominated for awards at six international film festivals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">466d0584a88035f4046b0e319c1b7d5a</guid></item><item><title>Australia's spring weather swings from hot to cold and back again in battle of the seasons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/whats-behind-springs-weather-whiplash/105992540</link><description>From heat, back to snow, fire danger and storm warnings — spring weather has given the country some serious whiplash. What's behind it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5c158372e457aaf291ff3ded19f5c1a</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party formally abandons net zero by 2050 climate target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/liberals-ditch-net-zero-commitment/106003712</link><description>The decision brings the party closer to the Nationals, which ditched its support for the target earlier this month amid internal turmoil over the Coalition's policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">516c28d84fda6c53ba1f075cb109b65e</guid></item><item><title>Victoria will introduce adult jail sentences for children, but experts warn it won't fix youth crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/jacinta-allan-victoria-youth-crime-laws-analysis/106000376</link><description>The Allan government will mirror Queensland with harsher jail sentences for children, but experts say the new legislation will not reduce youth crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c49c4408113c5d29798d45ed1023de5e</guid></item><item><title>Eliza West fell out of favour with Melbourne. Now she's leading Hawthorn in finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/eliza-west-from-college-basketball-to-captaining-aflw/105999536</link><description>Eliza West is leading the Hawks on a finals charge in the AFLW, but it comes after a 'disheartening' call at the Demons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9579b204f2f937bcabd5d3bb70fafd68</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owner slams Andrew Forrest legal rehash over sacred Ashburton River serpent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/andrew-forrest-rehash-sacred-ashburton-river-serpent/106003212</link><description>An Aboriginal elder has slammed Andrew Forrest as a state tribunal into plans to alter a WA river hears critical evidence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d47a4af8af8119a1eb5ff068f1159ce</guid></item><item><title>AC/DC concert shakes Melbourne all night long with low-level seismology recordings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/acdc-concert-recorded-seismology-readings/106004408</link><description>Rock royalty AC/DC power up the earthshaking riffs at the MCG, rattling Melbourne with low-level seismic recordings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c004cdd6830f88266c85d795a1a3681e</guid></item><item><title>How Fully Sikh author Sukhjit Kaur Khalsa's life was shaped by slam poetry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/sukhjit-kaur-khalsa-blue-room-theatre-perth-fully-sikh/105117820</link><description>This year, Sukhjit Kaur Khalsa earned an Order of Australia medal and published her first book, Fully Sikh, all while running an indie theatre in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df7c0b1a399e19b25357f92f4e0ffaf5</guid></item><item><title>Rival and traditional Adelaide sporting clubs under threat by university merger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/rival-traditional-sporting-clubs-under-threat-university-merger/106002466</link><description>Sporting clubs from the University of Adelaide and UniSA face an uncertain future in an amalgamation process that has pitted some clubs against each other in the race to be a part of the new institute.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4621cedf2d5ccb36d09d20825ef759a</guid></item><item><title>Vote on releasing Jeffrey Epstein files set to go ahead as US government shutdown ends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/us-vote-on-epstein-files-release-to-go-ahead/106005544</link><description>As the longest government shutdown in US history winds up, a fresh bout of political infighting is brewing over the Jeffrey Epstein files.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61b2f581ed414e1862d33c9e1fa5405c</guid></item><item><title>Mezzo-soprano Joyce DiDonato, advocate for opera for all, on her first Australian tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/mezzo-soprano-joyce-didonato-talks-opera-for-all-australian-tour/105999456</link><description>Joyce DiDonato is one of opera's most in-demand mezzo-sopranos. She shares her passion for inclusivity and advocacy ahead of her first Australian tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c332620d823e87c0c78f29c1a5ddf16</guid></item><item><title>Shelby Cobra among a dozen allegedly stolen vehicles found in central Victoria police raid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/dozen-stolen-vehicles-found-at-regional-victorian-property/106005702</link><description>A $120,000 Shelby Cobra Roadster is found among a dozen allegedly stolen vehicles during a police raid in central Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">471865cc0040bd805b5a3162baabfbdf</guid></item><item><title>Justis Huni leads tributes for trainer Keri Fui after fatal collapse in gym ahead of boxing return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/justis-huni-leads-tributes-after-death-of-keri-fui/106006212</link><description>Justis Huni leads tributes for long-time ally Keri Fui, who died from a heart attack while training the heavyweight boxer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26371a553306ad9f6c84be036207d1cc</guid></item><item><title>Police used unreasonable force in fatal shooting of Bradley Balzan, coroner finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/coroner-finds-unreasonable-force-bradley-balzan-police-shooting/106004690</link><description>A coroner finds police used an unreasonable level of force during the fatal shooting of Sydney man Bradley Balzan, prompting sweeping recommendations to overhaul proactive policing practices in NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7f0cc390c9b5111de7d2a1098fcbae3</guid></item><item><title>Macquarie Point stadium order debated in Tasmania's lower house ahead of expected 'yes' vote</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/hobart-stadium-macquarie-point-debate-vote-in-lower-house/106004240</link><description>Tasmania's lower house has started debating an "order" to build the Macquarie Point stadium, with a vote expected to take place this evening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87f4840011ee0f8d204fa5c82f1bb377</guid></item><item><title>Jury in trial of Rajwinder Singh, charged with Toyah Cordingley's murder, shown photographs of boyfriend's hike on day of her death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/toyah-cordingley-murder-trial-cairns-far-north-queensland/106004464</link><description>Former Innisfail nurse Rajwinder Singh is charged with the 24-year-old's 2018 death in Far North Queensland. The jury has today been shown photos of her partner Marco Heidenreich's activities on the afternoon she died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cc629b0d269f0ae71bfaeb2104f8f38</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the ties between Donald Trump and Jeffrey Epstein</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/what-we-know-about-donald-trump-relationship-with-epstein/106004310</link><description>Years-old emails from Jeffrey Epstein mentioning Donald Trump have been released, raising new questions about the extent of their relationship. Here's what we know about the ties between them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f70546b19a3a7c57217a9ba6b87b3c7a</guid></item><item><title>Townsville mayoral candidate recruits lost tourist in exchange for lift to cruise ship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/townsville-mayor-candidate-joanne-keune-lost-tourist-campaign/106004700</link><description>Joanne Keune maintains the tourist says it was the best thing that happened to him in Townsville.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cac4ea4fb692737a9550380a15bd8083</guid></item><item><title>Shay Mitchell's new skincare brand for children sparks controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/controversy-over-shay-mitchell-rini-skincare-brand-for-children/105992902</link><description>A new skincare line for children by actress-turned-entrepreneur Shay Mitchell creates an online uproar, with many questioning the need for the products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70112c6a7088c70ed71b0d9c482e2db6</guid></item><item><title>Labor leader Josh Willie supports the proposed AFL stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/labor-leader-josh-willie-speaks-during-the-hobart-stadium-debate/106006636</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4e6ad7a516b2da8475ed8d04a616cdf</guid></item><item><title>Trump signs bill to end US government shutdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/trump-signs-bill-to-end-us-government-shutdown/106006856</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">147ee9928b3c102f2f3b78be4daa39ad</guid></item><item><title>Manslaughter charges dropped against Queensland couple over death of three-year-old</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/manslaughter-charges-against-parents-dismissed-townsville/105999420</link><description>Police drop manslaughter charges against a Queensland couple after the death of their toddler from a rare disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9a09e004c4744d651da9bac6bb20132</guid></item><item><title>Bribie Island officially reconnected as workers close breakthrough</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/bribie-island-breakthrough-officially-reconnected/106004404</link><description>Operators pushing tonnes of sand across a breakthrough at Bribie Island have officially closed the gap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c73fe9e941d9ce51ef6c1f321acebf42</guid></item><item><title>Rosalie Woodruff says the premier has not been honest with Tasmanians on the cost of the stadium.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/rosalie-woodruff-speaks-on-the-stadium-debate/106006966</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccdd8f57c0780d710e3746af5523470b</guid></item><item><title>Shire of Augusta-Margaret River doubles fines and looks at night restictions as part of illegal camping crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/illegal-camping-crackdown-margaret-river/106005144</link><description>A WA council has doubled fines for illegal camping and will look at locking people out of visitor hotspots at night, as it struggles to stop people staying in vans and tents at popular tourist spots.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69d576bd3b3ce2471d2cc2a3772aaa77</guid></item><item><title>South Australian woman wins four-year court battle over $104 parking fine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/sa-womans-parking-fine-court-win/106004454</link><description>A South Australian woman has won a four-year legal battle against an Adelaide council over a $104 parking fine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">282f27115382377ffb98fe1fa1f64dc6</guid></item><item><title>Independent David O’Byrne was critical of organised opponents of the stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/david-o-byrne-of-stadium-organised-opponents/106007228</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b0868fe09f64f394e5ad0e701b526dd</guid></item><item><title>Ley's net zero decision may bring her extra time as leader, but at what cost?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/sussan-ley-liberals-net-zero-albanese-politics/105978388</link><description>Ley's decision may have brought her extra time as leader. The question will be at what cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">959b320ef4cf2d7d6d8df53ed27fca63</guid></item><item><title>Cameron Green misses out on Sheffield Shield century on Ashes eve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/cameron-green-sheffield-shield-western-australia-queensland/106006362</link><description>Test all-rounder Cameron Green is dismissed six runs shy of a drought-breaking Sheffield Shield century, while Victoria coach Chris Rogers thinks he may have found Usman Khawaja's successor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b605595124ff0327c44008f0c566e2e</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man denied bail after high-speed chase ends with leap into Lake Burley Griffin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/act-man-denied-bail-drug-fueled-high-speed-chase-jump-in-lake/106006772</link><description>The 39-year-old will remain in custody after a judge rejected his request for bail to attend drug rehabilitation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0e96216a15920fd7383159a329f619c</guid></item><item><title>Unmasking the men who attended a Neo-Nazi protest outside NSW parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/unmasking-nsw-parliament-house-nsn/106005186</link><description>Around 60 men attended a protest at NSW parliament organised by the Neo-Nazi group National Socialist Network on Saturday. Without masks, it gave the ABC the opportunity to identify some of them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da7a1a09255ae470ca3f9e5c9a9da619</guid></item><item><title>Push to return 130GL of water to Murray-Darling Basin sparks backlash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/government-to-buy-back-130gl-for-murray-darling-basin/106007160</link><description>More water rights in the Murray-Darling Basin will be purchased from farmers and irrigators in a renewed push by the federal government to return 450 gigalitres of water to the environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db05f6316b25ed3745317d811840bfc3</guid></item><item><title>Jane Goodall farewelled in Washington, DC, Leonardo DiCaprio among mourners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/jane-goodall-funeral-washington-national-cathedral/106006984</link><description>The groundbreaking primatologist, who died in October, has been farewelled at a service in Washington, DC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d405826ead26b88875cf7804eb5498ac</guid></item><item><title>Growing evidence of secret taxpayer-funded boats for illegal foreign fishers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/fishing-boats-used-to-send-illegal-fishers-home/106005568</link><description>An Australian Border Force vessel has docked in Broome carrying four fishing boats, prompting anger from the fishing industry over a government scheme that gives illegal fishers boats to return home in.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b9163b8790e832a86acbd433652a510</guid></item><item><title>West Australian man Patrick Hunter found guilty of child rape, indecent dealings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/patrick-joseph-hunter-broome-child-rape-guilty-verdict/106001422</link><description>The 46-year-old committed offences against two children between 2019 and 2020, a Broome jury has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f68da5532a6443091f76bb2659d9841</guid></item><item><title>Thursday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-13/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106004868</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45d14807c1da154e7cc533fc32abf04a</guid></item></channel></rss>