<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2025 20:47:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>260 alleged fraudsters from African countries caught in Interpol's romance scam crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/interpol-african-romanc-scam-arrests/105823060</link><description>The scams targeted more than 1,400 victims who lost nearly $US2.8 million ($4.29 million).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c847a1b10d1899b3895a05e53e9be00f</guid></item><item><title>Latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/latest-financial-news/105823140</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a99f716d6cc9d9350073146aa3f0fa84</guid></item><item><title>Terrorism case against Kneecap rapper thrown out due to technical error</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/terror-related-charge-thrown-out-for-kneecap-band-member/105823280</link><description>Chief magistrate Paul Goldspring says charges brought against Liam Óg Ó hAnnaidh had been "instituted unlawfully and are null".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8acd24755cfcb7141862e52245519105</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu rails against foreign leaders at UN as Donald Trump flags Gaza deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/benjamin-netanyahu-walkout-united-nations-general-assembly/105823442</link><description>Dozens of diplomats stage a walkout at the UN ahead of the Israeli prime minister's speech, as US President Donald Trump says: "I think we have maybe a deal on Gaza."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35d9d0c0a30c9578b7d31b4dcbe35aaf</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese says Aussies are 'concerned' about far right's rise abroad, ahead of Donald Trump meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/anthony-albanese-says-aussies-are-concerned-about-far-right-rise/105819050</link><description>Anthony Albanese warns against the rise of populism and the far right ahead of his in-person meeting with Donald Trump next month, saying governments should "not seek to divide people".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26f76d3a7768af90f019f28385e9129a</guid></item><item><title>Australia's climate target doesn't eclipse today's tough questions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/climate-announcement-targets-emissions/105801294</link><description>As a nation, it's as if we're arguing about where to have a family holiday in 2035, and whether we fly economy or business. Meanwhile, nobody can agree on dinner tonight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4146131c7945d7a9befae50175a86f11</guid></item><item><title>Gulf states reevaluate US relationship as Israel replaces Iran as a threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/gulf-states-united-nations-general-assembly-donald-trump/105801292</link><description>The Gulf, along with Israel, will be wondering just how far Donald Trump really is prepared to push Benjamin Netanyahu.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e0e64a2d1db9bd1d64b2ebafe1d2ab8</guid></item><item><title>How Alliyah's community missed the signs of a female predator</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/female-child-abusers-hidden/105806706</link><description>Gender stereotypes "play a role" in allowing predators like Kellie Whiteside to fly under the radar, but that's not the whole story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5212f82642c02bf7652806df1582ca0</guid></item><item><title>The drug smuggling case of Japanese tourist Chika Honda and its parallels with Donna Nelson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/chika-honda-1992-drug-smuggling-case-australia-and-donna-nelson/105812710</link><description>A Japanese tourist who served 10 years in an Australian prison for drug smuggling offences sees her story reflected in the case of Australian Donna Nelson, who was sentenced to six years in a Japanese prison for smuggling 2 kilograms of methamphetamine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b06cef5818c953eb5ee9e418eeb4d004</guid></item><item><title>Soldier, Shakespeare die-hard, and the next Liberal leader? Andrew Hastie's week in the headlines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/andrew-hastie-liberal-party-leadership/105822510</link><description>The West Australian veteran has a clear vision for the future of the Liberal Party — and he's making it known.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c9cd9bedbb6ade58671fe793227f3da</guid></item><item><title>Geelong and Brisbane's AFL grand final meeting a clash of 21st-century titans 25 years in the making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-geelong-brisbane-grand-final-21st-century-titans/105817210</link><description>When they meet at the MCG on Saturday afternoon, Geelong and Brisbane are bidding for more than just the 2025 premiership. For the two most dominant clubs of a generation, true greatness is at hand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a8fca4f4487c82e1257eae08d6d9ec0</guid></item><item><title>Indians in Australia continue to face racist abuse one month on from anti-immigration protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/indians-racism-march-for-australia-protests-anti-immigration/105782222</link><description>Nearly a month after anti-immigration protests swept across Australia, some in the Indian diaspora say they are still facing racist abuse and constantly "looking over their shoulder".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50a690450fbc31f7c53d0d4ea03d629f</guid></item><item><title>When does the RBA meet next? Why aren't we expecting a rate cut?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/when-does-the-rba-meet-next-september/105805912</link><description>Cutting the cash rate results in cheaper mortgage repayments for most people paying off a home loan — but economists aren't generally expecting that to happen this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ceb26b9ef24d8699d82a621f37c5ebb</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files show flight with Prince Andrew and meetings with Elon Musk, Bill Gates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/epstein-files-six-pages-released/105823750</link><description>The documents include flight logs, massage messages and cash transactions in Jeffrey Epstein's ledger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f78ee953397b3a507669a6560c685081</guid></item><item><title>Sydney student compares his autism to 'limited edition Lego' in uplifting viral speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/sydney-student-leo-speech-on-autism-like-limited-edition-lego/105819812</link><description>Twelve-year-old Leo is the talk of his community thanks to a speech he made for his school's public speaking competition where he opened up about his neurodiversity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acbfc98d682b5458b7c616d84f85cb29</guid></item><item><title>Sydney schoolboy explains his autism and ADHD to peers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/sydney-schoolboy-explains-his-autism-and-adhd-to/105820440</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d120291fa023df6845d40764a23cb49</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with performing Nazi salute at AFL semifinal was former political candidate with history of racist posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/qld-man-charged-with-performing-nazi-salute-political-candidate/105815900</link><description>An ABC investigation reveals Tylere Baker-Pearce, a former political candidate who has posted a selfie smiling outside Auschwitz, was the man charged with performing a Nazi salute at an AFL game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30e54f094513d67b34962af67d4ac555</guid></item><item><title>The majority of Queensland councils are washing their hands of fluoridation under the watch of both sides of politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/qld-fluoride-water-supply-tooth-decay-politics-washing-hands/105820504</link><description>Attacks by Queensland Opposition Leader Steven Miles against Premier David Crisafulli over fluoride this week are more than hard to swallow after another local government's decision to stop adding the mineral to its water supply, writes Janelle Miles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3f79307107db030116e62bb5f9c648d</guid></item><item><title>Crocodile industry stakeholders urge Australian government to reform outdated code of practice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/code-of-practice-wild-farmed-australian-crocodiles/105821646</link><description>Thrust back into the international spotlight by the recent trial of Outback Wrangler star Matt Wright, questions are being raised about the Top End's lucrative crocodile industry and its outdated code of practice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5f0239291a3bab11069711c4f720cb3</guid></item><item><title>Best books out in September, from Ian McEwan, Patrick Ryan and Lee Lai</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/best-books-september-ian-mcewan-patrick-ryan-lee-lai/105805520</link><description>Wondering what to read next? This month's best books include the latest from literary giant Ian McEwan and Buckeye, a multigenerational family saga set in America's Midwest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0348b42f488a06fcaa90b607ac100204</guid></item><item><title>Retiring paramedic sounds alarm over plummeting job retention rate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/retiring-paramedic-sounds-alarm-over-low-retention-rate/105805372</link><description>Peter Maxwell and wife Rachel spent a combined 77 years as NSW paramedics, but they might be the last of a generation of lifers, with one in 20 leaving the workforce every year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ceb0b45376909c99278c668ab146956</guid></item><item><title>Persistent algae bloom causing political headaches as scientists are copping the flak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/algae-bloom-political-headaches/105821302</link><description>South Australia's algal bloom continues to cause political headaches for state and federal Labor. Perhaps that's why scientists are copping some of the flak now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4eda47c6abdb95b5e7cb1558c679e6d</guid></item><item><title>Nooramunga Land and Sea buys private islands to save them from development</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/non-profit-buys-bullock-and-little-dog-islands-off-vic-coast/105666678</link><description>For roughly the price of an inner-city apartment, conservationists have bought multiple small islands off the coast of Gippsland to protect their ecosystems and wildlife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c31e60140fdbcc5dfafc1267bf95eb5</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump warns 'there will be others' after James Comey's indictment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/trump-says-there-will-be-others-after-comey/105823804</link><description>Donald Trump expects more indictments to be issued against political figures after the former FBI chief was charged.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52700f3b187e6e4b599041821740bea8</guid></item><item><title>AI can't teach our kids to be curious and think critically</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/ai-revolution-classrooms/105756868</link><description>The AI dystopia might already be here but there are some things only humans can teach our children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a55b864c2b25cccc3569eb1e7b2df7c5</guid></item><item><title>Detailed designs of new lyric theatre inspired by Canberra's natural landmarks revealed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/act-new-lyric-theatres-detailed-designs-revealed/105823106</link><description>Detailed designs show plans for the new 2,000-seat lyric theatre, inspired by Canberra's natural landmarks, which will host major musicals, ballets and operas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32104f4565bc9ee2f42947c31b206b9c</guid></item><item><title>Is it worth moving to Tasmania for the cooler climate?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/moving-tasmania-climate-positives-and-negatives/105815096</link><description>Each of these eight families left the mainland in search of Tasmania's cooler, milder climate. But with challenges like health care, transport and limited services, do they have any regrets over the decision?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe4bcc9ccaae6e62bab1625ddabe94d0</guid></item><item><title>Conservation notice issued for alleged native vegetation clearing at Chittering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/dwer-issues-notice-over-alleged-native-tree-clearing-chittering/105807210</link><description>Western Australia's environmental regulator has issued a property owner with a vegetation conservation notice for the alleged clearing of a significant amount of native trees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a73ca93c90bcc1f5bb19f601570855d0</guid></item><item><title>Wool price soars as production crashes and Chinese demand lifts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/australian-wool-price-three-year-high-as-china-demands-rises/105819768</link><description>Australian wool prices lifted sharply this week for a few reasons, including a shrinking amount of wool being produced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58344a18424792f395eadbda8b6e6d6b</guid></item><item><title>Investigations continue after several Launceston General Hospital staff reported feeling nauseated and faint</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/launceston-general-hospital-incident-staff-reported-feeling-sick/105823900</link><description>Tasmania Police initially said the incident at the Launceston General Hospital was potentially a gas leak, but the Tasmania Fire Service later said it did not detect any gas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4fc62e9e3e20ebfcf52e8625114d8d6</guid></item><item><title>UN sanctions 'unfair, unjust and illegal', says Iran's president</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/iran-says-un-security-council-sanctions-unfair/105823898</link><description>The UN Security Council rejects another last-ditch effort to delay the reimposition of sanctions on Iran over its nuclear program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff1a6a0c02c16e1d84e6b2947a01c58c</guid></item><item><title>Police reveal link between man and woman found dead in New South Wales home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/police-investigate-after-two-bodies-found-in-coffs-harbour/105823928</link><description>Police found the bodies of a man and woman in their 60s when doing a welfare check at a Coffs Harbour property on Friday evening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47e234f9b8ecd79651a27ee1302b040c</guid></item><item><title>Gladstone Strollers walking group creates a village for postpartum mums</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/postpartum-mum-walking-group-mental-health-benefits/105820070</link><description>A Queensland mum desperate to have a positive postpartum experience when she had her second child found that just a few small steps were enough to make a huge difference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4aabdb9b02f032a6f0dfa2b02445682e</guid></item><item><title>WA teenager starts petition for shearing to be in Brisbane 2032 Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/wa-teen-starts-petition-for-shearing-to-be-in-the-olympics/105721670</link><description>We saw break dancing added to the Olympic program for the Paris Games, and now there is a push for shearing to be included for the Brisbane Olympics in 2032.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ce5973b6762c550d39695066a2eff91</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final 2025: Brisbane Lions thump Geelong Cats by 47 points, Will Ashcroft wins Norm Smith Medal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grand-final-2025-geelong-vs-brisbane-live-blog/105822258</link><description>Brisbane secures its second straight AFL premiership, taking control in the final quarter of an otherwise gripping grand final against Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ca0c766669a84c1c64d308b07e389c</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Storm Bualoi sweeps through Philippines leaving 10 dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/tropical-storm-bulaoi-philippines-flood-corruption/105823944</link><description>The death toll from a tropical storm that swept across the central Philippines and southern Luzon has risen to 10, as the country's north continued recovering from Super Typhoon Ragasa.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2df415b803d0ecbfbe0362606b7d507</guid></item><item><title>Fortescue offers measles vaccine boosters after Christmas Creek outbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/fortescue-measles-vaccine-boosters-christmas-creek-outbreak/105820426</link><description>Iron-ore giant Fortescue says it will offer vaccine boosters after three measles cases were confirmed at its Pilbara mine earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26e09d8753cc469c42fac166c15b08d3</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government investigating 'bungled IT system' which may have led to child safety information going missing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/qld-government-it-error-child-safety-department/105823978</link><description>Queensland's child safety minister is warning missing information could have serious consequences, including the death of a child.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfd0e5e2f585c511b044243e54e5ff89</guid></item><item><title>Cyclist on a gruelling journey to fight for a better future for people with dementia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/nic-tremaine-cycling-around-australia-dementia-fundraising-trip/105730642</link><description>Nicholas Tremaine is cycling more than 40,000 kilometres to raise $1 million to fight the condition that's befallen his mother and is now Australia's leading cause of death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08add1d8f7252bd94b473e9688d5ae02</guid></item><item><title>Clive Palmer ordered to pay more than $13 million after foreign investor claim dismissed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/clive-palmer-foreign-investor-claim-dismissed/105823966</link><description>The decade-long dispute was related to WA government legislation, which impeded Clive Palmer's ability to extract damages over the Balmoral South Iron Ore Project in the Pilbara.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b97d0fa74d42a0e0aad8a2eb639f05fe</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous teenager teaches Paakantyi language to teachers at Menindee school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/aboriginal-paakantyi-language-teacher-outback-nsw-school/105815440</link><description>Jaz Fusi has been passionate about learning Paakantyi language for most of her life. Now, she teaches it to her local school's teachers and is eager to see other kids do the same.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffc9b2d6c78f4e662e2f96fe4e5bf8a9</guid></item><item><title>WA government facing $400m cost blowout over Peel Health Campus redevelopment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/peel-health-campus-cost-blowout/105824094</link><description>The long-awaited redevelopment of Peel Health Campus is facing a $400 million cost blowout and potential delays, a leaked document reveals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7295950907094099603d65d0a0b06af</guid></item><item><title>All Blacks edge brave Wallabies to retain Bledisloe Cup for 23rd year at Eden Park, Morgan Turinui rants at referee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/live-updates-all-blacks-vs-wallabies-bledisloe-cup-in-auckland/105816056</link><description>The All Blacks have beaten the Wallabies 33-24 at Eden Park, extending their 39-year and counting winning record against Australia at the Auckland venue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13406db2d00d984b62fdf93c8404b3c6</guid></item><item><title>More outdoor live entertainment for NSW after changes to 'outdated' development applications</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/nsw-removes-development-applications-live-outdoor-events/105823902</link><description>Using outdoor public spaces for events and venues has been made easier in NSW under changes to development applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">900baaaf0953e92e8c0b8d4aa1fae752</guid></item><item><title>Relationship experts on the signs that it may be time to call it quits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/signs-it-might-be-time-to-end-a-relationship/105675792</link><description>If you are feeling indifferent about your relationship, have high conflict, or just don't really enjoy their company anymore, it is possible the partnership has reached its end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">499d5b97aa70d0462b93fa23afce5eb8</guid></item><item><title>Snoop Dogg, Baker Boy and Tash Sultana star in AFL grand final entertainment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/snoop-dogg-afl-grand-final-entertainment-mcg/105819406</link><description>The legendary rapper delivered a squeaky clean performance, incorporating local artists and a didgeridoo in a trip through his catalogue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">520a21469afd2968627cca416d5cdb69</guid></item><item><title>Matt Wright's lawyers reveal five grounds of appeal for Netflix star's guilty verdict, including allegation against judge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/matt-wright-five-grounds-of-appeal-revealed/105824618</link><description>Matt Wright's lawyers have revealed the five grounds they are seeking to appeal their client's guilty verdict on, including an allegation that the judge made an "impermissible comment to the jury".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45adde7e87d9110419b85a7a1e1c1ee1</guid></item><item><title>How the internet reacted to the Brisbane Lions winning the AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/internet-reacted-afl-grand-final-brisbane-lions-geelong-cats/105802198</link><description>Brisbane completed an historic back-to-back premiership, beating a wounded Geelong at the MCG, and the internet followed along with every kick.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b68c6dfe98a3f3cc3b923023a51e2931</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane's back-to-back AFL grand final wins suggest we could be back in a 'Lions era'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/brisbane-lions-defeat-geelong-in-grand-final-in-new-era/105824588</link><description>The Lions successfully defended their premiership to go back-to-back, and pose the question: Are we back in a Lions era?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7311d26402f791ca2c79be844c093f2</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final quick hits: Lions' Lachie Neale gamble pays off, Cats' Jeremy Cameron in the wars, and it's Country Road time at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grand-final-quick-hits-geelong-cats-brisbane-lions/105821966</link><description>Brisbane's gamble on Lachie Neale's fitness pays off with a team-lifting goal, a brave Jeremy Cameron has a painful day out, and Charlie Cameron's goals provide a Country Road soundtrack at the MCG. Here are the quick hits from the 2025 AFL grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef10be159c2c5da37bc2677e999bc6a9</guid></item><item><title>White House releases photo of Donald Trump and Anthony Albanese</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/albanese-trump-photo/105824944</link><description>A photo of a smiling Donald Trump, alongside Anthony Albanese, his fiancée Jodie Haydon and US First Lady Melania Trump, has been released by the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff4eec3691a0dfeed959566549f25d32</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese meets with King Charles at Balmoral Castle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/anthony-albanese-meets-king-charles-balmoral-castle/105825036</link><description>King Charles III has received Prime Minister Anthony Albanese in a royal audience held at Balmoral Castle in Scotland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6937ee0e6be00561e8724ba711d45b9</guid></item><item><title>Chinese presence in the Pacific runs deep and is now reshaped by Beijing's ambitions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/china-pacific-islands-untold-story-chinese-geopolitics-influence/105818894</link><description>China's presence in the Pacific is often viewed in the context of geopolitical tension and rivalry. But Chinese people have been in the region for generations — these are their stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6598aaeafdf808048e2ae2838622179b</guid></item><item><title>Geelong's strength-in-numbers approach fails its biggest test in AFL grand final loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/afl-grand-final-geelong-cats-brisbane-lions-analysis/105824608</link><description>It is the cruel irony of sport that what is usually the ace up Geelong's sleeve proved to be its downfall in the loss to the Brisbane Lions in the season decider.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1face944653c3d1f368bbbf10b8ded7</guid></item><item><title>As Australia's retirement savings grow into world's second biggest, government to review consumer protections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/as-australian-retirement-savings-grow-greater-regulation-needed/105820684</link><description>Compulsory super has led to higher levels of national savings, but, as the pool of savings grows, many argue that stricter supervision is needed to protect Australians' retirement savings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">727169d9557e7aa1856d8b008f7d6fd7</guid></item><item><title>When it comes to love, more of us are crossing the religious divide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/more-australians-are-marrying-across-the-religious-divide/105779468</link><description>Exclusive data for 5.2 million couples shows nearly one in five marriages are between people of different religions – double the proportion recorded in 1986.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">013dc6d1c3729b713228afd937c045d6</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz Kids: Tom Gleeson's back to put Australia's pint-sized hot shots in their place</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/hard-quiz-kids-weekly-trivia/105773368</link><description>The grump's back to take on the grommets in a new series of Hard Quiz Kids. Don't let the pint-sized know-it-alls show you up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a862981fd7047144319126295a5f472</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump will send troops to 'war-ravaged' Portland, in latest deployment to US cities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/trump-orders-deployment-of-troops-to-portland-ice-facilities/105825548</link><description>The military says it is ready to mobilise as Donald Trump authorises "full force" to protect federal immigration facilities from "domestic terrorists".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7bbd1ebd2ce3c0d838911445a763b29</guid></item><item><title>Guy Sebastian reflects on Titus Day legal case and the lesson he's learned from fans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/guy-sebastian-the-assembly/105671828</link><description>Guy Sebastian opens up about the fan encounter that made him "burst into tears" and a court case with his former manager, Titus Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d1fceb0fd7d9b21cd61a61a6b4f7281</guid></item><item><title>Roosters on cusp of perfect NRLW season after beating Sharks 17-16</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/nrlw-preliminary-final-sydney-roosters-cronulla-sharks/105825564</link><description>Jocelyn Kelleher is relishing the chance to prove her credentials as the Sydney Roosters look to claim back-to-back premierships for the first time in their history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c98d6e82e7da5e596aaac09a0d982f4d</guid></item><item><title>Woppaburra people welcome ancestor's return but face final hurdle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/woppaburra-peoples-fight-to-get-ancestor-home/105788102</link><description>More First Nations remains are being returned to Australia from international institutions, but these Woppaburra men say laying them to rest on country can prove a fresh challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f2752aea82ec37f1fac83229df02a1</guid></item><item><title>England defeats Canada 33-13 in Women's Rugby World Cup final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/rugby-world-cup-final-england-defeats-canada/105825580</link><description>In front of a record crowd of more than 80,000 spectators, England delivers on the biggest stage with a 33-13 defeat of Canada in the tournament decider at Twickenham.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62fcacd86e45554323ddd632300502bc</guid></item><item><title>A small win for beachgoers and gardeners as washed-up sea life turned to compost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/algal-bloom-dead-sea-life-turned-to-compost/105807488</link><description>Dead sea life washed ashore during SA's marine algal bloom has been diverted into commercial compost for farms and gardens, in what has been viewed as a small win amid the large-scale devastation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4b9a8f084b8a14c310d2e1372a86ca2</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's coal royalty regime back in the spotlight after job cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/qld-coal-mine-royalties-regime-questioned-after-job-cuts/105818488</link><description>Despite a change of government, Queensland's controversial coal royalty scheme remains in place and recent job cuts are prompting renewed discussion about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05fc998cc23e435b2b1e012ba6d8ab22</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane and Geelong fans experience the ecstasy and agony of AFL's biggest game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/afl-grand-final-lions-and-cats-fan-reactions/105824822</link><description>For the second year in a row, Brisbane Lions fans were celebrating in the streets as their team claimed the premiership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6337aba73bc17913cc11052d6f937e4</guid></item><item><title>Russian Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov warns NATO, Europe that aggression will be met with a 'decisive response'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/russian-foreign-minister-sergey-lavrov-warns-nato-europe-at-unga/105825572</link><description>While Russia does not intend to attack Europe, its Foreign Minister Sergey Lavrov has not ruled out action against NATO aggression.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0368cfa881bd50ea3b87763fb766242f</guid></item><item><title>Lions AFL coach Chris Fagan vindicated with Lachie Neale sub call in grand final win over Cats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/afl-grand-final-brisbane-lions-chris-fagan-lachie-neale/105825616</link><description>Brisbane Lions coach Chris Fagan admits he took a punt by naming Lachie Neale as the sub ahead of their stunning win over Geelong in the grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">356d4d2bcf5d986dedc6cb7aff32d029</guid></item><item><title>Feral pigs illegally brought into SA from NSW, DNA testing confirms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/dna-testing-finds-feral-pigs-illegally-brought-into-sa-from-nsw/105806616</link><description>Dozens of pigs were released illegally over several attempts to establish populations for hunting, with a local landscape board warning of the danger a feral population could cause.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1875e7c11aebd493798a84587badd76b</guid></item><item><title>Rod Barwick has international fame as a daffodil breeder, but what matters to him is a love of gardening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/rod-barwick-daffodil-breeder-glenbrook-bulb-farm/105803774</link><description>Rod Barwick planted his first daffodil bulbs in the 70s. Within a few years, he began breeding daffodils and has since been recognised internationally for his work — but he says enjoying growing plants is the most important part of gardening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca3f901a514528002a7c6ff54fe81d6c</guid></item><item><title>Thirty years ago, Oasis made (What's The Story) Morning Glory? — a Britpop blockbuster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/oasis-morning-glory-30-years-anniversary-review-reunion/105816312</link><description>They'll soon tour Australia, but 30 years ago, Oasis were about to release (What's The Story) Morning Glory? — an enduring British rock classic. Here's how they did it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0332a614c6ebdac441c971670d46b82b</guid></item><item><title>Moment Brisbane Lions win 2025 AFL premiership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/moment-brisbane-lions-win-2025-afl-premiership/105825768</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb7106de6f4f1cb4bf66109d660b5cd7</guid></item><item><title>Ten-year-old mini bull rider from Cape York takes on world's best in Utah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/10-year-old-mini-bull-rider-competes-at-world-finals-in-utah-us/105817314</link><description>In a huge dark hat and shining belt buckle, a 10-year-old from Cape York proves he can mix it with the best at the world finals in Utah.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da9e4e8bec951353c341a9189fe44a20</guid></item><item><title>Dhakiyarr Wirrpanda's family in calls for fresh probe into mystery disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/nt-missing-yolngu-man-cold-case-police-killing-confession/105581636</link><description>The family of vanished Yolŋu leader Dhakiyarr Wirrpanda is calling on the Northern Territory coroner to pursue an ABC investigation's lead on his mysterious disappearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66e217a67165888621851fab3aed8814</guid></item><item><title>No word on Donald Trump's Israel ceasefire plan, says Hamas, as Gaza City attack intensifies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/no-word-on-donald-trump-s-israel-gaza-ceasefire-plan-says-hamas/105825646</link><description>Israeli strikes and gunfire have killed at least 50 people across Gaza in the past day, according to health officials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12b8f0064319e5abeac9916476b5a13a</guid></item><item><title>No subscriptions? No problems! Here are the best movies and TV series you can watch for free</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/where-to-watch-movies-tv-for-free/105809908</link><description>From family favourites to Australia's most controversial soap opera, here's some of the best movies and TV you can watch right now — no fee required!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1dd880d77579b98d0407d4f5c96f4df</guid></item><item><title>Kununurra's Barra Bash barramundi competition underway as restocking solution sought</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/barramundi-stocking-concerns-at-barra-bash-in-kununurra/105815558</link><description>More than 1,000 fishers hope to reel in a winning catch at Lake Kununurra, where a restocking program and ideal conditions have grown record-size barramundi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">923bf257f99baf7de30b4c08ce60dcfd</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese coy on critical minerals offer ahead of meeting with Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/albanese-offer-trump-critical-minerals/105825654</link><description>The prime minister would not say exactly what Australia's critical minerals offer to the United States included — nor whether it was exclusive to the Trump administration, after he discussed the issue with his British counterpart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d440be41b2395718c9785786a4c0dfc</guid></item><item><title>Lions show they're the complete team by beating Cats to claim second straight AFL premiership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/afl-grand-final-lions-cats-analysis/105827470</link><description>With contributors across the board, the Brisbane Lions clinically dismantled Geelong to show last year's premiership victory was no fluke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fe484cf746759bffa0be4bf28fe5c9d</guid></item><item><title>It's OK on the Macleay poster vandalism prompts calls for queer acceptance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/calls-for-queer-visibility-after-vandalism-at-pride-festival/105811572</link><description>A regional queer community says acceptance is improving in regional areas, but vandalism targeting an LGBTQI+ event shows there is still a way to go.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57d4bd6f43f48e213b4f3691a470e868</guid></item><item><title>More than 30 people dead in stampede at political rally for popular Indian actor Vijay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/india-rally-tamil-nadu-stampede-vijay/105825744</link><description>Eight children and 16 women were among those who died at the political rally for Vijay — who is campaigning for election after becoming one of his state's most successful actors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ed5fa9cbd33f3641044de5d8208fef0</guid></item><item><title>Selena Gomez marries music producer Benny Blanco in star-studded ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/selena-gomez-announces-marriage-to-benny-blanco/105827466</link><description>Singer, actor and beauty mogul Selena Gomez marries music producer Benny Blanco, with US media reporting Taylor Swift was in attendance at the star-studded affair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97200a44d196247f24b3ee1a047dc883</guid></item><item><title>Fixable 20th-century gadgets stand test of time in era of disposable tech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/old-electrical-appliances-made-to-be-fixed-and-still-performing/105791190</link><description>Analogue TVs, cameras and film projectors are just some of the items with sentimental value people fix rather than replace — and unlike much of today's technology, they were made to be repaired.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e71f9b54ca5badafa08edabe6ce69991</guid></item><item><title>Astronaut Katherine Bennell-Pegg says studying space will help Australia manage bushfires, floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/astronaut-katherine-bennell-pegg-study-space-bushfires-floods/105827566</link><description>With Sydney to play host to the world's largest space conference this coming week, Katherine Bennell-Pegg says it is more important than ever to highlight the benefits of growing Australia's space workforce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a22b012cfec7d5326f72f355ce13a7aa</guid></item><item><title>The benefits and risks of sleeping next to your dog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/the-benefits-and-risks-of-sleeping-next-to-our-dogs/105774468</link><description>While there are several benefits to keeping our pets close at night, there are a few minor risks to consider.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">932ca557de76cc1cae410a853cede833</guid></item><item><title>Colombian leader Gustavo Petro accuses US of violating international law after visa revoked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/colombian-president-us-visa-revoked/105827698</link><description>Colombian President Gustavo Petro accuses the US of violating international law after it revoked his visa following his criticism of Israel's actions in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c54d48f9f3fb2902500baf156ff15c30</guid></item><item><title>Crippling UN sanctions on Iran come into effect as Tehran warns of harsh response</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/un-reinstates-sanctions-on-iran/105827774</link><description>United Nations sanctions on Iran over its nuclear program are reimposed after a last-minute diplomatic push fails.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23d485401e55e67c2f4014dcbdce23c5</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos beat Penrith Panthers to reach NRL grand final as Adam Reynolds kicks game-winning conversion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/nrl-finals-live-updates-brisbane-broncos-penrith-panthers/105780678</link><description>Adam Reynolds nails a sideline conversion with three minutes left to send the Broncos into the NRL grand final and end Penrith's dynasty with a 16-14 win at Lang Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2dae682e54f4bfe7bd10f04e9f859f9</guid></item><item><title>New WA drivers face stricter rules including extra supervised hours, longer probation and limited phone use</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/tougher-rules-proposed-wa-young-drivers-/105827684</link><description>New drivers face tougher regulations in WA including extending their probation period, increasing their supervised hours and limiting phone use under a proposed plan by the state government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3adf09313969902c49773cd0558d56d6</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate death of man at Brisbane shopping centre in early hours of Sunday morning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/brisbane-man-found-dead-at-shopping-centre/105827860</link><description>Police were called to a suburban shopping centre in the early hours of Sunday morning where they declared the man in his 40s dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1f120a042247a986d3d85b34298ac38</guid></item><item><title>Polar bears take over abandoned research station in Russian Arctic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/polar-bears-take-over-abandoned-research-station-russian-arctic/105827636</link><description>A group of polar bears that have taken over an abandoned polar research station off Russia's coast is intimately captured in drone footage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd9190befe49ad2b23306dac25fde98f</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos beat Newcastle Knights to set up NRLW grand final against Sydney Roosters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/brisbane-broncos-beat-knights-to-set-up-nrlw-grand-final/105827872</link><description>Brisbane is back in the NRLW grand final for the first time in five years, setting up the long-awaited clash with the Sydney Roosters after a 30-6 win over Newcastle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67d02df9ba10a85033ed2d183c187b10</guid></item><item><title>St Kilda pulls off record AFLW comeback, Ebony Marinoff, Ally Anderson celebrate milestone games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/st-kilda-stuns-port-with-aflw-comeback/105828018</link><description>St Kilda outscores Port Adelaide 38-0 in the final quarter after trailing by 27 points at three-quarter-time, while Ally Anderson and Ebony Marinoff become the first players to feature in 100 AFLW games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8d47cda8140119afb1ab797fd99be53</guid></item><item><title>Russia launches major drone, missile attack on Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/russian-missile-and-drone-barrage-kills-four/105828200</link><description>Ukraine accuses Russia of pounding the country with "hundreds" of drones and missiles overnight, killing at least four people in the capital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">774c23cea6435b60c36bb3ba54786014</guid></item><item><title>Adam Reynolds and Reece Walsh explain the Broncos' game-winning moment against Penrith Panthers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/adam-reynolds-reece-walsh-nrl-final-game-winning-moment/105828288</link><description>Adam Reynolds took the kicking tee from the Broncos' biggest star in the biggest moment of their season so far, and it paid off in the biggest way possible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">536642d6505adba508e3c36f170c355a</guid></item><item><title>Vietnam evacuates thousands as Typhoon Bualoi approaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/typhoon-bualoi-forces-thousands-to-evacuate-in-vietnam/105828376</link><description>As Typhoon Bualoi approaches Vietnam, thousands of people are seeking safer ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34ba155386d3628844b99b19c8e4efb0</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese vows to defend democracy at UK Labour conference</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/anthony-albanese-speech-at-uk-labour-conference/105828690</link><description>Anthony Albanese and British counterpart Sir Keir Starmer embrace on stage in Liverpool, northern England, where rumours have been swirling about a leadership challenge to the UK PM.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66720743055a09553e9308d3cf9f1a0f</guid></item><item><title>Classified US intelligence warns of China's preparations for Taiwan invasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/us-intelligence-warns-china-ferries-built-for-taiwan-preparation/105606720</link><description>A classified US intelligence report, seen by the ABC, says vessels have been modified to carry tanks and partake in amphibious operations in what Taiwan considers part of China's "expansionist intentions".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75d1c1d291b29866fa07b6834b7eb3fe</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's 'climate hoax' comments belong to a well-resourced playbook landing on Australia's shores</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/trump-climate-hoax-comments-and-fossil-fuel-lobby/105810870</link><description>US researchers have tracked how dark money funds a tangled web of climate denial think tanks with vested interests in slowing climate action. And Australia is not immune.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">baad7cd0960fc50a010484697cc19237</guid></item><item><title>Optus owner Singtel awards employee big bonus as triple-0 crisis deepens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/singtel-awards-employee-bonus-after-optus-debacle/105824886</link><description>A week after an Optus network outage disrupted hundreds of triple-0 calls — and was linked to the deaths of three Australians — owner Singtel dishes out an employee "bonus".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd5f23e3359cf73406f4268b3b4a8c0f</guid></item><item><title>Anti-corruption chief Paul Brereton continued defence consulting after declaring he had resigned from role</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/nacc-chief-defence-consulting/105821158</link><description>The head of the national anti-corruption commission told a Senate inquiry he had resigned his role at the defence force's investigative arm. But the ABC has learned he continued consulting for them, and documents proving his resignation could not be identified.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2142fb25ce654eee8a08d853101c7865</guid></item><item><title>If China beats the US on fusion energy, its supremacy will be assured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/fusion-energy-china-united-states-coal/105720436</link><description>China is driving hard to supplant the US in this new military industrial complex, and has already achieved leadership in electric vehicles, batteries, drones and renewable energy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f2ed6434035cb358c677b916343d8b7</guid></item><item><title>Funding deal for research program about Australia's polar security rejected by Tasmanian government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/funding-deal-for-research-into-polar-security-rejected/105817408</link><description>A funding bid to establish a polar security research program has been knocked back, despite the changing geopolitical dynamics in Antarctica and the Southern Ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7caffffe60fab33afc201a1dced4018</guid></item><item><title>Hamas says it has lost contact with two Israeli hostages in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/hamas-says-it-has-lost-contact-with-two-hostages/105828834</link><description>The military wing of Hamas is calling for Israel to pull troops back and suspend air strikes for 24 hours so fighters can retrieve the captives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49ea90151f647f5df3aad9912d2d0239</guid></item><item><title>How Astrid Jorgensen turned a suburban pub choir into a worldwide musical phenomenon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/astrid-jorgensen-pub-choir-phenomenon/105785800</link><description>Astrid Jorgensen has an unusual condition — she finds many human noises unbearable. So how did she end up running the "world's biggest choir"?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c52ac986d15821498768cfce54f56e74</guid></item><item><title>Jewish patients say they feel ongoing fear months after Bankstown Hospital nurses video</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/jewish-community-hold-concern-following-bankstown-nurses-video/105790178</link><description>Some members of Australia's Jewish community say they have experienced ongoing trauma and fear months after a video came to light that included threats to Israeli patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76c4e1c74d2d6684705e8bddc17f4b6d</guid></item><item><title>Family of Melbourne man Kwar Ater searching for answers after his shooting death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/kwar-ater-remembered-after-fatal-melbourne-shooting/105808658</link><description>The 26-year-old was shot dead in Melbourne's CBD earlier this month, leaving his shocked family in search of answers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7da58ed54e19d399a6f3e67cf81bde98</guid></item><item><title>The deadly legacy of the 'forgotten pandemic' — and why it's drawing comparisons to COVID-19</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/qld-hong-kong-flu-dr-john-gerrard-covid-19-pandemic-vaccines/105774782</link><description>It's been dubbed "the forgotten pandemic" — possibly because it coincided with some of the most momentous events in world history. But Dr John Gerrard argues variants of the H3N2 flu, which led to the Hong Kong flu pandemic, continue to cost lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da8e7bee9c1d98aac2d29d06615ce658</guid></item><item><title>Mark Nawaqanitawase outlines what he misses most about rugby union on Nesian Footy show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/sport-mark-nawaqanitawase-nesian-footy/105822930</link><description>Mark Nawaqanitawase says there are many things he misses about rugby union, but moving to league is the best decision he has made in his life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83953cee38f9bb85258d19c5c2410db2</guid></item><item><title>Grieving family frustrated at lack of licence reform after seven-year coronial inquest wait</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/family-frustrated-licence-reform-coronial-inquest/105822734</link><description>Robert Hall was killed when he was struck by partially blind driver John Charles Robertson on the Horrocks Highway in 2018. His family feel their pleas for licence reforms have been ignored by the state government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">002af794efab261a0061e550c361a41c</guid></item><item><title>These Australians are homeless with a house</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/remote-nt-housing-amid-rising-temperatures-climate-change/105421962</link><description>Many Aboriginal people in Tennant Creek live in overcrowded makeshift shelters with no running water or electricity as they wait up to a decade for a home. But experts say the social housing being built is not safe for today's climate, let alone the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6114aa8701c7c5addd04a9559938ee86</guid></item><item><title>Four dead after gunman opens fire in a Michigan Mormon church service before setting it on fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/michigan-mormon-church-fatal-shooting/105828872</link><description>Hundreds of people were inside The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints in Grand Blanc Township when a 40-year-old man rammed his pick-up truck through the front door, then got out of the vehicle and started shooting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1ca82611da9d7ceda5f81d3deea5660</guid></item><item><title>Southern pygmy perch 'ear bones' provide data to re-establish populations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/fish-ear-bones-could-be-key-to-pygmy-perch-revival/105811482</link><description>Information gleaned from tiny growth rings on "ear bones" of native pygmy perch could be the key to bringing them back from local extinction in the lower Murray.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">649c11322dafbfaa01c2ce68e583e5e7</guid></item><item><title>Shellharbour Council proposes tiny home planning pathway in NSW first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/shellharbour-council-tiny-home-pilot-proposal-development/105811852</link><description>Shellharbour Council approves a plan for a tiny homes planning pathway which it says could be adopted statewide, as owners face uncertainty around legal installation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff8db8dbb4d397dada6c798c4cbe2283</guid></item><item><title>Government quietly extends Nauru contract, taking the cost to $787m — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/federal-politics-live-blog-september-29/105829016</link><description>The government has quietly extended a contract for the running of asylum seeker services on Nauru until 2027, taking the cost to $787 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3465f48fde355f222f3088b4fb0df59a</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police can monitor phones of DV offenders under new protections for victim-survivors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/nsw-courts-get-more-powers-to-impose-new-dv-protections/105828170</link><description>NSW courts can now allow police to monitor domestic violence offenders' phones and make them self-report if they open dating profiles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa443beb65b1b6b6c385e0a372661049</guid></item><item><title>New York City Mayor Eric Adams announces he is dropping his re-election bid after unpopular tenure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/eric-adams-drops-re-election-bid/105828948</link><description>Eric Adams announces he is dropping his re-election bid, but says he will "continue to fight for this city" until his term ends on January 1, 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e1a8b654c5ea5d1d7a7ff58bd246fdd</guid></item><item><title>ASX jumps 0.9 per cent ahead of tomorrow's RBA rates decision, gold surges — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/105828406</link><description>The ASX bounced out of the blocks, supported by banks and healthcare stocks gaining 0.9 per cent, while gold hit a new record high.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">428787f4ee6b264a3a2b68f2fceb29e9</guid></item><item><title>Ivan Cleary says NRL doctor's decision to rule Scott Sorensen out of preliminary final was a 'huge call'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/nrl-broncos-vs-panthers-ivan-cleary-on-scott-sorensen/105829092</link><description>Ivan Cleary says the NRL made a "huge call" in deciding to bench Scott Sorensen after a nasty head clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e1317d4d328348b5aa069d4adbf16b7</guid></item><item><title>Optus investigates outage that led to failed triple-0 calls in Dapto</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/optus-investigates-another-triple-0-outage-in-nsw/105829054</link><description>Embattled telco Optus has apologised for a network outage that led to nine failed triple-0 calls near Wollongong on the NSW south coast over the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80526d53f63f971d4e314371df58583e</guid></item><item><title>Children's author Pamela Allen's work showcased in interactive exhibition at State Library of NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/children-author-illustrator-pamela-allen-exhibition/105816018</link><description>At 91, Pamela Allen has published more than 60 books. This exhibition brings her work off the page and invites children and adults to play as they read.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79ba1502bd70c825488eecfa0f939e60</guid></item><item><title>National campaign against indicator flash as unofficial overtaking signal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/overtaking-signal-from-trucks-raises-road-safety-concerns/105818336</link><description>Road haulage industry leaders are planning a national campaign against using indicators as a signal it is safe to overtake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec43b17ffd8b7717cd672c6b62d5f594</guid></item><item><title>India defeats Pakistan with just two balls to spare in cricket's Asia Cup final, then refuse to claim trophy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/asia-cup-cricket-final-india-downs-pakistan-two-balls-to-spare/105829144</link><description>India defeats Pakistan with just two balls remaining in the Asia Cup final, then refuses to claim the trophy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afd15ee3ed653e96b920ce202b640afe</guid></item><item><title>Beer almost hits Erica and Rory McIlroy as Europe beats US in ugly Ryder Cup scenes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/ryder-cup-golf-beer-thrown-at-rory-and-erica-mcilroy/105829272</link><description>A beer launched from the crowd almost hits Rory and Erica McIlroy as Europe dominates America in a tense Ryder Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">086cdf33df3db298c9aec817516d824a</guid></item><item><title>Victorian emergency relief centres lose federal government funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/emergency-relief-centres-stripped-of-federal-funding-food-cost/105800534</link><description>The Victorian relief service that's fed those in need in the Wimmera for almost 30 years has had its funding slashed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd2acc303fc06e90a792d77f8816c216</guid></item><item><title>WA growers take precautions against mango twig tip dieback disease</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/wa-growers-protect-against-mango-twig-tip-dieback/105811470</link><description>Mango growers in Western Australia's far north are on alert as a mysterious dieback disease decimates crops in the Northern Territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f69d40f7595a9150097e2aeff4c5bcbf</guid></item><item><title>Vets warn dog owners as canine ehrlichiosis spreads across northern Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/canine-ehrlichiosis-endemic-spreads-across-northern-australia/105814976</link><description>The rapid spread of canine ehrlichiosis since it was first detected in Australia five years ago "has left a lot of destruction in its wake", a veterinarian says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8e6b345e66a66a94e042d799166c805</guid></item><item><title>The NRL grand final clash between Melbourne and Brisbane is the ultimate clash of footballing styles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/nrl-grand-final-broncos-storm-walsh-munster-clash/105828434</link><description>Neither Melbourne nor Brisbane is approaching perfection ahead of their grand final showdown, but with what they've been through, neither team would want to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">250624bcf063dfe15f4c8e75a31bcbb3</guid></item><item><title>Price of silver nearing record high – 29 September 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/price-of-silver-nearing-record-high/105829558</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f8635f3bfc49f0a01d8e88e8bee8bb0</guid></item><item><title>Three people charged with murder of Jayden Selfe in Attadale after body found in bush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/three-people-charged-with-jayden-selfe-murder-in-attadale/105807500</link><description>Three people face a Perth court accused of murdering 33-year-old Jayden Selfe, whose disappearance sparked an extensive investigation and led to the discovery of his body north of the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03cd3a0177766a1157e2a5340dfc2e15</guid></item><item><title>If you're looking to try out a career change, volunteering can give you a taste</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/volunteering-to-test-a-career-change/105788520</link><description>If you're considering a career change, or want a taste of a new industry, volunteering can be a great option.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8160f86239ba2807fc1b8d35ee83f8df</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says he will tell US military leaders 'we love them' after Pete Hegseth summoned them for a meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/donald-trump-pete-hegseth-us-military-meeting/105829802</link><description>The US president said he will tell military leaders "we love them, they're cherished leaders" during a meeting organised by Defense Secretary Pete Hegseth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a22fb4128e65a3c7a59aa5e8b1538f09</guid></item><item><title>Cycling great Tadej Pogačar rides away from the field to win men's road race world title in Rwanda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/pogacar-pedals-to-another-epic-world-cycling-title/105829612</link><description>Tadej Pogačar makes more cycling history with another incredible win in the world championship road race on a brutally tough course in Rwanda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee6b64a9670ca0fa0891eec61448a68d</guid></item><item><title>Aussie motorcyclist Daniel Sanders wins World Championship in record-breaking year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/daniel-sanders-wins-world-championship/105829266</link><description>Daniel Sanders' world championship comes during a record-breaking run of form in the World Rally-Raid Championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac3a23c14b521ae654e1841645267fd6</guid></item><item><title>Humanity's space ambition to be focus of first Powerhouse Parramatta exhibition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/task-eternal-space-exhibition-to-launch-powerhouse-parramatta/105829116</link><description>Humanity's ambition to explore beyond Earth will feature in the largest exhibition space in the country when Powerhouse Parramatta opens in the city's west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54153ffe9059ead5c032efe725a8e9e6</guid></item><item><title>Rory McIlroy defends wife Erica after 'astonishing' abuse from American Ryder Cup fans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/rory-mcilroy-defends-wife-erica-ryder-cup-abuse/105829570</link><description>Rory McIlroy supports his wife Erica, who was said to be on the receiving end of "astonishing" abuse from American fans during the Ryder Cup in New York.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d7fcf1cc21d22ea7fea1b398e9a7f5f</guid></item><item><title>Investigation begins after Townsville urology patients not given test results, follow-up care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/queensland-health-investigating-townsville-hospital-urology/105829310</link><description>Queensland Health will investigate reports patients did not receive crucial test results from north Queensland's largest public hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">679a4510a52eef9f63713a62046fc045</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast nurse sentenced after stealing patient's bank card</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/gold-coast-nurse-sentenced-for-stealing-from-coma-patient/105829196</link><description>Melelani Crelley was handed 12 months' probation after pleading guilty to fraud and stealing charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6596f48de954220a58ee54eaeea61f27</guid></item><item><title>Bad Bunny to headline Super Bowl Halftime show in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/bad-bunny-to-headline-super-bowl-halftime-show/105830316</link><description>Grammy-winning rapper Bad Bunny is set to headline the Super Bowl half-time show in Northern California next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2ce8791ba83bbac9fb185eb51568e24</guid></item><item><title>Tufi Junior Tauese-Auelua jailed for five years over firebombing of Jordan Shanks' Bondi home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/man-jailed-for-five-years-over-bondi-friendlyjordies-arson/105830364</link><description>Described as "a little boy in a very large body", the man who lit the blaze at the home of the YouTube comedian in 2022 apologised and said he would "rather die" than go back to jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1f43ca56edac53669d0466e7605132d</guid></item><item><title>When is the 2025 NRL grand final? Here's how to watch and everything you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/when-are-the-2025-nrl-and-nrlw-grand-finals/105829220</link><description>The NRL and NRLW grand final teams have been finalised and are getting ready to face-off this weekend. Here's what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83aee82f83ac81d24eb24f5d884f94e4</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm prop Stefano Utoikamanu labels Brisbane Broncos 'stuck up', Xavier Willison free to play NRL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/nrl-grand-final-melbourne-storm-brisbane-broncos-utoikamanu/105830590</link><description>Melbourne prop Stefano Utoikamanu lights the fuse for an explosive NRL grand final on Sunday, setting his sights on steamrolling "stuck-up" Brisbane opponents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">249ff19ee68f44495059a0506aca76e8</guid></item><item><title>Leisl Smith was killed by James Scott Church, NSW coroner finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/leisl-smith-was-killed-by-james-scott-church-nsw-coroner-finds/105829214</link><description>James Scott Church stood trial in 2022 for the 23-year-old's murder, but died before the verdict was handed down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd37a90df155e5c65bf3557ad54c99f0</guid></item><item><title>Four teenage boys arrested after car chase through Melbourne, pedestrian struck</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/bourke-street-mall-incident-police-pursuit-arrests/105830762</link><description>Police say they've arrested four teenage boys in Melbourne's CBD after chasing them from Doncaster in the city's east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27fa99b6c4ee07d50b1279a05aaad213</guid></item><item><title>Unregulated melatonin products had as much as four times the amount on label, TGA testing shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/tga-safety-concerns-over-melatonin-products/105829782</link><description>The TGA has urged patients to stop using unregulated melatonin products after testing revealed “significant discrepancies” between their actual melatonin amount and what was on the label.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">198d5ab8d2ff8a6e72cbefeb3197ef3e</guid></item><item><title>Death of Port River dolphin prompts calls for stricter boat regulations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/dolphin-death-port-river-sa/105830462</link><description>The "completely preventable" death of a three-year-old dolphin in Adelaide's Port River has prompted new calls for mandatory propeller guards on boats entering the sanctuary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0e18338b2ebf52c030f58a93d721358</guid></item><item><title>Stephen Fleming showed 'grave disrespect' by dumping Annette Brennan's body in bin, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/stephen-fleming-attends-presentence-annette-brennan-manslaughter/105829658</link><description>47-year-old Stephen Fleming, who has pleaded guilty to manslaughter, is accused of ending his new housemate's life last year and stuffing the English teacher's body in a green waste bin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6ea60a644a0a4b2d7360bcaa738d131</guid></item><item><title>NRL players, including Brisbane Broncos star Payne Haas, spruik crime-linked fashion line R4W Active</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/nrl-player-payne-haas-fronts-crime-linked-activewear-line-r4w/105828100</link><description>The grand final-bound Origin prop and at least three other NRL players are promoting a clothing brand linked to the Alameddine crime family, fuelling police concern the league has failed to stem the influence of organised crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">013c5a6b057a382fbbed566420a9e84e</guid></item><item><title>Kylie Soanes is an urban ecologist on a mission to prove nature belongs in our cities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/kylie-soanes-urban-nature-conservation-biodiversity/105315332</link><description>Kylie Soanes says urban development should not come at the expense of nature and there's no reason why we should not spot a fairy wren on the way to the bus stop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a914d2f5b0b9608997ecde0a91c37166</guid></item><item><title>How can we better prepare tourists at Cradle Mountain?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/how-we-can-better-prepare-tourists-for-cradle-mountain-hike/105829334</link><description>Cradle Mountain is one of Tasmania's most popular, and dangerous, tourism destinations. After another tragedy, questions are asked about what more could be done to ensure the safety of visitors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">302f535a72c3b49b49e79a02ae4d6fa9</guid></item><item><title>Larrimah Hotel sold for the second time since Paddy Moriarty's disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/larrimah-hotel-sold-again-after-dissappearance-of-paddy-moriarty/105829656</link><description>The Larrimah Hotel is sold again, after capturing the world's attention in podcasts and films about the disappearance 70-year-old Paddy Moriarty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8b4b29d6e72a4b3c4bb0089716d141b</guid></item><item><title>OC spray used at Darwin nightclub two weekends in a row as NT trial approaches one-month mark</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/nt-alleged-aggravated-assault-pepper-spray-misuse-oc-spray/105829090</link><description>Security guards at a Darwin nightclub have been confronted with pepper spray two weekends in a row, during the first month of a Northern Territory-wide trial of the weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65c431fb6284e043523493c1525de2bd</guid></item><item><title>Youth advocate calls for balance amid knife crackdown, police conduct 1,600 searches at Burnside</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/knife-searches-impact-on-young-people/105830924</link><description>SA Police conducted more than 1,600 metal detector searches at Burnside Village at the weekend, but the state's Guardian for Children and Young People says officials need to "get the balance right" amid a crackdown on knife crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9f06b963a51e8f4f3e76dcb45ce8003</guid></item><item><title>India claim they were denied Asia Cup trophy after win over Pakistan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/india-claims-they-were-denied-asia-cup-trophy-pakistan/105831210</link><description>India T20 skipper Suryakumar Yadav has claimed that his team was denied the chance to lift the 2025 Asia Cup trophy, after it beat Pakistan in the final by five wickets on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b678c1b2c791864e5d3679a316fcc0a</guid></item><item><title>Lismore looks to the future as flood buyback suburbs empty out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/lismore-urban-planning-house-buybacks-2022-flood-recovery/105799094</link><description>A rainforest minutes from the CBD, a food production bowl and riverside walkways are among the big ideas being discussed for Lismore as it continues to recover from the 2022 floods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e184fdd9b89341c132ef1ee0efbbec26</guid></item><item><title>Pedestrians describe police pursuit through Melbourne CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/pedestrians-describe-police-pursuit-through/105831362</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0a998c0e2ce0213e6810d874598dc2e</guid></item><item><title>Queensland coroner to examine cause of fatal house fire in 2017 which killed young boy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/qld-coroner-examining-house-fire/105830424</link><description>In 2017 two boys and their father, who cannot be identified for legal reasons, were badly burnt when their rural property went up in flames.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2004e51fb1f2a324af6cd702585106c</guid></item><item><title>WIM Resource mining employee charged with falsifying document</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/wim-resource-mining-employee-charged-with-falsifying-document/105675812</link><description>Suspended mining company employee Murray Wilson will fight a falsifying documents charge relating to a proposed mineral sands project in north-west Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67b2824f9ffca102ddc3d97dced78d13</guid></item><item><title>Body scanner to be used in ACT courts after significantly reducing prison strip searches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/act-electronic-scanner-expansion-reduce-strip-searches-jail/105830654</link><description>The ACT government will expand the use of electronic body scanners to the courts after their use in Canberra's only prison saw a dramatic drop in the need to strip search prisoners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8593aef0310bd16a46c4fdad86864527</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with performing Nazi salute at the AFL facing two new counts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/nazi-salute-charge-afl-semifinal-gabba-court/105829908</link><description>Tylere Baker-Pearce, 39, was arrested by counterterrorism police outside a Brisbane court on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87fbc67c3b22851008dd4e5af9765dac</guid></item><item><title>At least 13 dead after Typhoon Bualoi makes landfall in Vietnam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/apn-bualoi-vietnam-landfall/105831514</link><description>At least 13 people have died after heavy rain and strong winds from the former Typhoon Bualoi flooded roads, knocked off roofs in central Vietnam, state media reported, with residents describing it as "one of the strongest".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a633befcd32cf7b9b0648dcd1307f2e</guid></item><item><title>Climate change is hitting the Northern Territory harder than most places in Australia.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/climate-change-is-hitting-the-northern-territory/105831790</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">100fae9c1f74752eff6db46423f457d5</guid></item><item><title>Man found guilty of murder, two others of manslaughter in David Jenkins trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/verdict-murder-trial-of-david-wayne-jenkins/105816040</link><description>Luke Anthony Shaw, Paul William Shaw and Patrick Kenneth Dolbey were charged with the murder of David Wayne Jenkins, who was stabbed 11 times in October 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f07e01556336f49bccd6423c4f8448c</guid></item><item><title>Noemie Fox leads Aussies to kick off ICF Slalom World Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/noemie-fox-leads-aussies-to-kick-off-slalom-world-titles/105832024</link><description>Noemie Fox has just missed out on a dream start to the ICF Slalom World Championships, finishing fifth in the kayak cross time trials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e3ac00f6bdb3a68d08e0c2eb45d1592</guid></item><item><title>Crime scene declared after two people found dead at Kenmore Hills property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/qld-kenmore-death-two-people-police-investigate/105832174</link><description>A crime scene has been declared at Kenmore Hills after two people were found dead at a property just after midday on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a78aeb9b8f7383f34948d1082844dd37</guid></item><item><title>Will Ashcroft named best AFL finals player to win Gary Ayres Award to add to Brisbane Lions accolades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/will-ashcroft-named-best-afl-finals-player-brisbane-lions/105832244</link><description>Brisbane Lions midfield star Will Ashcroft has added the AFL coaches' award for player of the finals to his growing list of accolades in the wake of his team's 47-point victory over the Geelong Cats on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">468af182ae004fc8c704109b4dcae10a</guid></item><item><title>James Tedesco is named best NRL player by his peers for the fourth time despite Roosters falling short in NRL finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/james-tedesco-is-named-best-nrl-player-by-his-peers/105832318</link><description>The 32-year-old fullback joins Johnathan Thurston as the only four-time winner of the players' champion award, after the Sydney Roosters star was voted the NRL's best player of 2025 by his peers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1edf57f7450acb2b1112ffb830a7d4c</guid></item><item><title>Albanese invites Emirati retail giant Lulu Hypermarket to take on Coles and Woolworths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/albanese-invites-lulu-hypermarket-to-take-on-coles-woolworths/105832238</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has invited Emirati 'hypermarket' chain LuLu Group to set up shop on Australia's shores and take on supermarket giants Coles and Woolworths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dff2e97321eaa2a6005ab80c58f514cb</guid></item><item><title>Caboolture Hospital to review medical scans amid concerns about outpatient service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/caboolture-hospital-patient-scan-review-metro-north-health/105831662</link><description>A clinical team is reviewing the medical imaging results of up to 9,000 patients at Caboolture Hospital amid concerns about how results were communicated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce29051247b7daa71dd24ef941f4d60b</guid></item><item><title>Body scanner use in Canberra significantly reduces prison strip searches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/body-scanner-use-in-canberra-significantly-reduces/105832466</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05f29746247c8d56023470810333bcdb</guid></item><item><title>Monday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105832402</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e0efb10200a7cc4ba119bbef3e530ea</guid></item><item><title>Rick Morton's book about Robodebt, Mean Streak, among Prime Minister's Literary Award winners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/prime-ministers-literary-awards-rick-morton-mean-streak-robodebt/105808038</link><description>Journalist Rick Morton didn't want to write a book about Robodebt. Now that book, Mean Streak, has won the Prime Minister's Literary Award for non-fiction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5222686c405207b893f11605f1d249b6</guid></item><item><title>RSL NSW leadership embroiled in conflict of interest allegations and secret plan to takeover sub-branch assets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/rsl-nsw-embroiled-conflict-of-interest-secret-sale-plan/105820110</link><description>Serious allegations of conflict of interest and a secret plan to strip sub-branches of their assets have been made about RSL New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba3752ff9650565780131db97d40f5ad</guid></item><item><title>Secret plans and alleged conflicts of interests at top of RSL NSW exposed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/secret-plans-and-alleged-conflicts-of-interests-at/105832478</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e53fa18601bb93862ae33ad7320cb85c</guid></item><item><title>Federal budget deficit lower than forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/federal-budget-deficit-lower-than-forecast/105832494</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">137940a3e5122e9dd450ce55f08c2843</guid></item><item><title>Four teens arrested in Melbourne CBD after police pursuit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/four-teens-arrested-in-melbourne-cbd-after-police/105831944</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2236776dd2f4af63672264e89460c03c</guid></item><item><title>Childcare centre in Sydney's south-west shut down amid investigation over alleged safety concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-29/sydney-childcare-jennys-kindergarten-shut-down-over-safety-fears/105832450</link><description>A childcare centre in Sydney's south-west has been closed down immediately, with an investigation underway into concerns about children's safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7941bb7da810e1c49444e38f04a3fca</guid></item><item><title>US to impose 100pc tariff on movies made outside the country, Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/us-to-impose-100-tariff-on-movies-made-outside-the-country/105832688</link><description>US President Donald Trump initially threatened to impose such levies earlier in May but offered few details, leading to confusion among entertainment industry executives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c6b83ec49a52515805a0e1a9b788860</guid></item><item><title>Private equity consortium offers to buy Electronic Arts for $80 billion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/consortium-buys-electronic-arts-for-55-billion-dollars/105832746</link><description>A consortium of private equity companies, including one backed by Donald Trump's son-in-law Jared Kushner, is offering to take the video game giant private.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a06eae9e8baf8c4fc089531baf0884ed</guid></item><item><title>Iranian security forces tackle a suspected Mossad agent.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/iran-security-forces-tackled-suspected-mossad-agent-/105830336</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1e717eb7bc17d420d0c28c9afecebf7</guid></item><item><title>Inside Iran, a paranoid regime hunts for traitors and spies after its war with Israel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/iran-hunts-spies-and-traitors-after-israeli-spy-infiltration/105822466</link><description>For 12 days in June, the world watched as Iran and Israel traded blows. What came next was a brutal purge of spies and traitors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bd8ed2cd2c6a2db151383f80c45b3bf</guid></item><item><title>Will the Reserve Bank cut interest rates today? Only if hell freezes over</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/reserve-bank-set-to-keep-interest-rates-on-hold-at-sept-meeting/105830776</link><description>With markets pricing next to no chance of an interest rate cut today, what are the chances of another RBA move before year's end?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7391188e4fe7f994864ec7dc5831b5d4</guid></item><item><title>What could Thriving Kids, the NDIS alternative for some children, look like?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/thriving-kids-autism-developmental-delay-design/105793852</link><description>Despite the government wanting its Thriving Kids program for children with "mild to moderate" developmental delay and autism to start next year, the system is yet to be designed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b6c263c5db7a26886a74772271eb7d</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu agrees to Donald Trump's 20-point Gaza peace plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/israel-gaza-peace-plan-white-house-announcement/105832816</link><description>Israel has agreed to a US proposal to end its war on Gaza, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu and US President Donald Trump announce after holding talks at the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a1f4e181a9cb0ff116cb25c804daf0</guid></item><item><title>Clock is ticking for Optus boss as triple-0 disaster escalates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/optus-triple-zero-disaster-means-clock-ticking-for-ceo-rue/105832282</link><description>Analysts say the Optus CEO should "leave quietly" now or risk a more public exit once the reviews into the company's recent outages are complete.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d065263a83281a11837869d86cf3d983</guid></item><item><title>Consultancy bill to review 'struggling' submarine agency blows out to $12.1 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/submarine-agency-consultant-review-blows-out-aukus/105831752</link><description>The agency responsible for delivering AUKUS has spent five times what it first planned for consultants to review its operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf24c34870572f0d84606c9ed22dfb92</guid></item><item><title>Pro-EU party wins majority in Moldova election in setback for Russia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/pro-eu-party-wins-majority-in-moldova-election/105832904</link><description>Moscow is accused of attempting to sway the election in favour of a pro-Russian party, but a majority of voters backed the pro-EU Party of Action and Solidarity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96ceb7f4e8448574865973b7d1624d57</guid></item><item><title>Calvary St Luke's Hospital surgeries transferred after micro tears found in the floor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/calvary-st-lukes-hospital-micro-tears-in-floor-launceston/105832280</link><description>The shutdown of Calvary St Luke's Hospital will affect 40 planned surgeries this week, with 22 of those reallocated to nearby St Vincent's Hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e5a2a76e795eadb0cfe0ed7e9a6adce</guid></item><item><title>Tom Ballard's new show searches for the line between funny and offensive while pushing the comedy envelope</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/tom-ballard-jks-a-comedy-melbourne-fringe-festival/105829986</link><description>Comedian Tom Ballard is swapping a stand-up stage for a dramatic one as his new stage show asks, how do you remember a divisive figure?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8deace55743245b36e5fd8f6ad090d8</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn Hawks AFLW lose Emily Bates to injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/hawthorn-hawks-aflw-lose-emily-bates-to-injury/105832440</link><description>Top-four aspirants Hawthorn are set to lose Emily Bates for the run towards the finals after the star midfielder suffered a shoulder injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c55507c927534eed7b21f75ffeef1b11</guid></item><item><title>Robot for lunar and Earth construction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/robot-for-lunar-and-earth-construction/105831312</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c57ebbbeb8787aacaa657e1323defd81</guid></item><item><title>Australian homes could soon be built by spider-like robot called Charlotte</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/robot-backed-nsw-government-could-be-used-to-build-homes/105831202</link><description>Developers of a speedy, "spider-like" robot named Charlotte believe it could be building homes on Earth within years, and eventually further lunar exploration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da44e9233a44c61287572d5db4f5cb5c</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government writes off up to $4 million worth of COVID-19 fines years after they were issued</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/queensland-government-writes-off-covid-fines/105829608</link><description>The government has confirmed Queensland's state-run debt collection agency has now "finalised" all debts related to COVID fines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6041290208a40933a25acd204d0f629</guid></item><item><title>Teenage boys charged over car chase through Melbourne into Bourke Street Mall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/police-charges-four-teenage-boys-car-chase-bourke-street-mall/105831884</link><description>Police have charged two 16 and 17-year-old boys in relation to a dangerous incident involving an allegedly stolen car being driven into the pedestrian-only Bourke Street Mall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">877d9e2a6596c8c24ed8504b113ca23c</guid></item><item><title>Trump outlines plan for 'eternal peace' in the Middle East</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/trump-outlines-plan-for-eternal-peace-in-the/105833154</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bab01e7f8c95e0f3cf16e28f3d96238b</guid></item><item><title>'Huge change' to Australia's health system as registered nurses set to prescribe medication</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/registered-nurses-prescribing-medicine/105831424</link><description>Qualified registered nurses will soon be able to write prescriptions for medications, in a bid to ease pressure on a stressed public healthcare system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">964c1de9e42f333dca6628564d4d8ca1</guid></item><item><title>First Nations Australians launch class action against Work for the Dole scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/indigenous-class-action-against-commonwealth-work-for-the-dole/105831704</link><description>A class action on behalf of Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander people alleges a Commonwealth Work for the Dole scheme was tougher on remote participants than on jobseekers in cities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5362bf7775d5763f4aee198270866f7b</guid></item><item><title>Looming crisis for older Australian women who will retire into poverty if no urgent action taken, new report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/super-crisis-for-women-who-retire-in-poverty-new-report-says/105830680</link><description>Women's super balances are disproportionately impacted by events later in life, in addition to childcare duties, which could mean serious financial problems, research from Super Members Council (SMC) has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f10e93e0fbfcfdb37654ad8d0c08828</guid></item><item><title>Rescue founders outraged as kitten Pierre dumped within hours of adoption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/adopted-cat-pierre-dumped-owners-urged-to-desex-pets/105832316</link><description>Just 12 hours after he was adopted, eight-month-old kitten Pierre was found in his carrier in the middle of the road, drenched after an overnight storm. Rescuers are urging owners to de-sex their cats, to help prevent other animals from enduring a similar ordeal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03bfb1c1b88e01087bd8ae2e9cb3bd22</guid></item><item><title>Federal environment minister knew of rock art fears before granting Woodside North West Shelf extension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/murray-watt-murujuga-rock-art-woodside-extension/105831128</link><description>The federal environment minister was advised pollution from Woodside's Karratha Gas Plant may be causing irreversible changes to ancient rock art, before granting the company a 40-year extension with strict conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fe1024f68585a39e20b2ea2ecd5747f</guid></item><item><title>Will Skelton to return for Wallabies against All Blacks in second Bledisloe Cup Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-30/will-skelton-to-return-for-wallabies-against-all-blacks/105832340</link><description>Lock Will Skelton is set to return for the Wallabies ahead of the final round of the Rugby Championship against the All Blacks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8f1ba1dc3e0cf1c5ce16e0e8a5b29b9</guid></item></channel></rss>