<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 21:51:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Antisemitism royal commission welcome, but some say it was called too late</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/bondi-victim-families-react-to-antisemitism-royal-commission-/106211654</link><description>Community groups that lobbied for a national inquiry into antisemitism back the prime minister's announcement of a royal commission as the NSW premier pledges the NSW government's full cooperation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f5153fa8bcfbade566307a3531a93c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's comments about Greenland were once seen as a joke. Greenlanders are no longer laughing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/donald-trump-greenland-denmark-nato-comments-worrying-island/106210090</link><description>The United States has a long history of wanting to acquire Greenland, but people living on the island say Donald Trump's latest comments about annexation feel different.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">780d9c1f5e1d18550bf80d207f6c5b10</guid></item><item><title>How the internet reacted to the fifth Ashes Test at the SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/how-the-internet-reacted-to-the-fifth-ashes-test/106198770</link><description>The internet went wild as Australia dominated with the bat, led by Travis Head and Steve Smith, and England crumbled in the dying embers of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab73112ebb189dad0b2e311cb6ccdeb6</guid></item><item><title>Solar to the fore as grid sails through heatwave and record demand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/solar-powers-australia-through-heatwave-conditions/106211394</link><description>For so long, the pounding sunshine of an Australian heatwave was the grid's biggest threat. It has now become its greatest asset.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae701b0cb782c015f079002489ef8776</guid></item><item><title>US Senate votes to limit Trump's power to order strikes in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/senate-votes-to-limit-trump-war-powers/106212508</link><description>The vote in the Republican-controlled chamber still needs to pass the US House, and has virtually no chance of becoming law due to Donald Trump's presidential veto.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a5427cd6d6d5921804e7ab4c06fb178</guid></item><item><title>Insect enthusiasts helping researchers keep an eye on bug populations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/qld-bug-hunt-insects-photos-research-citizen-scientists/106171252</link><description>Queensland insect enthusiasts are snapping photos of their backyard bugs to help researchers monitor native and invasive species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4f7610e986e7cd15889efebe22c7a82</guid></item><item><title>Locals, summer tourists swelter through heatwave in South Australia's Riverland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/sa-riverland-heatwave-hot-weather-peak-tourist-season/106205990</link><description>South Australia's Riverland will swelter through yet another day in the mid-to-high 40s on Friday and will have to wait until the weekend for a reprieve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">156f32643cce0f3fd5034709d9ff285a</guid></item><item><title>RBA plays the long game on inflation, so an interest rate rise could still be some way off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/rba-deputy-governor-andrew-hauser-interest-rates-inflation-janda/106210128</link><description>The Reserve Bank says inflation is "too high", but that doesn't mean it will necessarily rush to raise interest rates next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">822c83de4d34fdbaba8bbaad3b53d3a5</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan and foreign prisoners to be released following seizure of Nicolás Maduro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/venezuela-prisoners-to-be-freed-after-us-seizure-of-maduro/106212566</link><description>The president of the country's parliament says that Venezuelan and foreign prisoners will be released in the coming hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">162dbf5e6813226eb49bca2ac138a569</guid></item><item><title>Matildas and Arsenal star Kyra Cooney-Cross returns home in wake of mother's cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/matildas-star-cooney-cross-returns-home-to-face-family-tragedy/106212710</link><description>Arsenal's Australia international Kyra Cooney-Cross flies back to Australia to be with her mother, who has been diagnosed with stage 4 cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">022d27429b844ff00f76299de5f2a1ab</guid></item><item><title>NT pokies clubs report member perks, lavish upgrades as 'community' benefits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/nt-pokies-community-contributions-member-perks-renovations-foi/106084120</link><description>Previously secret documents released under Freedom of Information laws have revealed how the Northern Territory's pokies clubs' community contributions are really being spent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b956be26d539f0a576209395e5c2ce80</guid></item><item><title>Top tips for learning a musical instrument or taking up singing at any age</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/top-tips-for-learning-a-musical-instrument-or-taking-up-singing/106206612</link><description>You can pick up an instrument or learn to sing at any age. Here are some helpful tips from experts and ABC Classic audience members to get you started.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b6a800c527cc85e14d26b021f88d536</guid></item><item><title>Assault-accused MP Nick McBride says home detention makes him 'more wedded' to electorate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/sa-assault-accused-mcbride-speaks-about-home-detention/106211188</link><description>South Australian MP Nick McBride, who has been charged with aggravated assault, says home detention will make him "more focused" on his electorate ahead of the SA election in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02f3f4438b200f30196cb731428b4151</guid></item><item><title>Man in anaphylactic shock on Virgin flight to WA's Pilbara saved by crew, another passenger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/selfless-act-saves-man-anaphylactic-shock-on-wa-virgin-flight/106209770</link><description>Pilbara resident Andrew Rawle found himself 30,000 feet in the air, unable to breathe due to anaphylactic shock, but was saved by the crew and the selfless act of another passenger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07f2dd24254e8cf0a23a06e972a26c2e</guid></item><item><title>Angela Jones's history-making ride from country upbringing to top of Queensland's jockey ranks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/angela-jones-journey-to-becoming-number-one-jockey-in-queensland/106158424</link><description>Angela Jones became the number one jockey in Queensland in 2025. Now, the determined young woman, who grew up on a central Queensland cattle farm, wants Group 1 glory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61a9fab622749cc9f453903462200fc3</guid></item><item><title>How The Pitt lured ER star Noah Wyle back into the emergency department</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/the-pitt-noah-wyle-er-r-scott-gemmill-john-wells/106118716</link><description>ER launched Noah Wyle's career in 1994. Thirty years later he's back in the emergency room — and scooping awards season — as Dr Robby in The Pitt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a195925d2de69fb82fd3317eb6f950</guid></item><item><title>Arsenal's Gabriel Martinelli apologises for 'disgraceful' act towards injured Liverpool player Conor Bradley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/martinelli-disgraceful-act-towards-injured-liverpool-player/106213400</link><description>Arsenal winger Gabriel Martinelli has apologised for shoving Liverpool's Conor Bradley, who was down with a serious knee injury, off the pitch during their Premier League clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">249ee65a474fdfd5395e9aa04686c802</guid></item><item><title>Rio Tinto in merger talks with Glencore, takeover could create world's biggest miner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/rio-tinto-in-talks-to-take-over-glencore-mega-miner-merger/106213252</link><description>Rio Tinto and Glencore are in takeover talks that could potentially lead to a combined mega-miner worth more than $US200 billion. Analysts are questioning whether Rio will be interested in Glencore's coal assets, having sold off its own in 2018.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">045687aff3f78cbc211b52c08acfbb59</guid></item><item><title>Diana Camacaro fled Venezuela when a friend close to Nicolás Maduro's regime texted her she was on a list to be arrested</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/nicolas-maduros-regime-came-for-these-women-who-fled-to-colombia/106207412</link><description>When a Telegram message landed on her phone, Diana knew she had to flee Venezuela. It was from someone close to Nicolás Maduro, and she says she would have been jailed, or worse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c98ade3c4b3047c53890d5f90ef7983</guid></item><item><title>The Bondi royal commission will be a long-term test of Albanese's leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/bondi-royal-commission-test-albanese-leadership/106213854</link><description>The prime minister's critics feel he failed to meet the moment in the immediate aftermath of the Bondi attack, but with the royal commission he has a chance to get it right.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">916f58de1d1e77dad7bbbe9ffc85cf2e</guid></item><item><title>Police urge drivers not to enter Queensland floodwaters and risk life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/police-ask-drivers-not-to-enter-queensland-floodwaters-risk-life/106210610</link><description>Authorities hope fines will deter motorists from driving into flooded waters, after nearly half-a-dozen vehicles are stranded in two weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c347a6c5dac263fc5c03174043fc97e2</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian author seeks to be reinstated to Adelaide Writers' Week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/sa-palestinian-author-calls-for-apology-over-writers-week-axing/106212878</link><description>Palestinian author Randa Abdel-Fattah has called for her appearance at Adelaide Writers' Week to be reinstated after it was axed, but SA's Premier has continued to back the decision, as dozens of authors cancel their appearances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bc84d20ac7f6de4042f859ef7f45602</guid></item><item><title>Surge in heat-related illness as temperatures continue to soar across south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/heat-illness-emergency-presentations-surge-heatwave/106213074</link><description>Emergency departments, medical centres and first responders are dealing with a surge in heat-related illness across Australia's south-east as temperatures soar to near record levels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b871b12491bc4d2dc8eaf82577c10a1</guid></item><item><title>Senior SA government officials reject claims of political interference into algal bloom causes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/sa-department-heads-reject-interference-claims-in-algal-bloom/106213376</link><description>Four of the most senior public servants working on South Australia's algal bloom have rejected allegations that departmental staff had been instructed not to investigate the cause of the ecological disaster until after March's state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">870976f9925aebd0a33e7f1bc1020da3</guid></item><item><title>Russia says it has fired its Oreshnik hypersonic missile at Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/russia-says-it-hit-ukraine-with-oreshnik-hypersonic-missile/106214842</link><description>A "massive" Russian night-time attack on Ukraine damaged 20 residential buildings in Kyiv and its suburbs, as well as Qatar's embassy, President Volodymyr Zelenskyy says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a8f4739db2dad29330326f7b3195830</guid></item><item><title>Accused scam kingpin Chen Zhi arrives in China after extradition from Cambodia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/accused-scam-kingpin-chen-zhi-extradited-china-cambodia/106213664</link><description>Accused scam boss Chen Zhi is extradited to China from Cambodia after being indicted by the United States over an alleged multi-billion-dollar fraud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">648a0ad4bdb7733943e6779b95d8d539</guid></item><item><title>Iranian leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei defiant amid growing nationwide protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/iranian-leader-defiant-amid-nationwide-protests/106215570</link><description>Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has remained defiant amid nationwide protests, saying his regime would not back down in the "face of saboteurs."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7824ad9e3d4314266df80acbf92fb3f4</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 10: The Sopranos changes television forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/the-sopranos-first-episode-aired-january-10/106184120</link><description>Restaurant owners in New York would eventually complain of "the Soprano effect" when they lost trade on Sunday nights as patrons headed home to watch the show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffcb2a4fb64b3420356a8e83d5d0d0e0</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump is reshaping American power and the threat to international order is alarming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/trump-power-venezuela-greenland-international-law-morality/106214406</link><description>There have been plenty of examples of the Trump administration's contempt for legalities, diplomacy and alliances, but this week Trump and his lieutenants went further.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c22187d11c5335ce0bf87ef3d56a102</guid></item><item><title>Elon Musk's AI bot says it is limiting its ability to 'undress' users. Australians want an opt-out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/grok-ai-undressing-australia-women-children/106213644</link><description>For more than a week, X's AI bot Grok has been generating sexual images of women and children at the request of other users, even when they ask it not to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22ff953eef024151d04f32634fee90bd</guid></item><item><title>Cautious hopes Beijing lifting soft ban on South Korean pop culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/china-ban-south-korean-pop-culture-could-lift-amid-warmer-ties/106205780</link><description>China has restricted access to South Korean pop culture since 2016, when Seoul received US anti-missile technology. Warmer bilateral ties are spurring optimism that will change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ba4fe5aa1d0f4321bc3f7f578639c8b</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave and extreme weather: Bushfire disaster in Vic; threat rises in NSW; cyclone forms in Qld — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/state-of-disaster-declared-bushfires-victoria/106215462</link><description>Out-of-control bushfires are continuing to rip through Victoria with at least 130 homes and buildings across the state lost and more than 300,000 hectares of land burned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4531b20bfb843f3cd9dc55a9cbfc4ffd</guid></item><item><title>Barmy Army turns Ashes defeat into Australian tourism win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/barmy-army-australia-cricket-england-ashes-tourism/106214260</link><description>The Barmy Army has continued the recent trend of UK travellers spending more time and money in Australia, despite a disappointing on-field performance from their side.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0e0cdaaf5650b5241200515e45b1db6</guid></item><item><title>A royal commission into the Bondi terror attack is going ahead. Here's what to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/nsw-bondi-beach-terror-attack-royal-commission-explainer/106214222</link><description>After growing calls for a royal commission into the Bondi terror attack, the prime minister has finally announced it would take place, saying it "was what Australia needs".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5c4db150b54ae496aa3b27cd3284f13</guid></item><item><title>NSW SES moves to embrace 'volunteers for a day' to boost members after May 2025 floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/nsw-ses-embraces-spontaneous-volunteering-from-mud-armies/106148252</link><description>Experts say volunteering is not in decline, but it is becoming more spontaneous. The NSW disaster agency is moving to embrace this after seven women mobilised 1,200 people to volunteer for a day in record-breaking floods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ec15e7a123bbf5e95ce4ac5c8fcc385</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave in southern states one of the most intense on record as Queensland braces for cyclone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/australia-weather-weekend-fire-threat-nsw-possible-cyclone-qld/106214346</link><description>The heatwave, which has engulfed southern Australia this week, has become one of the most intense on record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58204e4bff379826f49c6ba8cd360331</guid></item><item><title>BOM declares Cyclone Koji as category two system off north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/queensland-tropical-low-expected-to-intensify-into-cyclone-koji/106213662</link><description>North Queensland residents are readying themselves as a category two cyclone moves towards them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31ff50af30cc18bf007aa03d6532275f</guid></item><item><title>The daily struggle continues in Caracas as Venezuelans dare to hope for change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/inside-venezuela-daily-struggle-continues-in-caracas/106215776</link><description>The ABC hears from residents of Venezuela's capital, Caracas, about the struggles of daily life and their hopes and fears after American intervention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46481d872f8a29319917daa1f987ff21</guid></item><item><title>The King of Rock and Roll transcends language and culture at the Parkes Elvis Festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/parkes-elvis-festival-toki-toyokazu-singing/106209036</link><description>Japanese tribute artist Toki Toyokazu is part of a growing international presence at the annual Parkes Elvis Festival, which also includes women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10fce8d3fb0882e55de283e43848800a</guid></item><item><title>Talc Alf's carved artworks attract tourists travelling the Strzelecki Track in outback SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/talf-alc-art-gallery-off-strzelecki-track-in-outback-sa/106215944</link><description>Off the Strzelecki Track in outback South Australia lies the gallery of Talc Alf, so named for the artworks he carves out of soft, powdery talc.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df41f2abeace4c13f0d72aa4071eaece</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of protesters gather in the streets of Tehran</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/thousands-of-protesters-gather-in-the-streets-of-tehran-/106215926</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da8bb09418c81a8759b9950ffcf2784b</guid></item><item><title>Wildlife ACT calls for more volunteers as demand soars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/behind-the-scenes-wildlife-carer-need-for-more-volunteers/106197866</link><description>There are about 40-50 active volunteer carers within ACT Wildlife, but the organisation says more are needed, especially as the temperature soars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f5a4332242278a963a96a5f5349515f</guid></item><item><title>Gladstone company taking centre stage in AI revolution, providing a critical mineral to cool computer chips</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/alpha-hpa-gladstone-high-purity-alumina-ai/106213676</link><description>The industrial hub is playing a key role in the AI industry as it pumps out a critical material needed to cool high-performance computer chips.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d9c1e88cea4d8966d5dcf9a4a5eddaa</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of alcohol products still without 'mandatory' pregnancy warnings, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/mums-drank-pregnancy-alcohol-warning-labels/106154908</link><description>New research shows thousands of alcohol products remain on Australian shelves without mandated pregnancy warning labels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4783e5564f11c66b51e1823883c1fc40</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island plastics pollution battle for turtles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/christmas-island-turtles-battle-plastic-pollution/106092234</link><description>A beach on a remote island, and home to nesting turtles, is annually overwhelmed by tonnes of plastic garbage. Christmas Island is doing what it can to help stem the never-ending tide of pollution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d3dcc3dcbe6121099810921fa255ce7</guid></item><item><title>NT town of Katherine home of Australia's best tasting tap water, nine years after PFAS detected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/katherine-pfas-australia-best-drinking-water/106184842</link><description>The tap water in the Northern Territory town of Katherine — which includes a "designer" mix of river water from the world-famous Nitmiluk National Park and mineral-rich groundwater — has been named Australia's best drop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">261a9a94bd6f12376ce7733c8591bf93</guid></item><item><title>Coronial inquest into death of Indigenous woman identifies 'chain of failures' at Royal Darwin Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/nt-inquest-indigenous-woman-died-at-royal-darwin-hospital-rdh/106214552</link><description>The Northern Territory coroner has determined a series of human errors contributed to the 2022 death of an Indigenous woman at Royal Darwin Hospital, in the weeks after she sought a routine surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f42a17b1714b5d0d3ff6fc9d137f0e5</guid></item><item><title>Hollywood-backed Wrexham knocks Nottingham Forest out of FA Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/fa-cup-wrexham-beats-nottingham-forest-on-penalties/106216130</link><description>As actor and co-owner Ryan Reynolds watched on in the grandstand, Wrexham defeated Nottingham Forest on penalties to advance to the fourth round of the FA Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91bb5ae037795ce58b925a93a6f7f216</guid></item><item><title>NSW bakes through temperatures above 40 degrees as fire crews successfully contain blazes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/fire-danger-heatwave-winds-expected-across-nsw/106215426</link><description>Scorching temperatures lingered late into Saturday across NSW with the hottest place in the state's far west recording 44.6 degrees Celsius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b231cedc2fe401167227036f94b22b8e</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says oil executives will have 'total safety' if they invest in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/donald-trump-calls-on-oil-executives-to-invest-in-venezuela/106216060</link><description>The US president has pivoted to portraying capturing former Venezuelan leader Nicolás Maduro as as a new-found economic opportunity for the US, seizing tankers carrying Venezuelan oil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dc2fcdae1c71862418dd85affd8a742</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's bushfires spread as two blazes burn out of control in Otways</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/bushfires-victoria-otways-harcourt-ravenswood-evacuation-orders/106216316</link><description>Fires in the Otway National Park are moving towards the town border of Colac, as firefighters continue to battle blazes across the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1eb719b39b488ae1230329f141585bab</guid></item><item><title>Australia will join G7 countries to discuss critical minerals in Washington next week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/australia-india-invited-to-g7-meeting-on-critical-minerals/106216434</link><description>India was also invited to attend the meeting, but it is unclear if it has accepted the invitation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5033c9e681d0a3e4dbd6b5122cd4832d</guid></item><item><title>Video shows fire damage and spread in the Ravenswood-Harcourt fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/fire-damage-at-harcourt/106216668</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85ede2102be24b61a7ecac9f5c46a595</guid></item><item><title>Former Adelaide Festival leaders pressure board to reinstate Palestinian author</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/adelaide-writers-week-board-letter/106216140</link><description>Nearly a dozen former leaders of the Adelaide Festival are calling for Randa Abdel-Fattah to be reinvited to Writers' Week, adding to a mounting crisis over the Palestinian-Australian author's exclusion from the literary festival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">419d86892f36312376cb6d948b7d5fd7</guid></item><item><title>Harcourt residents assessing damage after more than 50 structures lost in Ravenswood fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/harcourt-residents-assessing-fire-damage-50-structures-destroyed/106216128</link><description>Harcourt residents describe their devastation and gratitude in the wake of a massive blaze that swept through the town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41a20d508de1332022c43cad5ffab3d8</guid></item><item><title>Jakara Anthony wins gold, Matt Graham silver at Val Saint-Côme World Cup moguls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/jakara-anthony-wins-val-st-come-moguls-gold-matt-graham-silver/106216564</link><description>Jakara Anthony and Matt Graham both move to the top of the overall FIS Moguls World Cup standings with success at Val Saint-Côme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc6737a14624333a7254e0de0bc51b8c</guid></item><item><title>Scenes of destruction in Natimuk after Grass Flat fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/scenes-of-destruction-in-natimuk-after-grass-flat-fire/106216792</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8d99457fc813ac3e502a7f2e1f38727</guid></item><item><title>RFS vision of bushfire burning at Brassknocker Firetrail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/rfs-vision-of-bushfire-burning-at-brassknocker-firetrail/106216834</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db8e70a5e4f29cb1266090a8566c5c8b</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja stars as Brisbane Heat beat Sydney Thunder in Big Bash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/bbl-brisbane-heat-beat-sydney-thunder-usman-khawaja-stars/106217066</link><description>Usman Khawaja's international career may be over, but he showed he is far from a spent force by stroking a fine 78 to help the Brisbane Heat to a BBL victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c207ff6a675044a194a5ef775cf96b0a</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 11: Smoking link to cancer announced in groundbreaking report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/today-in-history-january-11-smoking-cancer-link-/106185276</link><description>In 1964, a major scientific report laid bare the deadly risks of smoking, at a time when the tobacco industry had a stronghold on the public and government coffers. Delve into the ABC Archives to discover how Australians reacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f3b760fbe172c75b58503d89275571c</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open quiz: Can you get through this round in straight sets?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/australian-open-quiz/106213602</link><description>Take the covers off centre court! It's Australian Open time again. How well do you remember grand slams past?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a690bc29611ee04f1908e393963045b6</guid></item><item><title>Has Trump landed a dud with his Venezuelan oil play?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/has-trump-landed-a-dud-with-his-venezuelan-oil-play/106214900</link><description>While debate rages over the legality and the potential fallout from America's incursion, there's been a quiet acceptance that it is all about oil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c33d1561d445544b079145ddf3e5d257</guid></item><item><title>Albanese and Allan unveil $19.5 million support package as crews take stock of Victorian fire devastation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/bushfires-victoria-longwood-otways-walwa/106216856</link><description>Anthony Albanese and Jacinta Allan announce a multi-million-dollar emergency relief package for those affected by Victoria's devastating bushfires, as authorities warn hundreds of structures have been lost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e3e9e246e6c576c1c48b9911fa8cd42</guid></item><item><title>Victorian fires: One killed in bushfire disaster in Victoria as hundreds of structures lost — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/bushfires-victoria-nsw-heatwave-live-coverage/106217152</link><description>Several fires have been downgraded to watch and act but authorities are still battling to control many of the blazes that have claimed one life and destroyed hundreds of structures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acb9c066d8210639d9c8ba8dd9319e36</guid></item><item><title>From Madonna to Metallica, these are the big albums turning 40 this year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/1986-albums-turning-40/106186462</link><description>Pop and MTV ruled supreme but 1986 was also a banner year for hip hop and metal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05306a3fa6e1d11e44c9247761024678</guid></item><item><title>Endangered animal populations bounce back on Kangaroo Island thanks to predator-proof fence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/kangaroo-island-native-animal-populations-bounce-back/106209894</link><description>Five years after feral cats were removed from inside the Western River Refuge on Kangaroo Island, populations of endangered species have boomed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ed4f14a274779c62d099d330ae29b52</guid></item><item><title>Catholic priest swaps sermons for rock 'n' roll guitar solos in the Australian outback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/indonesian-catholic-priest-swaps-sermons-for-rock-n-roll/106096618</link><description>An Indonesian priest brings a deep love of rock 'n' roll to his pastoral care in western NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d84d083c89e34414fa2cbae127dec1a1</guid></item><item><title>Fr Oche singing Lord's Prayer in church</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/fr-oche-singing-lord-s-prayer-in-church/106211280</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89b5f0a8167a901d2053f0a42db401a5</guid></item><item><title>NSW community bands hit hard as association misses out on vital government funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/nsw-community-bands-lose-government-funding/106196730</link><description>Wollongong’s collective of brass and wind bands have been putting on a show for locals for almost a century, but it is one of dozens of community bands across the state that faces an uncertain future due to a recent loss of funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fa89331aaf2258eff5338749a99d08e</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Bree Walker claims World Cup monobob victory ahead of Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/world-cup-monobob-bree-walker-australia-wins-gold/106217414</link><description>With the Winter Olympics on the horizon, Bree Walker proves she is among the medal favourites in the monobob with a World Cup victory in Switzerland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84e8862d0672515637f26584a6b46c59</guid></item><item><title>Can spin bowling survive in pace-obsessed Australia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/future-of-spin-bowling-in-australian-cricket/106213212</link><description>After an Ashes series dominated by pace bowlers, what does the future hold for young spinners wanting to play Test cricket for Australia?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7d50c175dee070bd0124853f6491eaa</guid></item><item><title>Coco Gauff beats Iga Świątek but Poland advances to United Cup final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/united-cup-tennis-gauff-swiatek-us-poland/106217432</link><description>Coco Gauff gets on top of Iga Świątek ahead of the Australian Open, but the US star fails to stop Poland from reaching the United Cup final in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8241c7ff1abc94b0bf1fa4ed4bfaf6d4</guid></item><item><title>Floodwaters from Queensland bring life to remote NSW wetland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/floodwater-brings-narriearra-caryapundy-swamp-to-life/106136450</link><description>In a remote and isolated part of NSW, nature is enjoying a deluge of water still around from floods in Queensland last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cd922e8927464df3ee2214f5d28a73b</guid></item><item><title>Arsenal comes out in support of Kyra Cooney-Cross in wake of mother's cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/arsenal-shows-support-for-kyra-cooney-cross/106217464</link><description>Arsenal players and supporters pay emotional tributes to Matildas star Kyra Cooney-Cross following her return to Australia to be with her mother, who has been diagnosed with cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cd8e980134097674a6aa51baa58a92a</guid></item><item><title>Australia wins World Cross Country Championships relay gold after Jessica Hull's anchor leg</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/australia-wins-cross-country-gold-medal-mixed-relay/106217508</link><description>Olympic medallist Jessica Hull guides Australia home in the mixed relay event at the world titles in Florida.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a06bfe83793d80a6ae82ba788f25bd13</guid></item><item><title>Middle Island underwater observatory once a star attraction for Great Keppel Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/great-keppel-island-underwater-observatory-star-attraction/105282860</link><description>It was once a star attraction alongside Great Keppel Island, with hundreds of tourists daily in the 80s and 90s, but these days snorkellers and fish are the only visitors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ec691adcfad7a9c65242cf297b16d68</guid></item><item><title>Tennis racquet stringer numbers take a hit in Australia while tournaments grow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/tennis-racquet-stringer-numbers-take-a-hit/106158244</link><description>Behind the scenes of the world's most elite tennis tournaments there is a team of people working on keeping the majors' racquets well strung.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e19b85d4afa7ebee66e1230d98b7492</guid></item><item><title>Regional healthcare disparities leaving lipoedema patients without adequate care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/lack-of-services-leaving-nt-lipoedema-patient-without-care/106187588</link><description>Women with lipoedema in the Northern Territory are struggling to access the care they need, forcing some to relocate for specialist treatment. The condition, often misunderstood, requires better medical support in regional Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cf3f553788b7739e7792aca653b52f5</guid></item><item><title>Rodeo up-and-comers backed by veterans to make it on world stage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/youth-rodeo-mentoring-western-australia-cowboys-cowgirls/106014112</link><description>WA's brightest cowboys and cowgirls are being flown across the world to learn from champions of the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dca903a8a77ff22c1b3aad753210fc6b</guid></item><item><title>Bob Weir, founding member of American rock band the Grateful Dead, dies aged 78</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/grateful-dead-founding-member-bob-weir-dies-at-78/106217686</link><description>Bob Weir's death was announced on Saturday in a statement on his Instagram page.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b178e464044d0565ff4d6653adda88c2</guid></item><item><title>Macclesfield beats FA Cup champion Crystal Palace 2-1 in major upset</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/fa-cup-champions-crystal-place-beaten-by-macclesfield/106217706</link><description>Non-league Macclesfield delivers one of the biggest upsets in FA Cup history by stunning defending champion Crystal Palace 2-1.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">278b23bc335caf167a6d70d2d9d5725d</guid></item><item><title>Puppies of Muster Dogs champion find homes with next generation of farmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/muster-dogs-next-generation/106076694</link><description>In small towns scattered around Australia, five kids have hit the jackpot. They've each been given a puppy from a champion muster dog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6215e769acfa2f5006fc31c26bf83f23</guid></item><item><title>Iranian protesters chant anti-government messages as authorities signal intensifying crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/iran-protesters-chant-anti-government-messages/106217578</link><description>Anti-government chants filled the streets of Iran's capital on Saturday night, as protesters pressed the biggest movement against the Islamic republic's rulers in more than three years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7db66be9c7bee782fc67cefaef55938a</guid></item><item><title>Destruction after bushfire in Harcourt, Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/destruction-after-bushfire-in-harcourt-victoria/106217892</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">010754ec10522854911105f298f54fbd</guid></item><item><title>Family saves Acheron home after Longwood fire encircles property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/acheron-longwood-fire-locals-save-family-home/106217756</link><description>Everywhere you look around the Irvines' farm near Alexandra are signs of the fire that surrounded their home and burnt right up to the front porch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d13a19daef4d01956b938f4221cce743</guid></item><item><title>Aftermath of bushfire in Victoria’s Central Highlands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/aftermath-of-bushfire-in-victoria-s-central-highlands-/106218114</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ce6e6ca4d68aec2809c4d2ba3abb2b0</guid></item><item><title>Planes drop fire retardant ahead of Walwa bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/planes-drop-fire-retardant-ahead-of-walwa-bushfire/106218120</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ba29b3dcd47430460aca3a0b36156a4</guid></item><item><title>Shaun Tan's Tales from Outer Suburbia, now adapted for TV, shows the magic of the everyday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/shaun-tan-tales-from-outer-suburbia/106159172</link><description>Writer Shaun Tan highlighted the magic and whimsy of everyday Australia in his book Tales from Outer Suburbia. He talks about finding inspiration in the mundane, and what it was like turning his tales into TV.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3edc4b4127f4c0bd736e41d9e0e2cd3f</guid></item><item><title>Police discover human remains near car in bushfire-ravaged area east of Seymour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/victoria-bushfires-human-remains-found-longwood-fire/106218144</link><description>Victoria confirms its first fatality in the bushfire emergency ravaging the state, with police discovering human remains east of the town of Seymour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f48177119b0657449c023ba885bfe11</guid></item><item><title>Volunteer firefighter's Alexandra home burns while he battles Victorian bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/cfa-volunteer-firefighter-discovers-burnt-home-during-shift/106217532</link><description>CFA volunteer Michael Harper discovers through the truck radio while on shift that his home is under threat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c0a6cb7dbb65315c1dc52db85da06df</guid></item><item><title>Winds push bushfire smoke north, triggering air quality and health warnings for Victoria and NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/smoke-and-air-quality-warnings-health-bushfires/106217952</link><description>Health experts and authorities are urging people living north of Victoria's bushfires to limit their time outdoors as a weather system pushes bushfire smoke across the state and into New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">358d63d080f9df3c2162496f14d5aef5</guid></item><item><title>Festival chair, board members quit after author's cancellation from Writers' Week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/fallout-amid-writers-week-cancellation-of-randa-abdel-fattah/106217646</link><description>The Adelaide Festival board's decision to cancel the appearance of Palestinian-Australian author Randa Abdel-Fattah from this year's Adelaide Writers' Week has prompted further fallout, with several board members and the chair stepping down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da2c4b2cf2ad5c5edceae8c85ba6aeb9</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka wins second-straight Brisbane International women's final, beating Marta Kostyuk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/aryna-sabalenka-vs-marta-kostyuk-brisbane-international-final/106218052</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka has claimed her second-straight Brisbane International title, beating Marta Kostyuk 6-4, 6-3.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd6ca667c6147eec17022a291370ef01</guid></item><item><title>At least 500 killed in Iran protests as Trump weighs up intervention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/iran-vows-to-strike-back-if-us-attacks/106218450</link><description>The US-based Human Rights Activists News Agency says a further 10,600 people have been arrested as Iran's theocratic government attempts to crack down on the demonstrations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd30dd7511bc35404c8800db8a13feab</guid></item><item><title>Mackenzie Coupland, Pat Eddy win AusCycling road race national championships in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/auscycling-road-nationals-perth/106218174</link><description>Under 23 neo-pro Mackenzie Coupland and unheralded rider Pat Eddy have stunned the elite peloton to claim brilliant victories in the AusCycling road nationals in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1368c3661057ace09379c37954ecc9a5</guid></item><item><title>Daniil Medvedev beats Brandon Nakashima to win Brisbane International men's final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/daniil-medvedev-vs-brandon-nakashima-brisbane-international/106218054</link><description>Daniil Medvedev enjoys Australian Open warm up with first Brisbane International crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1129e2e6c5c21d8ee9e7f028edf761c2</guid></item><item><title>One dead in Longwood fire as Victoria's bushfire emergency enters its sixth day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/vic-bushfires-turn-deadly-conditions-ease/106218116</link><description>On Sunday afternoon, emergency services discovered the body of a person in Central Victoria. The fatal turn comes as firefighters use favourable conditions to contain more than 20 blazes across the state, but emergency warnings remain in place for some areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56288155cfddf331de0ae2382dbd98d5</guid></item><item><title>Former UK ambassador Peter Mandelson says he did not know about Epstein abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/peter-mandelson-jeffrey-epstein-apology-abuse-bbc/106218564</link><description>Peter Mandelson, who was fired as the UK's ambassador in Washington DC over his ties to the convicted sex offender, has apologised to victims of Jeffrey Epstein "for a system that refused to hear their voices".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99c68e7226523d02a89479406f6668a9</guid></item><item><title>Remote fire detection technology set to double across Tasmania after AI cameras spot hundreds of blazes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/remote-fire-detection-ai-cameras-tasmania/106209074</link><description>As fire crews were responding to two fires on Tasmania's east coast in December, an AI camera nestled in a nearby vantage point spotted a third blaze. The early detection meant the fire was extinguished just two hours later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eedfe0e57deefc5fa696a1585e462d1f</guid></item><item><title>This week in history quiz, January 12: Test your knowledge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/this-week-in-history-quiz-january-12/106193058</link><description>Holy giant toads, Batman! Will you ace this week's look back at the past?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2337f7eb7ee53e1c40d55847695a5f81</guid></item><item><title>In Minneapolis, the deadly ICE shooting has reopened old wounds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/minneapolis-targeted-in-largest-ice-operation-before-shooting/106218184</link><description>Minneapolis had been the target of a massive immigration enforcement operation in the weeks leading up to Renee Nicole Good's death. Now, the shooting has opened old wounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c71026b1d066cab096b64e9e77b9556</guid></item><item><title>Harcourt's heart in ruins but community standing strong after bushfires hit regional Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/harcourt-residents-stay-strong-after-bushfire/106218316</link><description>In a region famed for its lush pastoral farmland, locals thought Harcourt was less likely to be hit than neighbouring bush towns Castlemaine and Barkers Creek.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f11128fbc47c13ac88204e17be9d56e4</guid></item><item><title>Joining the Michelin Guide would put Australian restaurants 'on the world map', Sydney chef says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/should-australia-join-the-michelin-guide-for-restaurants/106206560</link><description>If you're a food lover, chances are you've heard of the Michelin Guide – you may have even dined at a Michelin-starred restaurant, but not here in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46d76ffc266c069b3512a72f429c12ad</guid></item><item><title>Weight loss drug Wegovy to be subsidised for Australians with severe obesity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/wegovy-to-be-added-to-pbs/106218104</link><description>The cost of weight loss drug Wegovy will soon be massively subsidised for Australians with severe obesity who have had a stroke or heart attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7319c2093a41449f89ba253e1f3c121</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump tells Cuba to 'make a deal' as US cuts off Venezuelan oil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/trump-says-us-will-block-all-oil-entering-cuba/106218928</link><description>The US is enforcing a strict oil blockade on Venezuela, the communist country's main supplier of oil, as the Trump administration continues to push Latin American countries to align with it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07b11b6e681c559027ee0ec33ebbcba7</guid></item><item><title>Nick McBride could get $100k in taxpayer funding for re-election campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/nick-mcbride-public-campaign-fund/106216122</link><description>Independent MP Nick McBride, who is currently on home detention bail for the alleged assault of his wife, could receive around $100,000 in public funding to support his re-election campaign, according to the state's electoral commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6da77d577333a78823f3d1e500ec53a8</guid></item><item><title>Protests spread across major cities in Iran</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/protests-spread-across-major-cities-in-iran/106218978</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02ec67153742107b24af93241973d180</guid></item><item><title>Elite sportswomen have shared their stories, and these are the hard truths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/abc-elite-athletes-womens-sport-survey-results/106100946</link><description>Low pay, discrimination, disordered eating, sexism and online abuse are just a few of the prevalent issues ABC's Elite Athletes in Women's Sport Survey has revealed, despite recent progress in women's sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8e3515998c70a3bad0d527e0a77a77f</guid></item><item><title>ABC Elite Athletes in Australian Women's Sport Survey: Results summary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/abc-elite-athletes-womens-sport-survey-full-summary/105989848</link><description>Here is a summary of the results from ABC Sport's inaugural Elite Athletes in Australian Women's Sport Survey, in partnership with Deakin University.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1e6dee17ebd83a7af5416cfe297060e</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka is the woman to beat at Australian Open, showing even more versatility to her game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/aryna-sabalenka-australian-open-variety-power/106218486</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka has won yet another title on Australian soil, showing that the Australian Open is hers for the taking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1297dfad37d0350f974c7aed2a34990d</guid></item><item><title>In a rare interview, the Taliban's chief spokesman exposes the gap between narrative and reality</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/interview-with-taliban-spokesman-in-kabul/106210452</link><description>The Taliban's chief spokesman agreed to an unscripted, sit-down interview with me, there was just one non-negotiable condition, writes Meghna Bali.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d61530e9c23537620a91bd341abaf596</guid></item><item><title>Labor MPs apologise over game of 'shoot, shag or marry' at public festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/tasmania-labor-mps-apologises-for-inappropriate-remarks/106217588</link><description>A federal assistant minister and two Tasmanian state Labor MPs apologise after a complaint was made about their behaviour at the Taste of Summer festival in Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45852f61c01b68fc8fa58245093441c7</guid></item><item><title>The Sydney suburbs saying no to fast food giants in the name of 'heart and character'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/sydney-suburbs-fighting-fast-food-giants-kfc-mcdonalds/105979334</link><description>Nutrition, vibe and culture concerns fuel these communities that want to protect their suburbs' identity and businesses from the fast food giants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba87f5d1c090fd5df3f1a7b0bce11b67</guid></item><item><title>Victorian fires: Twelve major fires still burning as number of buildings destroyed climbs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/victorian-bushfires-live-updates-crews-battle-emergency-blazes/106218614</link><description>Firefighters continue to battle fires across the state after the grim news that a person had been found dead and at least 400,000 hectares burnt. Look back at our live coverage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5dbd66e4c9a594c18aa0d1d6377208e</guid></item><item><title>Campus Life program helping young people with disabilities transition after school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/qld-campus-life-program-helping-young-people-with-disabilities/106210350</link><description>A Brisbane mum was worried about what her son would do after high school, so she created a transition program to help other neurodivergent young adults.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23638ab11baca2f1f2e162604247cee5</guid></item><item><title>Supporting your child when starting child care or kindy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/supporting-your-child-when-starting-child-care-or-kindy/106115412</link><description>It's natural to feel nervous about transitioning your baby or child into early childhood education. Knowing some settling techniques, as well as what you can advocate for on behalf of your child, can help their transition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d03690a51df17649ec94389e7563f80</guid></item><item><title>Summer festival-goers continue to abandon truckloads of camping gear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/camping-gear-abandoned-at-festivals-causing-huge-waste-problem/106210328</link><description>With campsite trash accounting for more than half of the rubbish accumulated at music festivals, there are calls for a "cultural shift" in the behaviour of those attending.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">917eebb589e7b5e85306f3ae40cf6fd5</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open: Iga Świątek plays down fitness concerns after Belinda Bencic loss in Poland's United Cup win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/iga-swiatek-fitness-united-cup-poland-switzerland/106219014</link><description>After two losses at the United Cup over the weekend, world number two Iga Świątek insists "everything is fine" with her fitness in the lead-up to the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">736247d766789001e712ac0518d62dbf</guid></item><item><title>Thousands march in wake of ICE shooting in Minneapolis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/thousands-march-in-wake-of-ice-shooting-in-minneapolis-/106219102</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0837cdba1b45352cfca3d687737374db</guid></item><item><title>Fed chairman Jerome Powell facing criminal probe, ACCC set to sue Coles, Woolies for price gouging, ASX rises — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/106218522</link><description>US Federal Reserve chief Jerome Powell confirms he is facing a Department of Justice investigation, while Australia's competition watchdog will use new powers to go after the big supermarkets, according to a report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f66a462fee893d966b5a09a35b60d04</guid></item><item><title>Flood emergency warning for Clermont in central Queensland as ex-Cyclone Koji moves inland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/heavy-rainfall-north-queensland-ex-cyclone-koji/106218210</link><description>Authorities have issued a Flood Emergency Warning for the central Queensland town of Clermont as large parts of the state are on flood watch in the wake of ex-Tropical Cyclone Koji.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd1ad9cdb4ffc769b035aff7427bb01b</guid></item><item><title>National bulk-billing rates are increasing, according to Cleanbill report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/cleanbill-bulk-bill-doctor-gp-report-medical/106212998</link><description>The percentage of GP clinics fully bulk-billing has almost doubled, according to a new report, however, the government says the data cannot be relied on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92fcbdfbd61bdc32c7a030f43bc9b842</guid></item><item><title>National domestic violence commissioner, legal services say Katherine court unsafe for women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/dv-commissioner-legal-services-say-katherine-court-unsafe-women/106205754</link><description>Australia's domestic violence commissioner and local legal services have raised concerns about women's safety at Katherine Local Court, saying urgent upgrades are needed to protect victim-survivors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da52fb02414fec8cf0b4fba0707e58e2</guid></item><item><title>Man allegedly wearing a vest covered in duct-taped objects in Bondi charged with offensive conduct</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/man-charged-with-offensive-behaviour-bondi-wore-duct-tape-vest/106219114</link><description>A man allegedly carrying a vest covered in duct-taped objects in Bondi has been arrested and charged by NSW Police, with his vest examined by the bomb disposal unit and deemed safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">423cb203d6a79b9f533c3a6ad59029e9</guid></item><item><title>High hopes for endangered white-throated snapping turtle after record number of clutches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/high-hopes-for-white-throated-snapping-turtle-with-record-clutch/106210694</link><description>A record number of clutches of white-throated snapping turtles have been found along the Burnett River in Queensland's Bundaberg region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a66bab0694c751fc33a87edbb83aa921</guid></item><item><title>'Extraordinary' number of clutches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/-extraordinary-number-of-clutches/106212992</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">485e74923f36d5cbaaf664fbe165e826</guid></item><item><title>WA health report card exposes where the state is struggling most</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/wa-health-report-card-exposes-where-the-state-is-struggling-most/106211258</link><description>The latest WA Health and Wellbeing report reveals how regions stack up when it comes to things like diet, smoking, exercise and mental health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f44dd9e47fc9741ca7462528474a7fa</guid></item><item><title>Alex Carey comforts daughter, top scores for Adelaide Strikers in BBL return loss to Perth Scorchers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/alex-carey-adelaide-strikers-bbl-return-daughter/106219170</link><description>After a sensational Ashes series, Alex Carey returns to Adelaide and the Big Bash with a bang, although it was a tougher night out for his daughter, Clementine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">460bfb484b27eb06511821e29cd9913b</guid></item><item><title>Golden Globes 2026 updates: Rose Byrne wins first Globe, One Battle After Another and Adolescence win big</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/golden-globes-live-blog-2026/106195414</link><description>Australian actor Rose Byrne wins a Golden Globe for her performance in If I Had Legs I'd Kick You, while Jacob Elordi, Sarah Snook and Joel Edgerton miss out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d1fb76c0fcca255fb1af09c2e76e2c3</guid></item><item><title>Bushfires leave trail of destruction in northern Victoria town</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/bushfires-leave-trail-of-destruction-in-northern-victoria-town-/106219536</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee6b616df8d6764ec196bf69cc3b902b</guid></item><item><title>Report reveals Bunbury port authority's failure to protect historic Leschenault Homestead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/southern-ports-failed-to-protect-degrading-leschenault-homestead/106178744</link><description>A report obtained by the ABC under Freedom of Information shows a port authority not only failed to prevent a heritage-listed building from deteriorating, but likely made things worse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2854381c256344295b98898452fce58</guid></item><item><title>Golden Globes red carpet 2026: Hudson Williams, Ariana Grande, Emma Stone debut award show looks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/golden-globes-red-carpet-2026/106219490</link><description>The Golden Globes ceremony is today, with stars arriving on the red carpet in their best frocks and finery. See what they wore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04cd4b6ef108580c3486efe76b278dd3</guid></item><item><title>Meta removes 550,000 accounts from social media platforms to comply with under-16s ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/meta-removes-half-a-million-users-social-media-ban/106219186</link><description>More than half a million Australian children have been kicked off Facebook and Instagram by Meta to comply with Australia's social media ban for under-16s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e4d85c34efe58fda3834b6eba74772a</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police Inspector Amy Scott, praised for Bondi Junction stabbing response, diagnosed with breast cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/police-inspector-amy-scott-bondi-junction-hero-cancer-diagnosis/106219590</link><description>NSW Police Inspector Amy Scott, who was praised for bringing the Westfield Bondi Junction stabbing attack to an end, has been diagnosed with a rare and aggressive form of breast cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6af8c5bfb4543d26e60f6af733daa25</guid></item><item><title>Danielle Scott wins Lake Placid World Cup aerials ahead of Milan-Cortina Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/danielle-scott-wins-aerials-gold-at-lake-placid/106219716</link><description>After almost three years without gold, Australian Danielle Scott wins the aerials at the World Cup event in Lake Placid less than a month before the Olympics in Italy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">265ad638c6aa25726fc652503131b6e8</guid></item><item><title>Trump administration sending more agents to Minneapolis despite outrage over fatal shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/trump-admin-deploys-more-federal-agents-to-minneapolis/106219476</link><description>US Homeland Security Secretary Kristi Noem says hundreds more federal agents are heading to Minneapolis, brushing aside demands by the city's Democratic leaders to leave after an immigration officer fatally shot a female protester.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">590b8f973e722f6ce271a2d2eb5b560e</guid></item><item><title>US federal prosecutors open criminal inquiry into US Federal Reserve chair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/criminal-investigation-opens-into-us-federal-reserve-chair/106220038</link><description>The US attorney's office in the District of Columbia has opened a criminal investigation into Jerome Powell, the chair of the Federal Reserve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b73ea0c3599df6a5f16f85ec47bfa4b</guid></item><item><title>Golden Globes 2026 winners list: Owen Cooper, Stephen Graham win for Adolescence performances</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/golden-globes-awards-winners-list-2026/106199402</link><description>Here is the full winners list from the Golden Globes, where Adolescence sweeps all categories and the Pitt wins best drama series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed5dbf577fe1902316f981cc01d7f8d</guid></item><item><title>US Federal Reserve Chair responds to Department of Justice inquiry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/us-federal-reserve-chair-responds/106220170</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3aa65358ff54e3e9efcc29752560f07</guid></item><item><title>Iran's mass protests are not just about a repressive theocratic regime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/iran-history-protests-bazaaris-economy-revolution/106219578</link><description>Understanding how events unfold in Iran requires understanding how its society and economy have reconfigured in the 47 years since the Islamic revolution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbd389b22117ccbebd302033bedeff87</guid></item><item><title>Marta Kostyuk explains stance on not shaking Aryna Sabalenka's hand after Brisbane International final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/marta-kostyuk-aryna-sabalenka-handshake-brisbane-international/106219864</link><description>Marta Kostyuk explained that not shaking Aryna Sabalenka's hand and talking about Ukraine following her Brisbane International defeat was her duty, and to not highlight the issues at home would be "inhumane".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9c1b54169d0b5f21a84aeab0c9b28d5</guid></item><item><title>How I have fun with friends without spending money</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/perspective-koren-on-free-fun-with-friends/106055938</link><description>I've kept low-cost, high-fun habits alive for years, even after returning home to a city where socialising often seems to mean shelling out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a76d75b2115ed8d249c4c6396faeda38</guid></item><item><title>Rose Byrne wins best comedy nod for If I Had Legs I'd Kick You, and other key moments from the Golden Globes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/golden-globes-key-moments-2026/106217878</link><description>This year's Golden Globes saw hits and misses for Australia, last-minute snubs and a humbled Timothée Chalamet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7481c2eb26013c8233135e7953618d04</guid></item><item><title>Federal minister backs decision to axe Palestinian author from Adelaide writers' festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/minister-backs-adelaide-writers-festival-decision-to-axe-author/106217558</link><description>Resources Minister Madeleine King's comments come amid a growing furore over the decision that has led several board members to resign and dozens of writers to withdraw from the Adelaide literary event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67d90f44f6d06b944e57c469892189ed</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese recalls parliament to introduce hate speech and gun laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/anthony-albanese-recalls-parliament-hate-speech-gun-laws/106220636</link><description>Anthony Albanese has recalled parliament early to deal with sweeping hate speech and gun laws in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c900b2dea212ad5cd5b846c52aaa72c7</guid></item><item><title>Danish PM says her country faces a 'decisive moment' in its feud with the US over Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/danish-pm-comments-on-trump-greenland-remarks/106220382</link><description>Donald Trump says controlling Greenland is crucial for US national security and he has suggested using force to seize the Arctic territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef4a2cea03f103d8631bb44f11473c2b</guid></item><item><title>Key freight line reopens north of Port Pirie following 'complex' 97-hour operation to recover derailed wagons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/east-west-freight-back-online-after-port-pirie-derailment/106219496</link><description>A key part of a national freight route is operational again following a 97-hour operation to recover partially derailed wagons, after a derailment between Port Augusta and Port Pirie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b588429eaa5c0b1fd078ff2ff0fa4731</guid></item><item><title>Alexei Popyrin, Emerson Jones bow out of Adelaide International as Ajla Tomljanović advances</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/adelaide-international-emerson-jones-alja-tomljanovi%C4%87/106220998</link><description>Alexei Popyrin only made 68 per cent of his first serves and lost a crucial break point in the second set as he was defeated in straight sets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c75121d187336f5ef06a9ff630250cb1</guid></item><item><title>Herbal remedy ArmaForce causes severe reaction for Perth woman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/complementary-remedy-armaforce-causes-anaphylaxis-for-woman/106221004</link><description>A popular supplement linked to hundreds of adverse events is again in the spotlight after a Perth woman was hospitalised after taking over-the-counter herbal remedy ArmaForce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c50bc4d5e39f6187b8b4315906611a18</guid></item><item><title>Families wail beside bodies in Tehran as protests continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/families-wail-beside-bodies-in-tehran-as-protests-continue/106221416</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abed6ea834002c0348795339765fe74f</guid></item><item><title>Investigation underway after woman found dead at house in Buccan, south of Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/qld-buccan-death/106220552</link><description>An investigation is underway after a woman was found dead at a house in Buccan, south of Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb0fc25aeb7aceca9b3964a68a0f2a90</guid></item><item><title>Australian rookie Taylah Preston gets career-best win at Hobart International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/hobart-international-taylah-preston-wins/106221392</link><description>The 20-year-old wildcard, who is ranked 205 in the world, overpowered Spanish fifth seed Jéssica Bouzas Maneiro 6-4, 7-6 (7/4) in 88 minutes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">903dac19f250a87a333cc12ad65f1b9e</guid></item><item><title>Where to get financial assistance following Victorian 2026 bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/victoria-bushfire-disaster-relief-assistance/106220966</link><description>More help is promised to Victorians affected by devastating bushfires, including a $52,000 grant for eligible uninsured households.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c53adcf3f5b623aa65c6c917e4cd5458</guid></item><item><title>Future of Adelaide Writers' Week 'hangs in the balance' following removal of Randa Abdel-Fattah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/future-of-adelaide-writers-week-hangs-in-balance/106219462</link><description>The future of Adelaide Writers' Week (AWW) remains unclear as Palestinian Australian author Randa Abdel-Fattah says she is considering her legal options. Former New Zealand prime minister Jacinda Ardern is among those who will no longer appear at the event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5aedf8f189e3876c4765c6b69f3dec00</guid></item><item><title>Labor pledges fertility treatment rebates as SA state election nears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/labor-ivf-fertility-rebate-election-pledge/106220664</link><description>Families will be able to access fertility treatment rebates of up to $2,000 per cycle for two cycles, under a Labor promise announced ahead of the upcoming state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">116d5667504951553cec7771a9739dcb</guid></item><item><title>Why are people protesting in Iran? Mass anti-government demonstrations continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/why-are-people-protesting-in-iran/106219374</link><description>Thousands of Iranians have taken to the streets for more than a fortnight in protests against the country's government. Here's what to know about the situation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45556e0246ed4a11490f4754d5836a97</guid></item><item><title>Max Hobson identified as cattle farmer who died in Longwood fire near Seymour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/max-hobson-identified-fire-victim-longwood/106221240</link><description>Max Hobson has been identified as the person whose body was found metres from a car following the Longwood bushfire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ad3a0b03cad250830d05804c9dd21e3</guid></item><item><title>Imam thanks police after alleged roadside assault in Melbourne's south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/imam-thanks-police-after-alleged-roadside-assault-in-melbourne/106221398</link><description>An imam who was allegedly the victim of racial abuse during a roadside assault has thanked the police who helped him and his wife, and urged Australians to reject hate, Islamophobia and antisemitism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">200be2e64bb5aeddb1f5a64d8a99defc</guid></item><item><title>Health expert says 'it's a mystery' why WA is falling behind eastern states on illegal tobacco laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/wa-falls-behind-on-tobacco-laws/106220752</link><description>An eastern states public health expert says "it's a mystery" why Western Australia is lagging behind the rest of the country on updating its illicit tobacco laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">358d8c2802853d070f15372335116a6a</guid></item><item><title>Monday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106222016</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdc4747bb54a6011a9b1f6a58b50f143</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open qualifying: Bernard Tomic cruises through first round against Hugo Dellier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/australian-open-qualifying-day-one/106220762</link><description>Bernard Tomic looked in control throughout and comfortably moved his way into the second round of qualifying at Melbourne Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15eb5a61c8dfa9e865106cf8606013f2</guid></item><item><title>Couple heartbroken after new Harcourt home destroyed by Ravenswood fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/harcourt-couple-new-home-destroyed-in-ravenswood-fire/106221530</link><description>The couple was supposed to spend their first official night in the new home on Friday. It was destroyed by an out-of-control grassfire that afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d652307bb310cea84a321923c66cbb8</guid></item><item><title>NT government rejects Albanese's national gun buyback scheme over co-funding proposal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/nt-government-rejects-national-gun-buyback-scheme-over-funding/106221008</link><description>The Northern Territory government says it does not support the Commonwealth's proposed national gun buyback scheme, stating the territory should not have to share the cost 50:50.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f71817ef011a61cfc4957ccf6e04e3c</guid></item><item><title>Iran's blackout has sparked fears of what may be found in the aftermath. There is also hope for the return of Reza Pahlavi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/iran-is-in-blackout-reza-pahlavi-is-waiting-to-return-a-dynasty/106221764</link><description>Iranians have endured a blackout but for many the fears of atrocities committed by the Khamenei regime are real and based on reports of machine guns being used.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de9d705ebff82037ecd3d103138507b2</guid></item><item><title>Iran claims mass protests 'under total control' as human rights group says death toll has reached 648</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/iran-protests-under-control-says-tehran/106222170</link><description>Iran claims weeks of anti-government protests across the country have subsided, blaming the US and Israel for the violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb394f807acf2f6ab532f5d3b8f6626d</guid></item><item><title>Ex-tropical cyclone Koji slams North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/ex-tropical-cyclone-koji-slams-north-queensland/106221738</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86b24e5716b3819ed5e397de58b1ac96</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of structures destroyed in Victorian bushfires as locals assess damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/victorian-bushfires-longwood-walwa-harcourt-properties-destroyed/106221236</link><description>Some residents have returned home to take stock of the devastation. Meanwhile, authorities believe the Longwood fire was sparked by a trailer throwing sparks on the Hume Freeway</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e048bcc1aa16016b5cae12e824d2e534</guid></item><item><title>Iran cracks down on protesters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/iran-cracks-down-on-protesters/106221752</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53c0264087f2ef891d44f4b08d7d3780</guid></item><item><title>X AI Grok blocked in Indonesia and Malaysia over explicit image generation as UK launches probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/grok-ai-blocked-in-indonesia-malaysia-over-explicit-images/106222336</link><description>The AI platform championed by Elon Musk has come under significant criticism in recent weeks for its production of non-consensual images.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf127186097f455ae33bdfac74a2ff44</guid></item><item><title>Police post $1m reward 50 years after Eloise Worledge, 8, disappeared from Melbourne bedroom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/eloise-worledge-reward-missing-victoria-police/106221834</link><description>Fifty years after an eight-year-old girl vanished from her Beaumaris house, police increase their reward for information from $10,000 to $1 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71cb53cc6e65258b3bb9a87d48f6027e</guid></item><item><title>Daria Kasatkina and Thanasi Kokkinakis both advance after first round of Adelaide International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/daria-kasatkina-thanasi-kokkinakis-advance-in-adelaide/106222328</link><description>Daria Kasatkina defeated Greek wildcard Maria Sakkari in straight sets 7-6 (7-2) 6-4 on Monday, while Thanasi Kokkinakis beat American Sebastian Korda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">003b3efc57227a38f120990b371179f3</guid></item><item><title>The Gambia alleges Myanmar undertook a genocidal campaign against the Rohingya people at ICJ</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/the-gambia-myanmar-genocide-case-icj-the-hague/106222734</link><description>The case is being watched closely to see how the court might handle other genocide allegations against Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd52334e0c16656feeae42902157eb27</guid></item><item><title>Locals devastated as coolstore cooperative destroyed by Harcourt fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/coolstore-harcourt-fires-aftermath-ravenswood/106221066</link><description>More than 90 businesses used the coolstore in the central Victorian town of Harcourt to store wine, beer, apples, and other produce. Now it's gone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6875ea1c5920fd9a3cf7165e42aa1f7</guid></item><item><title>Greenland rejects American takeover 'under any circumstance'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/greenland-rejects-american-takeover/106222716</link><description>NATO allies are now scrambling to discuss beefing up Arctic security in the hope it deflects Donald Trump away from his intensifying rhetoric towards the island territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3237d31e34900596c234a790caeaf56</guid></item><item><title>Sail training ship 'Young Endeavour' docks in Hobart for the last time, as mission nears end</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/young-endeavour-final-hobart-trip-before-upgrade/106220818</link><description>For 38 years, it has been "changing young Australian lives one voyage at a time" — but now it is time for the Young Endeavour to make way for its successor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d23eacf992b8ee8a8ab35f4c099821c</guid></item><item><title>Geography quiz: How well do you know this wide, brown land?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/geography-quiz-/106213936</link><description>How well do you know this wide, brown land?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad7ef8ed5f607c66d79f1c0953c40345</guid></item><item><title>First Venezuela, then the US Fed — what the White House attacks mean for us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/venezuela-us-fed-white-house-donald-trump-attacks/106220958</link><description>In the past week, the US has dramatically expanded and accelerated its attacks both inside and outside its borders. Here's where Australia stands in the fray.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">610b383006c9008f2d0006423f55b606</guid></item><item><title>Gazans beg for shelter as winter storms batter millions and Israel limits aid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/gazans-beg-for-shelter-as-winter-storms-batter-millions/106205330</link><description>Homeless Gazans are begging the Israeli government to allow proper shelters into the strip as winter storms batter the enclave and destroy many people's tents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b26dfd5b27bbb77456772e5eed47af98</guid></item><item><title>Japan's journey from unlicensed 'baby hotels' to delivering restaurant-quality childcare food</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/how-japan-conquered-nutrition-in-childcare-centres/105893130</link><description>While Australia grapples with childcare scandals, Japan is delivering top-quality care with professional chefs serving up nutritious food. So how did they do it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">515f5c1b8a0c4dd2771e04d210ac32fe</guid></item><item><title>Elite female athletes speak out about struggles with body image and disordered eating</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/body-image-disordered-eating-elite-athletes-survey-results/106162622</link><description>Throughout her career, former ice dancer Matilda Friend struggled with disordered eating and felt pressure to look a certain way. ABC's Women's Sport survey shows she isn't the only one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67fc3738d69c6b117f73c7f94633e7e1</guid></item><item><title>Where to watch the Golden Globe winners, including One Battle After Another, Adolescence and Hamnet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/where-to-watch-golden-globe-winners-2026/106221328</link><description>The Golden Globes might be over but there are plenty of award-winning films and television to get caught up on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83ad5a93387a4fba1567a1c83e5d0a90</guid></item><item><title>Man charged over fatal stabbing at Mount Druitt as police release CCTV of hooded men</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/nsw-further-zac-mcrae-arrest/106222818</link><description>Police have released CCTV of three men dressed in dark hoodies, who they believe can assist with inquiries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2853f22858ba5a62eb94e94bd82508ae</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Writers' Week is in disarray — how did it reach this point?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/cancellation-of-randa-abdel-fattah-leaves-writers-week-in-doubt/106219608</link><description>The exclusion of novelist and academic Randa Abdel-Fattah from the upcoming Adelaide Writers' Week has prompted significant fallout in the form of withdrawals by other authors. Here's a look at how the events have unfolded, and how they could continue to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6138263c65230743904f225e557d70c1</guid></item><item><title>Alyssa Healy retiring from all cricket after upcoming series against India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/alyssa-healy-retiring-from-cricket-after-india-odi-series/106222846</link><description>Australia captain Alyssa Healy announces she will retire from all forms of cricket after a multi-format series against India in February and March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1472af2cb50650bf945a178b2824697</guid></item><item><title>Details of Labor's new hate speech and gun laws revealed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/details-of-new-hate-speech-gun-laws-revealed/106222256</link><description>Directly quoting from a religious text for the purpose of teaching or discussion may provide a defence under the federal government's hate speech laws proposed in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">657ebe71cbdb6dc5293d9f714f5e1f10</guid></item><item><title>How the Iranian regime uses the dead in its intimidation and propaganda machine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/iran-protest-deaths-regime-conditions-releasing-bodies/106220598</link><description>As images of rows and rows of dead bodies at a morgue in Tehran circulate, the regime is accused of making it impossible for families to grieve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f5e8c9788ae3e26f51b2caba725757d</guid></item><item><title>Waiting game for NSW border town as Victorian bushfires burn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/khancoban-smoke-victorian-bushfires/106219750</link><description>A town in the NSW Snowy Mountains is housing evacuees seeking refuge from the Victorian bushfires.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24f8b12c4d1fa8e581aa108f849d13a7</guid></item><item><title>Graziers call for action as government and Bureau of Meteorology point fingers over faulty rain gauges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/faulty-queensland-rain-gauges/106220168</link><description>Queensland graziers say they are being let down by under-resourced rain gauges during major floods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">031d1c9031589fa832d2d28c775e8044</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of ACT childcare documents show behind the scenes of embattled industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/act-thousands-childcare-documents-behind-the-scenes-industry/106221508</link><description>Never-before-seen documents reveal reports of sexual abuse, inappropriate educator discipline, and children missing from ACT childcare centres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e61c76dad4a791dd2d654d462706c47</guid></item><item><title>Fears fish protection measures could threaten Eden Creek Weir platypus population</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/eden-weir-fish-migration-measures-could-threaten-platypus/106173270</link><description>Landholders living alongside a northern NSW creek say a government plan to demolish a weir to improve fish migration will be devastating for the local platypus population.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88af25a46a06ef0d7ca4b63ba4e6428f</guid></item><item><title>Victorian fires live updates: Twelve major fires still burning as number of destroyed buildings climbs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/live-blog-victorian-bushfires-emergency-weather/106222152</link><description>Residents of the devastated Central Victorian township make a brief, escorted return to destroyed homes as firefighters continue to battle fires across the state, helped by cooler conditions. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">258ea72c0152586f2a8cd8e4ebbdda6b</guid></item><item><title>British and Irish dual citizens bear costly brunt of UK passport changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/australian-dual-citizens-bear-costly-brunt-of-uk-passport-change/106221062</link><description>British-Australian retiree Ian Fletcher is meant to be going on a seven-week holiday to the UK with his wife Vicki in April, but it may not go ahead due to passport changes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3d331283b8ac6dd3bc969442370a992</guid></item><item><title>Floodwaters have inundated the central Queensland town of Clermont</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/floodwaters-inundate-clermont/106222194</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d6b3f7e47dbc3f6743b48f983d60712</guid></item><item><title>Flood emergency warning continues for Clermont as ex-Cyclone Koji moves west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/flood-fears-as-ex-cyclone-koji-moves-west/106221118</link><description>A flood emergency warning remains in place for Clermont, as already-saturated western communities are being warned of possible heavy rains from ex-Cyclone Koji.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dcbfd2a6ef8cbd75145b47ecc7f1ce6</guid></item><item><title>Kevin Rudd to resign as Australian ambassador to Washington in March</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/kevin-rudd-ends-washington-posting/106222920</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese announces in Canberra that Mr Rudd will depart the role on March 31, a year before the posting was due to end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bfe4a52512f48c4cec28ee354aeb04e</guid></item><item><title>A national day of mourning for Bondi victims will be held on January 22, Albanese announces</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/national-day-of-mourning-january-22-bondi-victims/106222976</link><description>There will be a national day of mourning for the victims of the Bondi terror attack on January 22, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8f238352a3d2956fd270d8766843e52</guid></item><item><title>Live business news: Australian share market to rise, Wall Street rallies despite US Federal Reserve chair probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/asx-markets-business-live-news-jan13-2026/106222930</link><description>A rally on Wall Street is likely to send Australian stocks higher, as investors mostly brushed aside concerns about the US Justice Department's criminal investigation of Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell. Follow the latest updates in our live blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fcdc5b4bbb9d81984dc3ad25a8e3366</guid></item><item><title>ABC News report on Kings Cross erotic newspaper in 1971</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/erotic-newspaper-kings-cross-whisper/106223004</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eda543a517aa94eee6a63348332e3de3</guid></item><item><title>Satirical erotic newspaper discovered inside heritage Hobart hotel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/1970s-erotic-newspaper-found-in-hobart-hotel/106208900</link><description>A satirical and erotic newspaper from the 70s has been uncovered in the heritage-listed walls of a Hobart hotel. It shines a light on the underground media movement prevalent in conservative Australian culture in the mid-20th century.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d69c01fd0cb89e0c5c11646645519cf1</guid></item><item><title>Global financial system hangs in balance as Federal Reserve independence challenged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/us-federal-reserve-interest-rates-trump/106222076</link><description>A criminal probe into the US Federal Reserve chair threatens to undermine the US dollar and the global monetary system. Local analysts warn the implications for Australia are profound.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">977d0487074e76516bc24f98d4bb5b34</guid></item></channel></rss>