<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:47:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Family demands answers after patient with dementia found dead in river</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/walgett-family-heartache-after-death-of-patient-with-dementia/105861582</link><description>The family of a 73-year-old man, who was found dead in a river after leaving a New South Wales hospital, believes his death was preventable and that it has been let down by the medical system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">559f5a4ba430056c34fffc362113ec55</guid></item><item><title>Planetarium and observatory planned for Australia's only dark sky reserve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/river-murray-international-dark-sky-reserve-seeks-planetarium/105885452</link><description>Amid the global rise of "noctourism", the country's only officially listed dark sky reserve is working on an ambitious proposal for an underground planetarium and observatory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8302a3373ea1184cf83fd7462b5c0c1c</guid></item><item><title>WA neurosurgeon shortage delaying surgery for vulnerable spinal patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/perth-neurosurgeons-leading-to-delays-for-spinal-treatment/105709668</link><description>A Perth man's wait for surgery to treat painful pressure sores exposes delays and specialist shortages in Western Australia's spinal care system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed3e21f3d000d1ad436756bdde17f96e</guid></item><item><title>Dangerously Modern at the Art Gallery of New South Wales re-centres women in the history of Australian art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/dangerously-modern-exhibition-art-gallery-of-new-south-wales/105886336</link><description>At the turn of the century, Australian women artists travelled to Europe and returned with new styles and techniques. Their long-overlooked contribution to Australian art is celebrated in Dangerously Modern.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b9097ba58d930dd82435feeac3eff0b</guid></item><item><title>Australia looking for improvement in second Ashes Test, despite losing skipper Isaah Yeo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/roos-ready-to-roar-on-in-ashes-without-their-captain/105937008</link><description>Isaah Yeo's head knock will keep him out of the second Ashes Test with England but Australia is determined to improve, even without their inspirational leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9130aae2e71ce53fcacb9eba8ab54ecd</guid></item><item><title>Australian captain Pat Cummins out of first Ashes Test, will return to bowling this week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/pat-cummins-ruled-out-of-first-ashes-test/105937328</link><description>Pat Cummins is officially ruled out of the first Ashes Test against England, with Steve Smith named to step in as skipper in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c652c7853992ac952640d437f2fed3f</guid></item><item><title>Carbon credit profits used to fund restoration around UNESCO biosphere reserve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/fitz-stirling-corridor-restoration-with-carbon-credits-profits/105722304</link><description>A decades-long conservation project restoring vegetation between two renowned national parks could be accelerated using the carbon economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de970b2dfc8457c2ac7362f54eb03cd0</guid></item><item><title>Golden golfers a hit in the red dirt of this Broome backyard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/golden-golfers-hit-it-out-of-the-park-on-backyard-course/105931466</link><description>A daily round of golf and gardening in the red soils of Broome keeps this chipper couple on a healthy course.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4df98a09ffb2d22c7622d00fb2378805</guid></item><item><title>Coastal repairs underway for eroded beach on NSW far south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/surfside-beach-erosion-repairs-dredging-beach-scraping/105929262</link><description>Scientists hope the ocean current will help to replenish sand missing from a NSW beach decimated by recent storms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b603923a231337c5a230df22c60ba2f0</guid></item><item><title>Snow lands at low altitudes across Hobart suburbs and surrounding areas in 'uncommon' sight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/tas-snow-low-around-hobart-too-cold-for-tomatoes/105937192</link><description>Snow has fallen in Hobart suburbs, including Sandy Bay and Glenorchy, in a "relatively uncommon" sight, the weather bureau says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">536b18de4b3e5494b581b71bb5dd6b39</guid></item><item><title>Mum suffers 'chemical exposure' after moving into Housing Trust property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/housing-trust-meth-problems/105936030</link><description>An Adelaide mum says she and her son experienced wheezing, dry-retching and burning in the throat after moving into a drug-contaminated Housing Trust property she was told had been cleaned and maintained.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d81b5e919fa0692a79334dc93a488e3</guid></item><item><title>Northern hairy-nosed wombat joeys mark conservation success for rare Queensland animal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/conservation-success-for-rare-queensland-wombat/105934066</link><description>Three wild-born northern hairy-nosed wombats born in Powrunna State Forest mark a new chapter in the species' recovery from near extinction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e68d048f9a6286559c35c0d7fb94219d</guid></item><item><title>US says no federal food aid will go out from next month</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/us-federal-food-aid-stopping-november/105937556</link><description>The US Department of Agriculture says funds have run dry for its monthly food aid program, which more than 41 million Americans depend on to buy groceries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57b57132be7b1e6404739bda4da6692c</guid></item><item><title>Russia tests nuclear-powered Burevestnik cruise missile, Vladimir Putin wants to deploy it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/russia-tests-nuclear-powered-burevestnik-cruise-missile/105937742</link><description>Russia says the 9M730 Burevestnik "Storm Petrel" is "invincible" to current and future missile defences, with an almost unlimited range and unpredictable flight path.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3682d0a5b5c87ca1f6b85acc15235522</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne's AFLW dominance is a tide to lift all boats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/north-melbourne-aflw-dominance-and-success-a-good-thing/105937080</link><description>While some suggest that this year's AFLW premiers being all but known has caused some to lose interest, commentators say North Melbourne's dominance is inspirational.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">335c6b92348194b0870ec521f6919778</guid></item><item><title>Senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price denies involvement in 'coup' to overthrow central land council CEO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/jacinta-nampijinpa-price-defamation-trial-land-council-boss/105937412</link><description>Senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price has denied being involved in a leadership "coup" to remove the chief executive of the Central Land Council while giving evidence in the Federal Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d1d952cf596571e82aefca05c5f1304</guid></item><item><title>Woman killed after two cars smash into Perth CBD building in Hay Street</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/woman-critical-after-perth-cbd-crash-in-hay-st/105938338</link><description>A woman is killed when two cars smash into an office building in Perth's central business district.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cfe0617f9e0f5e5130de4e348007622</guid></item><item><title>Spirit of Tasmania operator sent wrong fender specs, leading to $9 million ferry fix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/spirit-of-tasmania-fender-error-9-million-dollar-fix/105917002</link><description>The head of Tasmania's state-owned ferry operator blames "human error" for a berth problem that needs a $9 million fix and modification to the hulls of the two new Spirit of Tasmania ships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8840425c9caf922aa890ec5754f4572d</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with domestic violence offence after Gold Coast crash that killed 3yo boy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/man-denied-bail-after-crash-that-killed-three-year-old-boy/105937646</link><description>A man arrested following the death of a boy in a Gold Coast car crash remains in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c80586ce639c4fc1d18a3d56c4bf4cba</guid></item><item><title>Who is Catherine Connolly, Ireland's new left-leaning, independent president-elect?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/irish-president-catherine-connolly-left-wing-independent-/105937490</link><description>The 68-year-old former barrister is known for being one of the leading pro-Palestinian voices in the Irish parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c146f44190fe609d309fd832757a120a</guid></item><item><title>As South-East Asia reels from tariffs, Donald Trump's flashy 'peace' deal falls short</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/trump-s-flashy-peace-deal-falls-in-short-south-east-asia/105937684</link><description>The US president, who is on a lightning tour of South-East Asia this week, casts a long shadow in the region. But even as he signs deals, nations are contemplating a future without him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">561a3f5c774016694bbebec7813b784f</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri loses F1 lead, but hope remains in his battles against Lando Norris and Max Verstappen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/oscar-piastri-f1-championship-battle-lando-norris-max-verstappen/105896154</link><description>Oscar Piastri has lost his lead in the Formula 1 drivers' championship. Despite momentum working against the Australian, there are still plenty of reasons to believe he can win the world title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a3dc10cd0a69d64210c5198b4bc41dd</guid></item><item><title>Courtroom filled with disgust for Hannah McGuire's killer, Lachlan Young</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/lachlan-young-hannah-mcguire-pre-sentence-hearing/105937608</link><description>Loved ones of Victorian woman Hannah McGuire looked on with shock as a prosecutor told the Supreme Court of her 2024 murder and the events leading up to it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0033dbf829596c623c924a11669c6eb</guid></item><item><title>NSW inquiry into unsolved murders, missing persons will divert police resources, Homicide Squad chief says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/nsw-inquiry-unsolved-murders-to-divert-police-resources/105938468</link><description>NSW Police Force Homicide Squad boss Joe Doueihi is concerned the state parliamentary inquiry will create an "excessive or extra workload" for investigators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b26227da4324ed8a1c35d25552f5f747</guid></item><item><title>Search for missing hang-glider pilot near Pacific Palms on NSW Mid North Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/search-for-missing-hang-glider-near-pacific-palms/105938200</link><description>Authorities are searching a vast stretch of the Mid North Coast where the man was seen losing altitude on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4c15c76dedc42e3420eab498dca1229</guid></item><item><title>What do we know about the investigation into the jewel heist at the Louvre?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/louvre-museum-heist-suspects-arrest-explainer/105937020</link><description>What do we know about the investigation into the jewel heist at the Louvre and what are some of the possible consequences?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef0d91db1ef53761176bab16ee15626f</guid></item><item><title>Cost-of-living crisis and 'weight of the world' means we're socialising less than ever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/decline-in-socialising-rates-impacting-our-wellbeing/105865064</link><description>Data from the latest HILDA survey indicate socialising rates have dropped over the past two decades, and, more recently, have not returned to pre-COVID frequency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f951e2d72f61ad15c8286e0e578eec68</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese raised concerns over 'unsafe' military encounter with Chinese premier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/albanese-chinese-premier-military-encounter/105938890</link><description>Anthony Albanese sat down with Premier Li Qiang — China's second most senior leader — on the sidelines of the ASEAN meeting in Kuala Lumpur on Monday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d652b34fd1cf7a1f9e0089fb86ceb461</guid></item><item><title>WA tops State of the States economic performance report, despite weak economic growth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/wa-tops-economic-performace-report/105938214</link><description>Western Australia again secures the top gong as Australia's best performing economy according to a new report by the Commonwealth Bank, despite the state recording some of the country's weakest economic growth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f2d994b134f9fb71852cd5b8f3b4b4b</guid></item><item><title>The NuvaRing contraceptive is going on the PBS. Here's how that may impact you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/nuvaring-going-on-pbs-from-november-1-expained/105938344</link><description>Including the NuvaRing on the PBS will slash the cost of contraception for tens of thousands of Australians by around two-thirds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd37cb390e553909164065dd802acebb</guid></item><item><title>The Western democratic world is at a 'civilisational moment'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/john-anderson-boyer-lecture-democracy/105937514</link><description>In his 2025 Boyer Lecture, former deputy prime minister John Anderson reflects on democracy and the end of the liberal global order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d15cbd4e99378b82bf4285e2366df73</guid></item><item><title>Four teenagers plead guilty to manslaughter over deadly Warrawong brawl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/warrawong-brawl-teens-plead-guilty-manslaughter/105939298</link><description>Four teenage girls have pleaded guilty to the manslaughter of Kristie McBride, who was fatally stabbed during a street brawl in Warrawong near Wollongong in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a26803388d07ccbe88e31a4e7f149a95</guid></item><item><title>California Governor Gavin Newsom to consider 2028 US presidential run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/california-governor-gavin-newsom-2028-us-presidential-run/105939000</link><description>The California Governor says he will make a decision after the 2026 midterm elections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f2ee686c0e73a115d3efa6780f7437e</guid></item><item><title>Australia's crumbling childcare safeguards put kids at risk. How can parents make sure they are safe?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/checking-safety-of-childcare-centres-parents-four-corners/105931674</link><description>The scale of Australia's childcare crisis is deeply distressing for parents. These are the simple questions to ask any childcare provider to know if your child is safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a7e1f6c81a2491a7cc8a9c98bd3c4a8</guid></item><item><title>Environmental watchdog drops charges against company responsible for burning Kealba landfill fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/kealba-landfill-fire-charges-dropped/105926760</link><description>A company responsible for a tip that has been on fire for nearly six years may be allowed to keep its landfill licence, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f535c02cd2782fb95a28530dce2d8fb1</guid></item><item><title>Arnold Schwarzenegger accuses US states of trying to 'out-cheat' each other under Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/arnold-schwarzenegger-criticises-surge-in-gerrymandering/105939400</link><description>Former California governor Arnold Schwarzenegger has expressed concern over the "crazy gerrymandering" that is taking place across the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">098d062f73db15abc818799307f668dc</guid></item><item><title>Why Cam Green staying at No.3 could help get the best out of Steve Smith during the 2025/26 Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/cameron-green-steve-smith-no-3-ashes/105895392</link><description>With Cam Green and Steve Smith shaping as the mostly likely candidates to be selected as Australia's No.3 for this summer's Ashes, selectors face a choice between pragmatism and tradition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a24e1615df4a3d0f5970efa8bbca9252</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of lighting Mount Gambier Valley Lake bushfire while wearing mask and cape denied bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/man-accused-of-lighting-mount-gambier-bushfire-denied-bail/105938734</link><description>Police allege a 37-year-old man lit six fires at Valley Lake, near Mount Gambier, at night while wearing a silver cape and a black mask, after allegedly stealing a cask of wine from a liquor store.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a67ad0e1ac6907998e7c2eca7e5000d</guid></item><item><title>Joshua Berrigan sentenced to 10 years' jail for fatal one-punch attack on Nathan McPherson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/joshua-trevor-berrigan-sentenced-for-maryborough-assault/105937194</link><description>The family of a 43-year-old one-punch attack victim told his killer their lives "have been shattered beyond recognition" during an emotional Queensland court hearing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ac42e4d501c26f63226d7a933811de9</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after Darwin priest stabbed in face with pen while setting up for mass</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/man-charged-with-stabbing-darwin-priest-in-face-with-pen/105937868</link><description>Police charge a 38-year-old man who allegedly stabbed a Darwin priest in the face with a pen while he was setting up for evening mass.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a2edc4c98da0e14fddf35ee83bc56f2</guid></item><item><title>Police scale back search for man missing in waters off Mornington</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/mornington-boat-capsize-missing-man-search-scaled-back/105939572</link><description>The family of a man who was on a small boat that capsized on Friday night say they are mourning the loss of their uncle, brother and friend, as police scale back their search.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6af5532ce13e55d879f276780e6775ed</guid></item><item><title>Argentina's Javier Milei wins in decisive midterms as Trump loan looms large</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/javier-milei-wins-argentina-midterm-elections/105939600</link><description>Argentina's libertarian President Javier Milei has won decisive victories in the midterm elections, in an election where Donald Trump loomed large.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a40f1ae4089cfd4b458c56a0bc2369cb</guid></item><item><title>Fans miss Diljit Dosanjh's Western Sydney concert over 'hurtful' religious dagger ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/nsw-diljit-dosanjh-sikh-concert-denied-entry-kirpan/105938442</link><description>Concertgoers who had tickets to see an Indian music superstar have been offered a refund after refusing to leave their Sikh dagger at the gate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51523a1957e4531d00a35c5428059782</guid></item><item><title>Neo-Nazi leader Thomas Sewell claims Ballarat rally was political but not offensive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/sewell-contest-hearing-ballarat-rally-political-not-offensive/105931344</link><description>Photos and videos shown to a Victorian court capture a racially charged speech given by Thomas Sewell before he leads a group of 30 masked men through Ballarat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb75038daf38909906d975bfff5fd8d2</guid></item><item><title>RBA governor Bullock says a severe market downturn would raise financial stability concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/rba-governor-michele-bullock-interest-rates-jobless-rate/105937584</link><description>The Reserve Bank governor tells a Sydney gathering of economists she and her overseas counterparts are perplexed by what they call "sanguine" financial markets. They question is whether it will "all end in tears".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8efa2e944fb48aa5c5aaf377c3f93f8</guid></item><item><title>Lithuania vows to shoot down Belarus smuggler balloons disrupting air traffic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-27/lithuania-plans-belarus-border-close-after-balloon-disruptions/105940242</link><description>Lithuania has drawn up plans to shut its border crossings with Belarus indefinitely, after the capital's airport was repeatedly disrupted by suspected sightings of balloons carrying contraband cigarettes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9abdd16c842c60a8da3dea3b6470f7a3</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says he 'would love' third term but rules out running for vice-president in 2028</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/trump-third-term-rules-out-vice-president-run/105940570</link><description>US President Donald Trump has ruled out running for vice-president in 2028, which some supporters have suggested could see him circumvent a constitutional bar against serving a third term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c29b604ecb04a1ba3674f0356bc983d</guid></item><item><title>Katy Perry and Justin Trudeau seen holding hands leaving Paris club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/trudeau-katy-perry-make-public-appearance-paris/105940684</link><description>The pair's public appearance on the pop singer's 41st birthday has added fuel to growing speculation the two are in a relationship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91fba639c6303162ad42f90dadb2f5d7</guid></item><item><title>Top firefighters warn West Gate Tunnel not safe until proper checks completed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/west-gate-tunnel-concerns-top-firefighters/105939060</link><description>Victoria's emergency services are unprepared for critical incidents in Melbourne's soon-to-be-opened West Gate Tunnel, senior firefighters warn.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb1c8717b33f8edec6bb0a943d868867</guid></item><item><title>Is it cheaper to end poverty than to maintain it? Research says yes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/cheaper-to-end-poverty-increase-jobseeker-than-maintain-hardship/105866692</link><description>In 2020, Australia massively increased welfare payments and conducted a live experiment in ending poverty, but when the subsidy was removed, many were thrown back into hardship. Leaving aside the moral dimension, would it be cheaper to end poverty than to maintain it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ca77a25ae7095974ca495e31dc9edef</guid></item><item><title>Israeli families wait for release of remaining hostages in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/israeli-families-wait-for-release-of-remaining-hostages-in-gaza/105940792</link><description>The father of one of the dead hostages still in Gaza says he does not trust Hamas's assurances it is doing all it can to find and return the remains of Israelis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abf488d7377a0c66ae1efe970c587608</guid></item><item><title>On the dark web, paedophiles are sharing tips on how to abuse children in child care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/paedophiles-share-childcare-abuse-tips-on-dark-web/105938932</link><description>Paedophiles are using the dark web to share information about how to gain access to childcare centres to sexually abuse babies and toddlers while avoiding getting caught.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3aed303c63fed183ebd546d6b76cd191</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu has rejected 'Bibi-sitting' claims but the US is watching Israel closely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/netanyahu-rejects-us-babysitting-claims-israel-gaza-war/105937532</link><description>Some of the most senior officials from the US arriving in Israel has prompted some to re-imagine the phrase "Bibi-sitting" — and question the motive behind it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57904ffb8efde08aebd45780655306d5</guid></item><item><title>Netanyahu's 'Bibi-sitter' advertisement for 2015 Israeli election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/netanyahu-s-bibi-sitter-advertisement/105937578</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae8e2b46469870817bef75534adad015</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew and Sarah Ferguson labelled 'hypocrites' by royal biographer over connection to Jeffrey Epstein</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/prince-andrew-sarah-ferguson-hypocrites-andrew-lownie/105931454</link><description>Prince Andrew is a "hypocrite" who believes he is above the law, according to author Andrew Lownie, who has written an unauthorised biography on the under siege royal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e296fb84b332a46f2f8835a9d8ad3db</guid></item><item><title>Russia's interest in Antarctic oil exposed after Ukrainian scientist's arrest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/antarctic-marine-protection-areas-impact-russia-hydrocarbon/105938976</link><description>A document linked to the arrest of a scientist has raised questions about whether Russia has long-term ambitions to exploit oil resources in Antarctica, where mining is banned indefinitely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bb663f99dcb6657381a041abca8d0b6</guid></item><item><title>Kids 'left in the dark' in family law matters, as Family Court of Australia makes new commitment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/impact-of-family-court-matters-on-kids-childrens-charter/105910866</link><description>Sally's legal battle in the Federal Circuit and Family Court of Australia may be years long gone, but the trauma of the experience lingers — especially on her eldest child.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8731e58a0356852552419ca9a4910e77</guid></item><item><title>Labor has pivoted from health to housing. How will SA voters respond?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/labor-pivots-from-health-to-housing-ahead-of-sa-election/105938990</link><description>If Labor’s 2022 campaign was all about ambulance patients locked out of hospitals, then 2026 is all about young people locked out of home ownership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f26c47e1d6e839ea1aeaf57064be0a4</guid></item><item><title>Survivors of paedophile teacher Peter Farmer sue Victorian Education Department</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/peter-farmer-victims-sue-education-department/105926948</link><description>Victims of a paedophile who used children's artwork to hide abuse are suing the Victorian Education Department, alleging his abuse should have been stopped earlier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">531bd3ddffcdb349ac04adee4c1b0180</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government drops special flood measures in Woolloongabba ahead of 2032 Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/qld-flood-protection-measures-droppedwoollongabba-development/105935510</link><description>Experts say changes by the Queensland government could ease construction costs by removing what the property industry describe as "unnecessary" restrictions, while residents could be left wearing the fallout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7f4006ffe5a9b63d878a5b80be78610</guid></item><item><title>Matildas to face England in Derby in first clash since Women's World Cup semi-final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/broken-hearted-matildas-after-revenge-against-england/105940904</link><description>Ella Toone's goal helped England break Australian hearts at the 2023 Women's World Cup. She knows, and Steph Catley admits, the Matildas are out for "revenge".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81bfba08e900809f5dc1c0de4bfc969d</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Labor declares 'nothing is off the table' in talks over Tomago smelter bailout — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/federal-politics-live-blog-oct-28/105939716</link><description>The defence industry minister says the federal government is fighting to keep the struggling Tomago smelter open, declaring every option is being considered to save the facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8fae252b9773e8f4218227f834852be</guid></item><item><title>Why the RBA should put a handbrake on property prices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/melbourne-cup-day-rba-rates-decision-could-lift-property-prices/105938524</link><description>Whether or not we're delivered a rate cut next Tuesday, there's a solid argument that the RBA should once again consider using its powers to curb runaway real estate prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93170051998f0e302a581b4d8a41f3f0</guid></item><item><title>Alexei Popyrin loses to Alexander Bublik in Paris, before Australian snubbed for post-match handshake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/mixed-fortunes-for-australians-seeking-success-at-paris-masters/105940968</link><description>Alexei Popyrin is knocked out of the Paris Masters, while the victorious Alexander Bublik walks off court without acknowledging the Australian.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df41c4ba137fa0306441bfa90b820ff4</guid></item><item><title>Brain cancer patient's tumour growth halted after immunotherapy identified by molecular testing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/brain-cancer-tumour-halted-after-molecular-testing-immunotherapy/105915842</link><description>Emma's brain tumour has stopped growing since she gained access to a type of immunotherapy identified by molecular testing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cc63e408f400690424e5a35e6861b21</guid></item><item><title>WA Governor Chris Dawson to apologise to traditional owners for Pinjarra Massacre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/pinjarra-massacre-wa-governor-chris-dawson-apologises/105939422</link><description>The descendants of people who were murdered in one of Western Australia's most brutal attacks on Aboriginal people — the Pinjarra Massacre — are set to hear an apology from the WA governor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f88ec26f944f951a2cc814e3a6f3c8c</guid></item><item><title>Families of WWI soldiers will be reunited with century-old letters discovered on WA beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/world-war-one-message-in-bottle-family-found/105939652</link><description>Family members of two World War I soldiers have been left stunned after a bottle containing hand-written letters was found on a WA beach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c773cce206a320a0941cf0a0b2197c90</guid></item><item><title>Athletes call for climate change action as Adapt2win campaign launched ahead of Cop30</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/athletes-call-for-climate-action-ahead-of-cop30/105941094</link><description>Ahead of next month's COP30 in Brazil, sports stars from around the world have helped to launch a campaign urging for action on climate change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edf8fb9aabfd75a9749eb24d0b38c925</guid></item><item><title>Fears planned salt work expansion could threaten internationally significant wetlands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/lake-macleod-salt-production-wetland-damage/105918200</link><description>There are concerns plans to expand salt mining operations on a wetland that stretches from Carnarvon to the Ningaloo Coast could cause environmental damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b760aa51c078007203c30824e866ed09</guid></item><item><title>WiseTech offices searched by AFP and ASIC over share trading allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/wisetech-office-searched-by-afp-asic/105941382</link><description>WiseTech says it was required to produce documents related to alleged trading in WiseTech shares by controversial co-founder Richard White and three employees from late 2024 to early 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">800ce288d12e9f6c789ff67dd1693776</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian couple takes on new adventure as caretakers of the Low Isles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/tasmanian-couple-moves-far-north-queensland-low-isles-caretakers/105930024</link><description>Life as the caretaker of a tropical island includes gardening and plenty of birdwatching, but the job is not all glamorous.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdb5e0d7b86e57891b60895747f73a14</guid></item><item><title>Trade key to peace in region: Don Farrell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/trade-key-to-peace-in-region-don-farrell/105941156</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82a7e40386107daa9c88aaecacc429ae</guid></item><item><title>Dogs filmed at wombat burrows in San Remo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/dogs-filmed-at-wombat-burrows-in-san-remo/105927096</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036b52981395d6e43d9ec7018dfb2183</guid></item><item><title>San Remo wombats under threat from dogs and development, conservationists say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/wombats-development-san-remo-dogs/105863602</link><description>Conservationists say wombats on Victoria's Bass Coast are under threat from off-leash dogs that have been spotted entering their coastal burrows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93c028c78c6ba730efb6ec9c496c7f41</guid></item><item><title>Massage therapist banned after sexually assaulting four clients in Orange</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/massage-therapist-banned-after-sexual-assault-of-clients/105941310</link><description>The Health Care Complaints Commission found the therapist would pose a "significant and unacceptable risk" to the public if he kept practising.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a31718a8d710ab5cf42ab76b04fed0c</guid></item><item><title>Plans to install cameras to capture moment Robe obelisk falls into the sea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/camera-to-show-robe-obelisk-as-it-erodes-into-sea/105920268</link><description>A seaside landmark will be lost to the ocean, and the council is hoping to catch the moment on camera.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bbd9a24474cbf0cd601d0b2677d2ced</guid></item><item><title>Google joins Microsoft in plans to restart US nuclear plants to power AI infrastructure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/google-microsoft-restarting-nuclear-plants-for-ai-power/105941378</link><description>Google has announced a nuclear facility shuttered in 2020 will return to service in 2029 to help power its "growing cloud and AI infrastructure in Iowa", a year after Microsoft signed on to reopen Three Mile Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">833085a25799fa233ff5a327aaf39d4f</guid></item><item><title>At least eight Queensland state high schools taught wrong topic for year 12 exam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/brisbane-school-apologies-teaching-wrong-topic/105941574</link><description>The state's education minister has ordered an investigation into the blunder, which was initially believed to affect one school, before that number grew.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">108fa1e8a6054989612ac2fe21de8006</guid></item><item><title>NSW government's drug summit response rejects medicinal cannabis defence for drivers for now</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/nsw-government-drug-summit-response-cannabis/105941584</link><description>The government says it was "investigating" a medical defence for drivers prescribed cannabis but ruled out the use of sniffer dogs and strip searches for suspected drug possession at music festivals in its response to last year's drug summit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a947513c37d9ffbc448fecfb8fed4dd5</guid></item><item><title>Celtic manager Brendan Rodgers quits, leaving possible opening for Ange Postecoglou</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/celtic-manager-brendan-rodgers-quits-postecoglou-speculation/105941616</link><description>Ange Postecoglou's name will inevitably be linked to a Celtic return after Brendan Rodgers resigns his post as manager of the struggling Scottish giants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d10900999e79b05451b3cc68e9ccbae</guid></item><item><title>First NZYQ cohort member deported to Nauru under opaque deal potentially worth billions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/first-nzyq-member-deported-to-nauru/105919846</link><description>Australia could end up paying the tiny island nation about $2.5 billion over three decades if the more than 350 former detainees are successfully resettled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28731859dc481725486f37eb09c5a470</guid></item><item><title>Venezuela accuses US of plotting false-flag operation in Caribbean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/venezuela-accuses-us-of-plotting-false-flag-operation/105941884</link><description>Venezuela says it has thwarted what it calls a CIA-linked plot to attack a US warship anchored in Trinidad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5750ffc1db6527fad23687e677ec14e9</guid></item><item><title>School strikes in Tasmania's north-west as public sector workers walk off the job</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/tas-public-sector-teacher-strikes-tuesday/105941232</link><description>Teachers, health workers and firefighters have walked off the job in Tasmania's north-west, with further stop-work action planned in other parts of the state over the next two days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfcb1fbe76d1674fee0f5088fa8a969c</guid></item><item><title>Teens with disabilities are worried about the social media ban becoming another barrier in their lives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/teens-with-disabilities-are-worried-about-the-social-media-ban/105941076</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ff3f1e9982b46897b5efd86c9a19742</guid></item><item><title>How the under-16s social media ban will impact teens with disabilities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/how-the-social-media-ban-will-impact-teens-with-a-disability/105929756</link><description>Teens with disabilities say they might end up losing contact with friends and online communities due to being banned from social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0180c7f683f1a01f1b62cd2289eaa125</guid></item><item><title>Supreme Court in Brisbane overturns controversial freeze on puberty blockers for adolescents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/qld-puberty-blockers-ban-overturned-by-court/105942094</link><description>Queensland controversially barred public doctors from prescribing puberty blockers to patients aged under 18 earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e442945a6f745dfc7a383410ba1c6e98</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Swans AFLW star Chloe Molloy to have season-ending back surgery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/back-surgery-ends-aflw-season-for-swans-star-molloy/105942446</link><description>Sydney will be without co-captain Chloe Molloy for the rest of the AFLW season in a major setback as their finals hopes hang in the balance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edc63b371a1f1dc351daa6a9307e23ae</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with vandalism after gas services cut at Sutherland hospitals in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/nsw-sutherland-hospital-woman-charged-after-gas-services-cut/105942328</link><description>A 42-year-old woman has been charged after water and gas mains were cut at two hospitals in what the NSW health minister says could have been a "catastrophic" incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58ff5f750f84d1871638d823b014e292</guid></item><item><title>Australia to form part of Pacific 'taskforce' set to stir regional controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/australia-part-of-pacific-taskforce-with-expanded-remit/105942604</link><description>A group of Pacific nations created to respond to humanitarian catastrophes will have an expanded remit, including "stabilisation" missions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a47b589c3c58957201d33264fa00d9b4</guid></item><item><title>Peter George, Greens lose faith in Rockliff government over promised Tasmanian salmon industry study</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/tas-peter-george-complaints-over-promised-salmon-review/105941524</link><description>A strong critic of Tasmania's salmon industry says the Liberal government has "ambushed" those who supported it to remain in power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af175cf57900fe607a3f819d85dcabd8</guid></item><item><title>Canberra Liberals suspend backbenchers Elizabeth Lee and Peter Cain from party room</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/act-elizabeth-lee-peter-cain-suspended-from-canberra-liberals/105943098</link><description>Canberra Liberals leader Leanne Castley has immediately suspended Elizabeth Lee and Peter Cain from the party room, and is seeking to remove them permanently.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">768cb3f92652476be62d0cb99cc3d774</guid></item><item><title>Tom Trbojevic signs one-year contract extension with Manly Sea Eagles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/tom-trbojevic-signs-one-year-contract-extension-with-sea-eagles/105943060</link><description>Tom Trbojevic's contract saga with Manly is over after the superstar fullback agreed to a one-year deal that will keep him at the NRL club until the end of 2027.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">888494d38c40416d1e43b6771feed4f3</guid></item><item><title>Japan and US sign deal on rare earths as new Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi goes on 'charm offensive'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/trump-japan-takaichi-trade-rare-earths-defense-meeting/105942246</link><description>US President Donald Trump visits Japan and signs a framework agreement for securing the supply of critical minerals and rare earths through mining and processing with Japan Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abdc1a4c49b10f7d8e8c22f44f3bf118</guid></item><item><title>Hannah McGuire's killer Lachlan Young stares blankly during minute's silence in the Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/lachlan-young-hannah-mcguire-murder-plea-hearing-continues/105942836</link><description>In a rarely-seen move, a Victorian judge halts proceedings in the Supreme Court to hold a minute's silence for a domestic violence murder victim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9de07ddf78331f913cd1fdec3d956d4d</guid></item><item><title>Man jailed for paying teen for sex and intimate images in the Kimberley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/terence-forrest-sentence-broome-court-child-exploitation/105938506</link><description>A 44-year-old man is sentenced after paying a teenage girl he met online for sex and distributing intimate images of her without her knowledge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d0a98e78b7fe71bb708b8bb0d2fb9bb</guid></item><item><title>Senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price accused of 'using her position' to defame Central Land Council boss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/jacinta-nampijinpa-price-defamation-trial-lesley-turner/105941218</link><description>Jacinta Nampijinpa Price has been accused of "using her position" to "promote" false claims about Central Land Council chief executive Lesley Turner, on the final day of her civil defamation trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">562b6efa48a883ef5add284ebecebb4b</guid></item><item><title>Farm owner cleared of all charges over worker's electrocution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/nathan-luke-stevens-cleared-after-pineapple-farm-electrocution/105124190</link><description>The owner of a pineapple farm charged over the death of a 25-year-old worker has successfully appealed his conviction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52fa24fc4e3bf3f5aca3d88ebadca4db</guid></item><item><title>NRL stands down South Sydney Rabbitohs winger Tyrone Munro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/nrl-stands-down-south-sydney-rabbitohs-winger-tyrone-munro/105943160</link><description>South Sydney's Tyrone Munro faces being sidelined for at least the start of next season, after being stood down by the NRL while facing domestic violence charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f9c85f3d85d1197adab702be2f732c4</guid></item><item><title>A higher-than-expected inflation figure would put the Reserve Bank in quite a spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/hotter-than-expected-inflation-would-put-rba-in-difficult-spot/105942718</link><description>If the September quarter consumer price index comes in higher than expected, it could postpone home loan relief for borrowers and create a dilemma for the RBA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0002c758b360cf1dec226e108c794075</guid></item><item><title>Nicole Kidman, Baz Lurhmann open Vogue World in tribute to old Hollywood glamour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/all-the-best-looks-from-vogue-world-hollywood/105941592</link><description>From a Nicole Kidman "revenge" dress to a dressing-gown tuxedo, these are all of the best Hollywood-style looks at this year's Vogue World event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a52b4ce3ba84e9539dec0adf0b363f71</guid></item><item><title>Castley says Liberal backbenchers have the opportunity to cross the floor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/castley-liberal-backbenchers-have-opportunity-cross-floor/105943596</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">188aba645ae0d811ce6c422487f07354</guid></item><item><title>What loving someone with an addiction or dependence can look like</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/loving-someone-with-an-addiction-or-dependence/105921866</link><description>An expert says it can be lonely caring for or supporting someone living with a dependence or addiction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca602d572cd427c90eb9368e2d97cfbc</guid></item><item><title>Magistrate finds Neo-Nazi leader Thomas Sewell not guilty of offensive behaviour over Ballarat rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/thomas-sewell-not-guilty-of-offensive-behaviour/105941348</link><description>A Victorian Magistrate says he has not been convinced that Thomas Sewell's behaviour during a 2023 Neo-Nazi rally in Ballarat was offensive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">388a581f2499869b743c7d2cb8af0df1</guid></item><item><title>Minister defends cost blowout for new eight-bed hospital in outback WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/cost-of-laverton-eight-bed-hospital-blows-out/105942844</link><description>John Carey has defended a decision to press on with the construction of a new eight-bed hospital in outback WA after costs blew out to $63.6 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b71cab8e63fcad06c73adf821aa115e</guid></item><item><title>WA Governor Chris Dawson apologises to descendants of Pinjarra Massacre, almost 200 years later</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/wa-governor-chris-dawson-apologises-for-pinjarra-massacre/105942492</link><description>Gathering on sacred land where their ancestors were slain in one of the most brutal attacks on Aboriginal people in Western Australia, Traditional Owners hear the word it took almost 200 years to say — "sorry".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6944ed971d79858d0748ea90bc9534d3</guid></item><item><title>WA Governor Chris Dawson apologises to traditional owners for Pinjarra Massacre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/wa-governor-chris-dawson-apologises-for-pinjarra-massacre/105943326</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c04e236efedc21eeeaeaca39ddd82dca</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government criticises timing of changes to Bureau of Meteorology website in aftermath of storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/qld-government-criticises-changes-to-bom-website/105943192</link><description>On Sunday, south-east Queensland was lashed by a severe thunderstorm, which left thousands still without power. The state government says the timing of upgrades to BOM's website was "not good enough".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4205236a2ccb0692da69355c403c61ae</guid></item><item><title>Australia wicketkeeper Alex Carey at peace with Ashes stumping infamy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/alex-carey-at-peace-with-ashes-run-out-infamy/105943578</link><description>Australia wicketkeeper Alex Carey says he wants to be part of more Ashes history, after being central to one of the most infamous moments during the previous series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">339e7dafb44389a67a2b322e7b861e34</guid></item><item><title>Australians with oral cancer forced to drain super or remortgage homes to pay for dental prosthetics because of funding gap</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/why-dental-prosthetics-arent-covered-after-cancer/105924804</link><description>Australians with oral cancer are being left tens of thousands of dollars out of pocket to cover dental prosthetics because of a gap in funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60943ecdcd6f2361e293072e625255ec</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds captain Liz Watson confident New Zealand losing run can end in fourth Test of Constellation Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/australia-diamonds-captain-liz-watson-constellation-cup-four/105944136</link><description>The Diamonds are "trusting the process" as they prepare for the Constellation Cup-deciding netball clash against the Silver Ferns in Christchurch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f08062ea8490801aa0f5cf71fa771171</guid></item><item><title>Mother repeatedly sedated with 'extremely high' doses before death, inquest hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/kumanjayi-brogus-ungwanaka-inquest-sedative-death-alice-springs/105938102</link><description>An emergency doctor has told an inquest into the death of an Alice Springs mother of three the tragedy "would not have happened" in Queensland and could have been avoided.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e77cb8cbb851e9bc05e07468be14c72</guid></item><item><title>Queensland man Za'id Abdus Samad sentenced over 2018 terror charges, weeks after murder conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/qld-zaid-abdus-samad-sentenced-terror-charges/105943018</link><description>Za'id Adbus Samad has been sentenced to six years imprisonment over terrorism charges less than a month after being handed a life sentence for the murder of his uncle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d1914735e7c34c0bec943791a21c4b6</guid></item><item><title>World Series 2025: LA Dodgers win game three, Shohei Ohtani 119-year first, Freddie Freeman home run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/world-series-game-three-shohei-ohtani-la-dodgers/105943346</link><description>Los Angeles Dodgers' star Shohei Ohtani has completed one of the greatest individual performances in the World Series game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02cf16ffbcafdac235f09fed3a917db1</guid></item><item><title>Japan's Shinzo Abe assassin pleads guilty in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/japan-shinzo-abe-assassin-pleads-guilty-in-court/105944482</link><description>A man accused of killing Japan's former prime minister Shinzo Abe has pleaded guilty, three years after the assassination in broad daylight shocked the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16b7d3c10336d54b5c717118e7e3d9cf</guid></item><item><title>Leaders pinpoint solutions needed to end Kununurra youth crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/kununurra-community-leaders-frustrated-youth-crime/105943196</link><description>Frustrated community leaders in Kununurra say overcrowded, unsafe housing and short-term staff contracts are contributing to a youth crime problem in the Western Australian town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55e492f6bd3501cea243f8a1940b38e2</guid></item><item><title>SA Museum investigates whether meteorite collided with car on regional highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/potential-meteorite-fall-augusta-highway-sa-museum-investigates/105942418</link><description>Andrew Melville-Smith was left covered in glass when an unidentified object smashed into his windscreen — and now scientists are investigating whether it was a meteorite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f92d60aa5cdb78c8affe24f6232f43db</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105943788</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fad8695f92ca723dd3d795a8482888f</guid></item><item><title>Humpback whale found dead tangled in shark net at Coledale north of Wollongong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/dead-whale-found-wrapped-in-shark-net-coledale-wollongong/105943666</link><description>The discovery of a dead whale entangled in a shark net off Coledale Beach ignites fresh debate on New South Wales's controversial shark net program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d282bc9ef8d6f201e3998319f448130</guid></item><item><title>Job cuts inevitable as BHP scales back Pilbara iron ore mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/job-losses-imminent-bhp-yandi-mine/105944514</link><description>A mining giant says its long-running Yandi iron ore mine in the Pilbara will be significantly scaled back next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">711d2673c003d6684214053cf3efd7f6</guid></item><item><title>Australians with oral cancer helped by 3D printing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/australians-with-oral-cancer-helped-by-3d-printing/105944464</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53d8fad23a09365c91db78cd216c81ec</guid></item><item><title>Bail revoked for teens accused of man's stabbing murder at Shellharbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/teenagers-taken-into-custody-over-fatal-shellharbour-stabbing/105943580</link><description>Four teenagers accused of luring a 25-year-old man to a Shellharbour train station and stabbing him to death are taken into custody after their bail is revoked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fb0d118746846913f0694c54cc926d3</guid></item><item><title>Sheffield Shield round 3: Jake Weatherald out for a duck, no play at the Gabba on day 1</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/sheffield-shield-round-3-day-one-weatherald-duck/105944830</link><description>Rain in Brisbane washes out the first day of play in the Sheffield Shield match between Queensland and New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a97560c2c932fd8da94212ea8eaad20d</guid></item><item><title>New AFP taskforce to target men 'hunting' young girls and coercing them into violent acts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/afp-to-target-men-hunting-young-girls-coercing-into-violence/105944838</link><description>In an address to the National Press Club on Wednesday, new AFP Commissioner Krissy Barrett will announce the new taskforce and flag a desire to recast the agency as a national security agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c06a9a5439c838e28d3b3397458d021f</guid></item><item><title>Bluey composer and Megan Washington among winners at 2025 Screen Music Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/bluey-joff-bush-megan-washington-screen-music-awards-2025/105878424</link><description>Bluey composer Joff Bush, Megan Washington and the music for Tony Armstrong's Eat the Invaders were among the winners at the 2025 Screen Music Awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d12a743491a3e773a3919dd817e5a0e</guid></item><item><title>Global climate plans need urgent acceleration to meet 2035 emissions target, UN report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/climate-goals-not-on-track-to-meet-2035-emissions-target-says-un/105945130</link><description>A report from the UN's climate change body shows global carbon emissions appear to be on track to fall by 10 per cent by 2035, far short of its 60 per cent target.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87e6964520ee46dafa6b6dc48e0cd4e8</guid></item><item><title>Fawlty Towers actress Prunella Scales dies age 93</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-28/fawlty-towers-actress-prunella-scales-dies-age-93/105945168</link><description>British actress Prunella Scales, best known for playing Sybil Fawlty in beloved sitcom Fawlty Towers, has died age 93.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3116aeb78c4ffb837336ed4120c9920f</guid></item><item><title>Amazon cuts 14,000 jobs as it ramps up AI push</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/amazon-culls-14-000-jobs-in-ai-push/105945212</link><description>The company is committing billions on data centre projects in the US as it tries to keep up with other tech giants making leaps in AI.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c4e18ddf9d36cc3e76f788dff34182c</guid></item><item><title>Elon Musk launches new AI-generated site Grokipedia to rival 'left-biased' Wikipedia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/elon-musk-new-ai-generated-site-grokipedia-to-rival-wikipedia/105945318</link><description>Billionaire Elon Musk has launched a new AI-generated site to compete with online encyclopedia Wikipedia, which he has accused of being "extremely left-biased".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bcb6c9e4edfbe9c82ea8e66addab188</guid></item><item><title>Sudan paramilitary group accused of killing 2,000 civilians in El-Fasher</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/sudanese-paramilitary-accused-of-killing-2-000-civilians/105945372</link><description>Sudanese paramilitary forces are accused of having "executed more than 2,000 unarmed civilians" since taking control of the western city of El-Fasher, as alarming reports of atrocities emerge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8ed0f857fc113db666e27f2e33e3658</guid></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa live: Category three storm brings widespread devastation to Jamaica, tracks for Cuba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/storm-melissa-jamaica-live/105945328</link><description>The World Meteorological Organization says the Caribbean region faces a "catastrophic situation" in the coming hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d230a5061201c1a23d9f8219f764c79b</guid></item><item><title>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu orders 'powerful' strikes in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/benjamin-netanyahu-orders-powerful-attacks-in-gaza/105945526</link><description>Gaza health officials say the Israeli strikes have killed at least 26 people, including four in Gaza City's Sabra neighbourhood and five in a car in Khan Younis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1313d2717f565798935fa12d7a29420b</guid></item><item><title>England dominate Matildas, win 3-0 in international friendly at Pride Park after Alanna Kennedy sent off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/live-updates-england-vs-matildas-international-friendly/105941470</link><description>The Matildas were criticised for playing at "walking pace" as two-time European champions England dominate at Derby's Pride Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">708ac3bc36414b3958f74ff4bc9a7392</guid></item><item><title>Health minister reinstates ban on puberty blockers hours after Supreme Court overturned freeze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/qld-health-minister-puberty-blockers-youth-supreme-court/105944876</link><description>The Queensland health minister has issued a new directive to ban public doctors from prescribing puberty blockers to youths six hours after a Supreme Court overturned the January freeze.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d60b3ef0d52c2e8021e434ac16b0cce0</guid></item><item><title>Watt defends intervention powers, saying it will not be used to fast track coal and gas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/watt-environment-laws-intervention-coal-gas/105942950</link><description>Murray Watt warns the Coalition and Greens not to "obstruct" environment laws being introduced to parliament on Thursday, while assuring a special power in the bill would not allow him to intervene on behalf of coal or gas projects.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4a05c994f871f763a6acc7e042504f5</guid></item><item><title>Super withdrawals for dental soar to new heights, prompting calls for more oral health funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/more-funding-for-dental-urged-as-super-withdrawals-soar/105939132</link><description>A 12-fold increase in Australians raiding their retirement nest eggs to fund expensive dental treatments in recent years has been labelled a "systemic failure".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b529e58485a6f57ed9a74804bb5f19e0</guid></item><item><title>Experts predict lengthy investigation into Cobar underground mine explosion that killed two people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/lengthy-investigation-into-mine-explosion-expected/105942064</link><description>A leading Australian expert in mining safety says the investigation into a fatal explosion at a western New South Wales mine could take a long time because "mining is getting more complex".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00b1c385105ae2359da93e6d4864c83f</guid></item><item><title>Kamala Harris reveals regret over 'reckless' decision ahead of US election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/kamala-harris-says-she-may-run-again-for-the-white-house/105943576</link><description>Former US vice-president Kamala Harris reveals she is contemplating another run for the presidency and says she was "reckless" to not stop Joe Biden from pursuing a second term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">195a90dcb9790fb09b4563b9339377e3</guid></item><item><title>Optus to be called before senators on Monday to explain triple-0 failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/optus-to-be-called-before-senators-on-monday-triple-0/105944796</link><description>An inquiry into the telco's triple-0 failure was green-lit by the Senate late on Tuesday and will hold its first hearings in Parliament House next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1c6acea870fbe41d4f0b0c317302a05</guid></item><item><title>When is your tax return due in Australia? Here's what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/tax-return-deadline-october-31-explained/105924968</link><description>Time is running out if you are planning on doing your 2024–25 tax return yourself. Here is everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7f3bb7594dc8f15750ff884b7faef31</guid></item><item><title>Pacific leader pushing Australia to 'close the deal' on hosting COP31</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/pacific-leader-pushing-australia-to-close-the-deal-on-cop31/105944274</link><description>One the Pacific's most high-profile leaders is pressing Anthony Albanese to fly to the global UN climate summit in Brazil next month to "close the deal" with Türkiye and secure COP31 hosting rights for next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42027408a43f45a89e573e6811876a58</guid></item><item><title>US private credit provider White Oak eyeing off Tasmania's troubled Liberty Bell Bay smelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/liberty-bell-bay-tasmanian-smelter-sale-speculation/105920136</link><description>As a pause in production at troubled smelter Liberty Bell Bay stretches on, speculation about its future builds after a series of meetings between a US private credit provider and Tasmania's industry minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4940798a24e2b304e4c993d59e69ada</guid></item><item><title>Malaysian Prime Minister Anwar Ibrahim discusses Donald Trump, China and Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/malaysia-prime-minister-anwar-bin-ibrahim-on-gaza-trump/105941600</link><description>The South-East Asian nation has been in the spotlight this week after hosting the ASEAN summit, which was attended by Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e739f0760adad30f516548a23851cbbe</guid></item><item><title>Safety authority investigates how cruise ship left woman's body on Lizard Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/authorities-investigates-lizard-island-death-coral-adventurer/105944314</link><description>The Australian Maritime Safety Authority will speak with the crew of a cruise ship that allegedly left behind an 80-year-old Australian woman, who was later found dead on a Queensland tropical island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2ad56e53820e1f29aed791c5d6f4a35</guid></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa barrels towards Jamaica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/hurricane-melissa-barrels-towards-jamaica/105945564</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49a6e39744a0e1ac6fb3967094cd61be</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government blasted over 'secrecy' after NZYQ cohort member deported to Nauru</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/government-blasted-over-nauru-deportation-deal-secrecy/105945196</link><description>Human rights groups and politicians say a deal between Nauru and Australia aimed at sending hundreds of former detainees to the Pacific island is "shrouded in secrecy".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">382ce475a9676087cbb57b1ddf95f89b</guid></item><item><title>Musicians react to 'random' City of Sydney busking limits in CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/nsw-city-of-sydney-council-busking-policy-introduced-music/105942862</link><description>Busking may be a familiar sight on Sydney's George Street, but most key spots for musicians have now been banned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7536eece8de626fce5040c09253dd236</guid></item><item><title>Construction delays on SA's three biggest hospital projects, auditor-general says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/sa-hospital-construction-delays-auditor-general-says/105942566</link><description>The South Australian government's three costliest hospital projects have all had "delays in starting construction", according to the auditor-general — but the health minister says they remain on schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c40a60a93f772f6adb5c5ad09ff6dd1</guid></item><item><title>Fears Lake Boga algae bloom will impact summer tourism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/lake-boga-algae-blue-green-fears-for-water-sport/105928970</link><description>Blue-green algae levels at Lake Boga in Victoria's north-west are three times the safe limit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d76c0f74c009be7dab2e79b42922bd05</guid></item><item><title>Markets live updates: Inflation comes in hotter than forecast as CPI rises 1.3 per cent, dashing hopes of rate cut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/asx-markets-business-live-news-29-oct/105945628</link><description>The headline inflation rate rose 1.3 per cent in the third quarter, according to ABS data. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7413cb277b129b49465662e9610799d6</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos name Harry Grant as captain for second Ashes Test to replace Isaah Yeo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/grant-gets-nod-to-replace-yeo-as-kangaroos-captain/105945594</link><description>Harry Grant is handed the captaincy of a major representative team for the first time as he is named to lead the Kangaroos in the second Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75a370013442003aaeba996f611f8b5f</guid></item><item><title>Taxpayer-funded cybersecurity course with 80pc dropout rate and recruitment issues labelled a 'patch job'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/tastafe-cybersecurity-course-dropouts-staff-issues/105921416</link><description>An 80 per cent dropout rate, compliance concerns, and a LEGO city sold as a "highlight" — this multimillion-dollar cybersecurity initiative has been labelled a "patch job".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dbe50c308028e242ede98e09f707e4c</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Sussan Ley stands by call for PM to apologise for Joy Division shirt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/federal-politics-live-blog-october-29/105944412</link><description>The opposition leader is standing by her call for Anthony Albanese to apologise for wearing a Joy Division T-shirt, despite some within her own party distancing themselves from the remarks. Follow Live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03d5ea6b18d8c2a1789ee8c4499e3453</guid></item><item><title>Tasman Bridge barrier concept designs released ahead of works to address safety concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/images-released-ahead-of-tasman-bridge-barrier-works/105943392</link><description>Plans to widen the pedestrian and cycling pathways on Hobart's Tasman Bridge were scrapped last year, but improved safety barriers and passing bays will go ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc94b2921849ab8e19c7c59fec03b8b</guid></item><item><title>Federal government investigates Inpex's Darwin oil spill, emissions error</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/federal-government-investigates-gas-giant-inpex-oil-spill/105939714</link><description>An oil spill that leaked into Darwin Harbour and the substantial under-reporting of toxic emissions have put one of Australia's biggest gas companies under federal investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebc466d6dc4b909e5a974adff49b82f4</guid></item><item><title>PM should consider his attire with 'great care': Bragg on Albanese's t-shirt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/pm-should-consider-his-attire-bragg-on-albanese/105945748</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dc2ddd4777c4504649f74d5ed986331</guid></item><item><title>Victorian traditional owner group calls for pause on mining approvals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/mining-licence-pause-traditional-owners-donald-rare-earths/105941112</link><description>The Federation of Victorian Traditional Owner Corporations calls for a pause on mining approvals until a formal benefit-sharing agreement is in place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8864fb0df432533d503ba320cae5745</guid></item><item><title>India confirms Shreyas Iyer recovering in hospital with lacerated spleen from ODI incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/iyer-recovering-well-from-spleen-injury-says-india-suryakumar/105945728</link><description>The Indian team confirms Shreyas Iyer is on the mend after a freak injury left him in hospital with a lacerated spleen in an incident during his side's ODI win over Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6036684696707d8ab4e7e19c293387c</guid></item><item><title>Governor's apology over Pinjarra Massacre renews debate over stripping Stirling name from WA landmarks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/pinjarra-massacre-apology-sparks-debate-over-name-stirling/105944398</link><description>The WA governor's apology for the Pinjarra Massacre sparks fresh debate over the renaming of roads and places that honour the state's first governor, James Stirling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">117b6732098f501fbe7d1a06e2a66764</guid></item><item><title>ABC taken into Gaza area under IDF control for first time since ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/abc-taken-into-gaza-area-under-idf-control/105945428</link><description>For the first time since the ceasefire started, the ABC has gained access to an area in northern Gaza under Israeli military control. This is what we could see from behind the Yellow Line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0dfc47bd2786b3b725075710e99c5fa1</guid></item><item><title>Study finds adverse links between PFAS exposure and reproductive health in mice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/animal-study-finds-high-pfas-exposure-impacts-male-fertility/105936778</link><description>A study using mice has found high exposure to PFAS lowered the male's sperm count, decreased testosterone and disrupted embryo development.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0edbd15dbc6fe3f8562fea6600d83341</guid></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa makes landfall as Jamaica's strongest-ever storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/hurricane-melissa-landfall-in-jamaica-strongest-ever/105945732</link><description>Hurricane Melissa made landfall in western Jamaica as a powerful category five storm and the strongest ever to directly hit the Caribbean nation of 2.8 million people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a1f3b39f243b5aec1830f0794e060f9</guid></item><item><title>State Administrative Tribunal upholds donkey cull notice at remote Kachana Station in the Kimberley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/tribunal-backs-donkey-cull-order-kachana-station-kimberley/105942850</link><description>The State Administrative Tribunal rejects an application to review a DPIRD order to cull more than 100 feral donkeys at a remote Kimberley station.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a83afc9691284f263bc8e1e7f37b9f7</guid></item><item><title>Kai Trump, granddaughter of US President Donald Trump, invited to play in LPGA Tour event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/donald-trumps-granddaughter-set-to-play-in-lpga-event/105945846</link><description>Kai Trump receives an invitation to play in a tournament in Florida ahead of starting her collegiate golf career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55182ca3cdbcc7ddd2a17262f57966d2</guid></item><item><title>The key role a 'lost' reef is playing in South Australia's algal bloom fight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/native-oyster-reefs-restored-algal-bloom-recovery-sa/105943318</link><description>A marine ecologist's discovery two years ago sparked a restoration project and has become a key element in South Australia's response to a devastating algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6da4b9d6a96705189c11b0f39230daf7</guid></item><item><title>‘Storm of the century’ hits Jamaica and heads towards Cuba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/-storm-of-the-century-hits-jamaica-/105946022</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7efd2eed35fe4372e9564544699c7eb0</guid></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology ordered to fix new website after torrent of complaints</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/bureau-of-meteorology-ordered-to-fix-website-after-backlash/105945832</link><description>Environment Minister Murray Watt tells the Bureau of Meteorology that its new $4.1 million website needs to be fixed after complaints from users.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8ada23e16b7ba6dc411fce5e6ac1299</guid></item><item><title>Dubbo's Carol Mudford wins AgriFutures Rural Women's Award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/carol-mudford-2025-agrifutures-rural-womens-award-winner/105942552</link><description>Carol Mudford's grassroots charity, sHedway, is dedicated to suicide prevention and positive mental health in the shearing industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b692f6fe2c8047620eb1453b9f5012cc</guid></item><item><title>Are you affected by the Queensland school exam blunder?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/qld-exam-callout/105945968</link><description>At least eight Queensland state high schools have taught year 12 students the wrong topic for an ancient history exam.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ceb323095f18a867c8550cc29b7f0e4</guid></item><item><title>At least 64 killed in Rio de Janeiro police operation ahead of COP30 events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/dozens-killed-in-rio-police-operation-targeting-cartels/105945882</link><description>More than 60 people have been killed in Rio de Janeiro's deadliest police operation, staged in the lead-up to the city hosting COP30 summit events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ce62531d294c71b9acd515f41aa0810</guid></item><item><title>World-first preterm birth prevention program has lowered the rate of early births by about 4,000 a year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/preterm-birth-prevention-program/105938716</link><description>A program introduced in Australia in 2018 has led to thousands of fewer babies born early each year, according to a new study.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f45aa37874709ca1c784f959f828e7d3</guid></item><item><title>Dicky Beach holiday park residents angry after Sunshine Coast Council decision</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/dozens-of-homes-now-worthless-after-council-van-park-decision/105916100</link><description>More than 100 residents face an uncertain future after a Queensland council votes to end permanent residencies at a holiday park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ac50bc59234ac58c8aca59875c1028a</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of childcare abuse allegations laid bare in Victorian watchdog's report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/victoria-commission-children-young-people-annual-report/105944994</link><description>Victorian authorities have received almost 1,000 reports of alleged abuse and misconduct against early childhood educators in the past year, according to a new watchdog report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">779c2c964edec8922c066427c36b72d0</guid></item><item><title>Workers stood down from GFG Alliance Tahmoor coal mine expect hard times</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/tahmoor-mine-workers-stood-down-without-pay/105941446</link><description>Half the workforce at the Tahmoor Colliery in NSW has been stood down without pay, with workers and their families facing weeks of financial uncertainty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8aabb08ff5fd4508d5cc20219ccad98d</guid></item><item><title>Nine Queensland high schools taught wrong topic for external ancient history exam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/qld-nine-schools-year-12-ancient-history-exam-wrong-topic/105945826</link><description>Queensland's education minister has put authorities on notice after nine high schools taught year 12 students the wrong topic for today's ancient history exam.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">469a584595ad1ad06d6acade30b032a5</guid></item><item><title>Darwin wakes to shaking from magnitude-6.4 earthquake in Banda Sea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/top-end-wakes-to-shakes-after-earthquake-in-banda-sea/105946056</link><description>People across the Northern Territory's Top End woke to shaking in the early hours during a magnitude-6.4 earthquake in the Banda Sea near Timor-Leste.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2de9a420eab7d83b50cfedc92489732</guid></item><item><title>Calls for clearer process to inform families if childcare educator is accused of sexual abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/act-sexual-abuse-in-child-care-centres-educators-inform-family/105941606</link><description>A Four Corners investigation reveals there are more childcare workers convicted or accused of sexual assault than the public has previously understood, including in the ACT.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">442ca54eafac1e6b0c4f056d98937dab</guid></item><item><title>Indoor cricket to no longer recieve operational and financial support from Cricket Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/indoor-cricket-to-be-cut-from-cricket-australia/105946412</link><description>Cricket Australia has conceded it has an "unsustainable" cost base, after cutting operational and financial support for indoor cricket and leaving the sport to manage itself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b2c1ff62b0f3362422263590612121d</guid></item><item><title>Hughenden locals fed up with water quality as CopperString project looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/hughenden-water-quality-issues/105937874</link><description>Hughenden business owner Jodie Coward says she has not drank water straight from the tap in two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a59ee153cd4060d849aa0ecebbc34a7c</guid></item><item><title>Elizabeth Lee and Peter Cain 'suspended indefinitely' from Canberra Liberals party room</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/lee-cain-indefinitely-suspended-canberra-liberals/105778148</link><description>Former party leader Elizabeth Lee and backbencher Peter Cain have been suspended indefinitely from the Canberra Liberals party room.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac39d4a95cc56cd2abf13634ef85e26</guid></item><item><title>A street in Kingston, Jamaica flooded after Hurricane Melissa made landfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/flooded-kingston-jamaica-hurricane-melissa/105946702</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48411e92b54fe2c24fc26608b372ddb1</guid></item><item><title>Australian captain Pat Cummins begins return to bowling with limited net session in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/test-skipper-pat-cummins-makes-tentative-bowling-return/105946422</link><description>Australia's Test captain Pat Cummins completes a brief return to bowling as he steps up his bid to play in the Ashes series against England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a68a16a9ca9a9dcec3e7f23f8004c6a</guid></item><item><title>Annual inflation surges to 3.2pc in September quarter, up from 2.1pc in June</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/september-quarter-inflation-2025-australia/105946244</link><description>Inflation data has came in much hotter than economists were expecting with annual inflation surging to 3.2 per cent in the September quarter, up from 2.1pc in June.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81ac1ac508d8a30ca4a8c42f2beb3241</guid></item><item><title>AVO application against Mark Latham likely to be 'resolved', ex-partner's lawyer tells court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/update-in-avo-matter-brought-by-nathalie-matthews-to-mark-latham/105944120</link><description>An apprehended violence order application against MP Mark Latham is "very much likely" to be resolved but remains ongoing, his former partner's lawyer has told a court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a3e7b5500e787e2fdf5d1f8c1def696</guid></item><item><title>Queensland education minister says nine schools impacted by exam bungle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/queensland-education-minister-year-12-exam/105946816</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74da933d36763c5d043ea383c5ee6112</guid></item><item><title>14 people killed as US carries out strikes on four more alleged drug boats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/14-people-killed-as-us-strikes-four-more-alleged-drug-boats/105946298</link><description>Mexican authorities are searching for a lone survivor seen clinging to wreckage following the strikes in the eastern Pacific Ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2660adffaaa19bc08628796da22a9293</guid></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa leaves trail of destruction in Jamaica's St Elizabeth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/hurricane-melissa-leaves-trail-of-destruction-in-jamaica/105946950</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edad848da11389f95af87ecffa65f45c</guid></item><item><title>John Cleese leads tributes to 'perfect' on-screen wife Prunella Scales</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/john-cleese-tributes-prunella-scales-fawlty-towers/105946292</link><description>Prunella Scales has been remembered as part of the golden era of British comedy for her numerous roles across film, TV and theatre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">689d141c16f380bd62bfb7d3caa78b80</guid></item><item><title>Video appears to show US strikes on suspected drug-trafficking vessels in Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/us-strikes-on-suspected-drug-trafficking-vessels-in-pacific/105947070</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e139c0a20262d706238ba87847f39fd</guid></item><item><title>Committal hearing begins for Perry Kouroumblis over 1977 Easey St murders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/easey-street-murders-committal-perry-kouroumblis/105946622</link><description>Prosecutors in Melbourne's Easey Street murder case tell a court that DNA found at the crime scene is highly likely to have come from prime suspect Perry Kouroumblis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57f82ccac926bb35f866e34f855ba329</guid></item><item><title>Vietnam tourist sites submerged as record rainfall causes major flooding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/vietnam-tourist-hotspots-flooded-record-rainfall-hoian/105946418</link><description>Heavy rains cause major flooding in central Vietnam, while a category five hurricane rages on the other side of the world in the Caribbean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcb8b7cf07c9e41cf8eccafbdd1aba20</guid></item><item><title>Sheffield Shield: Sam Konstas bowled in blow to Ashes Test selection hopes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/sheffield-shield-sam-konstas-bowled-ahses-selection/105947052</link><description>NSW opener Sam Konstas's bid to open the batting for Australia in the first Ashes Test has taken another hit, after the 20-year-old was dismissed early on day two of the Sheffield Shield match against Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c320099bda3224c31d808ad7babec336</guid></item><item><title>Bathurst childcare worker pleads guilty to recklessly wounding four-year-old</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/childcare-worker-guilty-plea-after-boys-head-glued-back-together/105946498</link><description>A NSW childcare worker has pleaded guilty to recklessly wounding the boy, who sustained a 2cm laceration when she tried to put him down for a rest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c2916dc39bd9aa64ccdf13c53613bd0</guid></item><item><title>Matildas launch fierce defence of Sam Kerr amid criticism of captaincy call</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/football-matildas-defend-sam-captaincy-call/105947148</link><description>Sam Kerr's coach and teammates aren't second-guessing the decision to re-install her as Matildas captain after returning to the field following a lengthy lay-off.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2d8393ab13f3e1c04babba54b9a6258</guid></item><item><title>Police call for information about man seen talking to Collie schoolgirl Lisa Mott</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/police-looking-for-man-seen-with-missing-girl-lisa-mott/105946798</link><description>Lisa Mott, 12, was last seen in the WA town of Collie almost 45 years ago. Now, police say a witness claims he saw her talking to a man leaning on a yellow panel van.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c26e59aa37b794dcc0062115eaee1f23</guid></item><item><title>George Orwell's Animal Farm gets AI makeover as students learn about online influence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/animal-farm-ai-education-win-the-farm-computer-game/105942084</link><description>George Orwell's Animal Farm is being used to help high schoolers identify how AI can be used to influence opinion, build power and shape narratives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba7b320df34d0d40eeeb51bc2c145394</guid></item><item><title>Liberal MPs question Sussan Ley's attack on Albanese's Joy Division shirt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/sussan-ley-questioned-joy-division-t-shirt/105947196</link><description>Sussan Ley stands by her criticism of the prime minister for wearing a Joy Division T-shirt while stepping off a plane last week. Privately, some of her Liberal colleagues are questioning the attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddd8f61603168e701b11911465b9e00d</guid></item><item><title>Inflation data kills November rate cut chances as RBA faces headache</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/september-quarter-inflation-kills-interest-rate-cut/105946770</link><description>A November rate cut is dead, buried and cremated. It now looks far from certain that interest rates will fall again at all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1613268faddcac18a19005bbd60b551f</guid></item><item><title>Canberra Liberals backbenchers Elizabeth Lee and Peter Cain speak about being suspended from the party room</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/elizabeth-lee-peter-cain-suspended-indefinitely-party-room/105947452</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b580648671d7d9ef4b63da1e900a16ae</guid></item><item><title>AFL confirms arrival of last disposal rule as one of seven changes for 2026 season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/afl-confirms-last-disposal-new-rule-changes-2026-season/105947430</link><description>The AFL confirms the arrival of the last disposal rule as one of seven rule changes aimed at making umpires' jobs easier while shortening the length of games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be15b4da805fe08c7ca263d3014d794e</guid></item><item><title>Algerian oak facing removal for transmission lines wins Tree of the Year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/algerian-oak-wins-tree-of-the-year-in-face-of-removal-threat/105942932</link><description>Residents of a small Victorian town hope a Tree of the Year award will save a beloved Algerian oak from being chopped down to make way for transmission lines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ddbe01f42b3306afce6b349670e0024</guid></item></channel></rss>