<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 11:13:55 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Three men found guilty and fined for performing Nazi salute outside Sydney Jewish museum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-10-24/three-men-guilty-nazi-salute-jewish-museum/104510908</link><description>The trio were captured on CCTV performing Nazi salutes outside the Sydney Jewish Museum in Darlinghurst on October 13, less than a week after the deadly Hamas attack on Israel last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f8c65e218461d0b3b5d916b1c057022</guid></item><item><title>Next-generation voters call for better engagement ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-18/federal-election-rural-next-generation-voters/105173450</link><description>Young people in Albury say issues that directly affect them and their communities are not being addressed by major parties for the 2025 election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ae182892b8c9591cd9ec35e6e57fcb9</guid></item><item><title>Albury's Macquarie Textiles celebrated for decades of manufacturing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-08/alburys-rich-wool-and-textile-history-celebrated-in-exhibition/105958750</link><description>Textile manufacturing took Albury's work to the Opera House, federal parliament, the Olympics and beyond.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e79d3a3fce1ccbf4621429603303d231</guid></item><item><title>A motorised hydrofoiler rides well clear of swimmers off Adelaide's metropolitan coastline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/a-motorised-hydrofoiler-rides-well-clear-of-swimmers/105990830</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95f075ad4df3f4435a61fd508c99d7ed</guid></item><item><title>The 'gun' shearer still setting a cracking pace at 85</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-15/john-harris-shearing-legacy-glengower-victoria/106009312</link><description>Australian shearing legend John Harris has returned to a central Victorian woolshed for the 75th year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94520388e9fce12775284bb46066f5c7</guid></item><item><title>Rupertswood: The Birthplace of the Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-20/rupertswood-the-birthplace-of-the-ashes/106027000</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0c80d09c33301400a6b208ac0a58a03</guid></item><item><title>Critically endangered night parrot captured by Martu rangers in east Pilbara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-23/thirsty-night-parrot-pilbara/106029246</link><description>After thousands of hours of recording, the elusive night parrot has been captured on camera drinking from a water hole for the first time, reshaping researchers' understanding of their needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2d81811f2cbdb83f25b0a1eec6f1057</guid></item><item><title>Yancoal begins plans to extend life of central Queensland coal mine to 2070</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-25/yancoal-central-queensland-coal-mine-extension-plans/106037050</link><description>Yancoal begins plans to extend the life of its central Queensland coal mine, which would see roughly 74 million tonnes of coal extracted over the life of the mine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4193c08b972127a904e0a454173cd539</guid></item><item><title>WA Premier Roger Cook says he has "industrial fomo"</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/vertical-roger-cook-industrial-fomo/106072992</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3907684179431c31f35634c3a523922f</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri's journey from humble beginnings to the brink of the Formula One championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-05/oscar-piastri-f1-abu-dhabi-melbourne-racing/106102654</link><description>After finishing last in his first race, Oscar Piastri has risen from humble beginnings to the brink of Australian sporting history as he chases his first F1 world title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">102f4804cb8a6644fd51e5f66e0f5109</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri qualifies third for Abu Dhabi F1 Grand Prix, behind rivals Max Verstappen and Lando Norris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/piastri-only-third-verstappen-takes-pole-for-f1-finale-abu-dhabi/106111500</link><description>Oscar Piastri warns he's not out of the Formula One title hunt yet, even if many only now have eyes on a Lando Norris-Max Verstappen duel for the crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d778222828df96a3c4c0c6798717f29</guid></item><item><title>Lando Norris claims F1 world title after dramatic Abu Dhabi Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/f1-live-abu-dhabi-grand-prix-oscar-piastri-lando-norris-max/105995116</link><description>Max Verstappen has won the Abu Dhabi Grand Prix ahead of Oscar Piastri, but Lando Norris finishes third to claim the world title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fd6f8c94f3d969c2ad20a822600258a</guid></item><item><title>Crops preferred to sheep in large parts of Australia's traditional mixed farming regions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/crops-preferred-to-sheep-in-traditional-mixed-farming-regions/106035940</link><description>Mixed farming, which involves growing crops and rearing livestock, used to be standard practice in Australia, but there are almost 100 million fewer sheep in Australia than there were 35 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3a750e588866118fa491cdd0f9f1d85</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri praised as future formula 1 world champion by rivals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/oscar-piastri-praised-as-future-formula-1-world-champion/106113274</link><description>Oscar Piastri's chief rival, new formula 1 world champion Lando Norris, says the Australian will "get the better of me" after their tension-filled title race decider in Abu Dhabi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bdac8d42b6f4d2a864e6f566e20a472</guid></item><item><title>Canadian traditional owners fear Australian-style LNG development</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/canada-traditional-owners-in-australia-to-protest-against-gas/106111960</link><description>Canadian hereditary chief Na'Moks wanted to find out what a gas pipeline on his land would look like, so he flew to northern Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fec3762dac068c1104d6fbd8727431f5</guid></item><item><title>Rare brain illness could not stop Milly from making country netball history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/milly-brock-tongala-netball-encephalitis/106098456</link><description>A rare brain illness left Milly Brock unable to walk or speak, but eight months later, she was back leading her regional netball club on grand final day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">821bba383f0020f9d6f99b0b9a15f322</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting gunman Naveed Akram was follower of pro-Islamic State preacher Wisam Haddad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/video-shows-bondi-beach-shooting-gunman-preaching-islam-to-teens/106145626</link><description>At least one of the gunmen who killed 15 people in Sunday's Bondi Beach terrorist attack was known to authorities as a follower of a notorious Sydney pro-Islamic State cleric, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b52ae302a33646b87014607b9cbabe0e</guid></item><item><title>Former NASCAR driver Greg Biffle and members of his family die in North Carolina plane crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/nascar-driver-greg-biffle-dies-in-plane-crash/106161496</link><description>NASCAR icon Greg Biffle dies in a plane crash in the US, along with several family members.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57664ec948ea19c7a4da9e76855e1e71</guid></item><item><title>Pilbara mining towns left out of government's battery rebate schemes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/mining-pilbara-towns-left-out-of-battery-rebate-schemes/106025508</link><description>Residents in small Pilbara towns with power grids run by mining companies are excluded from home battery rebate schemes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd12d9c00ad0b9fa1138dad056f18caf</guid></item><item><title>Newmont's Cadia Gold Mine to spend $300,000 on monitors after dust incidents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/newmont-cadia-gold-mine-buys-dust-monitoring-stations-epa/106170892</link><description>One of the country's largest gold mines in the NSW Central West will buy five new dust monitors after incidents at its tailings dam.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8b16aa24b0110d31f9b6c0be2269d84</guid></item><item><title>Canterbury-Bankstown Council shuts down prayer hall linked to notorious preacher Wisam Haddad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/nsw-sydney-council-shuts-down-prayer-hall/106174508</link><description>The City of Canterbury Bankstown Council says the site had been approved for use as a medical centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a105e72895dfd84218b4389d40ba9fa1</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach gunmen's phone pinged near Philippine region known for Islamic extremism: police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/bondi-beach-shooter-pinged-near-philippines-extremist-region/106176954</link><description>Mobile phone data suggests the Bondi Beach gunmen may have travelled near a region in the Philippines where Islamic State-aligned militants could still be operating, a police source has told the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d612ea3d7aa44793790596fd88c30a31</guid></item><item><title>Endangered malleefowl chick saved in 2,000-hectare fire at Wyperfeld National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/malleefowl-chick-saved-wyperfeld-national-park-bushfire/106176370</link><description>An endangered malleefowl chick has been saved from a 2,000-hectare bushfire in a regional Victorian national park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddefccd7a2b1c56365c12e2baad72bb7</guid></item><item><title>Sydney to Hobart pays tribute to Bondi victims with petals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/sydney-to-hobart-boat-tributes-bondi-victims-with-petals-/106180276</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1eb26c06a311d6aa9fafe2681d251de5</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen wins F1 Driver of the Year award for fifth straight year, Oscar Piastri comes fourth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/f1-title-runner-up-verstappen-driver-of-the-year-five-in-row/106189130</link><description>Max Verstappen may not have won the F1 world title, but his fast finish to the year wins him Driver of the Year for the fifth straight year, while Oscar Piastri's disappointing end to the season is mirrored in the voting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">139a9f7e6a9116fb2078199393ba0042</guid></item><item><title>Four titan arum 'corpse flowers' to bloom in a week at Cairns Botanic Gardens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-01/four-titan-arums-simultaneously-flower-in-cairns-botanic-gardens/106190260</link><description>Renowned for their size and stench, blooming corpse flowers are a rare occurrence. But to have four flowering in a week is "something of a record".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb7d7cc23915ad1269387ece32f2c817</guid></item><item><title>High hopes for endangered white-throated snapping turtle after record number of clutches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/high-hopes-for-white-throated-snapping-turtle-with-record-clutch/106210694</link><description>A record number of clutches of white-throated snapping turtles have been found along the Burnett River in Queensland's Bundaberg region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a66bab0694c751fc33a87edbb83aa921</guid></item><item><title>Koala captured on motion-sensor camera in rare sighting near Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/koala-captured-on-camera-rare-sighting-near-canberra/106223142</link><description>A motion-sensor camera has captured the rare sight of a koala in the wild at a wildlife sanctuary in Googong near the ACT border.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28f1290063bb8a0e8b7150b9ddc0bfd5</guid></item><item><title>Pilbara home to five animal species most impacted by habitat loss, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-14/does-mining-help-endangered-pilbara-animals-conservation/106213512</link><description>The Australian Conservation Foundation says tens of thousands of hectares of land were approved for clearing last year, double that of 2024, putting already endangered species at further risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a52728535cce5680a3394bb8b041dd3</guid></item><item><title>European troops won't change Trump's ambition for Greenland, says White House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/european-troops-in-greenland-do-not-affect-donald-trump-plan/106235716</link><description>As European countries send small numbers of troops to Greenland, the White House says their presence will not affect US President Donald Trump's ambitions for the island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab529e950b13b11d4fb0ac48b2c67c19</guid></item><item><title>Daniel Sanders shrugs off broken collarbone to complete 11th stage of Dakar Rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/motorsport-dakar-rally-daniel-sanders-return-collarbone/106236054</link><description>Daniel Sanders returns to complete the 11th stage of the Dakar Rally less than 24 hours after suffering a broken collarbone and sternum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e03583e93320c8126c9c4e2075c87b65</guid></item><item><title>US says it killed Al Qaeda operative linked to deadly IS ambush of Americans in Syria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/us-kills-al-qaeda-affiliate-tied-to-december-attack-in-syria/106241954</link><description>CENTCOM says it conducted a strike in north-west Syria that resulted in the death of an Al Qaeda operative linked to the ISIS gunman responsible for killing two US soldiers and a US civilian in Syria on December 13.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc5b8387939af07a882c07f6410e5b03</guid></item><item><title>Sheep under the eye of AI</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/using-ai-to-count-sheep/106250690</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c5af840e880887503748d0dd1f0eb2a</guid></item><item><title>Taskforce set up to address ongoing power outages across SA from dust pollution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/power-outages-across-regional-south-australia-from-dust/106252096</link><description>Ongoing dry conditions across South Australia since 2024 are causing dust and salt to build up across inland and coastal power networks, polluting insulators and leading to mass blackouts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfa755b708992c638b64e4eaec702edf</guid></item><item><title>Tropical low forecast to bring heavy rain to northern Cape York, Gulf of Carpentaria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/tropical-low-heavy-rain-cape-york-gulf-of-carpentaria/106260620</link><description>Saturated catchments along the Gulf of Carpentaria and north-west Queensland are bracing for more heavy rain next week, although the weather bureau says the likelihood of a cyclone is low.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75a8cf68a1a2c07acaa78e3d7876813e</guid></item><item><title>How to attract native wildlife and birds to your garden</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/how-to-attract-native-wildlife-and-birds-to-your-garden/106042150</link><description>There are simple things we can all do to encourage more native wildlife to our gardens, backyards, balconies and shared spaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a86ce4b9695adc5a6d1286749a33f7cf</guid></item><item><title>As Russia's war intensifies Europe is exploring military and economic independence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/davos-donald-trump-zelenskyy-russia-war-technology/106252046</link><description>As the world's elite gathered in Davos, European leaders confronted a reality in which they might need to defend themselves, and potentially against, the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">777407f3d912131f903aabe2a0e5650c</guid></item><item><title>Former state care kid calls for fundamental change to fix 'broken' residential care system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-25/state-care-children-say-system-is-broken-south-australia/106090498</link><description>Residential care is often a last resort for society's most vulnerable children, but being raised by a "system" can leave both physical and emotional scars. It's why those who have gone through it are asking for their voices to be included to reform it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f11503bf6b8a54ccd1a7e5d6836ec3d2</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane temperatures tops 35 degrees as Cairns and Townsville face soaking rain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/brisbane-set-for-hottest-australia-day-so-far-this-century/106267764</link><description>South-east Queensland is sweating through its hottest Australia Day so far this century, with Brisbane recording its highest maximum temperature since 1998.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d92e7e61df648d974c73da3f400d83a</guid></item><item><title>Australia Day heat record for Adelaide, as mercury hits 49C in Ceduna</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/adelaide-records-australia-day-heat-record/106270456</link><description>As Adelaide sets a new record for its hottest Australia Day, other parts of SA are enduring conditions that are even more sweltering, with the mercury climbing above 49C in Ceduna.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d0724e16a5e1fce8b2130181191edf8</guid></item><item><title>Rescue dog used in central Queensland koala monitoring program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/rescue-dog-used-in-central-queensland-koala-monitoring-program/106187550</link><description>This scruffy pup has gone from the pound to being part of a scat detection dog team, helping save endangered koalas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d2a0c927c72d280718730a5dab46b11</guid></item><item><title>Brandan Koschel denied bail over alleged hate speech at March for Australia rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/brandan-koschel-charged-with-inciting-hate-denied-bail/106273486</link><description>Brandan Koschel has been charged with publicly inciting hatred on the grounds of race causing fear after he made comments at an open mic session at the rally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce25543ed4562dfb7b87914bafb74a79</guid></item><item><title>Why some places can feel much hotter than the official temperature</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/how-do-we-measure-heat-official-temperature/106277628</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology's temperatures differ from those that may be shown in your car or on your phone. Here's how the "official" temperature is measured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cc54c0bddb35e2590d04016c20ad74c</guid></item><item><title>Great Southern residents praise WA firefighters who saved 30 homes from serious blaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/wandering-residents-praise-wa-firefighters-30-homes-saved/106275646</link><description>Firefighters in the Great Southern region of WA are being praised for saving 30 homes after lightning caused a fire that burnt out of control for four days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">848c376330b2a6d01389f7b95c66bb63</guid></item><item><title>Talison lithium mine blasts in regional WA ignite calls for home buyback scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/talison-lithium-mine-greenbushes-residents-want-home-buybacks/106262764</link><description>Home owners living beside the Greenbushes lithium mine in Western Australia are calling for a buyback or relocation scheme amid the mounting toll of blasting, dust and noise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c14dc3318797e8e1079726c364b0ca3</guid></item><item><title>SA man arrested for allegedly lighting multiple fires during Riverland heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/multiple-riverland-south-australia-bushfires-heatwave/106286030</link><description>A 49-year-old South Australian man has been arrested for allegedly lighting multiple fires in the state's Riverland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77106a453774cdd4f20e9ea14092dd10</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's many foreign policy bluffs come at a political price</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/donald-trump-iran-nuclear-foreign-policy-greeland-tariffs/106288164</link><description>As the US president faces domestic consequences for his violent immigration crackdown, his geopolitical bluffs across the world also come at a price.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b214da89e9b1ae9893f26e3535f5d06</guid></item><item><title>Much of Queensland set to sizzle ahead of cooler, wet change next week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/high-temperatures-forecast-for-qld-ahead-of-cool-change/106286996</link><description>The worst of the heat has moved into south-west Queensland, while temperatures in the south-east could still hit 40 degrees Celsius before a cooler change early next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d92e7026c523386155ab738bc5cc6f</guid></item><item><title>Trump administration eyes US Pacific territories as it moves towards deep-sea mining</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/trump-administration-seabed-mining-pacific-territories/106272964</link><description>A Trump administration push to begin deep-sea mining is gathering momentum — and stirring alarm in United States Pacific territories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cba1500e673e715190fab09dc62b80f</guid></item><item><title>Risso's and pantropical spotted dolphins seen off Port Macquarie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/rarely-seen-dolphins-port-macquarie/106288194</link><description>Deepwater dolphin species make a rare appearance on the NSW Mid North Coast, delighting scientists and marine wildlife enthusiasts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b35d7255829358ded47b9444ffa791f</guid></item><item><title>Inside the brand strategy behind the Beckham family drama — and who controls the narrative now</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/inside-the-brand-strategy-behind-the-beckham-family-drama/106284834</link><description>In a modern crisis, experts say control doesn't always come from speaking louder — but from knowing when, where and how briefly to speak at all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02c12da6214ed41b16eafa530a0cd912</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic drops retirement hint, suggests 2026 could be his final Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/australian-open-novak-djokovic-hints-2026-could-be-his-last/106293450</link><description>Novak Djokovic did not go into detail on what he meant, nor did he confirm a plan to retire this year, but he chose his words carefully on centre court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55495032c4ad20750eb9060adf5c00fd</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic praises Carlos Alcaraz after Spaniard wins first Australian Open title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australian-open-carlos-alcaraz-novak-djokovic-final/106293372</link><description>Despite the hollow feeling of defeat, 24-time major winner Novak Djokovic heaps praise on Carlos Alcaraz following the Spaniard's history-making Australian Open victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87c4c2aa20dbeaeb5ed2b49f3037427b</guid></item><item><title>Rare photo captures Christmas Island flying fox ferrying pup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/rare-photo-captures-christmas-island-flying-fox-ferrying-pup/106284950</link><description>Often compared to a "teddy bear", advocates hope the special snap of an endangered flying fox carrying its pup will shine a light on the Christmas Island animal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c88e0ee70cafc37e3aa2c4c11c901e9</guid></item><item><title>Banned tennis player Thomas Fancutt makes comeback after IV vitamin breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/banned-tennis-player-thomas-fancutt-makes-comeback/106303088</link><description>Thomas Fancutt has made his return to professional tennis after receiving a 10-month ban for a vitamin and magnesium infusion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42fc7b5264f3284f619a1da6e7afddf2</guid></item><item><title>Russia and Ukraine conduct POW swap after latest US-led peace talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/ukraine-russia-talks-united-states-trump/106312078</link><description>The Kremlin says it sees progress and positive movement in the talks, brokered by the United States, as Donald Trump urges both sides to reach a peace deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0de94a61b88dd48205673f167c316711</guid></item><item><title>ATO debt continues to drive record level of calls to small business financial helpline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/debts-to-ato-drive-record-level-of-financial-helpline-calls/106308516</link><description>Financial counsellors say small businesses struggling to pay debts owed to the tax office are driving calls to Australia's Small Business Debt Helpline higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5e7106c0d32cd232b4538e4271760e1</guid></item><item><title>Terrorist act declaration for Invasion Day attempted bombing shows WA has changed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/wa-will-never-be-the-same-after-invasion-day-terror-act-charged/106311080</link><description>It will take time and significant effort to repair relationships with the Indigenous community amid the fallout from last week's attempted bombing in the Perth CBD — but other growing rifts in society will be even harder to mend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23f6e3d28b465ad95a9a20c73b8a09a8</guid></item><item><title>The easiest way to clean your microwave and a common mistake to avoid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/what-is-the-best-way-to-clean-a-microwave/106307346</link><description>When was the last time you cleaned your microwave? According to experts, it's actually a lot simpler than cleaning other appliances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b708e459302ab8131d3d781a896a62ad</guid></item><item><title>Why it took police nine days to declare the Invasion Day attempted bomb attack in Perth terrorism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/process-to-declare-invasion-day-alleged-attack-terrorism-/106314916</link><description>When a homemade fragment bomb was allegedly thrown into a crowd on January 26, it took nine days for it to be declared an act of terrorism. The WA police commissioner explains why, as Indigenous leaders raise concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3aa7ffedfadafcc72701809222cd8964</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Festival leader Julian Hobba reflects on Writers' Week controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/sa-adelaide-festival-director-says-writers-week-saga-preventable/106306654</link><description>As Adelaide Writers' Week went up in flames, Julian Hobba contemplated resigning as Adelaide Festival's executive director. He now says "we needed to trust the judgement" of the literary event's former leader, Louise Adler.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6512b46457dc635dd9be1ece4907ad35</guid></item><item><title>Meringandan collector sells vintage tractors, trucks, machines on Queensland farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/meringandan-collector-sells-vintage-tractors-trucks-machines-qld/106305032</link><description>As the last man standing, 78-year-old cattleman Mervyn has parted with his collection of tractors and utes, pledging his estate to charity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">467219dc24b07990a0bbb37f1d3c6d41</guid></item><item><title>New Zealanders hoped never to see the Christchurch terrorist again. Now he wants to appeal his sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/new-zealanders-hoped-never-to-see-christchurch-terrorist-again/106317996</link><description>Extraordinary arrangements are in place in Wellington, New Zealand, as a convicted terrorist prepares to address the country's Court of Appeal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23b0ec4742644544facc21fdb7ac1d84</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Diamonds smash Jamaica again to seal three-game series in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/all-too-easy-for-the-diamonds-in-sealing-series-win-over-jamaica/106320414</link><description>Kate Moloney celebrates her 50-game milestone in style as the Australian Diamonds post a 32-goal victory over an understrength Jamaica in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17c58aaad7fd1ed71acafd10afe3d217</guid></item><item><title>Israeli President Isaac Herzog tells Sydney event antisemitism has been 'festering' in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/nsw-sydney-israeli-president-isaac-herzog-lands-bondi-attack/106320482</link><description>Isaac Herzog was invited by the governor-general and prime minister to join the Jewish community grieving the loss of life in the December 14 massacre of mostly Jewish Australians at a Hanukkah event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8477437267014ce2c5d1873b72d0a6d</guid></item><item><title>Backyard pods won't fix the housing crisis but they signal a shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/backyard-pods-wont-fix-the-housing-crisis/106314472</link><description>Australia's biggest hardware retailer has started selling tiny homes. Are backyard pods the answer to a national housing crisis?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dd2b8a3992ec554b10d8b236bba7c64</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos captain Adam Reynolds holds hope of Payne Haas contract backflip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/adam-reynolds-on-payne-haas-contract-broncos-rabbitohs/106324748</link><description>Brisbane prop Payne Haas is set to arrive in England for the World Club Challenge where his teammates will try to convince him not to honour his deal with South Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26ae11679cc83fdf4ab466c033c7a4f6</guid></item><item><title>Former ATSIC head Geoff Clark was jailed but his community says legal issues persist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/framlingham-aboriginal-trust-shares-court-fallout-geoff-clark/106305592</link><description>Former ATSIC leader Geoff Clark was jailed in 2024, yet some members of his community say legal issues linger on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec0abba8310f5f8dfa22011b1c737b70</guid></item><item><title>Turtles discovered in Dumaresq Dam could be dumped pets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/turtles-discovered-in-dumaresq-dam-could-be-dumped-pets/106304016</link><description>The unexpected discovery of four turtle species in a dam near Armidale has left researchers wondering if people have been dumping unwanted pets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3644822f63b6c74afb1a388ba0882f6d</guid></item><item><title>Raymond Reddington murder trial hears Sharon Fulton seemed scared in hours before 1986 disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/sharon-fulton-murder-trial-raymond-reddington-woman-was-scared/106327376</link><description>A close friend of a woman allegedly murdered by her husband in Perth 40 years ago tells a Perth court she seemed frightened in the hours before her disappearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78ffe88ad62d326c893e3ac20446550a</guid></item><item><title>Former NT police officer James Kirstenfeldt sentenced on drink driving, weapons offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nt-james-kirstenfeldt-sentenced-drink-driving-weapons-charges/106313314</link><description>A former Northern Territory police officer has been ordered to pay almost $5,000 in fines and undergo supervised treatment for post-traumatic stress disorder after drunkenly crashing his car outside his suburban Darwin home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94f3ae08a6978aeffd227f1b28acd709</guid></item><item><title>Protesters were punched, pushed, and arrested but were NSW Police actions excessive?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/verify-police-use-of-force-town-hall-protest/106328358</link><description>What is reasonable? It's a question being asked by some after footage of clashes in Sydney's CBD, during a rally against Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc032833c827cf116d697c6b10faca22</guid></item><item><title>Surgeon Kelvin Kong's life growing up Chinese and Indigenous in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/kelvin-kong-s-growing-up-chinese-and-indigenous-australia/106326388</link><description>Australia's first identified First Nations surgeon, Dr Kelvin Kong spoke about his Malaysian Chinese heritage during the annual Wang Gungwu lecture at Parliament House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3366e9b48200b228bb48ce12f315720</guid></item><item><title>Race against bulldozers to save ancient grass trees in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/race-to-save-grass-trees-south-west-wa/106323778</link><description>Some of WA's oldest grass trees are being rescued from land clearing and development amid a population and property boom, preserving a unique part of the South West's natural heritage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c035d16240b39fbe758a3a7788f5176</guid></item><item><title>Missing man Corey Chugg separated from friend while collecting firewood, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/search-for-missing-man-corey-chugg-in-tasmania/106328680</link><description>A 32-year-old man missing in Tasmania's north was collecting firewood with a friend when the pair became separated on Sunday, police have said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e1ef0edf011bcec194b5dfaf7f996fe</guid></item><item><title>Formula 1 2026: New engines and no DRS headline major changes in grand prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/formula-1-2026-new-engines-regulations-sprint-races/106325942</link><description>New engines, new regulations and an 11-team grid are just some of the changes in Formula 1 this season. Get up to speed with what is new in F1 ahead of the Australian Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fce942eea4fa4616a149450aa1c7158</guid></item><item><title>Emergency warning issued for grassfire near Sunbury, north of Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/grassfire-emergency-warning-sunbury-melbourne/106331508</link><description>Residents near Sunbury, north of Melbourne, were advised to shelter as a grassfire burned out of control.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">420def29d7839590619ead68334d84ba</guid></item><item><title>Axed literary magazine Meanjin is resurrected by Queensland University of Technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/meanjin-magazine-finds-new-home-queensland-university-technology/106331850</link><description>The 85-year-old literary journal Meanjin will return to Brisbane, where it was first published, after it was controversially closed by Melbourne University Press last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8381f55200bc2cef76893ac168c73d93</guid></item><item><title>Former Carlton legend Peter Dean hospitalised after serious assault in Albury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/former-carlton-legend-suffers-serious-assault-in-albury/106331586</link><description>Former AFL player Peter Dean is recovering in hospital after he sustained serious head and facial injuries in an alleged assault at Albury on the New South Wales Victorian border.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4ceb1d2b4738f0666d773a5bf7a2435</guid></item><item><title>El Paso flights resume after US anti-drone system prompts sudden shutdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/faa-closes-airspace-around-el-paso-airport/106333810</link><description>A secret military laser-based anti-drone system prompted the Trump administration to ban air traffic for more than seven hours in and out of the Texas border city of El Paso.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06473436525f8abf18f0d4e972c40d40</guid></item><item><title>Transparency concerns as Bougainville's Panguna mine that sparked civil war on path to reopen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/bougainville-signs-secretive-deal-to-reopen-panguna-mine/106331778</link><description>The Autonomous Bougainville Government signs a secretive deal to reopen the huge Panguna gold and copper mine that sparked a catastrophic civil war three decades ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a5ff00e0503cc102c30c6e22dae858</guid></item><item><title>Old Bureau of Meteorology website still getting thousands of clicks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/old-bom-website-drawing-traffic-months-after-new-page-launch/106326812</link><description>The new BOM website is still drawing criticism, with 400,000 users turning to the old site, despite $1.15 million in recent updates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6571b8e0e99bb64c79240519d9e09619</guid></item><item><title>Julian Assange's brother backs exiled former ASIO spy Marcus amid Bondi Beach gunman radicalisation claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/julian-assange-s-brother-supporting-former-spy-living-in-exile/106334144</link><description>Former undercover agent Marcus says he shared intelligence with ASIO about Bondi gunmen Naveed and Sajid Akram's alleged terrorism associations as far back as 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d342528c0b8c306cae08cb9c3c5a0d35</guid></item><item><title>New video shows violent arrest of Australian filmmaker James Ricketson at Sydney's anti-Herzog protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/video-shows-arrest-filmmaker-james-ricketson-sydney-protest/106337470</link><description>New video obtained by ABC NEWS Verify shows in vivid detail the arrest of a 76-year-old man, who was later released without charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8b85f342914cc4a1db8e8f827b072c</guid></item><item><title>Italy wins first T20 Cricket World Cup match as Australian-born players shine in 10-wicket win over Nepal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/italy-wins-first-t20-cricket-world-cup-match/106339406</link><description>Sydney-born brothers Justin and Anthony Mosca have guided T20 World Cup debutants Italy to their first win in the tournament, as their unbeaten half-centuries secured a dominant 10-wicket victory over Nepal on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3c6d0fe17105b65b0990f4c481c3845</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen critical of new Formula 1 cars as preseason testing continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/max-verstappen-critical-of-new-formula-1-cars/106339508</link><description>Four-time Formula 1 world champion Max Verstappen says the 2026 cars are "not so fun", claiming the increasing energy management demands on drivers are "just not Formula 1".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">950bfbf36871e9c9d62401075e1fd446</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Woods' mum reacts after stunning gold medal win in Men’'s Moguls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cooper-woods-mum-reacts-after-stunning-gold-medal-win-/106339924</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9330246f2d9b13f2b20e5765e9270dc4</guid></item><item><title>Organisations branch out to help men's mental health in regional NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/organisations-branch-out-help-mens-mental-health-rural-nsw/106332542</link><description>Keith Cowen was alone on his farm in regional NSW when he had a heart attack. It made him realise how much he needed mates around him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f33d23d5d6f337a5fe04f7b32b849b2f</guid></item><item><title>Detonated homemade explosive found on oval in south Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/police-information-detonated-homemade-explosive-found-canberra/106340128</link><description>Police have issued a call-out for information after a homemade bomb exploded on an oval in Canberra's south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78659dd92f1ed11830c1aa0c09d5c01c</guid></item><item><title>Bald Archy satirical art prize highlights political victories, a murder trial and protest movements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/bald-archy-prize-reveals-politics-crime-and-bob-irwin/106340644</link><description>From the trial of Erin Patterson to the landslide election victory, 2025 is pilloried in this year's satirical art prize, the Bald Archy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e360d2786aee3a4fd31acfa42d11981</guid></item><item><title>How do you find modern dating? Share your highs and lows with us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/audience-callout-modern-dating-love-stories/106287262</link><description>Whether you've shed tears of joy, sadness or even laughter in the process, we want to hear it all — but keep it under 150 words.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e85c8d73dd7cdf15e05f480eb2c663e8</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm accused by Parramatta Eels of asking NRL to intervene in Zac Lomax contract saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/nrl-zac-lomax-storm-eels-court-battle/106344514</link><description>Melbourne has been accused of asking NRL chief executive Andrew Abdo to "apply a blowtorch" to Parramatta as part of a desperate bid to sign Zac Lomax to the Storm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd8ae2aedf1ce47d254962dc1ec3d13c</guid></item><item><title>NSW Waratahs defeat Queensland Reds 36-12 in opening round of Super Rugby Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/nsw-waratahs-defeat-queensland-reds-super-rugby-pacific/106340136</link><description>The NSW Waratahs are in celebration mode after breaking the shackles to open the Super Rugby Pacific season with a rousing 36-12 derby win over the Queensland Reds in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88c0ddda0aba1b94926b4769e6f967a4</guid></item><item><title>Community, experts reflect on lessons from Black Saturday fires 17 years on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/lessons-from-black-saturday-bushfires-victoria/106152018</link><description>Seventeen years after Black Saturday, experts reflect on what was learnt from the disaster and how it informs Victoria's current bushfire response.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c168d26e16e17a00addaec4a9c9ff62d</guid></item><item><title>Illegal tyre dump near Townsville</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/illegal-tyre-dump-near-townsville/106321156</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14f2afdb70e9bc6bec783ddedfe81c48</guid></item><item><title>Chickens help autistic teen Summer Farrelly make sense of humans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/chickens-help-summer-farrelly-understand-humans-autism-book/106308084</link><description>While growing up, people didn't make much sense to Summer, but chickens always did. Now, Summer is using what they learnt to help other children with autism understand human interactions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69b349a86894794e632c23899a5e2185</guid></item><item><title>Easy, tasty and nutritious recipes for sharing this Ramadan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/easy-tasty-and-nutritious-recipes-for-sharing-this-ramadan/106331120</link><description>Looking for easy, nutritious Ramadan recipes? These options will help you prepare for and break your fast well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb9d0165cd75c38640ee10f031f1d403</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri raises safety concerns ahead of F1 Australian Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/oscar-piastri-raises-safety-concerns-f1/106340156</link><description>Oscar Piastri has raised concerns about safety issues at the upcoming Australian Grand Prix, worried about potential chaos at the very start of the F1 season opener.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a19793fef3d4f087577e45c38422ab30</guid></item><item><title>Australia and EU set to ink landmark free trade agreement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/australia-and-eu-sign-landmark-free-trade-agreement/106344826</link><description>Australia and the European Union are on the cusp of finally reaching a free trade agreement after years of sometimes fraught negotiations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2f93e456b2c17b3158f607d7dd04dcb</guid></item><item><title>Wool price jumps ahead of industry-first Chinese New Year break</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/wool-price-rising-ahead-of-chinese-new-year-break/106339658</link><description>As wool growers enjoy their best prices since 2019, the market will now pause to respect China's request for a week off to celebrate Lunar New Year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62ad96df10ee1750f91b3b33f2f16b56</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Jakara Anthony responds to adversity and delivers a golden reply she sorely deserved</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/jakara-anthony-dual-moguls-gold-winter-olympics-adversity/106345850</link><description>Jakara Anthony stared down adversity, swallowed back her pain, and delivered a performance for the ages to become Australia's greatest Winter Olympian.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c1f5e61f8f54a8f772ce615bad28c1c</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur through to ATP Rotterdam Open final with win over Ugo Humbert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/alex-de-minaur-through-to-atp-rotterdam-final/106346226</link><description>Alex de Minaur becomes the first man to reach three consecutive finals at the Rotterdam Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">841d065eed7395b080396f3f24d0b9bf</guid></item><item><title>ACT Brumbies defeat Western Force 56-24 in Super Rugby Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/act-brumbies-defeat-western-force-56-24-super-rugby/106346216</link><description>The ACT Brumbies have turned up the heat to blitz the Western Force 56-24 in a sapping season-opening Super Rugby Pacific clash in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10ef6f23013268c37706ceee148b7b16</guid></item><item><title>More than a dozen hate symbols banned in Queensland antisemitism crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/hate-symbols-banned-queensland-antisemitism-crackdown/106345062</link><description>The Queensland government has banned more than a dozen symbols associated with Nazi ideology and extremist groups as part of a crackdown on antisemitism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bede2502d95b0b34df8e2c0c50eb6784</guid></item><item><title>AFL State of Origin coaches hail success of concept following Victoria's win over Western Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/afl-state-of-origin-coaches-hail-success-of-concept/106346486</link><description>Winning Victoria coach Chris Scott and his Western Australia counterpart Dean Cox call for State of Origin to be played every year after the concept's stunning return in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a2310e59675ad0bac9b0b865d9ebaef</guid></item><item><title>As Jakara Anthony dealt with her singles moguls crash, her coach worked out how to pick her back up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/how-jakara-anthony-bounced-back-to-winter-olympic-gold/106346110</link><description>As Jakara Anthony dealt with the disappointment of her singles moguls crash, her coach Peter McNiel was working out how to pick her back up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6104582cfaf145ac938b3a35ff9908bb</guid></item><item><title>'Took the wind out of me': Why this man tested himself for plastics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/plastic-pollution-infertility-cancer-urine-test/106340122</link><description>Kal Glanznig had his urine tested as part of an upcoming documentary exploring plastic pollution in Australia. The results left him speechless.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20a78d9083be5d5b2872c764f9c0b081</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous side overturns 14-0 deficit to down Maori in women's All Stars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/womens-all-stars-indigenous-maori-jada-taylor/106347124</link><description>The Indigenous team overturns a 14-0 deficit to score a rousing comeback win over the Maori in the Women's All Stars clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f14485169561b894f2afb767bb7402d</guid></item><item><title>City of Melbourne quiet on plan for Southbank's 'ugly' red stairs, long after design competition announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/city-of-melbourne-southbank-red-stair-replacement-plan-stalls/106274362</link><description>A Melbourne council unveiled a lucrative competition to replace Southbank's much-derided red stairs. But a year after it was due to start, the plan appears to have gone nowhere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">074f26e344537a0ab6c98a25242c702d</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party divided over policy direction as Angus Taylor plots right-wing political shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/liberal-party-right-wing-division-realignment-four-corners/106331358</link><description>Angus Taylor says he will unite the Liberal Party, but a deeper rift is forming between those who want to overhaul the party's direction and those who believe doing so would mean political death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53f0561e891b7b1fdb5be75b1ca47a5a</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur claims Rotterdam Open with impressive victory over Felix Auger-Aliassime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/de-minaur-breaks-through-for-rotterdam-open-triumph/106347904</link><description>An inspired Alex de Minaur produces one of the biggest wins of his career, lifting the Rotterdam Open title by beating red-hot Felix Auger-Aliassime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f49207b10f6c3d8998833e02ddac8d3</guid></item><item><title>Australia defeated by India in opening T20 as Sophie Molineux era gets off to wobbly start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/australia-women-beaten-in-t20/106347920</link><description>Australia slumps to a rain-affected 21-run loss to India in their opening T20 at the SCG, after selectors opted to drop vice-captain Tahlia McGrath.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1d3ad1921ec592fc795d54bc3787c1b</guid></item><item><title>Dams and rivers run dry, forcing Victorian farmers to make tough decisions about their livestock</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/dams-rivers-run-dry-victoria-farmers-livestock-drought-no-rain/106334366</link><description>Victorian farmers are forced to cart water or destock as dams and rivers run dry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18d39a177a6ee9d81a317ca8e1820867</guid></item><item><title>DNA recovered from glove found near Guthrie home that appears to match suspect's glove, FBI says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/fbi-says-dna-recovered-from-glove-found-near-guthrie-home/106348058</link><description>The FBI says a glove containing DNA was found near the home of US TV show host Savannah Guthrie's mother and appears to match those worn by a masked person outside her front door the night she vanished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bec62a52c57acddb60fed5e8e2febd63</guid></item><item><title>Sydney scientist collects wild roadside apples to produce cider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/roadside-apple-cider-made-from-feral-apples-by-scientist/106321000</link><description>Lucien Alperstein has spent the past decade picking feral apples from trees along country back roads and making cider. They say their guerilla activity inspired their curiosity about the science of genetics and fermentation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">196237c7f040a77c709aab786700cd31</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach terror attack gunman Naveed Akram appears in court for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/bondi-terror-attack-gunman-akram-appears-court-first-time/106348400</link><description>Bondi Beach gunman Naveed Akram, who is charged with 15 counts of murder, has appeared via video link for the first time in a Sydney court as a senior magistrate extended existing suppression orders in the case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">371fada7ea7308c7ecec58d7debce4fb</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic type B killer whales seen for first time near WA's Bremer Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/visiting-orcas-steal-the-feed-of-local-killer-whales-in-wa/106345466</link><description>Sightings of Antarctic orcas in Australian waters are very rare. A tour group in WA saw what appeared to be a pod of Antarctic type B killer whales muscle in and steal the meal of a local group of orcas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39f109d1374dbb8d8c0891214ddd9157</guid></item><item><title>How cheating allegations have rocked the curling teams at the Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/winter-olympics-curling-cheating-allegations-explained/106349394</link><description>Controversy is swirling in curling at the Winter Olympics after the Canadian team was accused of cheating. Here's a look at the whole controversy and why it matters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">443f4b616e5ccdfab16fa6775d3ce790</guid></item><item><title>The night snow came to Livigno, turning this surreal valley into an even greater paradise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/snow-livigno-winter-olympic-games/106351744</link><description>Livigno is an Italian outlier in more ways than one. Already known for its special tax status and fairytale quality, the town has had a phenomenal dumping of snow, causing a significant shuffling of events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74681b168ba228a59936a1522013ca77</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian Motor Accident Insurance Board suing Melissa Oates for $934k in damages over Jari Wise's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/maib-chasing-jari-wise-death-driver-melissa-oates-for-934k/106349758</link><description>A woman who hit and killed her partner with her car in 2020 is being pursued for almost $1 million in damages by the Tasmanian Motor Accident Insurance Board.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d18263c5f7c1d7f98b5e30fb65d32e7</guid></item><item><title>Irish rugby to investigate racial abuse towards Test debutant Edwin Edogbo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/ireland-rugby-test-debut-edwin-edogbo-racial-abuse/106352164</link><description>The Irish Rugby Football Union has said it will launch an investigation after turning comments off a social media post that congratulated the country's newest Test debutant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">261d685409d12066905edfb9104ada79</guid></item><item><title>Police likely looking for motive during renewed search for Gus Lamont, retired detective says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/gus-lamont-search-a-hunt-for-motive-criminologist-says/106350820</link><description>Police are again at remote Oak Park Station searching for evidence related to the disappearance of missing four-year-old Gus Lamont, with a retired police officer saying detectives are likely "looking for a motive".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">325eb4db0ed179729629ac1fe1c84238</guid></item><item><title>Ex-footballer shot multiple times in Western Sydney drive-by shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/nsw-greenacre-shooting-police-public-place/106352298</link><description>Police have been told Matt Utai, who played for the Tigers and Bulldogs NRL clubs, was shot outside a home on the street by the occupants of an SUV, before they fled the scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba53d12aff8db788dde0bc0c13507507</guid></item><item><title>Own goal ends Macclesfield's FA Cup fairytale against Brentford</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/fa-cup-macclesfield-brentford-fourth-round/106352296</link><description>Non-league English football club Macclesfield's tremendous FA Cup run has come to an end, falling to Premier League side Brentford.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ef3637794f7ad3aecb3526517be191b</guid></item><item><title>Pod Save America and why Australians remain obssessed with US politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/pod-save-america-why-australians-are-obssessed-with-us-politics/106327878</link><description>Huge crowds have flocked to live shows for the popular and influential Pod Save America podcast, suggesting Australia's obsession with US politics isn't going away anytime soon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29fd6077abedec21a6c24a6198c4c894</guid></item><item><title>Search for abducted Sydney man Chris Baghsarian continues, family living 'a nightmare'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/kidnapping-chris-baghsarian-cousin-hostage-negotiator-sydney/106348436</link><description>The family of Sydney man Chris Baghsarian, who was abducted in a case of mistaken identity four days ago, are awaiting "some form of closure or resolution".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6758c13f5deb62b5d208a2ff0fee9db7</guid></item><item><title>Australia leads the world in moguls skiing. This is why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/australia-winter-olympics-moguls-dominance/106346256</link><description>To the surprise of many, the "beach nation" that is Australia is the best moguls skiing nation on earth. How the team got there is no accident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edc24052fc71a153cb8523cb4c296d67</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Eileen Gu medals despite blizzard, Ilia Malinin breaks his silence — day 10 quick hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/winter-olympics-day-10-quick-hits/106351560</link><description>A Norwegian skier melts down in the Italian cold as the Canadian women's curling team hits back at cheating accusations. Here are the quick hits from day 10 of the Milano Cortina Winter Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3e902ec1235988fcd9d5cb6b4f1c4e4</guid></item><item><title>Austrian man faces terror charges over Taylor Swift concert plot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/man-charged-over-taylor-swift-concert-attack-plot/106352344</link><description>Austrian prosecutors have filed terrorism-related charges against a 21-year-old man who they say planned to carry out an Islamist militant attack at one of Taylor Swift's 2024 concerts in Vienna.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a116a72410998a2bd5cd1447607781ad</guid></item><item><title>WA's illegal tobacco crackdown comes after less than $89,000 in fines issued last year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/wa-illegal-tobacco-enforcement-criticised-ahead-of-new-penalties/106350410</link><description>Amid moves to increase penalties for those involved in the illegal tobacco trade, Western Australian authorities are slammed for handing out just $88,100 in fines last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">533f151a81da30343f398451ee2797aa</guid></item><item><title>Plains-wanderer recorded for first time on outback Queensland cattle station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/rare-plains-wanderer-bird-recorded-on-cattle-station/106350256</link><description>A project with dozens of monitoring sites across the Queensland property confirms the presence of the critically endangered plains-wanderer by analysing bird calls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fb6753c73ebbb858ac8b4791fe49656</guid></item><item><title>Louvre tour guides accused of orchestrating $16m ticket fraud ring over a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/how-louvre-ticket-guides-ran-alleged-ticket-fraud-ring/106353046</link><description>Foreign tour guides and staff who were paid to remain silent orchestrated a counterfeit ticketing ring that robbed the Louvre of millions over more than a decade, Parisian prosecutors say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f41a7c8dc6c1eabf78d49897fd9c645f</guid></item><item><title>CCTV captures man on fire after firebomb attack on Thornton convenience store</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/man-on-fire-cctv-thornton-convenience-store/106353066</link><description>A man engulfed in flames is captured on CCTV after an arson attack at a Hunter Valley business.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9ee7213df91607b954f599de33584e7</guid></item><item><title>Liam Alexander Hall revealed as man charged over alleged terrorism act at Perth Invasion Day rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/invasion-day-alleged-terror-act-liam-alexander-hall/106353674</link><description>The man accused of throwing a bomb at Invasion Day protesters in an alleged terrorism act attack in Perth can be named as Liam Alexander Hall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff6d5e6a3dd2153ca8a25dcce52fcc95</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of murdering Canberra grandmother Irma Palasics pleads guilty to burglary charge as trial begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/irma-palasics-trial-begins-as-two-men-face-murder-charge/106348396</link><description>Lawyers for one of two men on trial for the 1999 murder of Canberra grandmother Irma Palasics tell the ACT Supreme Court he was just the lookout, and had nothing to do with her death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3017b2fe29aed44401597cb6ab90de37</guid></item><item><title>Fire crews battle blaze south of Launceston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/bushfire-warning-for-area-south-of-launceston/106355122</link><description>The Tasmania Fire Service has downgraded an emergency bushfire warning for an area south of Launceston, with helicopters and ground crews in attendance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00134fdf7a0cde3533cca8bcab9042fa</guid></item><item><title>Mobil Oil Australia to pay $16m fine for misleading claims about fuel sold in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/mobil-oil-australia-federal-court-fine-fuel/106354140</link><description>The ACCC said Mobil advertised its Mobil Synergy fuel but did not actually supply the product at the time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c4d1c10dddccaa2bbfc1015123368aa</guid></item><item><title>Addin Fonua-Blake and Briton Nikora embrace chance to play State of Origin following eligibility changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/addin-fonua-blake-briton-nikora-state-of-origin/106355576</link><description>Cronulla duo Briton Nikora and Addin Fonua-Blake have both praised the rule changes that will give the pair a chance at State of Origin football they thought had long passed them by.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ec581ac1f034662bed78ff674c00b7</guid></item><item><title>Sydney’s great fatberg hiding in the sewers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sydney-s-great-fatberg-hiding-in-the-sewers/106355414</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d86c2192d0e5b5504b2ff2bec1bd22ef</guid></item><item><title>Grammy-winning songwriter and hitmaker Billy Steinberg dies aged 75</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/grammy-winning-songwriter-billy-steinberg-dies-aged-75/106356348</link><description>Award-winning US songwriter Billy Steinberg, who wrote several top hit songs including Madonna's Like a Virgin, died on Monday aged 75, according to media reports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb0f5e86348cae84a5923360286fcd40</guid></item><item><title>Australia knocked out of T20 World Cup with one game left to play</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/australia-knocked-out-of-t20-world-cup/106356754</link><description>Australia can no longer catch up with Zimbabwe after it was awarded a point from a rained out match with Ireland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dfa50a4be411761518915d4c45e5985</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian salmon industry subject to stricter mortality reporting rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/tas-salmon-mortality-reporting-new-rules/106355012</link><description>Biosecurity Tasmania has introduced stricter requirements for Tasmania's salmon companies reporting on farmed fish deaths — but whether the public finds out is another matter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b4561f315abfbba772d736bf48eab4d</guid></item><item><title>Long-term solution to repeated Waterfall Way landslips on the horizon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/long-term-solution-repeated-waterfall-way-landslides/106353438</link><description>The NSW government hopes to reopen a key east-west transport route by April, as a long-term solution to frequent landslips in the area is explored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a127abafb503c04ed7b234a9aa7f0e</guid></item><item><title>Matildas expected to name Mary Fowler in Asian Cup squad, injured Charli Grant set to miss out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/matildas-set-to-gamble-on-fowler-fitness-in-asian-cup-squad/106357060</link><description>Mary Fowler is expected to be named in Australia's Women's Asian Cup squad on Thursday despite having played limited minutes in her return from an ACL injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3411cba4c526944d5b5fb418a7a5f2db</guid></item><item><title>Telstra accused of environmental breaches in culturally-significant area in SA national park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/telstra-investigated-environmental-breach-south-australia-site/106349226</link><description>Sources say the actions will likely affect Aboriginal communities and that the investigation was not shared with the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b5f492e4ab694c6050d7c2fadc97f21</guid></item><item><title>Trawool bushfire threat eases but authorities say blaze not yet under control</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/trawool-bushfire-central-victoria-properties-threatened/106355928</link><description>Authorities say weather conditions have helped fire crews battling a blaze that threatened homes near Trawool, south of Seymour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d378db88073d237f73af9307e8515037</guid></item><item><title>Federal Court finds factional and 'oppressive' control in South West Aboriginal Medical Service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/factional-disruption-oppression-swams-south-west-wa/106356254</link><description>A federal court judge has found that two board members factionally controlled a South West Indigenous Medical Service and unfairly expelled members to avoid scrutiny and maintain control.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f7c32eb3790c07f0e4455fc6dafbed2</guid></item><item><title>Equal time rule leads CBS to pull Stephen Colbert's James Talarico interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/cbs-pulls-stephen-colbert-james-talarico-interview/106357474</link><description>The Late Show host's on-air revelation that network executives refused to let him interview a Democratic Senate candidate puts a spotlight on how US media outlets treat political coverage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">676bcd3614265545e614a270c4db7af5</guid></item><item><title>Glove found near Nancy Guthrie's home fails to produce DNA match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/glove-found-near-nancy-guthrie-s-home-fails-to-produce-dna-match/106359296</link><description>The glove resembled a pair worn by an armed man in a ski mask seen in video footage shortly before she was abducted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab853563a7fa8ce16c63ba12962c8784</guid></item><item><title>Alcoa hit with record fine for illegally clearing WA jarrah forests for bauxite mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/alcoa-fined-for-clearing-jarrah-forest-for-bauxite-mine/106359988</link><description>US mining giant Alcoa is forced to pay $55 million after unlawfully clearing parts of a Western Australian native forest to mine bauxite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f74bb47c6f321183a916fc154005c8ee</guid></item><item><title>Former Coles manager admits 'human error' over Shapes 'Down Down' pricing in federal court showdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/coles-accc-discounts-federal-court/106358474</link><description>A former Coles manager has given evidence in the federal court on day three of a bombshell case between the consumer watchdog and supermarket giant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fac3387b11a41f3cb04ca5d82d1e043</guid></item><item><title>Footage shows gunman spraying bullets into suburban home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/footage-shows-gunman-spraying-bullets-into-suburban-home/106360196</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55dab837735b4e8baac3bf3d63e92a34</guid></item><item><title>Police treating spate of Western Sydney shootings and arson attacks as linked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/nsw-shootings-firebombing-st-clair-guildford/106358300</link><description>Raptor Squad detectives are treating three separate incidents as linked to a conflict between two organised criminal networks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b24aea455146642267ad7109b7c6523a</guid></item><item><title>Australian citizen with ISIS links in Syria hit with exclusion order, federal government says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/australia-issues-teo-against-isis-linked-citizen-in-syria-camp/106360092</link><description>The federal government has temporarily banned an Australian citizen linked to ISIS fighters from returning home from Syria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c976fea9e60fc65335285f7b529e237</guid></item><item><title>Solutions to stop people being radicalised raised at NSW inquiry into right-wing extremism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/prevention-methods-discussed-at-nsw-far-right-extremism-inquiry/106359330</link><description>Prevention methods to tackle radicalisation are being discussed by experts at a New South Wales inquiry into measures to combat right-wing extremism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a9b01e0ebe17ca3564cf006f8828956</guid></item><item><title>Claims of 'racist' comment in WA parliament after Chinese New Year event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/wa-parliament-lachlan-hunter-sabine-winton-war-of-words/106360278</link><description>WA Labor MPs call on a Nationals member to apologise for what they say was a racist comment directed at one of their colleagues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90b094442367e4afaca01338731e49d9</guid></item><item><title>Mechanic rescued after going missing in Queensland outback for almost a week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/mechanic-rescued-qld-outback-/106360478</link><description>A man in his 40s has been rescued after going missing in outback Queensland for almost a week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1096a84c273676bb24fd65a2dd8edfaa</guid></item><item><title>Victoria loses Australian MotoGP with 2026 race to be last in state</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/victoria-loses-motogp-after-refusing-to-move-from-phillip-island/106360086</link><description>Victoria loses the rights to host the Australian Motorcycle Grand Prix, ending a three-decade association with the event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfccc65e1d8b9b3f86fe36579af25b73</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Macarthur FC captain Ulises Dávila fined $11k over A-League card fixing saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/ex-a-league-captain-ulises-d%C3%A1vila-fined-over-betting-scandal/106358086</link><description>Former Macarthur FC captain Ulises Dávila avoids jail time over his involvement in a card fixing scandal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d649323fcbad3f77ec947285f3251da</guid></item><item><title>Navy chief's speech disrupted, bomb squad called after rocks thrown through glass door at Canberra hotel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/rocks-thrown-defence-industry-conference-hyatt-canberra/106357386</link><description>Officers are looking for two men who fled on bikes after rocks smashed a glass door, halting a defence industry event in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e12c9133d30ce455cfcf6db31deb63d2</guid></item><item><title>Overnight rain at Kilto Station.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/overnight-rain-at-kilto-station/106359962</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cb8089671d57d545b956c3341acefb5</guid></item><item><title>Heavy rainfall in WA's Kimberley sees students go to extra lengths to get to school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/broome-water-kimberley-heavy-rainfall-hard-school/106359220</link><description>Heavy rainfall in WA's far north has led to some students having to make alternative arrangements to get to school, including using a helicopter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab169a794f18ae909f63b27c1c12f38f</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 12</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide/106357404</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5927607c6b226a4fc3cd81eec0fa5c61</guid></item><item><title>Queensland man accused of offering $730 to adopt and abuse overseas children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/qld-man-refused-bail-over-alleged-child-sex-procurement-plot/106360740</link><description>A Queensland man accused of offering to pay more than $700 to adopt children overseas so he could have sex with them is refused bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0adc407b09567e623482d48b0cf6af66</guid></item><item><title>Human remains found during $13.3m construction project in Echuca</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/human-remains-echuca-police-victoria-park/106360670</link><description>An investigation is underway after bones were found during construction works for a $13.3-million project at Echuca.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d6942c4c85f203cb1d2631ae32f476b</guid></item><item><title>Ex-cop granted bail over alleged stalking following neighbour dispute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/ex-cop-granted-bail-over-alleged-stalking-charges/106359998</link><description>A former Queensland police officer accused of allegedly wearing a balaclava and Easter bonnet to harass and intimidate a neighbouring family has been granted bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aea69af313928f8cdfdf95d42f0e5112</guid></item><item><title>Man fined $30,000 for poaching rare snakes from Far North Queensland rainforest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/man-fined-for-poaching-rare-snakes/106360544</link><description>The court heard Clinton Spiteri was with two others when he visited a rainforest in the Cape York area to steal eight snakes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e054b8dba8caac08516c2d5f4789e82</guid></item><item><title>Two Doubleview house fires cause headaches for firefighters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/firefighters-called-two-doubleview-fires-on-huntriss-road/106360856</link><description>Emergency services extinguish two separate house fires in close proximity to each other in Doubleview in Perth's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7af2dd86bdc52c2a6d03a67403559e2</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters had to work quickly to bring two house fires in Doubleview under control.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/doubleview-house-fire/106361006</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6231d600282e114f06c283e4050a615</guid></item><item><title>Police arrest almost 60 people over unrest in NT community of Wadeye</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/58-people-arrested-over-wadeye-unrest-nt-police/106333000</link><description>Northern Territory police have arrested 58 people in relation to weeks of unrest in the remote Top End community, which has seen brawls involving up to a few hundred of people — some of them armed — spilling out onto the streets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">854e1d608482d9f26e1eec0eb51a86ce</guid></item><item><title>South Australia could host the Australian Motorcycle Grand Prix from 2027</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/sa-could-host-the-australian-motogp/106360386</link><description>An announcement on the future of the Australian Motorcycle Grand Prix is expected as soon as tomorrow amid widespread speculation the event is set to shift to South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b26fba3656006cb6dacc897cffc47d8</guid></item><item><title>Sisonke Msimang picked up what police said was an explosive device at Perth Invasion Day rally, gave it to them and waited for a slow response</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/sisonke-picked-up-ied-thrown-at-perth-invasion-day-rally/106360508</link><description>When Sisonke picked up a device that looked like a glass jar in Perth on Australia Day, she had a sense of foreboding so she took it to police. She says they took some time to act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4484d2c8c44530667bc645d156bdc3b</guid></item><item><title>Driver charged over Camden fatal crash escaped Cumberland Hospital mental health care before incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/cumberland-hospital-patient-absconded-before-camden-fatal-crash/106361010</link><description>A driver charged over a double-fatal crash used a staff pass to escape hospital the day before an alleged Sydney stabber fled the same mental health facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9b460c845ba44fdb8e18d6fdf3752c5</guid></item></channel></rss>