<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 13:17:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>NACC chief executive apologises to parliament for inaccurate evidence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/nacc-ceo-apologises-for-inaccurate-evidence/106056840</link><description>National Anti-Corruption Commission chief executive Philip Reed writes to parliament apologising for inaccuracies in evidence given during Senate estimates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb8d1ecdcffbfbfc1c41c57bd2226d88</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi College hit with wet weather as Tropical Cyclone Fina passes NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/tiwi-college-hit-with-wet-weather-as-tc-fina-passes-nt/106052956</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b0a3f1043e43e5e38868428e1197abf</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi College teachers airlifted off the island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/tiwi-college-teachers-airlifted-off-the-island/106052960</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aaced86ca4c5d8a4648a77d76b1687be</guid></item><item><title>Staff evacuated, calls for ADF assistance after Cyclone Fina wrecks Tiwi College</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/tiwi-college-calls-on-adf-for-cyclone-fina-clean-up-help/106052720</link><description>Staff have been evacuated from a remote boarding school on the Tiwi Islands, and students may not be able to return to classrooms this year, after Ex-Tropical Cyclone Fina tore through the region with devastating force on Saturday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0ccec1558ce2e95f7681db7fd96ebd9</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106055646</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09721726cfe86421116b376155fffee4</guid></item><item><title>South Africa defeat India by 408 runs in second Test match, win series 2-0</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/south-africa-defeat-india-by-408-runs-in-second-test-match/106057186</link><description>South Africa has clinched its first Test series win in India in 25 years with a crushing 408-run win in the second Test, claiming a 2-0 series sweep.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3df46d97963461ce877d85797c0217af</guid></item><item><title>Military helps with rescues in Thailand floods as death toll rises to 33</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/thailand-floods-death-toll-33-military-rescues/106056780</link><description>Floods across nine Thai provinces have killed 33 people and affected more than 2.7 million, with more rain forecast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">555f8758c561b3abed9be9c3910e2afe</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Stars defeat Hobart Hurricanes by 37 runs in WBBL</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/melbourne-stars-defeat-hobart-hurricanes-by-37-runs-in-wbbl/106057274</link><description>The Melbourne Stars will carry solid momentum into Saturday's big WBBL local derby, easily beating top side Hobart by 37 runs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a5a8b887385529d25e48f8c257a0486</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of international student's murder 'likely' had intellectual disability, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/brendan-kantilla-murder-trial-md-isfaqur-rahman-cognitive-state/106055982</link><description>A neuropsychologist has told the Northern Territory Supreme Court a man accused of murdering an international student in Darwin "likely" had an intellectual disability that impacted his ability to exercise self-control.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdba09821ead4cf78149879577427136</guid></item><item><title>US National Parks to raise fees for millions of international tourists to popular sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/us-national-parks-raise-fees-for-international-tourists/106057350</link><description>Changes set to take effect on January 1 will include annual park passes jumping to $US250 for foreign tourists, while US residents will continue to be charged $US80, according to authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6544a5e86aab374c3adc52c6f8f28473</guid></item><item><title>Scores of people killed as Hong Kong's worst fire in years engulfs high-rise complex</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/hong-kong-high-rise-blaze-kills-people-dead-missing/106057480</link><description>Fires that have burnt through the night are yet to be extinguished as firefighters struggle to reach those in need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43157a44fb1f441b52780f6750d6cdfc</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump defends Ukraine envoy Steve Witkoff after leak alleging he advised Kremlin aide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-26/trump-defends-steve-witkoff-leak/106057508</link><description>It comes as a senior Kremlin official confirms Steve Witkoff is set to visit Moscow next week as efforts to find a consensus on ending the nearly four-year war between Russia and Ukraine pick up speed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e99f0e2afb63bf1866f280b62cfb9596</guid></item><item><title>Former Royal Marine Paul Doyle pleads guilty to Liverpool FC parade car ramming charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/man-pleads-guilty-to-liverpool-fc-crowd-ramming/106057626</link><description>More than 100 people were injured at a Liverpool Football Club victory parade in May.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c005583d3519a15cda7490724fb26efa</guid></item><item><title>The sound of a Martian dust devil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/the-sound-of-a-martian-dust-devil/106051060</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23fefd0af540433bfc916c18178510fb</guid></item><item><title>Prawns, sneakers and spices: What we know about Indonesia's radioactive exports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/indonesia-radiation-contamination-explained/106057730</link><description>Authorities in the US and Europe have recalled goods as Indonesian authorities investigate the source of radioactive contamination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e71ac2b853862fe2565535c622520f1</guid></item><item><title>Judge dismisses 2020 election interference case against Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/judge-dismisses-trump-election-interference-cases/106057776</link><description>The abandonment of the Georgia case is the latest reflection of how the US president has emerged largely unscathed from a spate of prosecutions that once threatened to imperil his political career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bacb3a538d1c49248ce5a41d63c14910</guid></item><item><title>Labor is celebrating a successful year but tough budget choices lie ahead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/albanese-government-budget-repair-tax-reform-inflation-figures/106045644</link><description>The level of the prime minister's reform appetite has been discussed and debated since roughly 9pm on election night in May, when Labor's massive win became clear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc7d249f5a1fc31d045262e25487f88b</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos player Ash Riddell has entire school behind her ahead of Saturday's AFLW grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/aflw-grand-final-roos-brisbane-lions-ash-riddell/106055592</link><description>Roos star — and grade 6 teacher — Ash Riddell has an entire school behind her ahead of this Saturday's AFLW grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa1af0827399d6e8529afc6864dad710</guid></item><item><title>Australian music quiz: Test your knowledge of iconic Aussie acts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/australian-music-quiz-ausmusic-t-shirt-day/106024778</link><description>Celebrate Ausmusic T-Shirt Day with our Australian music trivia quiz. How well do you know your local legends?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04461578279a0e63af53eaac4a8c26ea</guid></item><item><title>Fire engulfs high-rise apartment buildings in Hong Kong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/fire-engulfs-high-rise-apartment-buildings-in-hong-kong/106057854</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6975391cd2aeff64d658407b3d156cd9</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump is a 'master of dominating the news' and spotting his distractions can be difficult</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/donald-trump-a-master-of-distraction/106053002</link><description>What does a dead cat have to do with Donald Trump and the Epstein files? Everything, according to some experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c77d8eb18cba465eca69489e5d98414</guid></item><item><title>Black Friday puts 'social pressure' on shoppers as more Australians rack up credit card debt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/black-friday-sales-pressure-pushing-families-into-debt/106050862</link><description>With millions of Australians tipped to spend record amounts this Black Friday, the value of personal credit and charge-card balances accruing interest has hit its highest level since 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed20bcd7ecc0d1ee384e872f40037a8d</guid></item><item><title>London Broncos rugby league hopes buoyed by Brisbane icon Darren Lockyer and players from PNG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/london-broncos-rugby-league-hopes-buoyed-by-brisbane-icon-darren/106054530</link><description>The London Broncos might be the only rugby league club in Britain to have experienced relegation before a season even began — and Darren Lockyer, through the help of PNG Players, is hoping to bring them back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adb18a1d230194d5cd653be6a57035e1</guid></item><item><title>Guinea-Bissau military seizes control and arrests president and opposition leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/military-seizes-control-and-arrests-president-in-guinea-bissau/106057826</link><description>Guinea-Bissau's military says it has seized control of the country and arrested its president following the discovery of a plan to destabilise the coup-prone west African nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96656a1757fcd9c9c3cafd0f82383040</guid></item><item><title>Rockliff's premiership tied to proposed stadium, but his is not the first to push a contentious project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/hobart-stadium-contentious-projects-not-new-for-tasmania/106031950</link><description>With the vote to decide the fate of the Hobart stadium a week away, Premier Jeremy Rockliff's political legacy is in the balance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f16a9e5fe18b1bb157e39386de502c9</guid></item><item><title>NSW deputy coroner to decide if teen's death was caused by meat allergy from tick bites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/nsw-central-coast-mammalian-meat-allergy-ticks-inquest/106050534</link><description>Jeremy Webb died aged 16 after eating sausages while camping in the Central Coast. Growing up, he was bitten by ticks outdoors multiple times.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cb275094f2c8b4ced3fb753f939f33f</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Premier David Crisafulli faces a political test on his home turf in Hinchinbrook by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/crisafulli-kap-hitchinbrook-by-election-north-queensland/106054982</link><description>If the electorate were to vote strongly against the government, it would sting first-term leader David Crisafulli and be spun as a rejection of the LNP's agenda, writes Alex Brewster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f61dcf4492645631956393c9afaccc0</guid></item><item><title>Here is what we know about Hong Kong's Tai Po fire and the role of bamboo scaffolding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/what-we-know-about-hong-kong-tai-po-fire-bamboo-scaffolding/106057774</link><description>The blaze in Tai Po that engulfed multiple high-rise apartment blocks is still burning, and authorities say it likely began in bamboo scaffolding that encased the buildings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3c70703dd65c0158e4a972c10588d22</guid></item><item><title>Death toll rises to 55 as Hong Kong blaze continues to burn, three arrested</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/hong-kong-apartments-kills-dozens-hundreds-missing/106057928</link><description>A massive high-rise apartment fire in Hong Kong's Tai Po district has killed at least 55 people and left hundreds more missing, with firefighters continuing to battle the blaze — as it happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4944c844f04d7dc04528ed1c46887f17</guid></item><item><title>Cricket and hockey among sports in contention to return for 2030 Commonwealth Games in India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/cricket-hockey-set-potential-to-return-commonwealth-games/106057916</link><description>Australia is expecting to see its medal chances boosted at the 2030 Commonwealth Games in Ahmedabad as sports such as cricket and hockey remain in contention to return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f91ed62dd10fe579213fcad75680f5b2</guid></item><item><title>Mother calls for new age limits after 8yo son killed in e-motorcycle crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/mother-calls-for-change-zeke-hondow-killed-emotorbike-crash/106038102</link><description>Kloe Weedon's son Zeke William Hondow, a schoolboy with a sharp wit and even sharper haircuts, was farewelled at a funeral last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">609e2e2d976d22162c79d00f932c38c8</guid></item><item><title>Two National Guard members shot near White House in Washington DC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/national-guard-members-shot-in-washington-dc/106057960</link><description>Authorities say the soldiers were ambushed by a lone gunman while on patrol in Washington, DC, as part of a Trump-ordered crime crackdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a60895cc50de27a7ee9cc8fb206623c5</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Barnaby Joyce quits the Nationals, Labor grilled on power prices in final Question Time of the year — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/federal-politics-live-november-27/106056740</link><description>Former deputy prime minister Barnaby Joyce quits the Nationals. Meanwhile, Labor is grilled on power prices in the final Question Time of 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">541194ba788a7849af6314ab76d415d3</guid></item><item><title>Kotoni Staggs will continue to represent Kangaroos if Kevin Walters remains coach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/rugby-league-kotoni-staggs-kangaroos-kevin-walters-coach/106057948</link><description>Kotoni Staggs must decide between representing Australia or Tonga at the international level, and says there is one key factor that will tip his decision either way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a3a520cd5ff15f4a4e022fd413d25b9</guid></item><item><title>TagEnergy Naracoorte big battery project raises concerns about take-up of agricultural land</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/tagenergy-naracoorte-big-battery-project-concerns-farm-land-sa/106053784</link><description>One of Australia's largest battery energy storage systems would be built on farmland in South Australia's south-east in a proposal that the developer says will lower electricity costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfc3956b34d7f4fc2985968c6a79a0c9</guid></item><item><title>Queensland potato farmers help fill supply gap as southern drought causes national shortage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/queensland-potatoes-in-high-demand-due-to-potato-shortage/106053778</link><description>Potato growers in Queensland's far north are suddenly in hot demand as drought-stricken paddocks in the country's south fail to deliver.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab54a48adc81583eac2c8289c34cc05a</guid></item><item><title>Thousands still without power in Western Sydney as outages plague business owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/nsw-weather-schools-closed-sydney-power-outages-fire-risk/106057966</link><description>Thousands of residents in Western Sydney are waking up without power and some schools across NSW will be closed after freak storms on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b10d44500e538876ee81821f47573618</guid></item><item><title>Global miner BMA drops Queensland mine expansion plan after a decade of environmental checks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/bma-drops-queensland-saraji-east-mine-expansion-plan/106054392</link><description>An environmental impact statement found the project site would clear 136 hectares of koala habitat and significantly affect 33.55 hectares supporting greater glider populations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a2b9f7cfefc3ea2ec835256e073a01c</guid></item><item><title>Suicide Prevention Australia issues report linking adverse childhood experiences with suicide risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/suicide-prevention-australia-recommendations/106051458</link><description>Suicide Prevention Australia says there's an "urgent" need for action to stop the "significant and lasting" impact of childhood trauma.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2fa1155aa0573b8317aeb32f56b965a</guid></item><item><title>Labor strikes deal with Greens to end environmental reform stalemate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/labor-strikes-greens-deal-to-end-environmental-stalemate/106054928</link><description>The years-long stalemate over reforms to environmental laws is set to clear in the final week of the parliamentary year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">457287247a78f8861b98c2a2a62e1428</guid></item><item><title>Varroa mite detected in bee hives at Sellicks Hill and Taratap</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/varroa-mite-detected-at-sellicks-hill-and-taratap/106057922</link><description>Beekeepers are being urged to monitor their hives more frequently after further detections of the deadly bee parasite varroa mite in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7eb6178921afeda19d18f99d63e45b70</guid></item><item><title>Man throwing item over fence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/man-throwing-item-over-fence/106055784</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afc43fd69b8878df07f8e99634932057</guid></item><item><title>Used needle thrown into backyard 'horrifies' Karratha mother</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/needle-thrown-into-backyard-sparks-horror/106046320</link><description>A mother is in disbelief after a needle she believes was used to inject drugs was thrown into her Karratha backyard, where her toddler loves to play.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9414e02a3ff53a6811c01cfa5307b833</guid></item><item><title>Matt Renshaw calls under-fire Usman Khawaja one of Australia's best-ever cricketers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/cricket-matt-renshaw-backs-usman-khawaja-amid-test-battle/106058068</link><description>Matt Renshaw is gunning for a spot in Australia's Test side, but does not want it to come at the expense of Australia's veteran opener Usman Khawaja just yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21256bb8c842b636950f520ea8d75c36</guid></item><item><title>Industry's power woes continue in mining city of Kalgoorlie as peak demand looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/power-woes-for-kalgoorlie-on-edge-of-grid-rear-head-again/106051784</link><description>The WA government has taken the first steps towards fulfilling its election promise of a $150-million, 50-megawatt vanadium flow battery for Kalgoorlie-Boulder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdd6e0c0236d7df04a0de4741a90efe4</guid></item><item><title>Liverpool in worst slump since 1953 after PSV thumping as Arsenal tops Champions League table</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/uefa-champions-league-wrap-liverpool-loss-arsenal-mbappe/106058376</link><description>Liverpool's nightmare run of form continues after being humbled at home once again as Arsenal flexes its muscles in a heavyweight clash to go top of the Champions League.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb2e15e43f350f887661fe28e758503f</guid></item><item><title>Ballarat Gold Mine operators charged over 2024 rockfall that killed miner Kurt Hourigan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/ballarat-gold-mine-collapse-charges/106031668</link><description>The operators of Ballarat Gold Mine have been charged over a rockfall that killed 37-year-old miner Kurt Hourigan and seriously injured a 21-year-old workmate in March 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">010111803eafbfddbe1540944f1ad016</guid></item><item><title>Floods leave at least 50 dead across Thailand, Indonesia and Malaysia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/floods-hit-south-east-asia-killing-at-least-50-people/106057902</link><description>The Thai city of Hat Yai received its heaviest rainfall in 300 years, while mudslides killed dozens on the Indonesian island of Sumatra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55ac0bd33d6d24697793ea836bc613fb</guid></item><item><title>Banking regulator APRA to impose home loan caps amid housing boom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/banking-regulator-apra-imposes-home-loan-caps/106058604</link><description>The banking regulator will impose restrictions on home loans from early next year to limit the number of "high-risk" large loans being issued to customers, which could have flow on effects in the housing market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e618ae3926dd5a073f3c4e646719968</guid></item><item><title>Victoria faces risky summer with bushfire potential fuelled by spring grass growth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/summer-fire-outlook-puts-victoria-at-high-bushfire-risk/105904142</link><description>Dry conditions dogging Victoria put the state at a high risk of bushfires this summer, according to the latest summer fire outlook.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cf73f58347b048623fa0fcf358ee844</guid></item><item><title>Eight-year-old boy injured in reported stabbing at Berwick school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/police-investigating-reported-school-stabbing-berwick-melbourne/106058974</link><description>An eight-year-old boy has been treated for non-life-threatening injuries after a reported stabbing at a school in Melbourne's south-east on Thursday morning, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">316e315328561c7f94077cdf6c9d7a6a</guid></item><item><title>Hotter than average summer forecast as fire authorities warn of 'highly flammable' conditions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/summer-bushfire-outlook-2025-afac-bom/106056420</link><description>An increased risk of bushfire is expected for parts of the country this summer, with most areas expecting hotter than normal temperatures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35de51530d6e65def2fe73a47d7fc215</guid></item><item><title>From Tehran to Roma: First permanent psychiatrist appointed in south-west Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/permanent-psychiatrist-roma-rural-queensland-farzin-rezaei/106050574</link><description>Farzin Rezaei has made the move from the Tehran University of Medical Sciences to the vast plains of south-west Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65fbc604044ece1cbbb01932b536d867</guid></item><item><title>Labor and Greens agree on extra ABC funding for kids' programs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/labor-and-greens-agree-on-extra-abc-kids-funding/106058638</link><description>A deal between the federal government and the minor party will see an extra $50 million go to the public broadcaster to facilitate passage of a bill to impose local content requirements on streaming platforms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c824131213857592fc38200c1446b5d9</guid></item><item><title>Drone vision shows the Hong Kong towers continuing to burn.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/drone-vision-shows-hong-kong-towers-continuing-to-burn/106072156</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8998c1cde1669c6e8a724cdfbef0dbf</guid></item><item><title>White wine grape oversupply 'another kick in the guts' for growers already in crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/white-wine-oversupply-set-to-deepen-grower-crisis/106049916</link><description>The wine grape industry has written to the SA government pleading for help as it reaches breaking point after indicative pricing for the next vintage is released showing growers could face losses of up to $270 per tonne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">151dd7784ca8f537f4b48874b3828488</guid></item><item><title>Government projected to badly miss 2035 climate target, fall shy of 2030</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/climate-target-2035-badly-miss-projection/106059034</link><description>The Environment Department projects Australia is expected to fall well short of its commitment to cut emissions by 62 to 70 per cent by 2035 — though the minister notes that is before accounting for a number of recent commitments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eebb6d19b55247b0bd317df371ca0e8</guid></item><item><title>ICC rates Perth pitch 'very good' despite two-day finish, putting spotlight on England's poor batting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/icc-rates-perth-stadium-cricket-pitch-very-good-two-day-finish/106071812</link><description>Suggestions the pitch at Perth Stadium was not up to scratch for the first Ashes Test have been well and truly put to bed as the ICC hands down its assessment of the playing surface.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34684565fdadc4fb9024644dcc6d6a51</guid></item><item><title>A new war looms one year on from the Israel-Lebanon ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/new-war-looms-israel-hezbollah-ceasefire/106054010</link><description>One year after Israel and Hezbollah agreed to a ceasefire, the IDF is bombing Beirut again. And Israel has promised its latest strike will not be the last unless Lebanon's government does more to disarm Hezbollah.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7f4b0f925d96470a8b995f7e62579af</guid></item><item><title>Bamboo scaffolding is seen falling from burning buildings in Hong Kong.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/bamboo-scaffolding-hong-kong-fire/106072298</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76a4aa0f6ac12afa3d7e836733e3865d</guid></item><item><title>Coroner releases findings into murder of Lilie James at Sydney school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/nsw-lilie-james-murder-sydney-coronial-inquest-findings/106055226</link><description>A NSW coroner has urged young people to consider their use of location-sharing technology after the "senseless" murder of Lilie James at the hands of her ex-boyfriend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fce86aa8cf89453a7bb4d17ab58df194</guid></item><item><title>Motherly love produces sweet jujube crop for grower near regional Victorian city of Mildura</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/motherly-love-produces-sweet-jujube-crop-mildura/106033130</link><description>Jujubes are a relatively unknown fruit for most Australians, but the sweet fruit has strong domestic demand for those looking for a taste of home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">baaea74624af0abd3a70790f1c1a8bcb</guid></item><item><title>Why housing, renewables and mining projects may speed up under new environment laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/how-new-epbc-environment-laws-may-speed-up-housing-renewables/106051844</link><description>Major housing, renewables and mining projects often get bogged down for years by Australia's aging environment laws. Now a deal to rewrite them could change that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74282892f23e8416aff1ac1dfeb6e18e</guid></item><item><title>Second company confirms asbestos present in imported lift brake pads at wind farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/asbestos-wind-turbines-renewables-import-goldwind/106058220</link><description>A second renewable energy provider says it is taking "immediate action" after the discovery of asbestos in imported brake pads used on access lifts at its wind farms around the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff25f126e9825176d97f85b99151ac92</guid></item><item><title>Jai Opetaia's opponent Huseyin Cinkara vows to knock him 'senseless' in Gold Coast title fight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/boxing-huseyin-cinkara-vs-jai-opetaia-threat-fight-preview/106072532</link><description>Jai Opetaia's next opponent, Germany's Huseyin Cinkara, believes he has the power it takes to defeat the Australian world cruiserweight champion when they meet in the Gold Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96679dd1e45bb0e451fbf4952a2698ff</guid></item><item><title>Why did Donald Trump send US National Guard troops to Washington DC in August?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/why-is-national-guard-in-washington-dc/106072368</link><description>The two US National Guard soldiers who were shot in Washington were among more than 2,000 troops deployed to the US capital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">862e004d68643e5fdd2535a53705e0f5</guid></item><item><title>Italy votes to make femicide a crime after series of killings and violence against women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/italy-votes-to-make-femicide-a-crime/106058866</link><description>Prime Minister Giorgia Meloni says the measure will help "defend the freedom and dignity of every woman", following a series of killings and other violence targeting women in Italy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f4d0455967c605a5862f1f3e986e80c</guid></item><item><title>Future of Tasmania's foresty industry uncertain as Labor, Greens agree on environmental reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/native-logging-industry-reacts-labor-greens-environmental-reform/106058926</link><description>The government has struck a deal with the Greens to overhaul Australia environmental laws, sparking concerns for the future of Tasmania's native logging industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e8d9edbe73058dca32b4efe24c1ef73</guid></item><item><title>Bali governor demands demolition of glass lift at Kelingking Beach in Nusa Penida</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/bali-governor-demands-demolition-of-kelingking-beach-glass-lift/106071962</link><description>A controversial glass elevator at one of Bali's most picturesque beaches will have to be dismantled, with authorities citing planning violations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92b6991ba8d42977b7801376bf6c6188</guid></item><item><title>Court hears murder of Steven and Min Cho 'utterly destroyed' lives of their family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/steven-min-cho-baulkham-hills-murder-family-speak-court/106072406</link><description>An emotional court hearing has been told the pain felt by the family of Min and Steven Cho after they were killed by a martial arts instructor almost two years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d1a849313be64fcb356990a875d58da</guid></item><item><title>Roger Cook declares he has 'industrial FOMO' as Law Society slams powerful development laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/premier-roger-cook-says-he-has-industrial-fomo/106072428</link><description>Roger Cook declares he has "industrial FOMO" and wants to take every opportunity to bring big projects to the state, as WA's peak legal body slams proposed new laws aimed at fast-tracking development.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e88ef60ee797b1e699e35742c01b480</guid></item><item><title>WA Premier Roger Cook says he has "industrial fomo"</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/vertical-roger-cook-industrial-fomo/106072992</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3907684179431c31f35634c3a523922f</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Health imposes three month closures on illegal tobacco stores after statewide raids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/queensland-health-shuts-down-tobacco-stores-across-state/106054716</link><description>Dozens of stores across every corner of the state have been closed for three months as officers exercise new powers passed in Queensland's parliament last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4ef6a2c8e5e629d96de4e9b6dd2f3a4</guid></item><item><title>Kimberley man jailed for five years over 'brutal' attack on heavily pregnant woman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/petrol-station-attack-pregnant-woman-kimberley-man/106056730</link><description>A Kimberley man has been sentenced to five years in jail after attacking a pregnant woman, forcing her to have an emergency caesarean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">654652137ac6b660f9428e79b99d1090</guid></item><item><title>Hunter school teacher Karly Rae pleads guilty to sexually abusing 15-year-old boy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/nsw-school-teacher-karly-rae-pleads-guilty-with-teen/106072046</link><description>High school teacher Karly Rae, 37, pleads guilty to sexually assaulting a teenage boy in the Hunter Valley region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e49528e9627d50634e406ccde70551c</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong inferno puts spotlight on risks of bamboo scaffolding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/hong-kong-inferno-puts-spotlight-on-risky-bamboo-scaffolding/106058820</link><description>Hong Kong's deadliest fire in three decades draws attention to its risky use of flammable bamboo scaffolding and mesh for building work, in a tradition dating back centuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47eb71c180cb2095a2970244e7a4e145</guid></item><item><title>Head of Queensland child safety inquiry flags subpoena as department accused of ignoring law</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/child-inquiry-legal-priorities-care-department-queensland/106071834</link><description>The head of Queensland's child safety inquiry says he "might need to subpoena" files from the department after hearing it was often "not" following its own legislation around preferred permanency options for children in care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1c3fe438c94c263bede033ddac7acef</guid></item><item><title>From harried mums to high-stakes magic here are November's best movies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/november-movie-wrap-what-to-watch/106044854</link><description>November saw the return of two beloved franchises; magic-filled Now You See Me and action classic Predator — but can either live up to their predecessors?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bb4ee3da5f8691e532198a7fd6f9ed4</guid></item><item><title>Community legal service warns more women enduring domestic violence being turned away</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/community-legal-services-call-for-funding-help-domestic-violence/105981066</link><description>A community legal service gave Daisy the help she needed after she returned home to find her children gone — but she is one of the lucky ones, and there's a warning things are getting worse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56f576d53dd5ad0bc2c5df312413a680</guid></item><item><title>United States says it has stopped processing all immigration requests from Afghan nationals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/us-immigration-stops-afghanistan-applications/106073890</link><description>The decision comes hours after US President Donald Trump said he was confident the suspect behind the shooting of two National Guard soldiers in Washington was from Afghanistan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94f55ec54347170d813acc90c4beda9e</guid></item><item><title>Temperatures soar across south-east Queensland as heatwave and humidity intensify</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/south-east-queensland-hot-weather-thursday/106058968</link><description>After days of relentless heat and storms, temperatures have jumped sharply again today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e285a8fb781432974ea7b6e1bcea2da</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce quits Nationals, will sit as independent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/barnaby-joyce-quits-nationals/106073080</link><description>The former leader and deputy prime minister has confirmed his long-awaited political move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad80d64fab33e97131a94af09ce91139</guid></item><item><title>Muhammad Abdur Rehman Mirza jailed over murder of Helen Marsuk after body found in a South Fremantle harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/muhammad-mirza-jailed-over-murder-of-helen-marsuk/106058954</link><description>A Perth man who stabbed a woman multiple times in a "ferocious attack" before her body was found in a South Fremantle harbour has been sentenced to 20 years in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0596f2dfa0728320bca460e47023e67</guid></item><item><title>Artificial reefs to be installed in Queensland's Great Sandy Marine Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/artificial-reefs-for-queenslands-great-sandy-marine-park/106072706</link><description>Claims new artificial reefs being installed in a protected marine park could damage a vulnerable natural coral reef are disputed by Queensland's environment minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adb041adf0a56dd405c9a5b94647401c</guid></item><item><title>Live grenade, firearms, sledgehammer seized by police after Sydney shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/live-grenade-sledgehammer-firearms-seized-police-sydney-shooting/106073960</link><description>The NSW Police bomb disposal unit and Australian Defence Force attended to safely remove the grenade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0165e566eed68cdcd24319a7e8ec447</guid></item><item><title>Rajwinder Singh, on trial for murder of Toyah Cordingley, told undercover officer he saw 'killers' and 'ran'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/toyah-cordingley-murder-accused-conversation-undercover-officer/106073564</link><description>The jury has been played a a covert recording of a conversation Rajwinder Singh had with an undercover officer in a police station cell in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">646a0cfdf15fd5f725422530296e9181</guid></item><item><title>How families tracked victims and survivors in real time during Hong Kong's Tai Po tower fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/how-families-tracked-hong-kong-fatal-fire-in-real-time-online/106073204</link><description>When a fatal fire tore through seven high-rise towers in Hong Kong's Tai Po district, thousands of families were glued to a single webpage that offered updates far more quickly than official government briefings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e2290560386f7b6709730cbd29a277f</guid></item><item><title>ASIC takes action over developer David McWilliams alleged spending of frozen assets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/david-mcwilliams-asic-ndis-developer/106058612</link><description>ASIC alleges businessman David McWilliams has continued to spend money in frozen bank accounts on cruises, gambling and a trip to Disneyland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ca5102e3beaa148f9f9314dd5b1ea77</guid></item><item><title>Long-time SA Labor MP Leon Bignell to quit politics at March election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/labor-mp-leon-bignell-quits-politics/106074020</link><description>Leon Bignell has announced he will retire from politics at the next state election bringing an end to his 20-year reign as the MP for Mawson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fbd580b44e677673d20c5c424767f91</guid></item><item><title>Joyce exits, Turnbull returns as Ghosts of Christmas Past haunt parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/pauline-hanson-barnaby-joyce-malcolm-turnbull-environmental-deal/106045622</link><description>In the end, it turns out not even a Wagyu steak from Gina Rinehart's cattle company cooked on a sandwich press was enough to lock in Barnaby Joyce's defection to One Nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c5b7ab2901acdb567b6d8b309e7f264</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder after Doomadgee crash leads to death of woman and girl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/doomadgee-man-charged-with-murder-remote-outback-community/105990700</link><description>A 28-year-old man has been charged with the murder of a 30-year-old woman and 10-year-old girl after a crash in the remote community of Doomadgee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">257c7e630165eca6c46118da3d56ac28</guid></item><item><title>James Anderson expects England to pick same side for second Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/anderson-expects-england-to-pick-same-side-for-second-ashes-test/106074560</link><description>England are unlikely to tinker with their side for the second Ashes Test against Australia starting in Brisbane next week despite being thumped in the opening match, former fast bowler James Anderson has said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">630bd12ba3bd647c27bb2bd361ffa514</guid></item><item><title>P-plater avoids jail for hit-and-run incident that killed Albany mother and nurse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/hit-and-run-accused-sentenced/106032134</link><description>A 21-year-old woman has been sentenced for being the driver involved in a hit-and-run incident which killed Albany woman Bronwyn Clark in July.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed84ee58cc04f6b25475a3e19d4c9ffd</guid></item><item><title>Australian PGA Championships round one cut short by storms, with Spain's Sebastian Garcia in the lead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/early-ace-as-big-guns-set-australian-pga-pace-in-brisbane/106074332</link><description>In-form Spaniard Sebastian Garcia shoots three strokes clear of a big-name leaderboard before Brisbane's storms halt his first-round charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddf655b2e4ac071eda0d28e0fccbc474</guid></item><item><title>Mental health defence flagged in trial of son accused of killing father with a crowbar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/milenko-snjegota-farmborough-heights-murder-trial/106074074</link><description>A NSW court is told heard Milenko Snjegota had limited capacity for reason when he allegedly murdered his 74-year-old father in their home near Wollongong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc59c7539bdb3cb0f392152e78c697db</guid></item><item><title>Dead fish, foam seen on metro beaches despite overall low Karenia algal levels</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/foam-and-dead-fish-seen-on-adelaide-beaches/106058862</link><description>Authorities say metropolitan testing shows Karenia algal levels remain low compared with last month, despite thick foam and fish deaths seen on some beaches in recent days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5642130694d61a2e34e5915ea6b79ecf</guid></item><item><title>With a deal on Australia's environmental laws, Murray Watt has cemented his reputation as a 'fixer'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/environmental-laws-deal-watt-a-fixer-greens-negotiations/106073524</link><description>In his deal with the Greens, Environment Minister Murray Watt has just scraped off one of the biggest barnacles clinging to parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">804e194f7bdde600f65fda9cfda2ac70</guid></item><item><title>Woman sentenced over Willetton hit-and-run crash that injured schoolgirl Alexis Lloyd</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/perth-hit-and-run-driver-tahira-shaheen-sentenced/106074546</link><description>A 49-year-old L-plater who kept driving after hitting a 12-year-old as she walked to school in suburban Perth, causing serious injuries, is jailed for 16 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ece4d8bc641987441319504bb45a62b</guid></item><item><title>Neuropsychologist in 'emphatic' disagreement over whether alleged murderer had substantial mental impairment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/brendan-kantilla-murder-trial-nt-supreme-court-neuropsychologist/106073702</link><description>A neuropsychologist tells the court an NT man accused of murdering an international student was not suffering from a substantial mental impairment at the time of the alleged crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bde41a5b3ead7c1c7c08d7599b187ea</guid></item><item><title>Breeding stallion St Jean, sire of Melbourne Cup winner Half Yours, dies after collision with fence post</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/sire-of-melbourne-cup-winner-half-yours-dies-in-paddock-accident/106075010</link><description>Stud operators mourn the death of "beloved" stallion St Jean — whose son Half Yours won the Melbourne and Caulfield Cups — after breaking his leg in a paddock accident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8eba85056e8a74d2007ac81b110f8656</guid></item><item><title>Cameron Reginald Welsh handed extra jail time for bashing prison guards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/man-who-bashed-prison-guards-to-serve-more-jail-time/106058328</link><description>A NSW inmate who bashed four prison guards will serve extra jail time, after a judge quashed his non-custodial term on appeal, calling it "an affront to the administration of justice".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">867eb3c3dca1a5e8302b8ba422e4a017</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106075062</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b37aa8afb73f4cf1a95b7336a26a230c</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong fire kills at least 83, hundreds still missing as firefighters continue to battle blaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/hong-kong-apartment-fire-kills-dozens-hundreds-missing/106074662</link><description>Authorities say the apartment complex blaze may have been caused by a "grossly negligent" construction firm using unsafe materials. Three men have been arrested on suspicion of manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbacd4bd18dc0d632ac34672c376e531</guid></item><item><title>Berkeley River Lodge caretakers survived 'apocalyptic' Cyclone Fina in underground bunker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/caretakers-survive-cyclone-fina-in-underground-bunker/106074722</link><description>Laura Stokes and Adam Zerna describe spending time in an underground bunker as the category three cyclone passed over, before emerging to find an "apocalyptic" scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cdd0632c6813ae38dd25f4518ffe26b</guid></item><item><title>NT rams through changes to Banned Drinker Register amid parliamentary debate on scrutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/nt-parliament-banned-drinking-order-changes-on-urgency-bdo-bdr/106056090</link><description>In the final hours of parliament for the year, the government has extended the time a person issued with a Banned Drinker Order is prevented from drinking alcohol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d9fdcacf79bdc27fe03cadca73109bc</guid></item><item><title>Correspondent James Oaten in Hong Kong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-27/correspondent-james-oaten-in-hong-kong/106075604</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f52cac8cd68669593c249840062f438e</guid></item><item><title>Putin says US plan could be 'basis' for end to Ukraine war, but threatens to take land</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/us-ukraine-text-could-form-basis-future-peace-agreement/106075894</link><description>Vladimir Putin suggests he is open to developing a new agreement, but says Russia will continue fighting if no deal is struck.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fc9c414169da28fc6d378dde93e8833</guid></item><item><title>Troops critically injured in Washington shooting named as FBI launches terror probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/national-guard-troops-critical-dc-shooting-lakanwal/106075898</link><description>Authorities identify the two National Guard members shot just blocks from the White House, as the FBI carries out searches of two properties on the US west coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3306015607d4d84545f785167cd7faea</guid></item><item><title>The ABC's explosive childcare investigations began with an email</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/four-corners-childcare-safety-investigation-profit-abuse/106054128</link><description>This story is about something deeper than policy or profit. It's about the trust parents place in childcare every morning when they hand over their children, believing they will be safe — only to find they're not.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">565a54873d41f4884181dcefb55e2629</guid></item><item><title>Student paramedic wins battle with Ambulance Victoria over beard policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/ambulance-victoria-mask-beards-ppe/106072778</link><description>A student paramedic who accused Ambulance Victoria of discrimination on the grounds of race and religion is "ecstatic" to have won his battle to allow cultural beards on the job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8603b192af88be50f617e729e0a3400a</guid></item><item><title>Patrick Lee Brown sentenced to three years in prison over 'inexcusable' Tasmanian car chases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/patrick-lee-brown-sentenced-police-chases-launceston-hobart/106074964</link><description>During sentencing, a Supreme Court Justice told Patrick Lee Brown he "completely disregarded the safety of anyone else" during two different police pursuits, including one in a stolen rental truck with blown-out tyres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f2d03e954f98247d476033a91f412b9</guid></item><item><title>Macquarie Point stadium planning panel tells parliament of ongoing concerns a week from crucial vote</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/stadium-expert-planning-panel-presents-tasmania-upper-house/106074672</link><description>An expert planning panel has defended their scathing assessment of Hobart's proposed Macquarie Point stadium while speaking to the politicians who will ultimately decide the project's fate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54d1b89e512468f2010ccb2e2c36f11d</guid></item><item><title>Frozen rewrote the Disney princess narrative — and 12 years later, it's still relevant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/frozen-movie-elsa-anna-disney-princess-narrative/106028062</link><description>It wasn't just a box office success — Frozen introduced a new type of Disney princess: one who was strong, flawed and uninterested in romance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a85819a41d9e434e1858a6a2f98a85c8</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong residents devastated by mega blaze engulfing blocks of flats in Tai Po district</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/hong-kong-fire-tai-po-district-devastates-local-residents/106058690</link><description>Locals are in shock after fire destroyed apartment blocks home to thousands of people, as questions remain about the suitability of building materials and a lack of fire alarms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e120ab685c2b233ab8699cf50790bf4</guid></item><item><title>Social media ban implementation will 'vary' across platforms, eSafety commissioner warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/social-media-ban-implementation-to-vary-across-platforms/106075376</link><description>Not all Australians aged under 16 will "magically disappear overnight" from social media, the nation's online safety regulator says, amid a legal challenge to pause the start of the federal government's ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4031126c5650441d0b4cced144d50d67</guid></item><item><title>Maduro sings Lennon's 'Imagine' during a rally with supporters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/maduro-sings-lennon-s-imagine-during-a-rally-with-supporters/106056320</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87d3d2420b03ff23df27551a932ea6b8</guid></item><item><title>The flashpoints leading the US and Venezuela to the brink of a conflict decades in the making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/us-venezuela-tension-flashpoints-and-history-explained/106037756</link><description>Tensions between Donald Trump and Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro Moros have been escalating after months of launching lethal air strikes on vessels accused of shipping deadly drugs north to the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e05d0863ab82c615187bd5305ff85bb7</guid></item><item><title>Calls for states to change alcohol laws ahead of women’s ministers meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/alcohol-delivery-violence-against-women-children-ministers/106075170</link><description>A major review into preventing violence against women and children called for changes to immediate alcohol home delivery</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75de4bdd1d698ed274797ef8f19599cc</guid></item><item><title>How to spot a scam during Black Friday and Cyber Monday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/how-to-stay-vigilant-for-black-friday-cyber-monday-scams/106020794</link><description>As scammers look to exploit sales during Black Friday and Cyber Monday, we explain what you need to know to avoid being duped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">603e861eec95b5b55d7aa539d56feb59</guid></item><item><title>Second storm of the year pushes tiny town of Nevertire to its limit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/storm-damage-onslaught-batters-rural-town-nevertire/106072008</link><description>A storm that hit a tiny rural NSW town, damaging one in 10 homes, is psychologically draining for residents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ee59ac88a5c7a76bc45eea502bcb1eb</guid></item><item><title>Perth Scorchers defeat Melbourne Renegades by four wickets in WBBL clash at Junction Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/perth-scorchers-defeat-melbourne-renegades-four-wickets-wbbl/106076168</link><description>Perth have survived a dramatic collapse to beat the Melbourne Renegades by four wickets, denying the Renegades a share of top spot on the WBBL ladder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">806f5cf45451ad7a88e7ea9dbbb0fec6</guid></item><item><title>One of Hong Kong's deadliest fires engulfed multiple high-rise towers in just hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/how-the-hong-kong-fire-unfolded-tai-po-district/106058300</link><description>Hong Kong's deadliest fire in decades tore through a group of high-rise residential towers in a densely packed housing estate, causing major issues for firefighters. This is how the catastrophe unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">795d89f719273c8195928d87916bc58e</guid></item><item><title>Greens out-step flat-footed Liberals on crucial environmental deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/labor-greens-deal-murray-watt-liberals-bowen-chalmers/106045646</link><description>The environmental deal is a major win for a government whose critics on the left are calling for it to be more reformist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbd419f5416a826abe1d7016a6c2b855</guid></item><item><title>When Sydney's popular swimming spots will reopen as weather heats up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/sydneys-popular-swimming-spots-reopening-as-weather-heats-up/106072988</link><description>From 'Pondi' to Sydney Harbour, here's when your popular spots will reopen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf4af291afc8e57b17f5b7d796bcf996</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri dismisses helping McLaren teammate Lando Norris win F1 drivers' championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/oscar-piastri-will-not-help-lando-norris-win-f1-title-in-qatar/106076210</link><description>Oscar Piastri says McLaren raised the prospect of the Australian helping his teammate Lando Norris win the Formula 1 world championship, but it was rejected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3ec980521382ffb12e9d33768384b86</guid></item><item><title>Infrastructure installed to probe Coorong storm surges and groundwater impacts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/coorong-murray-research-for-future-erosion-rising-sea-levels-sa/106013728</link><description>Infrastructure to monitor the impact of rising sea levels and storm surges on the Coorong in South Australia has been installed along the thin strip of coastline between Goolwa Beach and the lagoons of the Ramsar-listed wetland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d8134b101b12c53dff3475c445f3957</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne protesters throw fruit, rocks, glass at police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/melbourne-protesters-throw-fruit-rock-glass-at-police/106076318</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dc88592d63b4c5f785ce3bbc7c9fffd</guid></item><item><title>Cool weather sets cherry crops 'weeks' behind schedule in lead-up to Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/cold-weather-cherry-delay-crops-fruit-victoria/106059072</link><description>The latest casualty in a year of delayed crops is the cherry, with cold weather in some growing regions setting the festive favourite "weeks" behind schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3612aa2f5f80c3dc5098162be5c662b1</guid></item><item><title>US futures markets halted as CME data centre overheats — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-28-november/106074700</link><description>Derivates trading operator CME Group says trading in its markets has been halted due to a cooling issue at data centres. Global financial markets watch futures closely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ae0c62e2e60633eaddc29868f23f37f</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong residents react to deadly apartment block fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/hong-kong-residents-react-to-deadly-apartment-block-fire-/106076340</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7eec80d7d00058122d9124bcbb3c8d5</guid></item><item><title>Indian cricket star Deepti Sharma fetches highest WPL price, Australia captain Alyssa Healy unsold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wpl-cricket-record-auction-price-alyssa-healy-unsold/106076270</link><description>All-rounder Deepti Sharma fetched the highest price at the Women's Premier League (WPL) auction, while Australia captain Alyssa Healy, one of the marquee players up for grabs, went unsold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f71128bee52e51ebbd4cda7fbc61351</guid></item><item><title>Leaked memo shows Legal Aid NT board rejected service cuts exemption for children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/legal-aid-nt-service-cuts-board-refused-youth-exemption/106057132</link><description>A leaked internal memo shows the board of the NT's main legal aid service voted down a proposal to exempt children accused of crimes from sweeping service cuts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5abc04c60d69be9302e237ec9184937</guid></item><item><title>Will Infinity Planet succeed where other theme parks have failed?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/infinity-planet-park-proposed-elimbah/106023262</link><description>A mega theme park and entertainment precinct has been proposed for a rural township between Brisbane and the Sunshine Coast. But will this one happen?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0d5a5658895d94e90842dfeaa91abed</guid></item><item><title>How a breakdown in the search for a boat named Margaret led to adventure on the Birdsville Track</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/inland-barge-reconnects-outback/106045962</link><description>The ABC's Landline crew discovers extreme kindness with a can-do attitude after a mechanical breakdown in South Australia's outback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3900ff291da27d0cba5eb67d9f84795e</guid></item><item><title>Trump says US must re-examine Biden era immigrants from Afghan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/trump-says-us-must-re-examine-biden-era-immigrants-from-afghan/106076436</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81ab4e8ec577f66aa2f9170b3d83b067</guid></item><item><title>United States to begin reviewing all asylum cases approved under Joe Biden's presidency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/us-to-review-all-asylum-cases-under-biden/106076322</link><description>US Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) says it has begun "a full-scale, rigorous re-examination of every Green Card for every alien from every country of concern".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d5b5129d35a1d8e0f8954109f0262ce</guid></item><item><title>Former WA police officer Kaine Burgess relives the night his patrol car was rammed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/retired-police-officer-shares-harrowing-story/106011590</link><description>More than two years on from a serious crash that saw him medically retired, a former police officer says he can still hear the screech of tyres before the deafening bang of a car slamming into his police wagon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ee39cf3b5fdb5213f314ddcdd462d23</guid></item><item><title>'Brumby Bill' protecting heritage value of wild horses to be scrapped in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/nsw-upper-house-vote-scrap-brumby-bill/105916360</link><description>A widely criticised bill recognising the heritage value of wild horses in Kosciuszko National Park will be scrapped in a move celebrated by the Invasive Species Council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">218f14fa35313423c0ae0caa3984a13b</guid></item><item><title>Estella brings strength and resilience to her family as she navigates life with disability in remote NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/estella-jones-tennant-creek-fighting-spirit-sam-cameron-idpwd/106024834</link><description>Nineteen-year-old Estella Jones lives with a disability in her hometown of Tennant Creek, where she loves baking brownies, singing karaoke and spending time with good friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a69782b87662c716e55f95068ba1a663</guid></item><item><title>Fuzzy Zoeller, Masters and US Open champion, dies aged 74</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/fuzzy-zoeller-masters-and-us-open-champion-dies-aged-74/106076532</link><description>Fuzzy Zoeller, a two-time major champion and one of golf's most gregarious characters whose career was tainted by a racially insensitive joke about Tiger Woods, has died aged 74.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecc335a023b9a3cf1ee94ed8107808ec</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners in WA's north challenge state over fast-tracking mining exploration approvals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wa-challenged-over-fast-tracking-mining-exploration-approvals/106055862</link><description>Traditional owners in WA's north launch legal action against the state government claiming it is fast-tracking mining and exploration projects using "expedited procedure" approvals at cultural expense.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1acd9b4007bcc42af41bfabb5e31199e</guid></item><item><title>France to reintroduce voluntary military service amid growing threat of war with Russia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/france-to-restore-voluntary-military-service/106076506</link><description>French President Emmanuel Macron is reintroducing voluntary military service almost three decades after it was scrapped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5c85ec7dfcf0ceed09cb90cedadd5a0</guid></item><item><title>Widespread flooding in Hat Yai, southern Thailand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/widespread-flooding-in-hat-yai-southern-thailand/106076954</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74e334669c05711e0f083d09811ebb74</guid></item><item><title>Inquest concludes into death of SA boatie Tony Higgins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/inquest-into-death-of-anthony-higgins-ends/106074014</link><description>A coroner has found Anthony Higgins, who went missing in 2020 sparking the largest and most expensive marine search in South Australian waters, died two weeks later when he went missing again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61223a88fc3bf783740e8e43e1bf7a69</guid></item><item><title>Common antidepressant helps reduce some men's domestic violence, ReINVEST trial finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/reinvest-clinical-trial-anti-depressant-reduce-domestic-violence/105999382</link><description>The findings are significant not just because of how much the trial reduced domestic violence, but because only a few years ago it drew fierce criticism from women's advocates and politicians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5ae82aa88fb1df7aebdb637f7dac70e</guid></item><item><title>Benedict Bryant found guilty of dangerous driving causing the death of Jai Kalani Wright</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/nsw-benedict-bryant-verdict-jai-wright-death/106075564</link><description>Benedict Bryant had pleaded not guilty to dangerous driving occasioning death over the crash in inner Sydney in February 2022, which killed Jai Wright.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7851b2e4abcbdfd81ad9a630d7761b1f</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says National Guard soldier Sarah Beckstrom has died after being shot in Washington DC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/national-guard-member-shot-washington-dc-dies/106077076</link><description>Sarah Beckstrom, 20, has died in hospital after an ambush shooting near the White House on Wednesday. A male soldier who was also shot, Andrew Wolfe, is fighting for his life, the president says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a041c390c0306157b5291a220d28033</guid></item><item><title>Christmas prawns could be more expensive as wild-caught Australian seafood stocks drop off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/prawns-mackerel-crabs-barramundi-christmas-seafood-prices-high/106058324</link><description>Wild-caught Aussie prawn fishers are reporting a tough catch season. Here's what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38c830975e652eab6b006f6847ad8e55</guid></item><item><title>Award-winning regional pharmacist says relationship with patients is 'unique'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/pharmacist-award-ouyen-regional-communities-rural-healthcare/105999812</link><description>A north-west Victorian pharmacist is being celebrated for his contribution to his local community after winning an award for going the "extra mile".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11825fa9764b4ae42f7505f1fb4240e6</guid></item><item><title>Super Netball could grow to 10 teams as Netball Australia invites licence bids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/super-netball-could-grow-to-10-teams-by-2027/106077068</link><description>Super Netball could have two additional teams by 2027, with Netball Australia calling for expressions of interest to expand the competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f51d1aadcd45af0382e9a8ea5524b8e</guid></item><item><title>What time is the 2025 AFLW grand final? All you need to know as Brisbane and North Melbourne clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/aflw-grand-final-2025-what-time-does-the-game-start/106049752</link><description>Wondering what time the AFLW grand final starts and how you can watch it live? We've got you covered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c52c36fdd58c5fcf88e25fe664fef0a</guid></item><item><title>Rare West Australian seaweed scrapbooks provide glimpse into history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wa-seaweed-scrapbooks-glimpse-into-history/106052420</link><description>The State Library of WA is running an appeal to save a set of seaweed scrapbooks made nearly 100 years ago by a renowned Kalgoorlie-born naturalist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf4174762be5bbe41b633305d0598ec1</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong building fire prompts serious questions about construction safety</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/hong-kong-fires-prompt-questions-about-construction-safety/106074568</link><description>Just months ago, Hong Kong leaders were dismissing calls for a total ban on bamboo scaffolding on construction sites. Now they are facing one of the region's worst building-fire catastrophes, and anger is growing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c1eb75c0809317b5e5c2b262e0cf8c6</guid></item><item><title>Why the banking regulator is targeting property investors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/why-the-banking-regulator-is-targeting-property-investors/106074360</link><description>It's been called a bubble for more than 15 years but the great Aussie housing price boom has barely skipped a beat, as regulators eye the threat of risky loans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ca5ec2b583890693afd566c1fef922f</guid></item><item><title>Victorian regulator imposes conditions on Monash IVF after embryo bungles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/monash-ivf-victorian-health-regulator-conditions/106077192</link><description>Monash IVF has been ordered to be more rigorous when checking the biological origin of embryos to avoid more mix-ups, in order to stay registered in Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">533e38b17ff79f4b0fa25b439eeb33a4</guid></item><item><title>Regional newspaper printer facing uncertain future in modern media market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/regional-paper-printers-uncertain-future-in-modern-media-market/106074732</link><description>With Broken Hill's Barrier Truth newspaper in the process of selling off its usable assets, some wonder if its still-working press would be more valuable as scrap or even a museum piece.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2f9169a05493316aab35dbf26a33d45</guid></item><item><title>Jane Edmanson hangs up her Gardening Australia hat, reflects on labour of love behind show's success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/jane-edmanson-gardening-australia-retires/106027658</link><description>As Gardening Australia's longest-serving presenter, Jane Edmanson says farewell and shares the secrets behind the success of Australia’s favourite gardening program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">281e322ce0bc8aaface52c810fbad18a</guid></item><item><title>New Victorian opposition leader Jess Wilson targets coercive control in first major policy move</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/liberal-party-opposition-jess-wilson-coercive-control/106077044</link><description>Jess Wilson has announced her first policy as leader of the Liberal Party, promising to introduce legislation criminalising coercive control in Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7b56e6956ad1fd5af32540cc2c2f1e2</guid></item><item><title>Berkeley River Lodge caretakers survived 'apocalyptic' Cyclone Fina in underground bunker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/resort-caretakers-survive-cyclone-fina-in-underground-bunker/106077598</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ac0a638981477382a839c62467dab91</guid></item><item><title>French prisoners escape jail using saw and bedsheets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/french-prisoners-use-saws-and-bed-sheets-to-escape-jail/106077074</link><description>The fugitives broke out of the prison in the eastern city of Dijon in the early hours of Thrusday, local time, and 100 police officers are on their trail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44771861ad99da99531611f0f5fed7b0</guid></item><item><title>Locals begin clean up after floods inundate Sumatra, Indonesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/floods-inundate-sumatra-indonesia-as-locals-begin-clean-up/106077968</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56cd9a1c822c37dc50f651b8338c6c00</guid></item><item><title>F1 Qatar start time, how to watch grand prix, and drivers' championship standings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/f1-qatar-grand-prix-start-time-how-to-watch-driver-standings/105995172</link><description>Lando Norris has match point heading into the penultimate weekend of the Formula 1 season, with the British driver having one hand on a maiden drivers' championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cf99e225205d22e6b2cdd4aec07317d</guid></item><item><title>Doctors and nurses claim ramping protocol gives ambulance patients priority access to ED, but paramedics disagree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/tasmania-ambulance-ramping-protocol-emergency-department-nurse/106018196</link><description>Medical experts fear sick or injured Tasmanians who make their own way to emergency departments wait longer than others, due to pressures to fast-track ambulance patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2cbf4fa3c30c15c90451339cafc4607</guid></item><item><title>Dairy 'disrupter' wins science award for inventing spreadable butter in 1970s</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/farmer-who-invented-spreadable-butter-in-70s-wins-science-award/106058726</link><description>An 86-year-old farmer claims this year's Dairy Science Award for inventing spreadable butter, by mixing oils with cultured cream at a time when it was illegal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57efc9add8623d8b897b7403389e53a3</guid></item><item><title>Large police operation underway in Blacktown after man shot dead, two arrested</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/nsw-shooting-blacktown-western-sydney-police-operation/106078118</link><description>A man aged in his 20s has died after being shot multiple times near a police station in Western Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbded38203d1dadfef9c009192e04211</guid></item><item><title>Third renewable energy company discovers asbestos in wind farm turbine lifts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/call-for-border-force-review-asbestos-in-imported-products/106076286</link><description>An anti-asbestos advocate wants a review of import supply chains after a third renewable energy company confirmed the discovery of asbestos in wind farm turbine lifts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d7f9c928f6c8b8a0952caa7dd643ca8</guid></item><item><title>Australia names unchanged squad for second Ashes Test, with captain Pat Cummins still out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/pat-cummins-australia-second-ashes-test-england/106076408</link><description>Australia will go into the second Ashes Test against England in Brisbane next week with an unchanged line-up, meaning there is no place for captain Pat Cummins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">998b1e72e6fbe80fcf0b62145af7bc54</guid></item><item><title>City of Perth in turmoil as acting CEO quits amid dispute over Lord Mayor's workplace culture review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/city-of-perth-in-turmoil-as-acting-ceo-quits-amid-dispute/106074860</link><description>The City of Perth is in turmoil amid a dispute over newly elected Lord Mayor Bruce Reynolds's push for a ratepayer-funded workplace culture review, with the council's acting CEO resigning amid the saga.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66559cbf472dd646d7d877fea3af4507</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's education department and RSB Travel charged over child's attempt to drink engine coolant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/education-department-bus-company-engine-coolant-charges/106077516</link><description>Tasmania's education department and a bus company have both appeared in court after a child with a disability was allegedly left unattended on a bus with access to a bottle of engine coolant in a plastic water bottle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a384e06dbe017543ba08056058f5cb2f</guid></item><item><title>Pheobe Bishop accused faces court on a fresh charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/pheobe-bishop-accused-kieren-daniel-mittelheuser-fresh-charge/106076652</link><description>Kieren Daniel Mittelheuser has been charged with attempting to pervert justice, along with accessory to murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20287f46dac44e3411e750a679219750</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Travel Management embroiled in overcharging scandal potentially worth more than $100 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/corporate-travel-management-overcharging-scandal-100-million/106077806</link><description>Corporate Travel Management helps arrange travel bookings for clients ranging from Wesfarmers to the Australian government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b6d5e0f6a21ec3ecdc711385bed0e1a</guid></item><item><title>Whadjuk Aboriginal Corporation to oversee Rottnest Island cultural services</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/whadjuk-aboriginal-corporation-rottnest-cultural-services-/106078776</link><description>A strife-torn Aboriginal corporation crucial to heritage approvals across Perth wins a contract to oversee cultural services on Rottnest Island, Wadjemup, one of Western Australia's premier tourism destinations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1ba915a0f3aa07e41791c03b661320f</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos coach Darren Crocker opens up on difficult Mia King selection call ahead of AFLW grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/aflw-grand-final-darren-crocker-mia-king-kangaroos-selection/106078850</link><description>North Melbourne coach Darren Crocker says telling Mia King she isn't going to play in the AFLW grand final is "one of the harder conversations" he's had to have.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13aae557b26efb85a64e42a9c4739658</guid></item><item><title>Shopping centre stabbing leaves teen with life-threatening injuries and another in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/injuries-in-elizabeth-city-centre-shopping-centre-fight/106079074</link><description>A teenage boy is in hospital with life-threatening injuries after a stabbing at an Adelaide shopping centre in which a 20-year-old man was also injured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c715a96222def5963a955db41a7d2818</guid></item><item><title>Victims' families of Westfield Bondi Junction attack grateful for inquest but want 'reforms'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/bondi-westfield-stabbing-victims-families-want-reform-inquest/106076576</link><description>A lawyer representing one of the bereaved families took aim at the owner and operator of Westfield, saying they were "extremely disappointed".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0403311f0e2782dcdcf3c2a15bebebe1</guid></item><item><title>A crystal Fabergé egg is expected to sell for more than $40 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/crystal-faberg%C3%A9-egg-expected-to-sell-for-more-than-40-million/106078696</link><description>A rare crystal and diamond Fabergé egg is heading to auction with a price estimate of more than $40 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6099723b7ff7cfb11af19db108b58054</guid></item><item><title>Jury hears closing addresses in trial of man accused of murdering Bangladeshi student</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/brendan-kantilla-murder-trial-darwin-hears-closing-submissions/106078336</link><description>The jury in the trial of a Tiwi Islands man accused of murdering an international student in Darwin hears final arguments from the prosecution and the defence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8597fc8ae577cc77b90982ab2a3b4ac</guid></item><item><title>'Rare' cyclone in Indonesia among wild weather in South-East Asia that kills at least 115</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/rare-cyclone-south-east-asia-floods-disaster/106076572</link><description>The death toll is expected to continue rising after a week of record-breaking rain, flash flooding and a "rare" tropical cyclone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24dfcfea06d025032f1301a64b95d0e1</guid></item><item><title>Toyah Cordingley's accused killer '3.7 billion times more likely than not' to have contributed to DNA sample near burial site, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/toyah-cordingly-rajwinder-singh-murder-trial-cairns-dna-testing/106078870</link><description>The former nurse accused of the 2018 murder of Toyah Cordingley was 3.7 billion times more likely than not to have contributed to a DNA sample found on a stick where she was buried, his trial has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b210174034d9ee393eacc220d012cd63</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says America will pause all migration from 'Third World countries'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/donald-trump-migration-pause-from-third-world-countries-to-us/106079562</link><description>US President Donald Trump says his administration will work to permanently pause migration from all "Third World Countries" to allow the American system to fully recover.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79e0ad16bb4c35dc14bd5434c068e1df</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian government criticised for not signing up to federal Help to Buy home ownership scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/tasmanian-government-federal-housing-scheme/106079386</link><description>Tasmania is the only state or territory that is not joining the federal government's Help to Buy home ownership scheme, which aims to reduce the time it takes home buyers to save for a deposit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f76be8be6cc3bea21d5898416d4c47a9</guid></item><item><title>Legal battle begins over Virginia Giuffre’s multi-million-dollar estate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/virginia-giuffre-epstein-survivor-legal-battle-over-estate/106075194</link><description>A legal battle over the reported multi-million-dollar estate of Virginia Giuffre, who was abused by US sex offender Jeffrey Epstein, is underway in Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cf112f989a06c7e502a7a21067f20aa</guid></item><item><title>Preparing my garden for time away in summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/preparing-my-garden-for-time-away-in-summer/106051574</link><description>Leaving my garden in the heat of summer can feel worrying but some simple planning means it misses me less than I miss it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56b35dd6decc39572e5296aff34ea254</guid></item><item><title>Police believe stabbing at Elizabeth City Centre was not a random attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/police-believe-stabbing-at-elizabeth-city-centre-not-random/106079818</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dce233839c709fd80a55d5b1b6e841a5</guid></item><item><title>Struggling AFLW teams GWS, Collingwood and Gold Coast receive extra picks or list spots from league</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/aflw-have-nots-receive-league-boost-on-grand-final-eve/106079622</link><description>Three of the AFLW's worst-performing clubs will receive boosts to their lists, with the help announced the day before the grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">087d6c70c437791857888893255fa45d</guid></item><item><title>Lotterywest cancels licences of seven stores across Perth found to be selling illegal tobacco or vapes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/lotterywest-cancels-licences-over-illegal-tobacco-/106079700</link><description>Seven stores across Perth found to be selling illegal tobacco and vapes have their lotteries licences terminated, as attempts to disrupt the illicit and growing trade continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">deaa16d974f977f92fc4244b10fe4aeb</guid></item><item><title>Boy won't face charges after Melbourne primary school stabbing, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/no-charges-over-melbourne-primary-school-stabbing/106080018</link><description>Police say a boy who allegedly stabbed a child at a Berwick primary school will not face charges as he is under the age of criminal responsibility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f93f3f14d73885bdb2435df2a87f02fa</guid></item><item><title>Perth hacker Michael Clapsis jailed after setting up fake Qantas Wi-Fi, stealing sex videos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/perth-michael-clapis-guilty-airport-data-theft-sex-videos/105442798</link><description>A Perth hacker who copied intimate images and sex videos from women's personal online accounts and set up fake Wi-Fi on Qantas flights is sentenced to more than seven years in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">137224c08606535454faf495212728d1</guid></item><item><title>Kyra Cooney-Cross scores stunning long range goal as Matildas down New Zealand 5-0</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/kyra-cooney-cross-goal-matildas-defeat-new-zealand/106074508</link><description>A spectacular long range effort from Kyra Cooney-Cross has helped the Matildas to a dominant 5-0 win over New Zealand in Australia's penultimate game before hosting the Asian Cup in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ed492f5f89ed6ab1feddf18b1b73bf8</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong's aging towers face urgent questions after city's deadliest blaze in decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/behind-hong-kong-s-skyline-thousands-of-old-towers-fire-risks/106079352</link><description>Hong Kong's worst fire in decades exposed long-standing weaknesses in its aging residential blocks. The question haunting the city is whether the disaster could happen again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e527e3cdb4fb8aec5ae2e15796f2ecc</guid></item><item><title>One of seven Rosenberg's goannas from ACT reserve is missing from home for second time in two years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/act-rosenbergs-goanna-rum-missing-ainslie-majura-conservation/106080004</link><description>One of a handful of Rosenberg’s goannas living in the ACT’s hill reserves has once again wandered off, prompting calls from a local conservation organisation for help bringing him back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d236e04ccb909529cfe855fa2a4af683</guid></item><item><title>Brodie Kostecki wins Supercars grand final sprint race as Chad Mostert narrows gap to leader Broc Feeney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/kostecki-wins-as-mostert-closes-in-on-supercars-crown/106080514</link><description>Brodie Kostecki prevails in wet and wild conditions to win the opening Supercars grand final race, as Chaz Mostert closes in on the championship lead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a600518a7d11ed23c8999092c6e4bf7b</guid></item><item><title>Wala Kooral-bi juvenile justice facility opens in northern WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wala-kooral-bi-juvenile-justice-facility-opens-in-northern-wa/106057316</link><description>An on-country youth diversion facility has been built in the state's far north, offering a culturally grounded alternative to traditional youth justice programs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">142d8035e60293b2bfd4ea512b3d855f</guid></item><item><title>Confidence remains in WA iron ore industry despite forecast royalty drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/wa-iron-ore-royalties-forecast-down/106077818</link><description>Western Australia has long prospered off its hefty irone ore mining royalties, but new figures reveal that revenue may drop by billions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b59e6502bce4249b5b139e3efa48f011</guid></item><item><title>Qantas terminal at Melbourne Airport evacuated and flights delayed due to fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/melbourne-airport-qantas-terminal-evacuated/106080752</link><description>The Qantas terminal is re-opening after being evacuated because of a small fire inside Melbourne Airport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44f741960e995fb9479b357573d18ed2</guid></item><item><title>NT parliament hears claims of children in youth detention being transferred without families' knowledge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/nt-parliament-children-youth-detention-allegedly-moved-to-darwin/106080720</link><description>Two politicians allege NT children in youth detention are being moved from Alice Springs to Darwin without their families' knowledge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e1c0c9a0ccf30f57917a7f02d2f775a</guid></item><item><title>ICC rejects plea to release Philippine ex-president Rodrigo Duterte</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/icc-rejects-plea-to-release-philippine-ex-president-duterte/106080850</link><description>The judge says it is "necessary" for the 80-year-old to remain in detention as the conditions proposed by his lawyers do not meet the conditions for parole.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69d31e21ba06deee8c154d6e2ab9059b</guid></item><item><title>Anti-corruption body arrests eight people over deadly Hong Kong fire in Tai Po district that killed at least 128 people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/eight-people-arrested-over-deadly-hong-kong-fire-tai-po-district/106080926</link><description>The arrests come as the probe into what caused the deadly blaze that killed at least 128 people continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce9a1003dd5cc3333427e62260e00d1c</guid></item><item><title>ABC News - Trusted Source of Latest News &amp; Headlines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2011-07-26/sport-top-stories/2799958</link><description>ABC News - Trusted Source of Latest News &amp; Headlines</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef0d2998edda1e27d100a251175b38b4</guid></item><item><title>Home of Andrii Yermak, Zelenskyy's chief of staff, raided by anti-corruption unit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-28/andrii-yermak-zelenskyy-aide-home-office-raided/106080910</link><description>The raids come as Kyiv battles to persuade US officials to defend Ukraine's interests in peace agreement talks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5d4e479539240306c2c980146ac385d</guid></item></channel></rss>