<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 19:35:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Road repairs after flood delayed by 'excruciating' eligibility criteria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/buloke-shire-flood-funding-pot-holes-delays-unsafe-roads/105733714</link><description>Victorian councils say they are required to provide before-and-after photos of every 100 metres of road in order to be eligible for flood recovery funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d6870a6663a3b8139b0e567866cd586</guid></item><item><title>ANZ faces record $240m penalty for ripping off customers and government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/anz-record-penalty-asic-federal-court/105773084</link><description>ANZ bank has agreed to a record penalty with the corporate regulator over its dealings with about 65,000 customers, as well as the federal government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8475aebd937a4522870145c77b4667d8</guid></item><item><title>Inquest hears prison system failed Aboriginal inmate before he died</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/inquest-examines-clinton-austin-death-loddon-prison/105735924</link><description>A coronial inquest hears the system failed First Nations prisoner Clinton Austin before his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3728f892b4b408407004793ea3dc66f</guid></item><item><title>How is Australia affected by climate change? The National Climate Risk Assessment models the future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/national-climate-risk-assessment-and-why-it-matters-explained/105773936</link><description>For the first time, the government has modelled the threats from climate change on Australia's future. What's the point of a document like this, and can it help us avoid the worst-case scenarios?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ad84229da5de3e8a79b28e4eacc8cab</guid></item><item><title>A comment shared at a recent anti-immigration rally was met by cheers.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/townsville-protest/105776528</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4405398fe243aab76d9bb580416a0076</guid></item><item><title>Future of Bendigo Writers Festival unclear amid calls for transparent review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/bendigo-writers-festival-future-unclear-after-boycott/105773484</link><description>A councillor is demanding answers from his own executive over the botched Bendigo Writers Festival, asking colleagues whether they want to be remembered as the council that "killed" it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a2675a41175e051c99bd70c72ebf69a</guid></item><item><title>Nikki Webster sings with her children for 25th anniversary of Sydney Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nikki-webster-sings-with-her-children-for-25th/105778014</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c83bf0274f16a9fa314e120145c3d8f</guid></item><item><title>Shire of Coolgardie awaits decision on future after giving evidence to minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/shire-of-coolgardie-show-cause-notice-response/105774072</link><description>The embattled Shire of Coolgardie waits to hear whether it will be suspended ahead of local government elections over concerns about financial and managerial mismanagement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a60af1587b72855d0965e133f66c3a65</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds announce netball squads for Test series against New Zealand, South Africa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/australia-diamonds-announce-test-netball-squads-new-zealand-sa/105779230</link><description>Goal-shooter Lucy Austin is a shock selection in the Australian netball squad to face South Africa, winning a place after initially being included as an "invitee" to their training camp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f84722b6abee542504171a8343b1b82</guid></item><item><title>SA's ongoing harmful algal bloom labelled 'cultural emergency' by First Nations groups</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sa-algal-bloom-cultural-emergency/105631230</link><description>First Nations South Australians say the harmful algal bloom impacting the state's coastline is a cultural emergency, as it continues to devastate beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ed15cf74630a813b331beecfe638cdf</guid></item><item><title>Why 'everything feels easier' for Chloe Rykers since her breast reduction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/breast-reduction-changed-my-quality-of-life-chloe-rykers/105763294</link><description>Chloe Rykers says her "big boobs" had, in various ways, made her career harder and left her feeling uncomfortable and in pain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfb6d7d9d5d29c944f231ddddf5980dc</guid></item><item><title>GIM Trading director Darren Geddes blocked from leaving Australia in court order</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/asic-court-order-gim-trading-bond-fraud-allegations/105782628</link><description>After the ABC revealed GIM Trading had raised millions from customers who later suspected fraudulent activity, a judge has prohibited the current director from leaving the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86e4cbcd5a0b521eec9f167fe445b92f</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Barnes, Dave Faulkner among music industry voices in open letter urging ANU to keep School of Music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/jimmy-barnes-against-anu-school-of-music-cuts/105784002</link><description>Jimmy Barnes is among more than 40 music voices supporting an open letter to the embattled Australian National University (ANU) calling for the School of Music to be saved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c2e11e10aa99b2ef294abc946d1feaa</guid></item><item><title>Does the damning planning report mean the end for Hobart's Macquarie Point stadium?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/is-hobart-stadium-now-dead-explainer/105780834</link><description>The Tasmanian Planning Commission described the Hobart stadium as a "singular, large, bulky monolith" with "optimism bias" in the government's cost-benefit figures. What does this mean for the stadium?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6d2b782c8ad36854242ff8269a71dd8</guid></item><item><title>Albanese has found out nailing down Pacific agreements is harder than expected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/papua-new-guinea-defence-treaty-delays/105783902</link><description>Anthony Albanese was meant to emerge from his recent flurry of Pacific diplomacy holding no fewer than two major agreements — instead he's returning home conspicuously empty-handed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef894cba91b42943ab469518f13e2d11</guid></item><item><title>Perth council City of Bayswater loses legal bid to stop pet cats roaming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/cat-confinement-laws-dismissed-perth-council-wa/105784434</link><description>The WA parliament has intervened to stop a Perth council from bringing in fines for people who allow their cats to leave their properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e72259dd0fa8caf004c4a13f0837cef5</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout finishes third in 200m heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/gout-gout-finishes-third-in-200m-heat/105786314</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d8312214b2b9a31a74786f0c79c4763</guid></item><item><title>Man claims council bid to remove 'therapy' roosters is contrary to human rights conventions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/therapy-roosters-owner-tries-to-halt-court-proceedings/105775968</link><description>A South Australian council has taken a disability pensioner to court to remove his allegedly noisy roosters, but he has argued the council's application should not proceed because it is discriminatory and the birds are his "therapeutic" animals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12ef938f04ff77b3326d973d37ac0830</guid></item><item><title>Gaming history goes on display with Australian titles Hollow Knight Silksong and Team Fortress chronicled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/acmi-game-worlds-hollow-knight-silksong-neopets-team-fortress/105754152</link><description>An exhibition at Melbourne's ACMI will pull back the curtain on how iconic games like Hollow Knight Silksong, Team Fortress, Neopets and Sim City were made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fccda39e18804bf9590546dadaed39f</guid></item><item><title>Australia loses second ODI to India by record runs margin ahead of Women's Cricket World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/india-hands-australia-biggest-odi-defeat-on-world-cup-eve/105786766</link><description>A 102-run thumping, the biggest loss by runs for Australia's women's team, sets up a thrilling ODI series decider in India ahead of the Cricket World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">681ebe3c21776dc5fc833ede22b42e3d</guid></item><item><title>How youth orchestras foster lifelong friendships and open career pathways for musicians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/youth-orchestra-lifelong-friendships-career-pathways-musicians/105775992</link><description>With youth orchestras set to busk on the streets of Sydney and Melbourne this weekend, Australian musicians share how those orchestras helped shape their careers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39cc489e47ad597a9a2e2610c3bf0e4a</guid></item><item><title>Australian cow market at record high as US demand hits 'scary times'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/us-cattle-prices-soar-increasing-demand-for-aussie-beef/105776020</link><description>Australian cow prices are at record highs, but are still way below the United States where beef demand is going "crazy".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56f2d0555cc98f7f69e717a8162ea988</guid></item><item><title>PNG's much-wanted NRL team has had setbacks. Experts say history is on its side</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/png-rugby-league-history-new-nrl-club/105782492</link><description>Observers say Papua New Guinea's decades-long history of rugby league success and passion is on its side as it prepares for the next sporting leap into the NRL.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d3deca6b656ff8bd1468e46bc6f527e</guid></item><item><title>Australia's 2035 climate targets on path to net zero judged by the experts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/climate-targets-australia-2035-on-path-to-net-zero/105719910</link><description>After much anticipation, Australia has its new climate targets. Now that the dice have fallen, we consult experts on their assessment of how these targets stack up with what’s at stake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dabb8156d4044b51ff0dc8bd8feb97a4</guid></item><item><title>Albanese to meet with Trump after returning from Pacific empty-handed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/anthony-albanese-png-coalition-climate/105767026</link><description>This week in politics, the prime minister returned home from the Pacific empty-handed and the climate debate continued to unsettle the Coalition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e48586b5fbd1829a80e680eae1c55719</guid></item><item><title>National Gathering backs plans for new First Nations body, but tensions remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/national-indigenous-gathering-post-voice-referendum/105787906</link><description>First Nations leaders have endorsed plans for a new national representative body to be established. Here’s what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31e9e3c6ecd0c09297f677025d57e6b6</guid></item><item><title>Bindi Magic art exhibition opens in Alice Springs as organisation celebrates 25 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/bindi-magic-art-exhibition-opens-in-alice-springs/105789908</link><description>For 25 years Bindi Mwerre Anthurre Artists has been helping people with a disability to communicate through creativity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac6f9add20cd12006d1f874f0c4e4ec</guid></item><item><title>Police officer found not guilty of assault during shopping centre scuffle at Batemans Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/police-officer-not-guilty-assault-batemans-bay-shopping-centre/105775816</link><description>A New South Wales police officer is found not guilty of using unreasonable force while removing three girls and a woman from a scuffle at a shopping centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c14d987edba1b9dfa103c7bd81c6de2</guid></item><item><title>The climate conversation is stuck in a loop, but out in the world things are changing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/climate-conversation-is-stuck-but-things-are-changing/105787796</link><description>We don't have to wait for moonshot technologies to reach our climate targets. Most of the solutions to the climate crisis are already around us.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36fccec4cd29f75e6be2134b94cacc07</guid></item><item><title>Surprise La Niña hints at another wet and stormy Australian summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/la-nina-hints-at-wet-stormy-australian-summer/105790134</link><description>Australia's key drivers of weather variability are stacking up to produce another wet, severe-weather season, with an increased risk of flooding, thunderstorms and cyclones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a42ca16638c1124b410a58f0cccc3ecf</guid></item><item><title>Actress Joan Marion never returned to Tasmania, but 'her heart was always in Launceston'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/tasmanian-actress-joan-marion-maintained-links-to-launceston/105774964</link><description>Tasmania's Joan Marion became a star of the screen and stage abroad; her granddaughter says she maintained a connection to Launceston for much of her life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e512ba130678906d9cf74447a7e0d32</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout misses out on 200m final at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gout-gout-misses-out-on-200m-final-at-world-athletics-/105792462</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44814bf4d05e24efb9a86e9874126c57</guid></item><item><title>Rabbits cause 'devastating' damage to Junee cemetery in southern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/rabbits-cause-devastating-damage-to-junee-cemetery-southern-nsw/105792784</link><description>The Junee Shire Council says it is battling a rabbit problem, which forced a recent closure of the town's main cemetery for a week, including on Father's Day, for a baiting program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6e24632645222977003b4a6af3561fc</guid></item><item><title>China urges Papua New Guinea not to exclude other countries after it signed 'Pukpuk' communique with Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/china-warns-papua-new-guinea-against-bilateral-deal-australia/105794018</link><description>China has urged Papua New Guinea not to sign any deal that might exclude or restrict third parties from cooperating with the Pacific nation, as Australia scrambles to clinch a landmark defence treaty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad04d0391ea73681a5f0351d55692b32</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins hints at Ashes strategy amid recovery from back injury with 'starting aim' of playing in all five Tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/ashes-pat-cummins-australia-england-back-injury/105794594</link><description>As the men's Ashes approaches, the Australian captain reveals his hopes for taking part in the five-Test series against England as he steps up his injury recovery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cfd72c66626cbf51c7aab8346b10585</guid></item><item><title>Report scathing of police and CCC over failure to respond to complaints of police misconduct</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/police-ccc-complaints-misconduct-report-/105791424</link><description>WA Police and the CCC are put on notice after failing to adequately respond to complaints of serious police misconduct, including an allegation an off-duty officer choked a man following a road rage incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22bf87447571d6b73f5b6fc17bd6283e</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the Optus outage which disrupted triple-zero calls, linked to three deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/what-we-know-about-optus-network-outage/105796618</link><description>It's been two days since three people died after a devastating Optus outage caused hundreds of emergency calls to fail, but information about the incident remains scarce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81d841cfe097dc82a144e78eb4423953</guid></item><item><title>Senator calls for 'heads on spikes' to deter superannuation mismanagement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/heat-on-asic-first-guardian-shield-fallout-superannuation-fails/105790322</link><description>As questions mount about how Australia's retirement funds industry is regulated, a senator says regulator ASIC must more quickly and forcefully enforce the law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1384c0e0503cda0c65ca3e1bb58adaa9</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood and Brisbane meet again, two years on from classic 2023 grand final, for tantalising rematch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/afl-preliminary-final-collingwood-brisbane-preview/105793028</link><description>The 2023 grand final will go down as one of the best deciders in AFL history, and though the stakes are only marginally lower two years on, the numbers suggest Collingwood and Brisbane's 2025 preliminary final could be another classic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ec81c3cb39b858091335eeff1f3c10e</guid></item><item><title>Federal government's agriculture emissions reductions 'ambitious' but 'achievable'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/agriculture-industry-responds-toemissions-reduction-expectations/105792968</link><description>A professor of carbon farming says the agriculture industry will "naturally" contribute to a 28 per cent emissions reduction projected by 2050, but is unlikely to hit its own net-zero targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be4c701559d4d36210ea847a9fa9b087</guid></item><item><title>Remote NSW council holds election after 12 years in administration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/central-darling-shire-council-election-nsw-votes-after-12-years/105757794</link><description>The 700 voters living in the remote Central Darling Shire Council area of New South Wales will finally head to the polls to vote again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2af8d61243c1a142aa5a6b000bb6dea5</guid></item><item><title>Chelsea FC Women's star Sam Kerr presented with special football to mark 100 goals for club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/like-a-new-person-sam-kerr-all-smiles-after-comeback-goal/105797260</link><description>Sam Kerr is honoured with a special football to mark her 100 goals for Chelsea — and she can't stop smiling since the landmark strike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52628ebbe474caa569cc4274ed7dde0b</guid></item><item><title>Victor Caulfield moved to Florence in his 70s and became an artists' model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/victor-caulfield-moved-to-florence-and-became-an-artists-model/105762988</link><description>Victor Caulfield packed up his Australian home and moved to Italy, where he fell into the art scene as an accidental model.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf11c6e1cc2bef7d1c59c017a7b1915d</guid></item><item><title>One-tray honey chicken wings are an easy family dinner - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/one-tray-sticky-chicken-wings/105658174</link><description>It’s easy to make these irresistibly sticky wings that will have you licking your fingers and reaching for more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b49e38fcb0cc57c3220c789ba5301301</guid></item><item><title>Eucalypt trail named after botanist Dean Nicolle opens in SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/rail-trail-forest-blyth-dean-nicolle-eucalypt-walk-sa/105779316</link><description>A unique partnership between an artist and a botanist has resulted in an old rail corridor in South Australia becoming an eucalypt forest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a634367098f7c56af4d4f383b07c47fd</guid></item><item><title>'America is not happy': ABC under fire for pulling Jimmy Kimmel Live!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/complaints-about-kimmel-axing-meant-for-us-abc-sent-to-australia/105793428</link><description>The ABC has received hundreds of complaints about US talk show Jimmy Kimmel Live! being pulled off air and threats to boycott sponsors ... but that's the problem when two broadcasters from different countries share a name!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">058463060dc5663ada42854e5496b80c</guid></item><item><title>Near-blinded police officer reunites with those who saved him after rural motorcycle crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/police-officer-john-kenworthy-returns-to-thank-those-at-crash/105724428</link><description>Police officer John Kenworthy returns to thank the first responders in Mackay, and others who were with him in his darkest moments, after a rural motorcycle crash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af7195369dfa834fd85a7caed2683441</guid></item><item><title>World-first turtle tracking reveals secrets of flatback turtles in WA's Roebuck Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/world-first-tracking-of-flatback-turtles-in-roebuck-bay-broome/105794534</link><description>GPS tracking, motion sensors and video cameras reveal where flatback turtles in Broome's Roebuck Bay feed and travel, contributing to a richer understanding of the vulnerable species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6abd49307f41fd71e6160fa5f1479b4d</guid></item><item><title>UN says there's evidence organised crime scam centres are moving from South-East Asia into new frontier of the Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/organised-crime-scam-centres-move-into-pacific-united-nations/105775972</link><description>As scam centres run by organised crime find it harder to operate in South-East Asia, evidence emerges of them moving into the Pacific and setting up lucrative operations estimated to net billions each year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb89464594316563fc34dc56a716880e</guid></item><item><title>Transition from sheep to cropping in WA's Avon Valley leaving limited balloon landing sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/crops-to-sheep-hot-air-balloon-landing-sites/105794124</link><description>The move out of sheep by an increasing number of WA farmers is having an unexpected impact on the state's hot air balloon pilots.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c79d7f50ce8880f2a74edb7c05cab83</guid></item><item><title>From Jennifer Lopez to K-pop, meet the Australian backing artists helping superstars shine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/jlo-kpop-paul-kelly-backing-artists/105765732</link><description>Backup dancers and backing singers spend years perfecting their craft. But who are these artists and how does it feel performing in the shadows of superstars?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0b91ab8cfee821d0f58d79f05cf3da5</guid></item><item><title>Crowds flock to Toowoomba Carnival of Flowers despite wet weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/toowoomba-carnival-of-flowers-draws-crowds-despite-weather/105794286</link><description>Cold and damp conditions have not been enough to keep people away from Toowoomba's annual floral extravaganza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0670d318c12fc7fd9d19e3d22856487c</guid></item><item><title>Sharks and Knights reach NRLW preliminary finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/nrlw-knights-titans-cowboys-sharks/105798044</link><description>Cronulla keeps its season alive by defeating North Queensland, as Newcastle advances to a fourth NRLW preliminary final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7645684df002fee75327e38b809ba19c</guid></item><item><title>NRL finals updates: Cronulla Sharks defeat Canberra Raiders 32-12 in semifinal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/nrl-finals-live-updates-canberra-raiders-cronulla-sharks/105780662</link><description>An out-of-place nose doesn't hurt Joe Tapine as much as Canberra's NRL finals exit, but he hopes the pain of defeat will drive them to greater things next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2af84c91f7e4b5942651511648ab086f</guid></item><item><title>What is 'Solastalgia' and how are climate-affected communities tackling it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/climate-change-anxiety-first-nations-communities-respond/105793766</link><description>If you're overwhelmed by emissions targets, climate change and environmental collapse, start small and look to First Nations practices to help your wellbeing and the world around you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bff8375209835a394c77e6936900b17</guid></item><item><title>Pirate attacks and sea robberies surge in key South-East Asian shipping lane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/piracy-sea-robberies-rise-malacca-strait-asia/105736740</link><description>Piracy and sea robberies are increasing in the strategic straits of Malacca and Singapore, which could have implications for Australian imports and exports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2b3b37fb5cc2fee69c406b2aa0ccdc5</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: So you think you're a trivia guru? Go on, prove it!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/105792900</link><description>I like your trivia enthusiasm, but be careful — you're about to taste defeat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9d47761db7567cf5151ee9c4083f408</guid></item><item><title>Street artist Rone's new 90-metre mural a visual love letter to Geelong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/tyrone-rone-wright-new-mural-captures-geelong-faces/105762354</link><description>The faces of 14 people will be immortalised in an enormous mural on the side of a new building in Geelong by locally born, globally renowned artist Rone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28ac13e735d6c51ed4a4df9593e87271</guid></item><item><title>How skateboarding became a family affair for Townsville single dad Jay MacAskill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/qld-skateboarding-becomes-family-single-dad/105774582</link><description>For almost eight years, Jay MacAskill's skateboard was collecting dust at home — until his daughter found the skate park around the corner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ab26eabc2acb19d8f736401a36cb5d2</guid></item><item><title>Inside Ninga Mia, a forgotten community in the shadow of Kalgoorlie the city of gold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/ninga-mia-kalgoorlie-mining-aboriginal-reserve-homelessness-gold/105774862</link><description>There's an eerie silence in Ninga Mia, a once thriving community on the edge of Kalgoorlie. The Aboriginal reserve is a microcosm of the cycle of displacement endured by many First Nations people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eafa5daeccecbae05c7c9ef093e72c5</guid></item><item><title>Koori Court marks 20 years in Mildura as Victoria approaches treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/twenty-years-of-koori-justice-in-mildura-victorias-north-west/105784288</link><description>Mildura marks two decades since its Koori Court opened, as Victoria sees mixed results in the push to reduce Indigenous incarceration and offending rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d57275cbeb1abf5d81f15d9fb2c32b08</guid></item><item><title>How to clean out your wardrobe as the seasons change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/how-to-spring-clean-wardobe-clean-out/105780140</link><description>It's the kind of task that can seem overwhelming, but the change of season is the perfect opportunity to review what's in your wardrobe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf9c7f0a36323b3457588962f5d0b0b0</guid></item><item><title>Australia formally recognises state of Palestine as Anthony Albanese arrives in US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australia-formally-recognises-state-of-palestine/105799238</link><description>The historic decision foreshadowed last month has now become a reality, as Australia moves with Canada and the United Kingdom to join the growing list of countries to recognise Palestinian sovereignty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f7f36cbe6b5b1fbaaf3e78efd2951a2</guid></item><item><title>Can recognising the state of Palestine achieve a two-state solution as Israel continues bombing Gaza?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australia-recognises-state-of-palestine-two-state-solution/105799276</link><description>While the Israel Defense Forces bomb Gaza and bulldoze the West Bank for settlements, moves to recognise Palestine in pursuit of a two-state solution may appear like something of a sick joke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfa3467335da07f9ce07cf8e87421ac9</guid></item><item><title>The government says its 2035 climate targets are achievable but mathematics suggests a different story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/climate-target-2035-2050-carbon-emissions-global-warming/105799080</link><description>The problem with an emissions reduction target is that its mere existence implies it is achievable and that if we do achieve it, we will be fine. The truth is more complex.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55dd3a3450e5da05cd2e7e786ef836f8</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Kopp's teacher Paul Grealy groomed her at 15. As an adult, she held him to account</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/sarah-kopps-teacher-paul-grealy-groomed-her-from-15/105775958</link><description>Sarah Kopp's life was up-ended when a charismatic teacher twice her age started grooming her. Then they married and had children. When she sought justice 20 years on, she faced an impossible choice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">329e0e5fdb603a2e16d3f7e31513666e</guid></item><item><title>Storm-damaged turbine at NSW Central West wind farm raises safety concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/storm-damaged-turbine-at-nsw-central-west-wind-farm-concerns/105782400</link><description>After a wind turbine blade snapped in half during a storm, the NSW National Party has called for a safety audit into the renewable technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">020cbe7c7b785e21c8f3c2fd850c4be9</guid></item><item><title>Protesters in Philippines clash with police in rallies against corruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/protesters-in-philippines-rally-against-corruption/105800512</link><description>Thousands of Filipinos marched in the capital to vent their anger over a ballooning scandal involving bogus flood-control projects believed to have cost taxpayers billions of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffa83e3c2e5be80abb8e2dcb772951a9</guid></item><item><title>World leaders are meeting at the UN General Assembly this week. Here are four things to watch for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/united-nations-general-assembly-what-to-watch-for-in-new-york/105800440</link><description>World leaders are arriving in New York for the UN General Assembly — and for the first time, Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is among them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">761958b8abcd8c47c96a8d78d674b211</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage investigation underway as minister warns of 'consequences'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/optus-investigation-triple-0-outage/105800556</link><description>The Australian Media and Communications Authority begins its investigation into the Optus triple-0 outage that has been linked to multiple deaths in South Australia and Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64e8d943c326b70c38e9b095d514da19</guid></item><item><title>'Turning it up to eleven': Spinal Tap returns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/turning-it-up-to-eleven-spinal-tap-returns/105792970</link><description>The new film follows the fictional heavy metal band reuniting for one final gig with cameos from Elton John and Paul McCartney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4608648fffc66e4e36ba98d635f1990</guid></item><item><title>Is AI impacting your career or life plans? Has its rapid rise got you rethinking your future? The ABC wants to hear from you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/ai-artificial-intelligence-future-job-career-impact/105762606</link><description>Whether you’re a student halfway through a degree or a mid-career manager planning the next five years, artificial intelligence (AI) is reshaping lives across the country. If you've been feeling its effects, the ABC wants to hear from you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc9fb0b057b73e053ee1ce795957b20a</guid></item><item><title>Super Netball's Sunshine Coast Lightning enters new Global Sports Fund Management Group ownership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/super-netball-sunshine-coast-lightning-new-ownership/105801344</link><description>Almost a decade after being co-founded by the Melbourne Storm and University of the Sunshine Coast, Super Netball's Lightning is entering a new era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">725e5769d7aa41a90979ec4d3e47f5bd</guid></item><item><title>Endangered Littlejohn's tree frog finally bred in captivity amid habitat threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/endangered-littlejohns-tree-frog-finally-bred-in-captivity/105799502</link><description>Scientists have achieved a breakthrough in their work to save the Littlejohn's tree frog species which only exists in three isolated regions in New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">242f7f349ef09c427b4a7b8724bf30e1</guid></item><item><title>Brownlow Medal 2025: All the best fashion looks from AFL's night of nights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-red-carpet-wrap/105802436</link><description>Just after the fashion from this evening's Brownlow Medal? We've got you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8922390581e8430e878c1aa384dd8e2d</guid></item><item><title>WA Education Minister Sabine Winton rejects claims large workload behind high teacher resignations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/wa-teachers-resignations-set-new-record/105803332</link><description>WA’s education minister rejects claims a record number of teachers quitting their jobs is due to them being overworked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d265ab5d9004a28f3b8194cc5fd77f9d</guid></item><item><title>Latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/latest-financial-news/105804002</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a2a0a2b0118f619ddf3cb8e2061e8e4</guid></item><item><title>Ley writes to Republicans vowing to revoke Palestine recognition ahead of Albanese's UN address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/albanese-un-palestine-address-ley-republican-letter/105803078</link><description>In an unorthodox move, Opposition Leader Sussan Ley writes to a group of Republicans reassuring the Coalition would withdraw recognition of Palestine, ahead of a major United Nations address to be delivered by the prime minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98f3481476a06e3c9782e1032f1893d8</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar junta revoking citizenship of actors, singers and other celebrities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/myanmar-celebrities-left-stateless-after-criticising-junta/105787574</link><description>Myanmar's military junta is using citizenship as a weapon, targeting political opponents, activists and even celebrities who speak out against the regime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df5568a6e89118d9a0c2db08ec61854c</guid></item><item><title>Three Australians lay dead as investors of Optus's parent company Singtel were buying up its shares</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/three-australians-lay-dead-investors-buy-up-shares/105803922</link><description>The actions by Optus management in the hours following a series of failed attempts by its customers to call triple-0 raises questions about the telco's fitness to operate in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24e9f1bc9c2b8e3b2e1bdab5ae2ccb23</guid></item><item><title>Moment Matt Rowell announced as 2025 Brownlow medallist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moment-matt-rowell-announced-as-2025-brownlow-medallist/105805032</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4336530cc59f3c10ad2c74d7b058cebe</guid></item><item><title>Matt Rowell delivers Brownlow Medal acceptance speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/matt-rowell-delivers-brownlow-medal-acceptance-speech/105805042</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2002bf4ac5caada0dc95c1432e61966</guid></item><item><title>Sydney's inner west residents pack into forum on high-rise apartment plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sydney-inner-west-fairer-future-plan-housing-council-forum/105799454</link><description>Community members who showed up for the meeting on the Inner West Council's Fairer Future Plan were turned away at the door after being told the venue was full.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9616c9ea6e30d981b8478ab8be2118e3</guid></item><item><title>Doctors concerned easily accessible illegal cigarettes are causing smoking rates to increase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/act-easy-access-to-illegal-cigarettes-seeing-high-smoking-rates/105803450</link><description>Doctors say smoking rates are at levels they haven't seen in a decade due to easy access to illegal cigarettes that are a "quarter of the price" of legal cigarettes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">150ad4af75b20ef2e67ba79a215e5c20</guid></item><item><title>Byron Bay's 60-day holiday rental cap yields mixed results in first year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/60-day-caps-in-byron-bay-results-uncertain-after-one-year/105799696</link><description>A year after controversial holiday rental caps were introduced in Byron Bay to boost rental availability, the data is unclear about whether the endeavour has been a success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66035aa0e00835cc39a9f24d118bed47</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel reinstated after hundreds of stars back free speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/jimmy-kimmel-back-on-air-disney-says/105805048</link><description>US comedian Jimmy Kimmel's late-night show will be reinstated after being taken off air, following remarks he made referencing right-wing activist Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">868e8a8d3b8279fa34a833b46463ee3f</guid></item><item><title>Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera being robbed overshadowed Matt Rowell's Brownlow Medal win, and could change the voting process forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/afl-matt-rowell-nasiah-moment-brownlow-medal-voting-analysis/105804320</link><description>It is not often that the AFL's night of nights gets hijacked by a moment not involving the winner of the Brownlow Medal. This is exactly what took place when Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera was seemingly robbed in broad daylight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dfdde5b406fc68132f52c264d89b4c9</guid></item><item><title>Experts say paracetamol safe for pregnancy, no proof for autism link made by Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/trump-administration-links-autism-to-paracetamol-tga-says-safe/105803566</link><description>Australia's medicines regulator says paracetamol remains safe to use during pregnancy despite Donald Trump's administration linking its use to an increased risk of autism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9575c0f36522e77b42eccc5329990b40</guid></item><item><title>Deeming rates have increased after a five-year freeze. Here's how that could impact pension payments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/deeming-rate-freeze-ends-impact-on-pension-payments/105798966</link><description>The changes impact people on Centrelink payments who earn an income from financial assets, but pensioners are the biggest group to be affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2a6081a58d1e888118022ad40f5fcfd</guid></item><item><title>As a doctor I'm choosing self-care over resilience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/doctor-choosing-self-care-over-resilience/105728568</link><description>As a doctor who advocates for self-care, it took me a surprisingly long time to look after myself. Now I'm trying to be a good example for my patients and other doctors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96d1bd7d0cdf02ba7b181e19ec630701</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs Mayor Asta Hill tells of family tragedy that brought her back to home town</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/how-family-tragedy-brought-asta-hill-back-to-alice-springs/105784262</link><description>Asta Hill's grief over the tragic death of her younger brother 10 years ago is still raw, but the sad event is part of her story of connection to Alice Springs and hope for the outback town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a31d7502a77bae2501d929fd094d9fc2</guid></item><item><title>Experts say it is safe to use paracetamol during pregnancy and Trump's autism declaration is 'baseless'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/taking-paracetamol-during-pregnancy-does-not-cause-autism/105806092</link><description>Donald Trump's advice that pregnant women should limit the use of paracetamol in pregnancy has been criticised as "baseless". So what does it mean for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81c81571674ce6c676915af2ca81de9b</guid></item><item><title>Kevin Bacon on the importance of music, philanthropy and acting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/kevin-bacon-take-5-actor-music-philanthropy-interview/105793360</link><description>He's a prolific fixture on our screens who's famously six degrees from almost anyone. But Kevin Bacon is also a passionate musician and philanthropist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45104e05b24001759cca6f2985a81b97</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu plans to sign police deal with China while Nakamal pact with Australia is left hanging</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/china-vanuatu-police-agreement-equipment-training/105806934</link><description>Vanuatu declares it will sign a new policing agreement with China as the landmark Nakamal pact between Australia and the Pacific Island nation hangs in the balance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e015a5946bffafc3e5c33cd1d8fa895e</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage tragedy: What we know and how events unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/timeline-on-optus-triple-0-outage-what-we-know/105805890</link><description>The first sign something was wrong came late on Friday afternoon. Now we have a clearer picture of how the triple-0 outage unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c548c42002e87e4dd015358e8d8279e9</guid></item><item><title>Unproven autism claims like Donald Trump's risk undoing decades of progress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/trump-unproven-autism-claims-risk-undoing-decades-of-progress/105807344</link><description>The Trump administration's rhetoric only adds to the noise around autism and will make it harder for the community to feel understood and accepted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00fa47bf5ec49c44ed4dd1852e1689f4</guid></item><item><title>Sale of Australia's biggest sheep station at Rawlinna finally gets WA government approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sale-of-australias-largest-sheep-station-at-rawlinna-station/105807106</link><description>The WA government has finally signed off on the sale of Australia's largest sheep station almost seven months after UK-based Consolidated Pastoral Company announced plans to buy Rawlinna Station.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">453798f3baadfee94d513f7ea0e7efc3</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie's spray at 'muppet', 'coward' Liberal colleagues after post bemoaning loss of Aussie car making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/andrew-hastie-car-making-coward-muppet-liberals/105808280</link><description>Senior Liberal Andrew Hastie has taken aim at colleagues who questioned a social media post where he bemoaned the loss of Australian car making, calling them "nameless cowards" and "muppets".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa8f233e21c3cb087597a2e4648810dd</guid></item><item><title>Teenage girl to stand trial for alleged Hervey Bay caravan park murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/girl-to-stand-trial-for-alleged-hervey-bay-caravan-park-murder/105805474</link><description>One of the youngest Australians ever to be charged with murder will face a jury trial over the stabbing death in a Hervey Bay caravan park of a 24-year-old man in August 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ee4913dd0bfa32590ddaa5163670af</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105809052</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2291dde89e5f6f2e800c553bd2118818</guid></item><item><title>Denmark links drones at Copenhagen airport to hybrid attacks across Europe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/denmark-investigates-drone-activity-at-copenhagen-airport/105809166</link><description>Denmark links incident involving drones over its main airport to a series of recent suspected Russian drone incursions and other hybrid attacks across Europe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebee7e7802e9046c39907e2c6a3957b7</guid></item><item><title>Incoming triple-0 reforms may not have helped prevent Optus failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/triple-0-reforms-may-not-have-helped-optus-failure/105807524</link><description>The federal government has yet to pass legislation to empower a new coordinator for the emergency services line, but experts say tougher conditions are needed on the telco itself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">196d665b157a51d6ce3440ca5be81bfc</guid></item><item><title>Could artificial intelligence and a universal basic income eliminate 'meaningless jobs'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/will-we-need-a-universal-basic-income-to-deal-with-ai-job-losses/105747954</link><description>COVID showed just how "fragile" our economic security is. As artificial intelligence potentially takes jobs from humans, a universal basic income might be a solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5953e2ae7f84df41d0ff5021a284652b</guid></item><item><title>Australians are moving to Tasmania to escape climate change, but the island state is not immune</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/australians-moving-to-tasmania-to-escape-climate-change/105785996</link><description>Jack and Anna swapped the humidity of Queensland for chilly days in Tasmania, but is Tasmania really the climate refuge many think it is?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0ff7fbad477aed99626b4746b82c14c</guid></item><item><title>Holbrook Landcare Network wins 2025 Bob Hawke Award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/holbrook-landcare-network-wins-2025-bob-hawke-award/105803040</link><description>A landcare network at "the forefront of technology" has won the 2025 Bob Hawke Award for its innovative approach to sustainable farming practices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">704bd35d01dd4bdc8154c105eb49b76a</guid></item><item><title>Key moments from Trump's speech to UN General Assembly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/highlights-of-trumps-speech-to-un-general-assembly/105809546</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">625a3f17cbf39ff5d80c0a1dc0ce0116</guid></item><item><title>Dickie Bird, former English cricket umpire, dies aged 92</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/dickie-bird-former-english-cricket-umpire-dies-aged-92/105809586</link><description>One of international cricket's most recognised umpires is being remembered for his "fairness, humour and love of the game".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ea286fdda73733b0f123adaeb2b514e</guid></item><item><title>England names squad to face Australia in men's Ashes series 2025/26</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/england-name-squad-to-face-australia-in-men-s-ashes-series/105809606</link><description>England will bring a strong pace bowling attack, but several members of the squad, including captain Ben Stokes, are under injury clouds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d0a0a9cfab837e21e9251c67e841c3</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou 'excited' to defend his Europa League trophy with Nottingham Forest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ange-postecoglou-nottingham-forest-europa-league/105809674</link><description>Four months after leading Tottenham Hotspur to Europa League triumph in Bilbao, Ange Postecoglou has returned to Spain and UEFA's second-tier club competition with a new challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d7d5db2308c2c5b39a10ccc3cdf7870</guid></item><item><title>Unexplained lights in the sky sparks UAP chatter across much of Western Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/unexplained-uap-sightings-reported-across-midwest-wa/105803264</link><description>Perth Observatory says it has received reports of lights dancing in the sky across a significant part of WA's Midwest and Goldfields, with an explanation yet to be found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b4cb4ae36f5ab9e984491b519fa7152</guid></item><item><title>Why the legacy of the 2023 NRL grand final hangs over the Broncos and Panthers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/panthers-broncos-nrl-preliminary-final-grand-final-cleary/105809026</link><description>On Sunday, the Broncos and Panthers will face off in the finals for the first time since the 2023 grand final, but the memory of that night still hangs over both sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad8624f8c74a64751af52bbcd1e11c56</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fullback Andrew Kellaway ruled out of first Bledisloe Cup Test match against All Blacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/wallabies-andrew-kellaway-ruled-out-bledisloe-cup-all-blacks/105810670</link><description>Wallabies fullback Andrew Kellaway will miss Saturday's Bledisloe Cup Test match against the All Blacks in Auckland, ruled out with a calf strain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b979e7ef790b13cc2880a8a193f4dd</guid></item><item><title>Sculpture by the Sea could be cancelled due to $200,000 shortfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/sculptures-by-the-sea-facing-cancellation-funding-shortfall/105810510</link><description>Australia's famed sculpture walk is facing cancellation after failing to secure funding less than a month out from this year's event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ca69999aba4ff9483322749a16b717e</guid></item><item><title>Man behind iconic ABC TV programs, Graham White, dies aged 93</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/graham-white-abc-tv-and-radio-pioneer-dies-at-93/105806806</link><description>Graham White was a pioneer of Australian radio and television and played a key role in the creation of numerous television series, including A Big Country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54c9a84115c56f73f0923751c300a0e1</guid></item><item><title>Despite past controversy, NSW Police commissioner Mal Lanyon has a strong backing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nsw-police-commissioner-mal-lanyon-premier-chris-minns-analysis/105810774</link><description>For newly-announced Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon, Wednesday morning would have been both one of his proudest moments, and his most uncomfortable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed72f9bcc7ce20d2d722b8b43d539719</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel returns, addressing Charlie Kirk and 'un-American' axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/jimmy-kimmel-returns-thanking-supporters-speaks-to-free-speech/105808410</link><description>Despite the late-night host's return, several US ABC affiliates did not air the episode, excluding an estimated one-quarter of American households.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac8b78a8e557c0d2a91d42ed04e2eed</guid></item><item><title>How #RedundancyDiaries are busting the stigma of being let go</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/busting-the-stigma-on-redundancy-by-sharing-online/105751880</link><description>Camille says being made redundant was hard, so she began sharing her experiences on TikTok hoping to help others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69e9a0930ebbcb9805519c817968e9ee</guid></item><item><title>Why did the UN escalator stop after Donald and Melania Trump stepped on it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/donald-melania-trump-escalator-teleprompter-un-marcon-call/105810256</link><description>Footage of the US president and his wife's reactions to the mishap was shared widely on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87fdb12fe7af401b7964018acf19bc5f</guid></item><item><title>Optus admits procedural failure before outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-admits-procedural%C2%A0failure-before-outage%C2%A0/105811978</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b84c417046bbfc3acea16532e90a47cf</guid></item><item><title>Optus to pay $100m fine, as crisis engulfing Australia's second biggest telco continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-fined-100-million-for-sales-misconduct/105810174</link><description>In enforcing the fine today, the Federal Court's Justice Patrick O'Sullivan described the company's conduct as "extremely serious" and "appalling".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5b8ef086dc95c25b9efd2536b1850d6</guid></item><item><title>Christopher John Sullivan sentenced for stabbing partner Pauline Mountford in Gooseberry Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/christopher-john-sullivan-domestic-violence-sentencing/105812460</link><description>A 74-year-old man who slashed his partner's throat in their Perth Hills home is sentenced to 10 years in jail over the near-fatal attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b34ba7512fda4d4c878ff84234b915f6</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's gripe-filled United Nations speech unsurprising, Foreign Minister Penny Wong says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/penny-wong-responds-to-donald-trump-un-speech-albanese-meeting/105809070</link><description>Foreign Minister Penny Wong says the speech US President Donald Trump delivered at the UN is simply more of the same from him and "consistent" with his views and actions since being elected for a second term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d44f8f03841ac14753961232f5608cf4</guid></item><item><title>Former A-League footballers Clayton Lewis and Kearyn Baccus sentenced over betting scam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/a-league-betting-clayton-lewis-kearyn-baccus-sentencing/105811400</link><description>Both players were paid $10,000 each to intentionally get themselves yellow cards while playing for Macarthur FC against Sydney FC to influence overseas bets on the game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4d047a9369284c7941aaf5cccc0a654</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105813848</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbeee129e3122b06287a24ba6aa752ed</guid></item><item><title>Italy sends navy frigate to assist Global Sumud Flotilla after vessels targeted by drones off Greece</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/global-sumud-flotilla-says-vessels-targeted-by-drones/105812860</link><description>The flotilla carrying aid and pro-Palestinian activists said they heard explosions and saw multiple drones that targeted some of their boats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b77e1392b4829d64f6d75add8a54c81</guid></item><item><title>London mayor calls Trump racist, sexist and Islamophobic, hitting back at US president's 'sharia law' comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sadiq-khan-hits-back-at-trump-over-islamophobic-comments/105814108</link><description>The US president described Sadiq Khan as "terrible" and warned the British capital was heading towards "sharia law".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">422ae10fb37033a360fbadff60ea4a35</guid></item><item><title>Kimmel monologue racks up millions of views on social media as Joe Rogan slams government 'dictating'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/kimmel-video-and-rogan-lashing-viral/105814274</link><description>Kimmel's program was indefinitely suspended last week after he made comments about the late conservative commentator Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">125445d0de8a02f7060a350896e799ff</guid></item><item><title>Australia in a 'dangerous place' as AI adoption ramps up, prompting calls to protect jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/australia-in-dangerous-place-as-ai-adoption-ramps-up/105807430</link><description>Artificial intelligence is coming for our jobs — but will it take them away, or just give us a powerful new assistant?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48e1ecb4ff4fc7a8cb46b98272af471f</guid></item><item><title>Who is really pulling the strings at Optus and what does that mean for you?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/who-really-controls-optus/105813620</link><description>The Singapore government's sovereign wealth investment vehicle is the majority owner of Singtel, which owns Australia's second-largest telco provider.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6aded4f6f61a6898c3ed39fc7af059c2</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie taunted over claim that high immigration is making Australians 'strangers in our own home'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/hastie-migration-strangers-liberal-policy/105813654</link><description>The home affairs minister says Andrew Hastie should name which visa classes he would cut after the shadow home affairs minister suggested "unsustainable" immigration was making Australians "feel like strangers in our own home".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13e71a456d250f5a995b477b981c4622</guid></item><item><title>Hastie downplays 'mischievous' leadership speculation – as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/federal-politics-live-sept-25/105812720</link><description>Liberal frontbencher Andrew Hastie brushes off suggestions he is a threat to Sussan Ley's leadership after a series of outspoken social media posts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a1855533ef7e4ee2263abc39c01aed0</guid></item><item><title>AFL super fans prepare for the grand final clash between Geelong and Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-football-fans-brisbane-lions-geelong-cats-2025-premiership/105812254</link><description>From a unique tattoo to a personalised burger, the AFL grand final is more than just a game for these super fans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85ea949cc04c0beee30263008e182e01</guid></item><item><title>Will food prices ever come down? Don't bet on it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/will-food-grocery-prices-ever-come-down/105811296</link><description>While recent cuts to interest rates may have given mortgage holders a bit of a financial breathing space, the cost of food continues to creep upwards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fce87e998f0daf4d07d83c36c6038f70</guid></item><item><title>Independent review launched into fire ant eradication program amid 'closing window of opportunity'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/fire-ant-eradication-program-review-launched/105811790</link><description>Authorities launch an independent review of Australia's national fire ant eradication program to evaluate the country's fight against one of the world’s most destructive pests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c444298e462f9192611f3572f0c28de3</guid></item><item><title>Families demand inquiry into NSW Police handling of missing persons cases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/families-of-missing-persons-call-for-probe-into-police/105693338</link><description>Nikii Smith is one of 10,000 people who signed a petition calling for a NSW inquiry into the handling of missing persons cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86bd1e4db1094cebb0f4277ff0ad4c3b</guid></item><item><title>Solar, batteries and the 'phone charger dilemma': How a standards gap threatens clean tech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/smart-tech-benefits-at-risk-over-lack-of-common-standard/105808798</link><description>In the same way Apple and Samsung used different phone chargers, many clean tech products are not compatible with others. Experts say it is a big problem for the energy transition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84ec00dd3b63db045677af76a0c64880</guid></item><item><title>Family calls for change amid frustration at seven-year coronial inquest wait</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/anger-at-seven-year-coronial-inquest-wait/105805234</link><description>Robert Hall was killed when he was struck by partially blind driver John Charles Robertson on the Horrocks Highway in 2018. It has been a long wait for the family ahead of the release of coronial findings into his death next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dedbef63ba8aa61b8045e0d358939858</guid></item><item><title>Elevated E. coli levels recorded at major NT crocodile farm owned by luxury label Hermès</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/lambells-lagoon-crocodile-farm-nt-high-e-coli-levels-in-water/105806340</link><description>One of Australia's largest crocodile farms, owned by a subsidiary of luxury label Hermès, is consistently irrigating with water containing E. coli concentrations almost 500 times the national guidelines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcebaaf92f52cb686dddde475db8c67b</guid></item><item><title>Alexa Leary and Callum Simpson win gold medals for Australia at World Para Swimming Championships in Singapore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/alexa-leary-callum-simpson-gold-world-para-swimming/105814486</link><description>Alexa Leary's win in the final individual event of Wednesday night's action in Singapore bookended a golden night for Australia after Callum Simpson won gold in the first event of the evening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24509973b18c1db25ad97fe2c3eae8f7</guid></item><item><title>Magnitude-4.1 earthquake rattles Tasmania from Maydena to Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/tasmania-rattled-with-magnitude-4-1-earthquake/105814558</link><description>Tasmania records a magnitude-4.1 earthquake in the state's south-west that was felt from Maydena to Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84775edf57cd76c9bc0ca385f3b919d5</guid></item><item><title>'On guard' for share market correction, Optus debacle began in India — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/105814572</link><description>Optus has now told the ABC the firewall upgrade that led to disrupted triple-0 calls was initiated in Chennai, India. Meanwhile veteran stockbroker Marcus Padley says he's "on guard" for a share market wipe-out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d14279b842237d15d950214fbd7b970</guid></item><item><title>Who is Samoa's new prime minister, Laaulialemalietoa Polataivao Fosi Schmidt?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/new-samoa-prime-minister-election/105789496</link><description>Supporters are fervent in their enthusiasm for Samoa's new prime minister, but voters who are more sceptical of Laaulialemalietoa Polataivao Fosi Schmidt, question his motives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">625c6497fc8280a6929fa5f29c6e97f3</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of new dust-related lung disease cases recorded in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/new-cases-deadly-lung-disease-recorded-in-queensland/105800886</link><description>Nearly 300 workers from mines and work sites have had cases of lung cancer, black lung and other illnesses recorded by the state's dust disease register in the space of 12 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2884483a655c30376f0362816224a66</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy warns UN of 'the most destructive arms race in human history'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/united-nations-general-assembly-volodymyr-zelenskyy-speech/105814462</link><description>Ukraine's president calls for global action to regulate the twin threats posed by drone technology and artificial intelligence, warning "no-one can feel safe" from Russia's expansionist goals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5f96320cb70d90485b91a1058586e74</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final sprint won't feature all teams, as Gout Gout and Harry Garside to feature at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-grand-final-sprint-gout-gout-and-harry-garside/105814536</link><description>The AFL announces that only seven AFL players will run in the traditional grand final sprint, with Olympic boxer Harry Garside also joining in.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90c0207e2a6dabd51c17d24fbfdde78c</guid></item><item><title>Macquarie to repay Shield investors after super platform failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/macquarie-admits-to-shield-contraventions/105814728</link><description>Macquarie commits to repaying thousands of Australians who invested hundreds of millions of their retirement savings in the collapsed Shield Master Fund amid admissions it contravened the Corporations Act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6ef3dcad386254cfbd1a1063f29bbf1</guid></item><item><title>China's President Xi Jinping announces new climate goal to cut emissions by 2035</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/china-plans-carbon-emissions-cut-by-2035/105814492</link><description>Outlining China's new carbon targets in a video link to the UN climate conference in New York, President Xi Jinping says "green and low carbon transition is the trend of our time".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f28b3d1c00395f4695e9369d6c444f2</guid></item><item><title>ARIA Award nominations 2025: Ninajirachi, Dom Dolla, Amyl &amp; The Sniffers lead the pack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/aria-award-nominations-2025-aria-nominees-full-list/105815074</link><description>All the contenders are hopefuls vying for ARIA Awards glory at the music industry's glitzy ceremony, taking place next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">959594b1e7f091dd3de19e45dc3888ab</guid></item><item><title>Peter Tonagh to replace Catherine West as Nine's chair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/peter-tonagh-to-become-chair-of-nine/105814974</link><description>He replaces Catherine West, who spent 18 months in the position.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2a5f2c444b61e900f222e4b49c5f0b5</guid></item><item><title>Massive sinkhole disrupts traffic and power supply in central Bangkok</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/massive-sinkhole-disrupts-traffic-and-power-supply/105815094</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cce7d7b5d0f17665bf2d2fc459ec5537</guid></item><item><title>Dramatic footage shows sinkhole swallowing up road in central Bangkok</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sinkhole-swallows-road-in-central-bangkok/105814850</link><description>Social media footage shows powerlines being pulled down into the 50-metre deep hole and vehicles teetering on the edge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">341b949dae61cd2058ac47c271016c61</guid></item><item><title>Growing AFL fan club for people with disability helps forge friendships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-fan-club-gives-people-with-disability-a-place-to-socialise/105797970</link><description>A growing club on the border between Victoria and New South Wales helps AFL fans with disabilities connect with friends who share their love for the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e88b83291b9bd7812031211c737290f</guid></item><item><title>Andrea James to lead Ilbijerri Theatre Company as artistic director Rachael Maza steps back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/ilbijerri-theatre-company-artistic-director-andrea-james/105806022</link><description>Andrea James will take the helm of Australia's oldest Indigenous theatre company Ilbijerri, as outgoing artistic director Rachael Maza steps back after almost 18 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4a3dbe4751b97f43dde74a8c6965376</guid></item><item><title>NT para athlete Briseis Brittain wasn't born when Cathy Freeman won Olympic gold, but the moment fired a dream</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nt-para-athlete-briseis-brittain-new-delhi-world-championship/105810758</link><description>Arnhem Land teenager Briseis Brittain is set to represent Australia at the World Para Athletics Championships in New Delhi this month, competing in the 200m and 400m races.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc07264a34fb78aeac4e200e6ca98512</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese addresses UN on climate goals, Gaza and Australia's security council bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/albanese-united-nations-general-assembly-speech/105815200</link><description>The prime minister uses his UN speech to talk up Australia's emissions plan after Donald Trump called climate change a "con job", and confirms Australia is still seeking a temporary seat on the body's security council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a232f435066d64bce12998bbb55c68d5</guid></item><item><title>Figure skating star scraps program amid probe involving artist who co-wrote music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/figure-skating-star-scraps-program-amid-investigation-of-artist/105815302</link><description>Figure skaters spend months perfecting their programs ahead of big competitions, but now world champion Alysa Liu has to come up with a new short program months out from the Winter Olympics as her existing music involves an American artist under investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdb57cf2473b758d2fe046f294292f23</guid></item><item><title>Scott Selwood takes break from AFL after 'personally challenging year'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/scott-selwood-steps-away-afl-collingwood/105815996</link><description>Scott Selwood will take time away from football, stepping down as an assistant coach with Collingwood, following a year marked by personal tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41d251b3ccf71ca56edd70b60deeeab9</guid></item><item><title>AI image recognition technology used to detect traffic offences raises privacy concerns, Queensland audit finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/ai-image-technology-phone-speeding-offences-privacy-audit-qld/105815134</link><description>Queensland's transport department uses AI in its cameras to detect mobile and seatbelt offences, but a new audit has ordered called for a review into how that's done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11d46c909160642ceb7265e8809e201c</guid></item><item><title>Breastfeeding in public is protected in Australia. So why are mothers still facing discrimination?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/why-are-we-still-asking-mothers-to-hide-breastfeeding/105789046</link><description>Last week a breastfeeding mother was asked to leave a Virgin Australia lounge for pumping. Experts says while there is a level of awareness that breastfeeding in public is protected, some people in the community still view it as "inappropriate".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5341713f4b5168cc3ed1630a81ef91c6</guid></item><item><title>What are Australia's chances of returning to the UN Security Council?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/australia-renews-un-security-council-bid/105816596</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese makes a fresh push for Australia to get a seat on the United Nations Security Council in 2029-30.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12bbee71870039ed7798c50667d1fea5</guid></item><item><title>Snoop Dogg says AFL grand final is 'a way of life' ahead of headline show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/snoop-dogg-afl-grand-final/105816718</link><description>Snoop Dogg has strutted into the MCG for his official appearance ahead of a fascinating, somewhat controversial, AFL grand-final entertainment set.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b66d08f7f421a2cabf591d770048f0f</guid></item><item><title>Denmark PM apologises to indigenous Greenlanders who faced forced contraception</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/denmark-pm-apologises-to-greenland-over-contraception/105816090</link><description>The apology by Mette Frederiksen in Greenland’s capital, Nuuk, hopes to close a traumatic chapter in Greenland's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10e2f68d02a379a76e33cb0667531d03</guid></item><item><title>Forestry industry says it can meet demand for biofuels as climate targets near</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/forestry-wood-waste-into-biofuel-ships-planes-climate-targets/105806578</link><description>With biofuels earmarked as a way to power the transport sector in the future, one industry says its waste can be converted into aviation and shipping fuel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c43fb3bd94bcaa6f5b6b2cc07bb8ea3a</guid></item><item><title>Perth grandmother Donna Nelson loses appeal over Japan drug smuggling conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/donna-nelson-loses-japan-drug-smuggling-appeal/105804346</link><description>Convicted drug smuggler and Perth grandmother, Donna Nelson, loses her appeal against her conviction for smuggling two kilograms of methamphetamine into Tokyo Airport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47b528f98203d1300e8e1b40978bdddc</guid></item><item><title>Trio of space weather satellites launched to study the Sun's violent side</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nasa-launch-three-spacecraft-sun/105815108</link><description>NASA successfully launches multiple satellites designed to get a better understanding of the Sun's influence on Earth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59a16bd185eeee6f5d85c73a75953dbf</guid></item><item><title>TGA approves new brain stimulation device for treatment of depression</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/brain-stimulator-device-approved-for-treatment-of-depression/105816064</link><description>Some international users of Flow Neuroscience's device have labelled the wearable tech as a game-changer in treating depression, but not everyone is convinced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d613860a63e9e5d904cc9b6ac0bd749</guid></item><item><title>Key takeaways from day two at the UN General Assembly's world leaders week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/united-nations-general-assembly-day-two-takeaways/105814272</link><description>The world's most powerful people are meeting in New York this week. Here are the key takeaways from the UN summit's second day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddb580a737f4f04170f65ae765ac9dd6</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies vs All Blacks Bledisloe Cup: Team lists, what time is kick-off? How can I watch?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/wallabies-vs-all-blacks-bledisloe-cup-team-lists/105814670</link><description>Wallabies prop James Slipper will notch an important milestone against New Zealand on Saturday, while James O'Connor will start at fly half.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03e6a514a7b10816017fc77c6d1b0aaa</guid></item><item><title>Striking a Chord | Astrid Jorgensen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/striking-a-chord-astrid-jorgensen/105816660</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42d06a8633896cd66c178a10750772a5</guid></item><item><title>South Australia passes laws to protect victims of personal injury from 'claim farmers'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sa-claim-farming-laws-pass-parlia/105816232</link><description>Individuals who contact a survivor of abuse or personal injury without their permission to encourage them to make a claim for compensation could face fines of up to $50,000 under new laws which have passed in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70085da5c5bdc719bc2ab735b7ccda09</guid></item><item><title>Hastie lets loose, one-on-one with Albanese and Trump, and the politics of Palestinian recognition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/hastie-ley-trump-un-palestine-cop-turkiye-bradfield-byelection/105814488</link><description>It turns out that Prime Minister Anthony Albanese didn't need a can of Diet Coke and a cheeseburger to attracted the US president's attention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93642a3e3240ad1fdff7cfac3d949f64</guid></item><item><title>Celebrity crocodile wrangler Matt Wright set to appeal guilty verdict on five grounds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/matt-wright-set-to-appeal-guilty-verdict-on-five-grounds/105816918</link><description>Matt Wright’s lawyers have confirmed they will file a notice of appeal within the next 48 hours, indicating it will be based on five different grounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">235091d5d14d90d64ed46d67022a1cf6</guid></item><item><title>Ahead of the biggest game of his NRL career, Nicho Hynes returns to where it all began</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/storm-sharks-nicho-hynes-nrl-preliminary-finals/105816184</link><description>Ten years to the day since his first moment in the spotlight, Nicho Hynes returns to AAMI Park for the most important game of his NRL career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ba9e5f21df0896a8a84e51f1a77817b</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters race to set hazard reduction burns across Greater Sydney ahead of fire season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/firefighters-race-to-set-hazard-reduction-burns-across-sydney/105801784</link><description>Sydney's wettest August on record has dampened efforts by fire authorities to meet hazard reduction burn targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c594b646d35e85e315447033ddb7a1b</guid></item><item><title>Liberal veteran Amanda Vanstone chides Andrew Hastie for not being a team player, warns of runaway ego</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/andrew-hastie-warned-of-division-amanda-vanstone/105817288</link><description>A doyenne of the Liberal Party and veteran of leadership battles dating back to the 1980s Howard-Peacock era has chided Andrew Hastie for not being a team player.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7155a17bde099fcac4270569e823ea49</guid></item><item><title>Matildas strike force could benefit from having both Sam Kerr and Michelle Heyman firing fit up front</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/matildas-could-have-sam-kerr-and-michelle-heyman/105817900</link><description>A fit-again Sam Kerr doesn't necessarily spell the end for Michelle Heyman's time in the Matildas, if anything the A-League star can't wait for her return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c878d14058b221a67d55c4c8bdc80e94</guid></item><item><title>Lachie Neale and Rhys Stanley named in AFL grand final teams as Jarrod Berry fails to recover from shoulder injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-grand-final-geelong-brisbane-lions-team-selections-live-blog/105812378</link><description>Brisbane's co-captain returns just weeks after doctors gave him as little as a five per cent chance of featuring in his third straight grand final as Geelong welcomes back a familiar face to take the place of Tom Stewart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd6e232727e7d0a979b313cd8bef11d5</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide 36ers terminate Montrezl Harrell's contract amid China doping case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/montrezl-harrell-dropped-by-36ers-while-doping-ban-continues/105817866</link><description>The Adelaide 36ers terminate Montrezl Harrell's contract while he serves a provisional ban after testing positive for an illicit substance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51284986b60e643af30239de40743cff</guid></item><item><title>Albury Wodonga Health surgeon claims he was sacked for criticising development plans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/john-stuchbery-albury-hospital-redevelopment/105813170</link><description>An Albury Wodonga surgeon says the local health service dismissed him after he spoke out against a major redevelopment of the hospital and changes to the region's cancer centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5683d1879274b06a9d69932384c8ddb6</guid></item><item><title>Measles case detected in Brisbane, prompting calls for vaccination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/measles-brisbane-qld-health-alert-disease-infection/105817886</link><description>Queensland's health department says the person was believed to have contracted the virus in Bali, before visiting a number of businesses across Brisbane and the Sunshine Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69d52cc929c6deec63f591815c89b60a</guid></item><item><title>Lawyers for Raiders star Josh Papalii ask court to permanently stay charges over police group chat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/raiders-josh-papalii-lawyers-ask-court-for-stay-on-charges/105817698</link><description>The Raiders star's lawyers are asking the ACT Magistrates Court to permanently stay charges against him over a 2024 incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33a2e67d4e0df98eac893b5dbf74eab0</guid></item><item><title>Horse trainer Dwayne Schmidt jailed for raping and impregnating 13yo girl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/horse-trainer-raped-and-impregnated-13-year-old-girl/105813440</link><description>New South Wales horse trainer Dwayne Schmidt is sentenced to more than three years in jail for raping and impregnating a 13-year-old girl.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cff6a74bc32102a2a7bdba358773bf49</guid></item><item><title>Gympie Regional Council votes to remove fluoride from town's water supply</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/gympie-removes-fluoride-water-supply-dental-health-fears/105814678</link><description>Gympie scraps fluoride from its water supply and becomes the third region in Queensland to reject the practice in just over a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9960f09af437f02819e5359d8481878</guid></item><item><title>Coroner finds Monash Health provided unreasonable care before toddler Dio Kemp's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/coroner-finding-into-death-of-dio-kemp/105816186</link><description>Three-year-old Dio Kemp was taken to Monash Medical Centre four times over 10 days before she died of sepsis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b865829bea191edfe0af886035c9e4</guid></item><item><title>Mass puffer fish deaths and red-bell jellyfish bloom put Pilbara coast on alert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/pilbara-coast-alert-jellyfish-bloom-toxic-puffer-fish-deaths/105815554</link><description>Hundreds of dead puffer fish are found on a Pilbara beach, as an epic red-bell jellyfish bloom prompts a warning from the region's ports authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39c787a5232b58cd251e6bebea3ae077</guid></item><item><title>Arts industry leaders call for tax reforms to help struggling sector</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sydney-arts-leaders-calling-for-tax-reform-to-the-sector/105816210</link><description>Arts industry leaders say creative tax form is needed to create greater opportunities for Australian artists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7181bdf23c74d11e765b61f89bc136e</guid></item><item><title>All the latest finance news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/all-the-latest-finance-news/105818574</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">024e11ae51d50a5a396284951c067a9d</guid></item><item><title>Denmark's defence minister says 'professional actor' behind drone flights over airports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/denmark-defence-minister-says-professional-actor-behind-drones/105818578</link><description>The drone flights occurred over several airports across the country throughout the week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20f1e4ac4ecc78b08f38c32ffe5fa970</guid></item><item><title>Former French president Nicolas Sarkozy found guilty of criminal conspiracy in case linked to Muammar Gaddafi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nicolar-sarkozy-found-guilty-of-criminal-conspiracy-libya-trial/105818560</link><description>Nicolas Sarkozy is found guilty of obtaining millions of euros in illegal financing from late Libyan dictator Muammar Gaddafi for his successful 2007 presidential bid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96ff22933c8a0523f09fb4365a1711db</guid></item><item><title>Jerry Robertson found guilty of murdering partner with sledgehammer in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/jerry-robertson-found-guilty-of-dv-murder-of-woman-alice-springs/105806492</link><description>An NT Supreme Court jury finds an Alice Springs man guilty of murdering his female partner in July 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">693256933f0d4ab5bb1c7eda5803141d</guid></item><item><title>Fourth NZYQ member issued Nauruan visa as Labor steams ahead with deportation plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/fourth-nauruan-visa-issued-to-nzyq/105817222</link><description>The former detainee was returned to immigration detention on Thursday and could be the first person transferred under the multi-billion-dollar deal inked with Nauru earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad0acd68e16e51eb3bff42b299e11dc0</guid></item><item><title>Sean 'Diddy' Combs seeks to appeal to prostitution conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/sean-combs-returns-to-court/105819070</link><description>The former hip-hop mogul was found guilty by a jury on prostitution charges but cleared him of the more serious counts of sex trafficking and racketeering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">939980e64084cf527632d2ce32f228d4</guid></item><item><title>Amazon fined $3.8bn for misleading American Prime subscribers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/amazon-fined-over-prime-subscriptions/105819274</link><description>Around 35 million Prime customers, equivalent to one in 10 American citizens, will be eligible for a payout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e66d7952eebe4a7ab86c99093620d2f</guid></item><item><title>Out-of-pocket costs, eroding trust contributing to decline in childhood vaccination rates, new report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/research-urges-action-on-declining-childhood-vaccination-rates/105815232</link><description>A new report finds out-of-pocket costs and eroding trust are contributing to a "concerning" decline in childhood vaccination rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfdd1a56127bc667f2e5ffab313e2712</guid></item><item><title>GIM Trading used virtual office space to create veneer of legitimacy as it allegedly defrauded millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/gim-trading-bond-fraud-allegations-investigation/105782912</link><description>GIM Trading has been accused of defrauding Aussie investors out of millions of dollars. Financial investigators say the company created a veneer of legitimacy and evidence suggested overseas criminals could be involved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6cac9ce30ae5a47bbfc9f7617e7dc39</guid></item><item><title>China aid and investment returns to Solomon Islands's Malaita province after ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/china-aid-solomon-islands-malaita-road-development/105789780</link><description>The Solomon Islands's province of Malaita made global headlines five years ago when it banned Chinese investment. But today, a new China-funded road project is on the way — and the people are all for it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aef86fbb6ca57b72f9ef6089dc9580e9</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners slam state premiers for 'disgraceful' call to push ahead with Santos gas project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/peter-malinauskas-under-fire-over-santos-gas-project-gomeroi/105817448</link><description>The debate over Santos's Narrabri gas project reignites, with traditional owners condemning 'disgraceful' comments made by two state premiers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ff7b86ab36f41d01a1fc6371f793a89</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A viral Donald Trump moment, a retracted study and daylight saving time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/abc-weekly-news-quiz-friday/105815222</link><description>It's that time of the week again. Test your news knowledge to see how much you remember for the week that was.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df7a412c56b638cb983f8287e8d386ed</guid></item><item><title>Teachers and students affected by anti-Palestinian racism, report into schools shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/report-into-anti-palestinian-racism-in-schools-students-teachers/105809084</link><description>The Australia Palestine Advocacy Network releases its first national register report to examine "the climate of fear, censorship, intimidation and punishment" experienced by students, teachers and members of the school community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc6ae6006e0c7e5384aa1c97d37b83e2</guid></item><item><title>Imported potatoes threaten Tasmanian growers, as companies look for cost savings overseas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/imported-potatoes-price-cuts-threaten-australian-potato-industry/105815458</link><description>Cheap potato imports from India and China are threatening the livelihoods of Tasmanian growers, as stalled negotiations with potato giant Simplot leave some farmers about to plant this year's crop without a contract.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddc6d456a4e47433bae32855e5b52bae</guid></item></channel></rss>