<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 03:54:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Dolly Parton responds to concerns about her health, says she is not dying</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/dolly-parton-reassures-fans-after-health-concerns/105869280</link><description>Dolly Parton has taken to social media to hose down speculation about her health after a comment from her sister sent fans into a tailspin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9cf814360dff4a14df6f80136217574</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr returns to Champions League in Chelsea's draw with Twente Enschede</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/sam-kerr-returns-to-champions-league-football/105869372</link><description>Australian striker Sam Kerr makes another appearance for Chelsea off the bench, getting 23 minutes of playing time but unable to break a 1-1 deadlock with their Dutch opponent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8be88f2cf245467da33d855cd83d496a</guid></item><item><title>Israel and Hamas agree to first phase of peace plan, Donald Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/israel-hamas-agree-first-phase-peace-plan/105356144</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Israel and the militant group Hamas have accepted the first phase of a peace plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57611618e3e61827cbf9c31d5a43d060</guid></item><item><title>Gaza updates: Israelis and Palestinians celebrate agreement on first phase of peace proposal — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/israel-and-hamas-agree-to-gaza-peace-proposal/105356146</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Israel and the militant group Hamas have signed off on the first phase of a Gaza peace proposal that would see a pause in fighting and the release of at least some hostages and prisoners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e786618afe3994238f153a2d53cf775</guid></item><item><title>Argentina-Puerto Rico football friendly moved from Chicago amid immigration crack down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/argentina-puerto-rico-game-moved-over-national-guard-in-chicago/105869564</link><description>An Argentine Football Association executive confirms an upcoming football match against Puerto Rico is moving from Chicago due to the National Guard being called in to quell immigration protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35a5e12e2ec1b8bc2ccbf801832e994b</guid></item><item><title>Mount Gambier's Urgent Care Clinic to reopen but GP shortage continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/mount-gambier-regional-gp-shortage-urgent-care-clinic/105861462</link><description>While a government-funded medical clinic is set to reopen, residents in SA's second biggest city are still struggling to access local care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f53c13275143fe091b55545b7173e4d</guid></item><item><title>RFS firefighter seriously injured by falling tree at Coutts Crossing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/firefighter-injured-by-falling-tree-at-coutts-crossing/105869728</link><description>A volunteer firefighter is hospitalised with head and neck injuries after being hit by a falling tree on a fireground on the NSW north coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">654deebe092f5cd200812102adee8fc4</guid></item><item><title>Fertiliser plant uncertainty puts Mount Isa Copper Smelter future in doubt despite bailout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/dyno-nobel-fertiliser-plant-impact-on-mount-isa-copper-smelter/105869194</link><description>Mining giant Glencore's government bailout was touted as its outback smelter's saving grace, but uncertainty about a fertiliser plant it relies on could still see it cease production before 2028.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42624d0211cf45c084e8456b48de4067</guid></item><item><title>Albany's tiny art gallery joins growing global community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/tiny-art-gallery-albany-global-movement/105857528</link><description>A new tiny art gallery on WA's south coast adds to a growing global movement of community verge-side offerings that range from puzzles to seed exchange.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbdc3d5da80b26f3c016522a14117d79</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government defends bail laws as opposition criticises new judicial guidance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/victoria-government-defends-bail-laws-opposition-criticism/105869076</link><description>The Victorian government defends the strength of its bail laws, after the opposition criticised a recently updated guide instructing bail decision-makers to release an alleged child offender "whenever possible".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4d0a9a5e55410b59a1778929d8746f6</guid></item><item><title>The draft order to approve Hobart's stadium has been released. So what's in it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/hobart-stadium-draft-order-released/105869502</link><description>Tasmania's parliamentarians have received a draft version of the order they'll vote on to determine the fate of the Macquarie Point Stadium project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e435ec76e14e5d0b3b06f97c8960bb31</guid></item><item><title>Madeleine McCann's mother tells court she is distressed by stalker who claims to be her daughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/mother-of-missing-maddie-mccann-tells-of-fear-of-alleged-stalker/105869518</link><description>The mother of Madeleine McCann says a woman accused of stalking her for over two years made her feel distressed and "invaded" by approaching her at her house and claiming to be her daughter. Madeleine went missing in 2007, aged three.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f8625e45bd8b707808a0ca9dfc3e675</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Liberal MP Wendy Lovell makes mass citizenship email mistake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/liberal-mp-makes-mass-citizenship-email-mistake-wendy-lovell/105869436</link><description>A mass email from a Liberal MP wrongly congratulates many people across northern Victoria on becoming new Australian citizens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de9f75949de48bd80fb71bf87aabccb6</guid></item><item><title>Hit-and-run driver Jake Danby's case sparks outrage in NT communities as victim's family calls for jail time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/jake-danby-case-sparks-outrage-victim-family-calls-for-jail-time/105823972</link><description>A fatal hit-and-run case in Darwin has exposed deep disparities in the NT’s justice system, say Aboriginal leaders, as the victim’s family speaks out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aafeaf2228951fb63aed6e6d324353dd</guid></item><item><title>Former ACT attorney-general Gordon Ramsay charged with grooming teen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/act-former-act-attorney-general-gordon-ramsay-in-court-grooming/105869620</link><description>Former ACT attorney-general Gordon Ramsay has faced the ACT Magistrates Court, charged with grooming a teenage boy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7d05b4213863efaf98964e01572dd4b</guid></item><item><title>Cessnock Rifle Club captain charged with manslaughter after pig hunting incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/rifle-club-captain-charged-with-manslaughter-pig-hunt-shooting/105869672</link><description>A 63-year-old rifle club captain has been granted bail after being charged with manslaughter over a shooting incident in the NSW Hunter Valley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">853e43073071b277baf547c22ab7d96d</guid></item><item><title>Israel and Hamas have reached an agreement. What does this mean for the Gaza peace plan?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/israel-and-hamas-gaza-peace-plan-hostage-deal-explainer/105870194</link><description>All of the living Israeli hostages in Gaza could be released as soon as next week under the first phase of a peace plan led by the United States — but the full details are yet to be released. Here is what we know so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8da3d97ca5dce024309cb5991f9e3f7c</guid></item><item><title>UN to slash quarter of peacekeepers in nine operations globally due to lack of funds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/un-slash-peace-keeping-force/105870788</link><description>That would amount to between 13,000 and 14,000 troops and police removed from their nine operations around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1c7789b92595e9ac432e52bc0b9a5ae</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with careless driving over fatal crash involving CBH grain train near Albany</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/careless-driving-charge-redmond-cbh-train-fatal-crash/105872938</link><description>The man behind the wheel of a car that collided with a freight train near Albany, killing his female passenger, has been charged with careless driving.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76699ea87e10bffd531ee1f19cc70349</guid></item><item><title>Former RAAF pilot Robert John Crawford to stand trial over alleged murder of wife, Frances Crawford</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/robert-crawford-ipswich-magistrates-committal-hearing/105869272</link><description>Robert John Crawford has pleaded not guilty to the murder of his wife Frances Crawford, who was found dead at the couple's home last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11cd33f6a1d112d9431e984377ced9c0</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins's injury recovery continues ahead of Ashes, Mitchell Starc confident he can perform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/pat-cummins-backed-by-mitchell-starc-in-ashes-tests/105865832</link><description>Australia captain Pat Cummins is in serious doubt for the Ashes and has almost been ruled out of appearing in the first Test as he continues his recovery from a back injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3777906494e600c595b49e6589350fb9</guid></item><item><title>Denmark to ban social media for under 15s, following Australia's world-leading laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/denmark-to-ban-social-media-for-under-15s-following-australia/105870694</link><description>Denmark is planning to ban children under 15 from using social media, following Australia's world-first laws to curb social media use among teenagers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbb9686f20f19c6ff490a40ff33dd199</guid></item><item><title>Gaza emergency doctor evacuated, reunites with husband Dr Mo in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/gaza-dr-mo-nour-reunite-perth-australia/105858548</link><description>Mohammed Mustafa and Nour Dalloul got married while bombs exploded around them. Now their war-torn love, forged in the emergency rooms of a Gazan hospital, has found a home in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7558a8e49bfdc55a3cdbe724d3d74777</guid></item><item><title>Bell Bay Aluminium delivers 'unsettling news' to staff ahead of power deal expiry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/bell-bay-aluminium-delivers-unsettling-news-to-staff-/105869370</link><description>Bell Bay Aluminium has told staff the company faces a "significant risk" after negotiations for a new power deal stalled, jeopardising its future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6a799ca0ee5a9a7a0516228a1102673</guid></item><item><title>How reading romance has helped keep the spark alive for this couple</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/romance-books-a-doorway-into-improved-sexual-intimacy/105734524</link><description>After 10 years of marriage and two kids, Joseph Heath and wife Laura are still in the "honeymoon phase". He says romance novels are a large part of why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e4147b61abe9cc6aa8f9a59e8b43f57</guid></item><item><title>Man charged over alleged death threat against Prime Minister Anthony Albanese refused bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/man-accused-of-making-death-threats-anthony-albanese-court/105870888</link><description>A Queensland man accused of threatening to kill the prime minister has been refused bail, with a magistrate describing his alleged threats as "deeply disturbing."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93cb357d791beef63d9cec6b0c0ce97d</guid></item><item><title>Tony Burke suddenly keen to answer questions about Islamic State relatives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/tony-burke-andrew-hastie-anthony-albanese/105858462</link><description>This week in Canberra, Tony Burke finally answered questions about the return of Islamic State relatives, Senate estimates turned into an episode of Utopia, and Andrew Hastie quit the frontbench.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c1650235972fc3a8c1d9de82b0cc008</guid></item><item><title>Former transport official Ibrahim Helmy tells corruption watchdog he artificially inflated invoices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/nsw-icac-transport-ibrahim-helmy-says-he-received-cash-payments/105871166</link><description>Former NSW transport official Ibrahim Helmy tells the corruption watchdog he artificially inflated invoices for work provided to the government before splitting the profits with contractors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ceb7d19f10b2665dd248454c24378059</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanians urged to prepare for wind gusts of up to 125kph</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/tasmanians-urged-to-make-preparations-for-damaging-wind-gusts/105869730</link><description>Residents on the north and west coast of Tasmania are being warned to secure loose items around their homes ahead of wind gusts of up to 125 kilometres per hour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd3f34d6777160f9f308d5b13e5847cf</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroo Island visitor details 'extraordinary moment of timing' family came across shark attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/kangaroo-island-shark-attack-witness-extraordinary-moment/105873108</link><description>A man who witnessed the "extraordinary" moment a surfer was bitten by a shark chasing a seal offshore Kangaroo Island has spoken to the ABC after his footage circulated online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d0e5cadb01ecb795fa49f3d163b5f24</guid></item><item><title>First look inside the Sydney Fish Market, with opening date yet to be confirmed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/sydney-fish-market-fist-look/105869460</link><description>The NSW government is expecting construction for the long-awaited Sydney Fish Market development to be completed by next month, but an opening date for the $700 million project is yet to be announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca1a9ee73ddfb5826bb72526f304f43d</guid></item><item><title>Israel and Hamas's first-phase peace plan agreement is monumental but the end of the war is far from certain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/question-marks-on-israel-hamas-peace-agreement-details/105870198</link><description>The announcement that Israel and Hamas have agreed to phase one of a peace deal in Gaza is significant. But despite the celebrations, the end of the war is still far from certain, writes Matthew Doran.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9b24489302e1fcdf06a4b33cf35d476</guid></item><item><title>Netball fights for recognition amid influx of women's sports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/netball-fights-for-recognition-amid-influx-of-womens-sports/105869454</link><description>Netball Australia is taking elite-level netball to regional communities, hoping to showcase the sport's global impact and inspire the next generation of athletes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c29340636422638897d13e7c3376d3f</guid></item><item><title>How drought inspired Goondiwindi's thriving art movement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/goondiwindi-lanescape-sculpture-trail-festival/105867942</link><description>Goondiwindi's Lanescape art collective transforms the Queensland border town into an open-air gallery featuring large steel sculptures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dff5c0bac15384a50569b46b3772841</guid></item><item><title>Israelis celebrate deal announcement with US flags and Trump costume</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/israelis-celebrate-deal-announcement-with-us-flags/105874066</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f21f0df054032c8c96db83af9221f070</guid></item><item><title>Mitch Brown was thrust into the spotlight after coming out. He wants to use it to 'call people in,' not out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/mitch-brown-hate-after-speaking-out-on-queer-issues/105862948</link><description>After coming out, Mitch Brown became an unofficial spokesperson for queer issues in the AFL. While that experience has been overwhelmingly positive, it's also come with an onslaught of hate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e05331597384262a651057a5ba1156ec</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne boosts Ashes hopes with One-Day Cup century for Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/ashes-australia-england-marnus-century-in-one-day-cup/105873938</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne's case for a men's Ashes call-up continues to build after he scored a second century in the space of a week and third of the domestic summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">362174f44227618140154caed43afb5a</guid></item><item><title>Future of pokies boss hangs in balance after US gaming licence troubles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/future-of-pokie-boss-hangs-in-balance-after-us-licence-troubles/105458416</link><description>An Australian pokie machine giant says it is reviewing its chief executive's future after a US gaming regulator spurned his licence application. It comes months after the ABC revealed he was the subject of a corruption investigation in Austria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae656b170969f4c342d640a338150205</guid></item><item><title>Competition watchdog approves Elders' $475m acquisition of agribusiness rival Delta</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/elders-delta-acquisition-approved-by-accc-competition-watchdog/105869652</link><description>The consumer watchdog has given the go-ahead for Elders to acquire its competitor, Delta, but it must sell six Delta stores in WA to improve competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dda21e910c76f2e0fe579ad341f4b7a</guid></item><item><title>Family 'quite nasty' to woman who married step-uncle before his alleged murder, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/zaid-abdus-samad-murder-trial-kuraby-queensland/105869882</link><description>A woman who married her step-uncle under Islamic law — before he was allegedly murdered by her brother at his Brisbane home — has told a court her family accused her of committing incest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7c900bc8030d0b27705c24c0f1221c9</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm grants Nelson Asofa-Solomona immediate release from NRL contract</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/nrl-melbourne-storm-nelson-asofa-solomona-contract-release/105874194</link><description>Melbourne will clear Nelson Asofa-Solomona's salary from its cap after the powerful front-rower was granted a release from the final two years of his deal with the club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b68459e3d2d56c43d3bea81b42409d1</guid></item><item><title>Teenager denied bail after allegedly posting Islamic State propaganda and threatening synagogue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/teenager-denied-bail-alleged-islamic-state-propoganda-extremism/105873474</link><description>A teenager who allegedly posted terrorism propaganda online and made threats to kill has been denied bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49561fb65189712eeea0c418650f7165</guid></item><item><title>Nebal Farsakh from the Palestinian Red Crescent Society</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/nebal-farsakh-from-the-palestinian-red-crescent/105874528</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5511df97ae5517725e062407713610f0</guid></item><item><title>Bunbury massage therapist Anthony Brain sex assault trial begins with French nudist colony claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/bunbury-masseuse-anthony-brain-sex-assault-trial-begins/105861108</link><description>Bunbury masseur Anthony Brain told women clients he needed to work on intimate parts of their bodies to relieve tension, but in reality it was for his own pleasure, a Perth court hears as his sexual assault trial gets underway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">160cfd8379cb2de41693229bccb1b6a6</guid></item><item><title>Thursday's Finance news with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/thursdays-finance-news-with-daniel-ziffer/105875676</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfc1a0f4a149ab3f13a46d956339861b</guid></item><item><title>Deloitte caught out using AI in report for federal government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/deloitte-caught-out-using-ai-in-report-for-federal/105874634</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73a40e241a39295c35b76e8f87cb1de6</guid></item><item><title>Questions over Optus's priorities during the triple-0 crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/questions-over-optuss-priorities-during-the-triple/105874638</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a04cae1697cfd7c08bf89286d042e1f1</guid></item><item><title>The first phase of a Gaza peace deal has been agreed upon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/the-first-phase-of-a-gaza-peace-deal-has-been/105874648</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">973bb4b43edd06a3e9acc285af85cd38</guid></item><item><title>Sharren Haskel on Trump's role in negotiating peace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/sharren-haskel-on-trumps-role-in-negotiating-peace/105874654</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6186c4e1a6509812f15dd71a08a007a0</guid></item><item><title>Ahmad Hodroj handed five-year jail term for domestic violence manslaughter of Amira Moughnieh</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-09/ahmad-hodroj-jailed-for-manslaughter-of-amira-moughnieh/105874532</link><description>Amira Moughnieh's estranged husband will be released from prison in 2026 after being sentenced to five years' jail for her manslaughter on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">369b5a131e5016a3f856864e35c1bc94</guid></item><item><title>Ruby Hunter, Shellie Morris and Missy Higgins among recipients at Australian Women in Music Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/australian-women-music-awards-winners-2025/105818332</link><description>The Australian Women in Music Awards recognised contributions across the music sector, from artists, to photographers, journalists, filmmakers, and leaders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6a9fa96fc27f3c059d502ac8fe237a0</guid></item><item><title>Europe Commission President Ursula von der Leyen survives no-confidence votes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/ursula-von-der-leyen-no-confidence-vote/105874816</link><description>The European Commission president has faced criticism from the left and right after striking a tariff deal with the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38f9eb683dff13f9b08da77359695e43</guid></item><item><title>China further limits the export of rare earth materials and products</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/china-rare-earth-exports-limited-further/105874886</link><description>The issue has been a key sticking point in the trade war between Beijing and Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5225fa84dc406f960ab2eba29fe1bd5</guid></item><item><title>Jail term increased for man who appealed Gisele Pelicot rape conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/man-appealing-pelicot-rape-conviction-has-jail-sentence-increase/105875152</link><description>Husamettin Dogan, 44, was the only one to have maintained his appeal after the first trial last year of 51 men, including Gisele Pelicot's husband, in the case of mass sexual abuse that shocked France and the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6b4306b2ebdced96d1b3c168eab3648</guid></item><item><title>Google is abruptly changing the game for journalism — again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/google-meta-ai-journalism-future-rug-pull/105866774</link><description>The launch of 'AI Mode' ushers in a future where news sites are kept alive to train AI chatbots for a US tech company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c1035f383510c24ed89699e014ac496</guid></item><item><title>Gaza updates: US sending 200 troops to Israel to help monitor peace deal — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/israel-hamas-peace-deal-agreement/105874592</link><description>The Israeli cabinet has approved a framework for the release of hostages, according to Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaca924593267cbefdf218bdd353e087</guid></item><item><title>Vladimir Putin is fearful the return of his convict army could destabilise Russian society, sources say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/russia-braces-for-return-of-convict-army-post-ukraine-war/105812936</link><description>The Russian president views the prospect of an army returning en masse as a potential risk he wants carefully managed to avoid destabilising society, three sources close to the Kremlin said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63589d280dfa3d97b98a39b22696cc63</guid></item><item><title>First Guardian super trustee Diversa 'ticked off' investments, says former financial adviser Ferras Merhi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/first-guardian-shield-super-trustees-diversa-and-equity-trustees/105833840</link><description>A former financial adviser involved in placing thousands of clients into the First Guardian Master Fund says he was given clearance by superannuation trustee Diversa to do so after the trustee initially flagged compliance concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e63548bd7baad68bd71fdff6112324db</guid></item><item><title>Ceasefire announcement met with joy and some scepticism in Israel and Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/ceasefire-announcement-met-joy-scepticism-israel-gaza/105859468</link><description>The announcement of an agreement to phase one of a ceasefire deal between Israel and Hamas brings great joy to many people in Israel and Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6287b88a3d91d9e217c0620510ac952</guid></item><item><title>World leaders praise Donald Trump for achieving 'first phase' of Gaza deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/world-leaders-praise-donald-trump-for-achieving-peace/105875278</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c9daa1e8a2d22ed6ead229d96bd45f4</guid></item><item><title>Trump says hostages to be released early next week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/trump-lays-out-hostage-release-timeline-/105875328</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85cb50918805dc29769a5fd4b26752a5</guid></item><item><title>Sick sea turtle rescued from algal bloom recovering at Adelaide Zoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/sick-turtle-rescue-algal-bloom-south-australia/105870382</link><description>A walker says Adelaide Zoo's care for an injured sea turtle he rescued from Moana beach is a small sign of hope amid the destruction of South Australia's algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b126a2a5ee8a3c2fa5ccdc27936d7e9</guid></item><item><title>Will the Liberals hold firm in the fight over freedom of information?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/freedom-of-information-foi-liberals-transparency/105858416</link><description>Crossbenchers are joining forces to condemn the government's FOI bill, calling for its withdrawal and an independent inquiry. Will the Coalition stand for transparency?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d4f97d3849ac29bf5f057276b05c41a</guid></item><item><title>The US sees Pacific Islands as 'tip of the spear', but locals fear becoming China's 'bullseye'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/united-states-military-presence-pacific-guam-palau/105861216</link><description>The United States is spending billions of dollars muscling up across its Pacific Island military outposts, but locals fear their peaceful islands will become a target.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b686686c787aed163ffe21d540cdc7e</guid></item><item><title>Coal-fired power stations to operate in Queensland until least 2046 as energy road map unveiled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/queensland-government-to-establish-400m-energy-fund/105874318</link><description>The five-year plan lays out what role coal, gas, wind, solar, pumped hydro and battery storage will play over the long-term in Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98cea3b3afe6b8fefd1c007967742783</guid></item><item><title>Beyond Blue survey finds loneliness has deeper impact on some Australians' mental health than financial hardship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/beyond-blue-survey-loneliness-deeper-impact-financial-hardship/105870174</link><description>A new national report by Beyond Blue has revealed loneliness and social isolation has reached new heights, with 46 per cent of respondents listing it as a bigger mental health stressor than financial hardship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1a340ced02484f41a772729fdfd0f33</guid></item><item><title>Why Alliyah is identifying themselves as a victim-survivor — and the power this act holds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/alliyah-identifying-as-abuse-victim-survivor/105865908</link><description>Alliyah's decision to talk about their abuse was a brave act that exposed the red flags that weren't caught along the way — and they hope it helps others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef3b7c86d2e08ce64793b8a13d322eee</guid></item><item><title>Inside the NSW government chat group as the Sydney Harbour Bridge pro-Palestinian march unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/inside-the-nsw-government-chat-group-as-the-sydney-harbour/105867960</link><description>Documents obtained by the ABC reveal internal discussions within the NSW government did not align with the external NSW Police messaging that the march could have been "catastrophic".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1105269e8ef2e54edc7c23640078465</guid></item><item><title>Advocates mixed on plans to bolster undercover police powers to share child abuse material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/afp-police-powers-child-abuse-material-mixed-response/105869926</link><description>The spread of child abuse material in Australia has come under renewed focus following high-profile incidents of childcare workers abusing toddlers, and a push by the Coalition to introduce mandatory minimum prison sentences for child exploitation offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41ecfaa5a41a9f0d75b44fd9cf4a4991</guid></item><item><title>Global pilot shortage could mean more delays after push to raise retirement age</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/grounding-pilots-age-65-international-flights/105869998</link><description>A bid to raise the retirement age for pilots has been grounded, with some experts warning the decision could worsen flight delays, cause cancellations and increase airfares.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">383777dcff769f6cbd9f7d1b3a76f6aa</guid></item><item><title>London is the world's 'phone theft capital', but one Aussie decides to fight back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/london-phone-theft-capital-australian-fights-back/105864288</link><description>Emma Van Der Hoek had only just moved to London from Sydney when her phone was stolen. She was inspired to do something about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">649c2e51f2ebf2e278643bc49e375f4f</guid></item><item><title>Man returns to boxing after sepsis forces partial amputations of his arms and legs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/man-returns-to-boxing-after-quadruple-amputation/105802512</link><description>Adam Smith became "fixated" on returning to the gym after sepsis forced the partial amputation of his arms and legs. Now he can press 365 kilograms and get back into boxing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afd4bacb212ecb09e96e14340d62c3aa</guid></item><item><title>Boy, 16, among three alleged 'contract criminals' charged in Sydney 'kill car' blitz</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/nsw-alleged-contract-criminals-charged-sydney-kill-car-police/105875324</link><description>Strike Force Flodine is investigating a network of alleged "contract criminals" hired by organised crime groups, and their use of staged vehicles or "kill cars" in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec8f096fc6e7a439df4d1928ef0eb16e</guid></item><item><title>South Africa defeat India by three wickets in Women's Cricket World Cup at Visakhapatnam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/south-africa-defeat-india-womens-cricket-world-cup/105868672</link><description>South Africa defeats co-hosts India by three wickets in the group stage of the Women's Cricket World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">344af34c876b9d1fd805b45a4e937c11</guid></item><item><title>New statistics show Victoria's most dangerous roads are in regional areas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/victoria-most-dangerous-roads-are-regional/105858040</link><description>In regional Victoria, potholes are not being fixed and major rural road projects have stalled, despite the loss of life from accidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f21ea12d59704621728578e03da03e8b</guid></item><item><title>'Sigh of relief': Israelis react to first phase of Gaza peace deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/israelis-react-to-first-phase-of-gaza-peace-deal/105875508</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a72956b4e25dac4a7e00cc28a8997bbe</guid></item><item><title>Israelis gather at Hostage Square in Tel Aviv to celebrate peace deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/israelis-gather-at-hostage-square-in-tel-aviv-/105875500</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c4bf2b01c2bd8a637ef9f0a6752b489</guid></item><item><title>The NT's first Alice Springs-based police commissioner has a rocky road ahead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/new-nt-police-commissioner-martin-dole-challenges-ahead/105872198</link><description>Martin Dole has been a Northern Territory police officer for nearly 30 years — but as the new commissioner, his most challenging role now lies ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62a4fe70a93c35ff3bf4d9dd3e6e2dbc</guid></item><item><title>Two dead on private property in Tasmania after tree falls in wild winds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/tasmania-wild-weather-two-dead-in-tree-fall/105875332</link><description>Two people have died after a tree fell on them on a rural property in Tasmania's north-west, during Friday's severe winds and wet weather, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">762b5ecc8c7afc01f1284936da8823ae</guid></item><item><title>RBA governor Michele Bullock fronts Senate hearing, ASX ends the week lower — As it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/asx-markets-business-live-news-10-oct/105875398</link><description>Michele Bullock says either shoppers or merchants will have to pay more under the central bank's proposed debit and credit card changes. The ASX closed lower after oil and gold prices retreated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7b054430694d7b28c309ac6d16c7891</guid></item><item><title>Rain causes crashes during first Bathurst 1000 practice sessions on Mount Panorama</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/bathurst-1000-mount-panorama-supercars-practice-thursday/105875440</link><description>Supercars heavyweights Triple Eight lead the charge into the Bathurst 1000 with one eye on the trophy and another on the weather forecast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c73e68997f4588b80602c150f382881a</guid></item><item><title>What the State of WA’s appeal of Dion Barber’s $2.8 million compensation win could mean for abuse survivors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/-dion-barber-abuse-compensation-appeal-to-set-legal-precedent/105873760</link><description>Less than a decade after the door opened for victims of historic child sexual abuse to seek justice in WA, abuse survivors could be at risk of having that door shut again, writes Cason Ho.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09b69bd78ea93e7d62f375821a7ebad0</guid></item><item><title>Hamas is trusting Trump as his 'eternal peace' in Gaza turns into a shaky ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/analysis-trump-eternal-peace-in-gaza-turns-into-shaky-ceasefire/105874742</link><description>With Israel and Hamas not sticking to Donald Trump's proposed "20-point plan", the deal to bring "eternal peace" in the Middle East looks more like a temporary ceasefire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e597e0e0fb47c628dfaca2d504bc30d</guid></item><item><title>Letitia James, NY attorney general and Donald Trump foe, indicted for bank fraud</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/letitia-james-ny-attorney-general-trump-foe-indicted-bank-fraud/105875568</link><description>New York Attorney General Letitia James, a longtime foe of US President Donald Trump, is indicted for bank fraud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7794029ca8b380e949956f97889ca8f</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day five recap: Geelong opens Charlie Curnow bidding as Sydney looms, Ben Ainsworth and Campbell Chesser join Blues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/afl-trade-period-day-five-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105875584</link><description>The chase for Carlton star Charlie Curnow heated up on day five of the AFL trade period, with Geelong seeing an offer rejected as Sydney prepared its bid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1af08ce39a4f267630c93fa4dbf8386</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic advances to Shanghai Masters semifinals, qualifier Valentin Vacherot continues fairytale run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/novak-djokovic-advances-to-semifinals-of-shanghai-masters/105875540</link><description>Fourth seed Novak Djokovic battled past a spirited Zizou Bergs 6-3 7-5 on Thursday to reach the Shanghai Masters semifinals for a 10th time, setting up a clash with surprise package and world number 204 Valentin Vacherot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">745b0675e4a5c74aaa50698faa310769</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia urges respect for its sovereignty after Australia-PNG defence treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/indonesia-responded-pukpuk-defence-agreement-australia-png/105869738</link><description>The landmark agreement commits both countries to "meet the common danger" in the event of an armed attack on either. With that, questions have been raised about Australia's role if the conflict in West Papua escalates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d73f53cf0f068b144851c0c5f4cd706</guid></item><item><title>When is the Nobel Peace Prize awarded? Who decides the winner?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/how-does-the-nobel-peace-prize-work/105870196</link><description>As we wait for the announcement tonight, let's unpack how the awards work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89cda7e751d1afa2530d6153ece46b77</guid></item><item><title>What NSW court ruling on Sydney Opera House pro-Palestinian march means for future protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/what-ruling-on-palestinian-opera-house-rally-means-for-protests/105874496</link><description>The state's three top judges have ruled to block a pro-Palestinian march at the Sydney Opera House this weekend, but experts say an element of their decision sets a precedent that could have major implications on protests going forward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b44cae55f475162efeb8d639c9afc48</guid></item><item><title>Israeli government approves phase one of Gaza ceasefire and hostage deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/israel-government-approves-gaza-ceasefire-deal-first-phase/105874642</link><description>The Israeli government has approved Gaza's ceasefire and hostage deal, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's office said early on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba82c5f54c63b4cb4cce011d677a0e9f</guid></item><item><title>Australia's dark matter experiment construction nears completion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/the-global-race-to-detect-dark-matter-stawell-lab-sabre/105861050</link><description>Deep underground in an old gold mine in regional Victoria, scientists enter a worldwide race to understand the composition of dark matter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20bdfc9fdb6ec2c681a7dae294b644ed</guid></item><item><title>Netanyahu and US envoys address media after Cabinet meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/netanyahu-and-us-envoys-address-media-after/105875886</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8569563443ad443504dd0b9d6b3b25a5</guid></item><item><title>Industrial businesses to ramp-up noise monitoring over humming noise in Sydney's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/epa-closes-in-on-businesses-over-disturbing-humming-noise-sydney/105870234</link><description>The NSW environmental watchdog has acted on complaints by residents in Sydney's north-west who have been kept awake at night by a disturbing humming noise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c7f8ce47ec86c2e6609ce33551985d2</guid></item><item><title>Several Australian Gaza flotilla activists home after being detained by Israel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/flotilla-activists-detained-by-israel-arrive-home/105875740</link><description>Australians who were on the Global Sumud Flotilla, a fleet of ships intercepted by Israel's navy off Gaza last week, are met by supporters upon their arrival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23ee2234ee1455b66ebd1f3782bcd5a3</guid></item><item><title>Principals' power to ban aggressive parents from school grounds to extend to social media behaviour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/safety-protections-parents-schools-aggressive-parents-review/105875552</link><description>Principals in Victoria already have the power to ban aggressive or violent parents from school grounds, but the state government is looking to apply the power to parents' behaviour on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cfdbdd1cc62140ca01e0eeea675488e</guid></item><item><title>Federal government investigates PFAS spread in Rockhampton amid concern for property prices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/pfas-contamination-rockhampton-airport-concerns-for-properties/105830932</link><description>Christine Stasch was planning to sell her family farm and retire further north. Now, she is fighting for compensation after discovering PFAS contamination on her property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8211dd335880fe3781624b719dbbcd7a</guid></item><item><title>David McBride's last-ditch attempt to overturn conviction thrown out by High Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/high-court-rejects-last-appeal-david-mcbride-jail-sentence/105875970</link><description>The former military lawyer was sentenced to five years and eight months in jail after sharing classified material with journalists in a case that has raised debate about whistleblower laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">175d998fc7a5b5ddf9511c969794f36e</guid></item><item><title>Hollywood icon Paul Feig to take audiences behind-the-scenes of Bridesmaids at SXSW Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/paul-feig-to-go-behind-the-scenes-at-sxsw-sydney/105876010</link><description>Hollywood director Paul Feig has a special strategy that's served him well when it comes to making popular movies and television shows that stand the test of time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bbf931ff2574bffc35e9ba72be36763</guid></item><item><title>Synergy apologises after overcharging customers $40 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/synergy-overcharged-customers-40-million-perth-wa-electricity/105876426</link><description>More than 170,000 customers have been overcharged a total of $40 million by WA's state-owned energy retailer Synergy since 2009, sparking an apology from its CEO.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67d73171919c8e48e6b613a22ccee7a2</guid></item><item><title>Princess Kate warns screen time feeds 'epidemic of disconnection' that threatens child development</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/princess-kate-warns-about-screen-time/105876024</link><description>In a joint essay with a Harvard Medical School professor, Princess Kate says the young generation may be the most digitally connected but is "simultaneously being more isolated".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6f9a300869f85a6925f55c9cbea97db</guid></item><item><title>Public health alert for nitazenes issued after person dies in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/queensland-records-death-from-synthetic-opioid/105875620</link><description>Queensland Health issues a public health alert warning nitazenes have been detected in tablets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74030fde7f87fd50b0bcb255243ada39</guid></item><item><title>Cairns faces prospect of water restrictions at wettest time of year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/cairns-facing-water-restrictions-wettest-time-year/105874192</link><description>Cairns residents are urged to cut down on their water use as multiple infrastructure failures put the city at risk of water shortfalls heading into summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f3a138386a7fabdb54be0b3faf38c82</guid></item><item><title>PM says there's 'nothing unusual' in Treasury meeting on contentious superannuation tax proposal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/albanese-plays-down-treasury-request-superannuation-tax/105875570</link><description>Anthony Albanese says his request for Treasury to examine a controversial proposal to lift taxes on some superannuation balances is "nothing unusual", rejecting claims he is planning to rewrite it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe7afdcdf15f814487b7881f7653bc89</guid></item><item><title>Matildas confirm return of Sam Kerr to squad for England and Wales friendlies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/matildas-confirm-return-of-sam-kerr/105875916</link><description>Sam Kerr is back in the Matildas squad for the first time since late 2023, ahead of friendlies against Wales and England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5aeea9e4dce40106f87d459df2eade18</guid></item><item><title>Judge dismisses Drake's lawsuit over Kendrick Lamar diss track Not Like Us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/judge-dismisses-drake-lawsuit-kendrick-lamar-not-like-us/105876144</link><description>The judge says a reasonable listener could not have concluded that Not Like Us was conveying objective facts about Drake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f5f53f791e2466fdbe508fd95f87668</guid></item><item><title>Working dog makes championship comeback after leg amputation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/cheese-the-champion-three-legged-dog-comeback/105833270</link><description>Cheese was on track to be a champion when an accident cut his working dog trial career short. A year on from a leg amputation, the border collie is back in the yards and the winner's circle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30087740aaa42038b8fd192bd39249e7</guid></item><item><title>Two dead after magnitude-7.4 Philippines earthquake sparks tsunami warnings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/magnitude-7-4-earthquake-strikes-philippines-tsunami-warning/105877252</link><description>The quake hit in the Mindanao region at a depth of 62 kilometres below ground level and could cause hazardous tsunami waves along coasts within 300km of the epicentre, seismology authorities say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0203a68b6ef5ddf44b4d1ebd08c9622e</guid></item><item><title>RBA governor Michele Bullock says First Home Guarantee could lead to riskier loans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/rba-governor-michele-bullock-senate-grilling-property-price-rise/105873716</link><description>RBA Governor Michele Bullock says the federal government's First Home Guarantee scheme could see some Australians taking out riskier loans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38ef789309a652d1ddba94eab70c3783</guid></item><item><title>David Pocock reinvited to parliament sports club after prime minister weighs in</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/david-pocock-parliament-sports-club-gambling-lobby-sponsorship/105876446</link><description>The former star Wallabies player turned independent senator was kicked out of the social sports club after raising concerns about its links to the gambling industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd97cdeba6a6b1da2db09b46e5826137</guid></item><item><title>Victorian fruit grower to stand trial over coolroom death of truck driver</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/fruit-grower-trial-not-guilty-plea-coolroom-death-shepparton/105870460</link><description>A fruit-growing company in northern Victoria will stand trial over the death of a 50-year-old man who was found unresponsive in a coolroom in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3e990fdcfe84a1cf57503d815864671</guid></item><item><title>Vladimir Putin says Russian air defences were to blame for Azerbaijani jetliner crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/azerbaijani-plane-crash-russian-air-defences-to-blame-putin-says/105876934</link><description>The Russian president makes his first public admission of responsibility for the crash, in an effort to improve relations with Azerbaijan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">397860cc5db8e0d72e7856342cddcf24</guid></item><item><title>Australia 'still optimistic' Pat Cummins will play first Ashes Test against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/ashes-australia-england-pat-cummins-first-test/105877424</link><description>With the opening men's Ashes Test six weeks away, Australia coach Andrew McDonald is not willing to rule out Pat Cummins taking the field in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1447a7d5df1ddcc1e1d81f8972e49486</guid></item><item><title>Patients may not see benefits of $8.5 billlion bulk-billing boost for four years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/bulk-billing-incentive-boost-may-not-flow-for-years/105877228</link><description>Patients may not see the benefits of higher bulk-billing for years, and average-out-of-pocket costs are expected to rise, the health department has conceded — despite $8.5 billion being tipped into the GP subsidy scheme from November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59bcd666888fb324634b523eb9d30802</guid></item><item><title>Sydney rock oysters to be grown at Lakes Entrance on the Gippsland Lakes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/victorians-could-soon-enjoy-homegrown-sydney-rock-oysters/105876316</link><description>Victoria could have its own Sydney rock oyster industry after a trial in the state's east yielded positive results.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c3ab285fc280a71bdaa80e9d36de7f0</guid></item><item><title>Can you ever throw out a previous home owner or renter's mail?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/can-you-ever-throw-out-someone-elses-mail/105837974</link><description>Even years after moving in, you might still be receiving someone else’s bills and letters. Here’s what can you do about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bad6b718ab042dcb408f6ce3edd8d58c</guid></item><item><title>Teens charged with murder after deaths of Dau Akueng and Chol Achiek refuse to attend court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/teenagers-charged-murder-refuse-to-attend-court/105877662</link><description>Two teenagers charged with murder after the deaths of Dau Akueng and Chol Achiek have refused to board the prison van to attend court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33f4aeff4cdc6b54653b6715a2005368</guid></item><item><title>Donna Nelson drops attempts to overturn Japan drug smuggling conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/donna-nelson-abandons-japan-drug-smuggling-appeal/105877124</link><description>A Perth grandmother duped into becoming a drug mule in an elaborate love scam abandons her final line of appeal on drug importing charges in Japan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">206f27669cbf42ca05647fc2575cb5ab</guid></item><item><title>David Sharaz served bankruptcy papers by former WA Senator Linda Reynolds after defamation win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/linda-reynolds-brittany-higgins-david-sharaz-bankruptcy-served/105878088</link><description>Brittany Higgins's husband David Sharaz is served bankruptcy papers by former Senator Linda Reynolds, as she tries to recover damages awarded to her by a Perth court for defamation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1256d5d93c57b054c08e985d405d0b7f</guid></item><item><title>Former Olympic basketballer Danny Morseu 'disappointed' retrial abandoned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/olympic-basketballer-danny-morseu-charges-dropped/105877170</link><description>Danny Morseu's conviction has been wiped but he says he will struggle to find a job, a home, and a source of income after Queensland's Director of Public Prosecutions decided not to pursue a retrial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">225218dcd9709b51e823ef5322977d84</guid></item><item><title>More Indian cough syrups recalled after 19 children die by poisoning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/more-indian-cough-syrups-recalled-19-children-die/105876056</link><description>The World Health Organisation flags the risk of unregulated export of poisoned Indian cough syrup after 19 deaths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a27bbb9499a2201c6fc01b2dd90f3af9</guid></item><item><title>LIV's financial losses do not deter SA premier from $50m golf course</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/liv-golf-losses-will-not-impact-sa-golf-course-plan-premier-says/105877386</link><description>Premier Peter Malinauskas has rejected suggestions his government's North Adelaide golf course redevelopment is a risky investment with LIV Golf losing hundreds of millions a year, as he revealed where the Saudi-backed tournament will be hosted in 2027.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a665172221b8b91d065521a8b05f783</guid></item><item><title>Court throws out man's attempt to charge government officials using archaic practice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/port-augusta-council-charged-with-350-common-law-offences/105876884</link><description>A Port Augusta resident's attempt to charge several government officials and his local council with more than 350 criminal offences using an archaic concept of common law is tossed out by court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cedce768bfdc9cc5e2a3e9c63942deb0</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos wary of Canada ahead of international friendly in Montreal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/international-friendly-socceroos-vs-canada/105878752</link><description>In the build-up to Saturday's match in Montreal, Socceroos coach Tony Popovic feels Canada has given his squad the ultimate compliment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8f0c47995749d6a1c13b42cea53e946</guid></item><item><title>State government urged to reject Comiskey Group's Coochin Fields music festival site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/qld-regs-coalition-opposes-coochin-creek-development/105875640</link><description>A coalition of Sunshine Coast community groups is calling on the state government to scrap a major music festival development because of ecological concerns raised by the State Assessment and Referrals Agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0539c64bdbb5c4af23a9fcf63d332535</guid></item><item><title>Correspondent Matthew Doran at Hostage Square in Tel Aviv</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/correspondent-matthew-doran-at-hostage-square-in/105879334</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e83cef0757bfdd6b6e0f297912844fe</guid></item><item><title>Australians travelling to Europe warned of long delays at airports after new entry rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/border-rules-change-europe-schengen-zone-security/105877556</link><description>Facial scans and fingerprinting will replace passport stamps across 29 countries in the Schengen Zone from October 12.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74bdcf2255b838d3cd2899c4e4240842</guid></item><item><title>Brodie Kostecki sets qualifying record to snare Bathurst 1000 provisional pole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/bathurst-1000-qualifying-brodie-kostecki-sets-record/105879396</link><description>Brodie Kostecki looks a strong chance to become the third driver to claim three consecutive Bathurst 1000 poles after going fastest in Friday's qualifying session.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7507b3e62b65366d3ca4a6fdabe8fb7</guid></item><item><title>Protecting rock art from wasp nests in Central Australia's Trephina Gorge with chopsticks and brushes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/rock-art-cleaning-at-trephina-gorge/105867252</link><description>Rock art has significant cultural importance to traditional owners, and is a highlight for visitors who make the hike to see it. These Ltyentye Apurte Rangers are working to help keep them protected from wasp nests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e32adeeb4bd3293608b4c2b5f2f9468a</guid></item><item><title>Hoop pine may set record as Australia's tallest rainforest tree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/hoop-pine-discovery-might-be-tallest-rainforest-tree/105876058</link><description>Researchers mapping millions of trees as part of a climate change study think they have found Australia's tallest rainforest tree.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5b9000e787551f9b2e1e6206dd33c0d</guid></item><item><title>Coalition frontbencher tries to reframe immigration policy debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/paul-scarr-reframes-immigration-policy-debate/105878470</link><description>Shadow Immigration Minister Paul Scarr has called for a "measured and considered" debate over migration levels after incendiary comments by members of the party's right flank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">009be0aa615f933c89b4f08de8b7d5ef</guid></item><item><title>Japan's ruling coalition splits, throwing Takaichi's PM bid into doubt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/japan-ruling-coalition-komeito-party-splits-sanae-takaichi/105879610</link><description>Japan's Komeito party on Friday said it would quit its coalition with the Liberal Democratic Party (LDP). Its departure could trigger an unwinding of the so-called "Takaichi trade", which had been driven by investor optimism around fiscal stimulus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c099a37d396da198c4abec6237491ab</guid></item><item><title>SA government 'cautiously optimistic' about toxic algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/sa-government-cautiously-optimistic-about-toxic-algal-bloom-/105879314</link><description>SA government officials say there are some positive signs around the toxic algal bloom crisis as it continues to affect the state's metropolitan beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff7f4f2252b7d9c923a41ed25ffcc4d9</guid></item><item><title>Latest finance news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/latest-finance-news/105879480</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83b3f6cc6c027d4ba22acdae17f46292</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan opposition leader María Corina Machado awarded Nobel Peace Prize</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/nobel-peace-prize-awarded-mar%C3%ADa-corina-machado/105879576</link><description>The Venezuelan opposition leader is awarded the prize for "her tireless work promoting democratic rights" in the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e08335f42623c0315e2e8fa011581819</guid></item><item><title>Ceasefire begins but IDF to remain in Gaza Strip until Hamas disarms, Netanyahu says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/ceasefire-in-gaza-starts/105879726</link><description>The Israel Defense Forces announces a ceasefire has begun, but Benjamin Netanyahu says Israeli forces will remain in Gaza to pressure Hamas until it disarms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e522f39f337f20a791e2d552f3cf9189</guid></item><item><title>Japan's decorated trucks facing extinction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/japans-decorate-trucks-facing-extinction/105876222</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">978f4b2e9949dfe33839423942f03ad5</guid></item><item><title>Experts say Donald Trump had 'no chance' of receiving Nobel Peace Price</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/donald-trump-no-chance-at-winning-peace-prize/105878636</link><description>Donald Trump has not been awarded the Nobel Peace Prize. Despite his persistent claim that he "deserves" it, experts are not at all surprised he is not the recipient.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31bc4dedbf7891cb8dc5dbbf015e19e1</guid></item><item><title>Western Bulldogs extend Essendon's losing streak with 57 point thrashing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/western-bulldogs-thrash-essendon/105879214</link><description>The Western Bulldogs have kept their faint AFLW finals hopes alive with a commanding 57 point drubbing of Essendon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac92bfe6e1f2c52e8561d9563d00cbb4</guid></item><item><title>Top stories from ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/top-stories-from-abc-news/105879860</link><description>Listen to ABC News interviews and commentary and analysis from radio programs like AM, PM and The World Today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a7ef31125cf99a7e937df8cdafc91fc</guid></item><item><title>International Criminal Court rejects Rodrigo Duterte's bid for release from detention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/icc-rejects-rodrigo-duterte-bid-to-be-released-from-detention/105879846</link><description>Former Philippine President Rodrigo Duterte must remain behind bars while awaiting trial, judges at the ICC have ruled, saying he might use his freedom to interfere with the legal process and suggesting he was a flight risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ec05a77bae27bbba4cacc40494c16dd</guid></item><item><title>Melania Trump has 'open' line of communication with Vladimir Putin on Ukrainian children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/melania-trump-has-open-line-with-putin-on-ukranian-children/105880086</link><description>The US first lady tells reporters at the White House that eight children have been reunited with their families in the last 24 hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5180e9c2497ade32c5102ddf6efd2d88</guid></item><item><title>Liberals find brief lull in internal hostilities for a passable week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/coalition-andrew-hastie-tony-pasin-anika-wells-chris-bowen/105858494</link><description>If there was some internal call within the Liberals to show some discipline after the last few weeks, it worked at a basic level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98db697ba6641fa4f18bac1f61add805</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump to impose new 100 per cent tariffs on China after Beijing restricts rare earths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/trump-new-china-massive-tariffs-threat/105880136</link><description>The US President takes to Truth Social to say he sees "no reason" to meet Xi Jinping after Beijing's "hostile" move to restrict rare-earth exports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c593e331aa58e6e28231bfbe40174ca6</guid></item><item><title>Memories from the rubble</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/verify-tracking-the-destruction-of-a-neighbourhood-in-gaza/105814932</link><description>When 25-year-old Nour imagines herself back home in Gaza City, she remembers the things that made her smile. Now that's all gone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef31548e58d9f19f9724991b39be12c6</guid></item><item><title>Older borrowers taking out later-in-life loans risk post-retirement mortgage pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/housing-prices-older-borrowers-risk-mortgage-debt-in-retirement/105867244</link><description>Property analysts, brokers and banks report more borrowers are taking on big housing debts in their late 40s and 50s and, potentially, a retirement still saddled with mortgage repayments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cea624f58afd0c1f6bdfb886c7aaa758</guid></item><item><title>Japan's decorated trucks face 'extinction' but fans and truckies are trying to bring them back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/japan-culture-of-dekotora-decorated-trucks-under-threat/105862672</link><description>The dekotora, large decorated trucks covered in colour and bright lights, were once a common sight across Japan. Now they are fighting for survival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eb195808234a2a8b67b318263d22ece</guid></item><item><title>Las Vegas licence hearing turns nightmare for boss of Australian pokies giant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/las-vegas-licence-withdrawn-australian-pokies-boss/105878214</link><description>Regulators in the world's most influential gaming jurisdiction have dismissed a licence bid by the boss of Australia's Ainsworth Game Technology, branding him "arrogant", "misleading" and lacking in "emotional intelligence".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c92d4ad80838c1474d9c5146b5c7914</guid></item><item><title>Queensland plan to extend life of coal-fired power stations sends 'mixed messages'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/queensland-coal-fired-power-stations-energy-plan/105879574</link><description>Communities across Queensland have welcomed plans to keep coal and gas burning across the state, though some warn a lack of future planning could undermine short-term benefits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa49ed8303cabfa57e2ba899e8da02ed</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump deserves credit for stopping the war on Gaza, but his key claim is overblown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/donald-trump-gaza-ceasefire-plan-lyons-analysis/105880080</link><description>In the tragic arc of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, Donald Trump may have closed the latest — and most violent — chapter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35343a2a556ecc6c9cc2d961d8d4a821</guid></item><item><title>Gaza updates live: UN agencies still waiting for details on aid rollout for 'critical' relief as ceasefire takes effect</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/palestinian-families-return-to-ruins-ceasefire-takes-effect/105880190</link><description>Displaced for the past two years, Palestinians begin returning to their destroyed homes in Gaza as the Israel-Hamas war ceasefire takes effect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50449524b9592c37aa0873df2d052902</guid></item><item><title>Queensland heating up with weekend thunderstorms forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/hot-conditions-and-thunderstorms-forecast-for-qld/105876568</link><description>The weather bureau says much of the state can expect above average temperatures with possibly severe thunderstorms in the south-east today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd2bd926a0f251fc64594556239145cf</guid></item><item><title>Chaotic weather outlook raises prospects of summer bushfires across eastern states</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/chaotic-australia-weather-outlook-a-forecasting-nightmare/105878032</link><description>An atmospheric "tug of war" for control of Australia's weather is taking place this spring, and it is a forecasting nightmare.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b71072a2e473fdafe1fcd7f320252c0</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians stream north and hostage families wait anxiously as Gaza ceasefire begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/palestinians-stream-north-as-gaza-ceasefire-begins/105874744</link><description>Thousands of Palestinians sheltering in southern Gaza rush to the north, hopeful the ceasefire will hold long enough for them to return home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b1a6a9142fe1ed3903c13142c480d8e</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste workers part of PALM scheme helping to fill NT workforce gaps</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/palm-scheme-workers-timor-leste-nt-workforce-shortages/105876688</link><description>The Northern Territory struggles to find workers for low- and semi-skilled jobs, but with increasing numbers of foreign workers arriving under the Pacific Australia Labour Mobility (PALM) scheme, that may be changing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2c6d5a6c01ae7f403bd6befbcc0d5bb</guid></item><item><title>Alameddine crime network suspected in murder of UFC fighter Suman Mokhtarian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/gunned-down-sydney-ufc-fighter-suman-mokhtaria-alameddine-links/105879342</link><description>Police had intelligence that Sydney's Alameddine organised crime network wanted a former UFC fighter dead more than 18 months before his shooting murder this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f204ff3bc4b1ce27c00eca55cb4de20</guid></item><item><title>AI-generated images of missing 4yo Gus raise legal concerns about misinformation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/ai-generated-images-of-4yo-gus-prompt-call-for-stronger-laws/105873218</link><description>The thought of a missing boy lost in the outback is indescribably harrowing — but what's almost as disturbing is the realisation that some on social media have seized on the disappearance of four-year-old Gus as an opportunity to spread misinformation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19de89ce1b41ee68a56b0ec4b71b1cdf</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur loses 6-4, 6-4 to Daniil Medvedev in Shanghai quarterfinals to miss out on career milestone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/de-minaur-bows-out-to-medvedev-in-shanghai/105880016</link><description>Alex de Minaur is eliminated from the Shanghai Masters, going down 6-4, 6-4 to former world number one Danil Medvedev in the quarterfinals, denying the 26-year-old Australian a chance of his 300th tour win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d00438342ad763a6953e65f8b5283119</guid></item><item><title>The Australian Championship a second chance for 'heartbeat' of football</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/australian-championship-second-chance-heartbeat-football/105856550</link><description>The new second division for Australian football has been dubbed a second chance for some of the country's oldest clubs, which hope it will usher in a new era for the game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93645922c0eb73200c9a5c582b315cd7</guid></item><item><title>Rockbank man charged with murder over the death of woman at Epping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/rockbank-man-charged-with-murder-after-womans-death-epping/105880244</link><description>A 50-year-old man faces court charged with murder after the death of a 44-year-old woman in Epping on Thursday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f854561e09dcbd87bdb467eff3f1f23</guid></item><item><title>Concord Hospital's Ebola practice run-through tests department's emergency response plans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/hazmat-ebola-emergency-practice-exercise-at-sydney-hospital/105877344</link><description>A high-stakes mission was undertaken at Concord Hospital this week — an exercise to test how multiple government agencies would react to any future infectious diseases outbreak.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae1003d959fd5041db58be9e5f30a1fe</guid></item><item><title>Fashion's misogyny problem might end up in your wardrobe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/fashion-gender-equality-dior-chanel-misogyny/105858400</link><description>Men sit at the top of the world's fashion houses while women designers get torn apart online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35cb2c216556832c5dcdb317d8f6718a</guid></item><item><title>Derek Gee facing $54 million damages claim after moving from Israel-Premier Tech due to 'safety and personal belief'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/derek-gee-facing-damages-from-moving-from-israel-premier-tech/105880232</link><description>Canadian cyclist Derek Gee terminates his contract with Israel-Premier Tech due to a "safety and personal-belief" standpoint, but says the team is seeking damages worth 30 million Euros ($54 million) as a result.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b387dd1c4cb1a3b5845d6d08ac5d3a15</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous elder Alby Clarke remembered for ultramarathon and cycling feats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/indigenous-elder-alby-clarke-endurance-athlete-remembered/105827808</link><description>An Indigenous elder well-known for his sporting achievements, including using long-distance running and cycling to advocate for Aboriginal reconciliation and health, is remembered by loved ones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">571dd2ed6d993a3e06e1bc1389cb6c92</guid></item><item><title>Lung cancer researchers identify 'breakthrough' patterns predictive of treatment success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/university-of-queensland-lung-cancer-immunotherapy-keytruda/105635628</link><description>University of Queensland researcher Arutha Kulasinghe studied lung biopsies from the tumours of almost 250 patients with non-small cell lung cancer across Australia, the United States and Europe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecb1d23ae546828475fc34189782320a</guid></item><item><title>Escapee Australians became undercover agents in Yugoslavia during World War II</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/australian-undercover-agents-yugoslavia-genocide-wwii/105467248</link><description>It started a researcher down a rabbit hole "beyond anything anyone could ever dream up", involving deception, double agents, secret names and plans for a genocide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">586c5dddc3a2fb6c880c9092ed3168b9</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Fish Market to open doors on January 19 next year as old site enjoys its 'last hurrah' in lead-up to Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/new-sydney-fish-market-opening-january-next-year/105880252</link><description>Sydney Fish Market CEO Daniel Jarosch says the new development will be able to "open with a bang" on January 19 next year, even though construction at Blackwattle Bay is set to be completed in mid-November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54c5a9b8f2381f45c8f60f3575214ab2</guid></item><item><title>GFG Alliance accused of not meeting Tasmanian loan conditions over manganese ore supply</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/gfg-accused-of-failing-to-meet-loan-conditions/105879418</link><description>Australia's only manganese smelter is at the centre of a dispute, after failing to restart a troubled smelter in Tasmania's north despite being given a $20 million loan from the Tasmanian government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">caf8a13e8bda652ad5f5cb908b30f461</guid></item><item><title>Art courier Laurie Burgess grows his collection as he travels Australia delivering to galleries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/laurie-burgess-art-courier-delivery-driver-collector/105878528</link><description>Laurie Burgess has dedicated two decades to transporting artwork across the country, and has developed an appreciation and knowledge of the Australian art world few could rival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3379fa8a63412be8885047e73fac3f8</guid></item><item><title>Hotel owner mocks Wollongong Council's palm tree art after renovation refusal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/illawarra-hotel-renovation-refusal-protest-mocks-palm-tree-art/105870512</link><description>A Wollongong hotel owner goes to unusual heights to mock a controversial piece of public art and protest against a council decision to knock back a development application.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b1031ea2e23cee5d58514f5c7757b2a</guid></item><item><title>Aerial video shows the aftermath of the explosion at the Tennessee plant.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/aerial-video-shows-aftermath-of-tennessee-plant-explosion/105880344</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9609a6bf60b19858909639944a8363d1</guid></item><item><title>Tennessee military munitions plant explosion leaves 19 people missing and feared dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/tennessee-blast-leaves-19-missing-at-munitions-plant/105880274</link><description>The explosion at Accurate Energetic Systems in rural Tennessee on Friday morning is heard from miles away and is described by local law enforcement as "one of the worst" tragedies the area has seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd7733098257e94b3ae5d1ffeab531e4</guid></item><item><title>Crispy pita bread, warm chickpeas and garlic yoghurt is an easy dinner - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/fattet-hummus-crispy-pita-bread-warm-chickpeas-yoghurt-sauce/105774760</link><description>This popular vegetarian Lebanese dish with crispy pita bread, warm chickpeas and a garlicky tahini yoghurt sauce is ready in 30 minutes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5fb42664c5b17dc7aa90f429712af7f</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos beat 2026 FIFA World Cup co-hosts Canada 1-0 with Nestory Irankunda scoring only goal in Montreal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/socceroos-vs-canada-internatonal-friendly-live-blog/105880362</link><description>Nestory Irankunda's late strike has given the Socceroos a 1-0 victory over FIFA 2026 World Cup co-hosts Canada in in Montreal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beb7355019e2604569237fb868f651b4</guid></item><item><title>Soccer the name of the game in Borroloola, even reigning over Australian Rules Football</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/borroloola-strikers-remote-aboriginal-womens-soccer-team-revived/105874590</link><description>Aussie rules football is life for many in remote NT Aboriginal communities but in Borroloola, barefoot young women and girls dream of following their hero into soccer's A-League.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbd37b3db762ecdab8799d372f09e535</guid></item><item><title>Drone video shows displaced Palestinians moving north following ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/drone-video-shows-displaced-palestinians-moving/105880384</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31830d36f949fc9ebc02ee6a4125e872</guid></item><item><title>Mount Burr Swamp thriving after rehabilitation from farmland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/mount-burr-swamp-revival-wetlands-conservation/105869900</link><description>The Mount Burr Swamp in South Australia is brimming with water, giving conservationists hope its success can be a blueprint for the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e20e0fc5376bd3364f7296a6c0e9c3c</guid></item><item><title>Bunbury man Stanley J Clemons sentenced for shooting neighbour's dog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/stanley-j-clemons-sentenced-for-shooting-neighbours-dog/105878244</link><description>The Bunbury Magistrates Court hears how Stanley J Clemons shot his neighbour's dog and discarded its body, which still has not been found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6abd68cd38014303bda976e6328b657</guid></item><item><title>Two-time world 400m hurdles champion Femke Bol steps up to 800m in 'next challenge'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/femke-bol-steps-up-to-800m-jess-hull/105880298</link><description>Jess Hull once called running the 800m a "fun little side quest". For two-time world champion hurdler Femke Bol though, it's just "the next challenge".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34a81f517c59e930e5c5050c190d6469</guid></item><item><title>Watchdog says Synergy not the only energy company overcharging amid $40m bungle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/synergy-billing-mistake-could-affect-other-companies/105879468</link><description>A $40 million overcharging bungle by WA's largest energy retailer was a result of serious governance failures and other businesses may have also fallen foul according to the state's economic watchdog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89094235c0602560ac4d9fb70e033767</guid></item><item><title>Three killed in plane crash at NSW's Shellharbour Airport with victims having 'no chance of being saved'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/plane-crash-three-dead-shellharbour-airport/105880496</link><description>Officers from Lake Illawarra Police District were informed that a light aircraft headed for Bathurst crashed shortly after take-off on Saturday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca54f7a624ea7ed912c61dc1d7a54389</guid></item><item><title>Big Bathurst 1000 barrel roll sparks safety car as SuperUtes driver walks away</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/bathurst-crash-sparks-safety-car-in-v8-superutes/105880434</link><description>Dave Casey rolls his Mitsubishi Triton twice on race two of the V8 SuperUte Series at the Bathurst 1000, but walks away from the incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6307f27275f7cb54d6a85fe4ffe28b72</guid></item><item><title>Machete brawl between groups spills into shopping centre in Melbourne's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/vic-broadmeadows-machete-brawl/105880438</link><description>Investigators say a brawl between two groups armed with machetes spilled into a shopping centre in Broadmeadows on Friday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5dab909acd080dba0340e61fed2aa5d</guid></item><item><title>Wrestling star John Cena to headline WWE Crown Jewel Spectacle in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/wwe-event-with-john-cena-to-attract-thousands-to-perth/105879262</link><description>Wrestling mania hits Perth, with a three-day World Wrestling Entertainment blockbuster featuring stars like John Cena expected to draw tens of thousands of people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a74797aaa8d1b5f77f2483987fde3b0</guid></item><item><title>An educational trial where a robot takes year 11 student Amadeo's place in class has transformed his learning.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/missing-school-robot/105880526</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbb3617d7a4cb69038dc55cbc8df4162</guid></item><item><title>Machete brawl brawl inside the Broadmeadows Central shopping centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/machete-brawl-brawl-inside-the-broadmeadows/105880554</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca1dc6c38f34f92fbbc73f1092860f5a</guid></item><item><title>Constitutional challenge to social media ban is on the cards, and teen activists could be the key</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/constitutional-challenge-considered-over-social-media-ban/105876686</link><description>A constitutional fight is brewing over Australia's world-first social media ban, according to top legal scholars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b797aa976b097e6ad06fab895441b6c4</guid></item><item><title>Kimberley woman part of Seven Sisters project makes submission to UN in fight for justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/irene-davey-seeks-justice-with-un-for-daughter-kimberley/105870006</link><description>It has been close to three decades since Irene Davey's daughter disappeared, now she is taking her case to the United Nations in an attempt to finally get justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">157d801424833657379f8a718b6fc70c</guid></item><item><title>Three people were killed in plane crash at Shellharbour Airport, south of Wollongong.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/three-killed-in-plane-crash-at-shellharbour-airport/105880594</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74d4c00cf54bc3bad4acfd810c86a00d</guid></item><item><title>Only four people in Australia have been diagnosed with rare genetic disease CHOPS</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/rare-genetic-disorder-chops-syndrome/105648828</link><description>Fourteen-year-old Isla Steed has unique challenges as one of just four people in Australia diagnosed with CHOPS syndrome.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eebec15926b1d18c6a3efe3b4cef5a61</guid></item><item><title>Sydney FC's Amelia Cassar likened to Matildas World Cup heroes ahead of A-League Women season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/alw-sydney-fc-recruit-amelia-cassar-likened-to-matildas-stars/105880668</link><description>At 17, Amelia Cassar is likened to some of Australia's World Cup heroes, as she embarks on her first season with the Sky Blues in the A-League Women competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">520e9770ff315b1b3d2a8cbba1880f38</guid></item><item><title>Defunct NDIS provider given record $2.2 million penalty after Queensland man fatally hit by car</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/qld-ndis-penalty-two-million-death-participant-federal-court/105880582</link><description>Proceedings began against the now-defunct provider following the death of a Queensland participant in 2023. The penalty is the highest civil sanction imposed on an NDIS provider to date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6acb3225c56ca35a28372adb3d37a9f0</guid></item><item><title>National Rugby League award for Karratha Kangaroos named best community club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/karratha-nrl-community-club-award/105620432</link><description>WA may traditionally be an AFL state but a club in the Pilbara has been named among the nation's best in another footy code.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b809a8c9f2b25b721e97ba288e56b42</guid></item><item><title>'Brilliant time capsule' of historical street images returns to Bendigo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/allan-doney-photographic-collection-returns-to-bendigo/105867172</link><description>A collection of photographs taken by an amateur photographer in a regional Victorian city in the 1950s, 60s and 70s has been returned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">827179a8b6679bc401bc821dbe6910f8</guid></item><item><title>Emmanuel Macron reappoints Sebastien Lecornu as French PM just four days after his resignation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/macron-reappoints-lecornu-as-french-pm/105880586</link><description>39-year-old Sebastian Lecornu, who was first elected prime minister on September 9 but resigned on Monday after 26 days in office, says he changed his mind "out of duty", with France</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6edbc765c7289b4333468cf8376e46a4</guid></item><item><title>Roaring jet boats to return to Victoria for first time in 15 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/jet-boats-find-home-in-elmore-victoria/105865604</link><description>From tractors to jet boats at Elmore, as Victoria prepares to host Australian series jet boat event in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bd1a38cda11cf4c394fc5acf0033196</guid></item><item><title>Israel announces list of Palestinian prisoners to be released, but one key name is absent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/israel-announces-250-palestinian-prisoners-to-be-released/105880378</link><description>Israel's Ministry of Justice provides the names of prisoners it will release in exchange for Israeli hostages, but Hamas says no agreement has been reached.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">057adbbf0cd2e62eda8543f65fbc9bd0</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's opposition leader launches fresh shadow cabinet ahead of state election next year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/victoria-opposition-leader-brad-battin-new-shadow-cabinet/105880368</link><description>Opposition leader Brad Battin has brought in Kew MP Jess Wilson as shadow treasurer and promoted three first-term MPs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67cfbda81d030e123f37297883ec2064</guid></item><item><title>Trump allies at odds as US moves forward with Qatari military training facility 'on the sacred soil of America'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/us-qatar-military-training-facility-idaho/105880722</link><description>The US military is moving forward with plans to build a dedicated facility in Idaho to train pilots from Qatar. But not everyone is happy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">226b076a0d46540239264bdbf91a8727</guid></item><item><title>Genomic medicine could be huge but 5 million Australians may miss out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/genomic-medicine-could-be-huge-but-5-million/105878606</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed6e2fb9d4d9d0324e237a7c8b62bfe</guid></item><item><title>Genomic medicine researchers work to fix 'European bias' in DNA databases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/diverse-communities-needed-for-national-dna-project/105865644</link><description>Researchers are trying to fix the "Western bias" contained in many DNA databases with a new national project targeting multicultural communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c6b641519f66ec459f59a401ceae20d</guid></item></channel></rss>