<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 09:13:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Mackay riverfront under the microscope as community grapples with addiction and homelessness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/mackay-riverfront-grapples-with-addiction-and-homeless/106117362</link><description>The banks of the Pioneer River near Mackay's CBD are home to makeshift camps nestled among the trees, while others reside in picnic shelters by the wharves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07e12624fb72728b2861297dd7541855</guid></item><item><title>Australian man Lamar Ahchee accused of smuggling cocaine in Bali tells court he was 'coerced'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/lamar-ahchee-trial/106122748</link><description>Lamar Ahchee was arrested in Bali in May after Indonesian police tracked the delivery of two packages containing cocaine to his apartment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02501394495649542a4da17150b1e071</guid></item><item><title>Queensland family living in a tent in Bundaberg say they're not considered homeless</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/queensland-tent-family-not-considered-homeless/106120606</link><description>Simone Owen is living in a tent with her husband and two children, but she says they are not considered homeless so do not qualify for crisis accommodation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cb587c58fdbc8ba2214692139124124</guid></item><item><title>Why the football Dylan Brown showed for New Zealand can make his record-breaking move to Newcastle pay off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/dylan-brown-golden-boot-newcastle-knights-contract/106126952</link><description>The football Dylan Brown played for New Zealand should have won him the Golden Boot but it could also be the key to his record-breaking move to Newcastle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b66459bac729932c38199a2ed35baba1</guid></item><item><title>Hollywood director Carl Rinsch convicted of scamming Netflix out of $16.5m</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/hollywood-director-convicted-of-scamming-16-million-aud-netflix/106135428</link><description>Carl Erik Rinsch is convicted on charges that he scammed Netflix out of $US11 million for a show that never materialised, instead using the cash for purchases including luxury cars and homewares.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e8489bf4a398903633591b2660742f</guid></item><item><title>Iron deficiency is a challenge for many female athletes, like Super Netball's Zara Walters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/zara-walters-victorian-institute-of-sport-iron-deficiency/106108280</link><description>Zara Walters felt tired, dizzy and unable to recover from training sessions — then she found out she was low in iron. It's a condition that often goes undiagnosed, especially in female athletes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ee03bad452a9f38b43e0a5a4d93185d</guid></item><item><title>Researchers call for water safety to be part of English education for migrants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/call-for-water-safety-to-be-incorporated-into-english-learning/106119112</link><description>As the country heads into the summer holidays, experts are again warning Australians to be aware of swim safety at beaches, pools and other waterways.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4390c5ccee6eff142d214ab84533e218</guid></item><item><title>Bondi terrorists travelled to Philippines for 'military-style training', security sources say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-gunmen-went-to-philippines-for-military-style-training/106148662</link><description>Father-son gunmen Sajid and Naveed Akram travelled to the Philippines to receive "military-style training" in the month before they killed 15 people at a Hanukkah celebration at Bondi Beach, security sources have confirmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52edb6122488935f51e540d7c1ade39e</guid></item><item><title>Farmers' Facebook group racks up 100,000 followers as they seek support across seasons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/australian-farmers-harvesting-the-crop-facebook-group/106143522</link><description>A group dedicated to Australian grain farming created more than a decade ago has just cracked 100,000 followers with about 20,000 people following from overseas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45bd01ef5eb6e271490a8f818c46382c</guid></item><item><title>Diverse university entry in the spotlight as NSW year 12 students await ATAR results</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/nsw-university-pathways-in-spotlight-amid-atar-result-release/106130518</link><description>A south-west Sydney graduate who received disappointing final exam results is now pursuing a career in social work, encouraging high school students to avoid pinning their future goals to their grades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9f94af9503152f77795b707529d8558</guid></item><item><title>Call for action on homelessness as WA government falls short of target to end rough sleeping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/call-for-action-on-homelessness-as-rough-sleeping-target-missed/106151378</link><description>Social services want the WA government to use its significant budget surplus to invest in breaking people out of the cycle of homelessness, after it failed to achieve its goal of ending rough sleeping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88ca5d2f55c6502293c0bdf39d0bbdcf</guid></item><item><title>Local organiser calls on Albanese to attend every Bondi funeral</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/local-organiser-calls-on-albanese-to-attend-every-bondi-funeral/106158020</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a6cd0012b70b9fcf85704506b20d205</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Surf lifesavers pay tribute to Bondi victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/nsw-surf-lifesavers-pay-tribute-to-bondi-victims/106166140</link><description>Hundreds of surf lifesavers and lifeguards, many of whom responded to the Bondi terror attack, form a human chain in a moving tribute to the 15 people killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">259f9d3e9b53d11c180ca7cec88ea48d</guid></item><item><title>Best podcasts of 2025, from Forged to Fela Kuti: Fear No Man</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-23/best-podcasts-2025-forged-fela-kuti-fear-no-man/106138476</link><description>Our favourite podcasts of the year include tales of art forgery, a documentary about the life of Fela Kútì and a true-crime thriller about a dead body in the ocean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ccd2f33573cb77c395b8b3bf699ea6c</guid></item><item><title>Girl, 12, critical after being pulled from water at Trigg Beach in Perth's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/girl-critical-after-being-pulled-from-water-at-trigg-beach-perth/106176930</link><description>A 12-year-old girl is in a critical condition after a surfer pulled her unresponsive from the water at Trigg Beach on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dc476927fc0183985b0e8c682a29246</guid></item><item><title>AI technology gives swimming pool lifeguards an extra set of eyes this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/ai-system-to-help-lifeguards-in-pools-swim-safety/106172140</link><description>An AI system used in 120 public pools across Australia analyses swimmers' movements and sends an alert to a lifeguard's smartwatch if it detects someone in trouble.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4981359265166fe70bf2f7d449ec0d3b</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro held in New York prison described as 'hell on earth'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/nicol%C3%A1s-maduro-in-the-new-york-metropolitan-detention-center/106199184</link><description>The facility where detained Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro has been taken is a notorious New York jail that has held a string of high-profile and celebrity criminals, from drug cartel leaders to hip-hop stars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">784a697b58d4fb284175a75608400421</guid></item><item><title>Dragons sign Keaon Koloamatangi from Rabbitohs on massive five-year NRL deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-06/nrl-keaon-koloamatangi-signs-with-dragons-from-rabbitohs/106202500</link><description>Dragons supporters will have to wait until 2027 to see Keaon Koloamatangi wearing the Red V, but the club describes his signing as the "biggest" in their recent history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed9ce3b0406bc0a0762d38d5e4b6f92</guid></item><item><title>The tough balance of circumstance and support systems as WA woman faces eviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-07/balance-of-circumstance-and-support-system-wa-mother-eviction/106205110</link><description>As protesters strive to keep a woman from community housing eviction, the complexities of her situation collide with a housing provider's options.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d8ea6cf63b10324e9c1f2392dfdf238</guid></item><item><title>Golden Globes 2026 winners list: Owen Cooper, Stephen Graham win for Adolescence performances</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/golden-globes-awards-winners-list-2026/106199402</link><description>Here is the full winners list from the Golden Globes, where Adolescence sweeps all categories and the Pitt wins best drama series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed5dbf577fe1902316f981cc01d7f8d</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong fire at Wang Fuk Court killed 168 people, local authorities announce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/hong-kong-fire-at-wang-fuk-court-tai-po-killed-168-people/106235288</link><description>The final death toll is seven higher than previously reported and comes months after the fire tore through the apartment complex.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fce4181054efb6c2951dbecd213c5e8</guid></item><item><title>Plans for Kununurra Aboriginal short stay accommodation abandoned despite dire need</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/kununurra-aboriginal-short-stay-accommodation-axed/106228666</link><description>Leaders in Kununurra say the Cook Government's decision to dump plans for Aboriginal short stay accommodation in town could be putting more people at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c06dd6e462f4e217c665a9750f5b47d4</guid></item><item><title>Four arrested as Queensland Police seize guns, kilos of drugs in Townsville</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/townsville-police-arrest-guns-drugs-trafficking/106244526</link><description>Police find 100kg cannabis, 8kg of methamphetamine and 1kg of cocaine as well as illegal firearms hidden in bush at a Townsville property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecd99c93b49491f432b2888450905a34</guid></item><item><title>Shooters 'anxious' as ACT government looks to reform 'outdated' gun laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/shooters-concerned-act-government-gun-law-reform/106243768</link><description>Professional and recreational shooters say they want to see extensive community consultation before any changes are made to the ACT's gun laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb86d0593e40fa8c039e0a3f4386a3cf</guid></item><item><title>WA is losing the tobacco wars as gangs target vape stores and cheap cigarettes flood market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/wa-losing-the-fight-to-control-illegal-cigarettes/106242556</link><description>Burnt out storefronts in Perth and regional cities are testament to the government's inability to control the illegal tobacco trade — and it's not clear when things will change, writes Keane Bourke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">280b53748e89776c07bee7fd574bc253</guid></item><item><title>Iranian official says verified deaths in Iran protests reach at least 5,000</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/iranian-official-says-verified-deaths-in-iran-protests-5000/106246384</link><description>The death toll includes about 500 security personnel and exceeds that of any other round of protest or unrest in Iran in decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1881129ec8352a4f180454980115f1f</guid></item><item><title>Albanese apologies for Bondi Beach terror deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/albanese-apologies-for-bondi-beach-terror-deaths/106259358</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94b82df021fca2826d2b7b9e1c9e2f51</guid></item><item><title>How to attract native wildlife and birds to your garden</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/how-to-attract-native-wildlife-and-birds-to-your-garden/106042150</link><description>There are simple things we can all do to encourage more native wildlife to our gardens, backyards, balconies and shared spaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a86ce4b9695adc5a6d1286749a33f7cf</guid></item><item><title>FBI arrests ex-Olympian Ryan Wedding, likens him to drug kingpin Pablo Escobar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/olympic-snowboarder-ryan-wedding-faces-murder-drug-charges/106264912</link><description>Former Olympic snowboarder Ryan Wedding has been charged with drug trafficking, multiple murders, and has been linked to Mexico's Sinaloa Cartel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5c090160c9dea19036a54f4fab02ea0</guid></item><item><title>Fire destroys Portsea home on the Mornington Peninsula, south of Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/fire-destroys-portsea-home/106265028</link><description>The blaze in the large Mornington Peninsula home took dozens of firefighters more than two hours to bring under control.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc9c9638b5c9d6f866719a7eabb9e722</guid></item><item><title>Two men dead after drowning in Never Never River north of Bellingen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-26/two-men-dead-bellingen-drowning/106269014</link><description>Two men have drowned and another remains in a stable condition in hospital after a mishap in a river on the New South Wales Mid North Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cc48ed752f1b52f104bdd42a01fa475</guid></item><item><title>Woman discovers Holocaust descendants through DNA testing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/australian-woman-dna-test-family-tree-jewish-holocaust/106252638</link><description>Adriana Turk grew up believing there were no survivors on her Jewish father's side after World War II, but a DNA test showed that was not the case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cff4f7c21a5e88d8d950ff7583a128cc</guid></item><item><title>Noosa houseboats forced off river as new maritime rules take effect</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/houseboat-owners-forced-off-noosa-river-as-crackdown-looms/106267124</link><description>A David and Goliath battle is playing out on the multi-million-dollar shores of the Noosa River, where dozens of houseboat residents say they are being forced out and potentially into financial ruin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4a6ba483f912ebdb7967e10a86a07c7</guid></item><item><title>Health courses the most popular area of study for Australian university students in 2026, as IT enrolments fall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/university-degrees-australian-students-picking-2026/106247426</link><description>Data from the country's tertiary admissions centres shows health courses are again the most popular area of study for university students in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">139a0ca6dd78a91330e6c5f3629e5bb4</guid></item><item><title>Parramatta provided with emails from Zac Lomax's lawyer as contract drama plays out in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/zac-lomax-eels-contract-case-lawyer-agent-storm/106284054</link><description>Parramatta has been given nine emails sent by Zac Lomax's lawyer as the case between the former Eels winger and his former club prepares to hit the courtroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6fab00ca9fdf9b673ff2ad88952bce4b</guid></item><item><title>Bluey tops streaming charts in US for second year running</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/bluey-tops-streaming-charts-in-us-second-year-running/106284782</link><description>Americans tuned in to watch 45.2 billion minutes of Bluey, Bingo, Bandit and Chilli last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">359b77f5544572ac6d4f3b8653a634d0</guid></item><item><title>Catherine O'Hara from Home Alone and Schitt's Creek dies aged 71</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/catherine-o-hara-from-home-alone-and-schitts-creek-dies-aged-71/106290662</link><description>The Canadian-born actress died at her home in Los Angeles at the age of 71 "following a brief illness", according to a statement from her agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cec17b0e9c8d5e5c57455b7b63492832</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister and SA premier announce $800 million deal for 17,000 new homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/prime-minister-and-sa-premier-announce-800m-housing-deal/106290888</link><description>Funding for water infrastructure, urban renewal projects and first-home buyer schemes has been announced in a partnership between the Commonwealth and the state government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f79ccb35961ad839a0f5eeea304cfbeb</guid></item><item><title>Leon Ford and Celia Pacquola show why it's always the reluctant dads who need pets most in Dog Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/dog-park-celia-pacquola-leon-ford-interview/106263024</link><description>In the new cathartic drama/comedy starring Leon Ford and Celia Pacquola, dogs are the answer to everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77e3d407b9bf5c223080f596cb2325d9</guid></item><item><title>Children in stable condition after Townsville house fire left them fighting for life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/townsville-house-fire-two-children-severe-breathing-issues/106292532</link><description>Two children are now stable but still in a critical condition after being pulled to rescue through the roof of a home on fire in north Queensland early this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcf891ce1326fc358838c9b64ca57c68</guid></item><item><title>Lily Allen has made a huge comeback — soon she'll be in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/lily-allen-australia-tour-hottest-100-interview-west-end-girl/106281950</link><description>The British singer made her triumphant return to the annual countdown with two tracks from her latest album West End Girl.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8417be1c3cac2641d258357cf5b590c5</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic drops retirement hint, suggests 2026 could be his final Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/australian-open-novak-djokovic-hints-2026-could-be-his-last/106293450</link><description>Novak Djokovic did not go into detail on what he meant, nor did he confirm a plan to retire this year, but he chose his words carefully on centre court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55495032c4ad20750eb9060adf5c00fd</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic praises Carlos Alcaraz after Spaniard wins first Australian Open title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australian-open-carlos-alcaraz-novak-djokovic-final/106293372</link><description>Despite the hollow feeling of defeat, 24-time major winner Novak Djokovic heaps praise on Carlos Alcaraz following the Spaniard's history-making Australian Open victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87c4c2aa20dbeaeb5ed2b49f3037427b</guid></item><item><title>Youth homelessness leaves 'huge hidden population' seeking safety at school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/call-for-action-to-help-youth-homelessness-hidden-population/106292964</link><description>A coalition calls for action to help the "huge hidden population" of young people in Western Australia who are experiencing homelessness, with children left feeling ashamed and alone even in the safety of school.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66146df6025a02725621f0bf0ab2b79c</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane baby coffee assault tests Australia-China relations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/brisbane-baby-coffee-assault-australia-china-relations-beijing/106294458</link><description>Sixteen months after a stranger poured scalding coffee over a baby in a Brisbane park, China's decision to send a working group to Australia marks the first tangible shift in a complicated case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e117a579109e547bee7eb4bc5d3fff4</guid></item><item><title>How decluttering your digital streaming subscriptions can save you money this year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/how-decluttering-your-digital-subscriptions-can-save-you-money/106294296</link><description>With Australian households now holding an average of 3.7 digital entertainment subscriptions each, doing an audit on what you're using and whether it's providing value can be a good place to start when looking to cut costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c13fa3915e6c9c3a59644cc8b377541</guid></item><item><title>Palliative care specialists see living wakes growing in popularity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/living-wakes-growing-in-popularity/106302946</link><description>There is growing interest in living wakes, which allow people whose time is short to farewell their loved ones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f9da212566e524d0ff20195d909f820</guid></item><item><title>New resource connects people with organisations on front lines of bushfire relief effort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/resource-connecting-people-with-frontline-bushfire-relief-orgs/106273490</link><description>A new online resource aims to make it easier for people to contribute to bushfire relief efforts across Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd36f19dbab5f9df4c883c9b96a27f9f</guid></item><item><title>Invasion Day bomb declared terror act, as accused's 'pro-white ideology' probed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/perth-invasion-day-rally-attempted-bombing-terrorist-act/106303806</link><description>The attempted bombing of an Invasion Day rally in Perth's CBD last week is declared a terrorist attack by authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bc486c32a0f3eb6459afa4f7641f5a9</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds defeat Jamaica in first netball Test match in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/diamonds-defeat-jamaica-in-adelaide/106311692</link><description>The Diamonds made a flying start with the initial six goals in a comprehensive 72-41 victory at the Adelaide Entertainment Centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be741f4d1fb677fd340efe1016d77511</guid></item><item><title>Satellite images reveal build-up of US fighter jets and missile defences ahead of US-Iran nuclear talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/us-military-escalation-iran-middle-east-nuclear-talks-satellite/106309628</link><description>Ahead of planned nuclear talks between the United States and Iran, satellite imagery reveals how the US is positioning itself for potential military escalation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed602ad892f5d9ee098d6c3222a26202</guid></item><item><title>US hopes to challenge China's critical minerals dominance with new trading bloc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/us-pitches-new-critical-minerals-trading-bloc/106309202</link><description>The US is urging dozens of countries to follow Australia's lead and sign on to a plan to stop relying on China for the critical minerals used in modern technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4c34d4de059770202fdc288ddc3883b</guid></item><item><title>What Israel's President Isaac Herzog has said about Gaza, and why he won't be arrested in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/herzog-will-be-aware-controversy-wont-be-arrested-in-australia/106311734</link><description>When Israel's president lands in Australia this weekend, he can expect an official red carpet treatment. But he will be all too aware of the controversy his visit is generating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ffdecd9e59cf515e239536238754ac7</guid></item><item><title>ATO debt continues to drive record level of calls to small business financial helpline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/debts-to-ato-drive-record-level-of-financial-helpline-calls/106308516</link><description>Financial counsellors say small businesses struggling to pay debts owed to the tax office are driving calls to Australia's Small Business Debt Helpline higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5e7106c0d32cd232b4538e4271760e1</guid></item><item><title>Two young sisters die in hospital days after fire ripped through their Townsville home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/townsville-housefire-fatal-sisters-died-in-hospital/106312218</link><description>Two children die in hospital after a fire ripped through a Queensland home earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66f700459e25e048e2ab7a18d1fd627b</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Snook, The Newsreader and Bring Her Back triumph at AACTA Awards — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/aacta-awards-2026-live-blog-winners-sarah-snook-celeste-barber/106295178</link><description>Australia's answer to the Oscars — the AACTAs — lit up the Gold Coast tonight, with horror Bring Her Back and The Narrow Road to the Deep North dominating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">473742d5b25ca33648f2c7c0647748d5</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Festival leader Julian Hobba reflects on Writers' Week controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/sa-adelaide-festival-director-says-writers-week-saga-preventable/106306654</link><description>As Adelaide Writers' Week went up in flames, Julian Hobba contemplated resigning as Adelaide Festival's executive director. He now says "we needed to trust the judgement" of the literary event's former leader, Louise Adler.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6512b46457dc635dd9be1ece4907ad35</guid></item><item><title>Why 13yo Austin Appelbee's story of survival resonated so strongly across the globe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/austin-appelbee-quindalup-rescue-global-phenomenon/106306482</link><description>The remarkable story of Austin Appelbee's marathon swim for help went around the world, so why did it spark such an emotional reaction?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df0506ffba50ac7075d62dfa75270cd6</guid></item><item><title>New Hobart zip-line proposal for public land, but this one wouldn't be on Kunanyi/Mount Wellington</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/hobart-zip-line-proposal-ridgeway-reserve/106318728</link><description>Another zip-line is being proposed for public land near Hobart, almost a year after the last proposal on Kunanyi/Mt Wellington was knocked back by the Hobart City Council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3997c608e904e0abce11d1e58922f507</guid></item><item><title>3 Doors Down frontman Brad Arnold dies after stage four cancer battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/3-doors-down-frontman-brad-arnold-dies/106318798</link><description>Brad Arnold, a founder and the lead singer of American rock band 3 Doors Down, dies nine months after revealing he had kidney cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cbbceb57b53ce8d7ad340e98b862894</guid></item><item><title>Equine photography in demand in Australian performance horse industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/equine-photography-in-demand-in-performance-horse-industry/106298426</link><description>From leaf blowers to dance moves, photographers use every trick they can think of to get the perfect shot for the biggest performance-horse sale in the southern hemisphere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22805fcce898863bfe3fedf070b53d08</guid></item><item><title>Court appoints statutory trustee to sell rundown Rockhampton Plaza Hotel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/federal-court-orders-sale-of-rockhampton-plaza-hotel/106308402</link><description>After years of complaints from local authorities, a judge has ordered the sale of the property which sits surrounded by temporary fencing, with smashed windows and timber boards nailed across its seven-storey façade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99c69af1176e9dd66374681c276f4de9</guid></item><item><title>Jon Kudelka, Walkley-winning Tasmanian cartoonist, dies from brain cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/jon-kudelka-tasmanian-cartoonist-dies/106321714</link><description>Award-winning Tasmanian cartoonist Jon Kudelka dies after being diagnosed with brain cancer in 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b64794da6dd1ff79a97006ebfd7d1f1b</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian cartoonist Jon Kudelka and the art of cutting through political spin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/jon-kudelka-tasmanian-cartoonist-illustrator-obituary/106322196</link><description>Hailed as an artist who "knew the power of comedy in holding truth to power", Jon Kudelka once described himself as "like a monkey with an automatic rifle".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57fe9e141789e47e0247d8471e7bb6b6</guid></item><item><title>More people say they'll vote One Nation. What are they voting for?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/one-nation-policy-platforms-pauline-hanson/106296838</link><description>One Nation questions if man-made climate change is real, wants to wind back access to abortion care and plans to pay the HECS debts of doctors working in the regions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed4bdf450e353d8bca00c742667777f</guid></item><item><title>Former ATSIC head Geoff Clark was jailed but his community says legal issues persist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/framlingham-aboriginal-trust-shares-court-fallout-geoff-clark/106305592</link><description>Former ATSIC leader Geoff Clark was jailed in 2024, yet some members of his community say legal issues linger on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec0abba8310f5f8dfa22011b1c737b70</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth asks to meet Roblox following reports of child grooming. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/commonwealth-roblox-reports-of-child-grooming/106323242</link><description>Roblox has been called to an urgent meeting with the federal government in the wake of reports that children are being groomed by predators and exposed to sexually explicit material on the popular online gaming platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8186dce135dbe17f29c38ae0b2e5a4fb</guid></item><item><title>Chappell Roan no longer represented by talent agency led by Casey Wasserman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/chappell-roan-no-longer-represented-by-casey-wasserman/106327330</link><description>Pop star Chappell Roan says she is no longer represented by the talent agency led by Los Angeles 2028 Olympics chief Casey Wasserman, who has faced criticism for flirtatious email exchanges with convicted sex trafficker Ghislaine Maxwell more than 20 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfd514ef3d53768e08f6b605a9551524</guid></item><item><title>At school, I was my brother's protector. But I needed more support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/support-i-wish-i-had-at-school-while-caring-for-my-brother/106279156</link><description>I was my brother's protector at school, but the education system could have done more to support us both.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8737a14dea75637ab0e525bab21121a9</guid></item><item><title>High-rise apartments at remaining activity centres mapped across Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/activity-centre-building-heights-map-melbourne-housing/106327152</link><description>The state government releases draft maps of the remaining activity centres around Melbourne that show apartments of up to 20 storeys could be built in the south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9ef5299484ca6bffb9bd43f18cad423</guid></item><item><title>Australian T20 World Cup squad looks different but do not count it out, Mitch Marsh says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/injury-hit-australia-open-t20-world-cup-campaign-against-ireland/106329438</link><description>Despite a slew of key injuries leaving the Australian team unrecognisable, captain Mitch Marsh is confident about the experience left in the side.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e7e79b7afbfde0a033b919098cc0b12</guid></item><item><title>Surgeon Kelvin Kong's life growing up Chinese and Indigenous in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/kelvin-kong-s-growing-up-chinese-and-indigenous-australia/106326388</link><description>Australia's first identified First Nations surgeon, Dr Kelvin Kong spoke about his Malaysian Chinese heritage during the annual Wang Gungwu lecture at Parliament House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3366e9b48200b228bb48ce12f315720</guid></item><item><title>DPP apologises after office 'dropped the ball' over police officer assault case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/sa-police-grant-stevens-concerned-about-police-assault/106329878</link><description>A court decision in which a woman who assaulted a South Australian police officer with a glass bottle was spared jail prompts an extraordinary concession from the Director of Public Prosecutions (DPP).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8f6d35fb3085ec7867365bd29fc6a55</guid></item><item><title>Axed literary magazine Meanjin is resurrected by Queensland University of Technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/meanjin-magazine-finds-new-home-queensland-university-technology/106331850</link><description>The 85-year-old literary journal Meanjin will return to Brisbane, where it was first published, after it was controversially closed by Melbourne University Press last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8381f55200bc2cef76893ac168c73d93</guid></item><item><title>Bondi: Path to Terror</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/bondi-path-to-terror-four-corners/106332752</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3e3ec0c11f67bf60a856adfabe308d3</guid></item><item><title>US bars Palau senate president and former Marshall Islands mayor over alleged corruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/us-bars-palau-marshall-islands-officials-for-alleged-corruption/106329288</link><description>A senior Palau politician rejects accusations from the United States Department of State that he accepted bribes from "government, business, and criminal interests from China".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4c5d3311f093881fd48b21aa27d5d56</guid></item><item><title>Audio of Austin Appelbee's incredible Triple Zero call after marathon swim to save family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/audio-of-austin-appelbee-s-incredible-triple-zero-call-after-mar/106333512</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a07e12a8516d493dc30141c630813b8</guid></item><item><title>Britney Spears sells rights to music catalogue in reported $281m deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/britney-sells-rights-music-catalogue-primary-wave/106333696</link><description>Spears is the latest music star to sell the rights to their work, a decade after the release of her ninth and last studio album.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46d37ff06c7881b67f6362f876d81145</guid></item><item><title>Baker Boy talks new album Djandjay, Riverboats festival and family legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/baker-boy-djandjay-album-riverboats-festival-racism-fresh-prince/106321578</link><description>The Yolŋu artist known as the Fresh Prince of Arnhem Land is the king of feel-good bilingual bangers. But heavy is the crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a7e4fe54da381b9b3169df148ff7976</guid></item><item><title>Australians feel divided as Albanese asks to 'turn the temperature down'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/social-cohesion-anthony-albanese-isaac-herzog/106294752</link><description>Most Australians want greater social cohesion here, even if they don't see much of it right now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa28ba119db2dd3922f89dee680cc738</guid></item><item><title>Future of Port Hedland's West End uncertain after buyback scheme ends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/port-hedland-buyback-ends-leaving-uncertain-future/106050394</link><description>As Port Hedland's controversial dust buyback scheme winds up, Pilbara Ports quietly walks away from major plans to build a training facility and accommodation, with development plans for the area still uncertain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3587d18364662f59c0d70ef1c4dbc441</guid></item><item><title>Barbeques Galore enters receivership as debt burns into bottom line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/barbeques-galore-enters-receivership/106337962</link><description>Barbeques Galore has plunged into receivership, leaving question marks for nearly 100 stores that employ about 500 staff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69523934e505732dbc33d0c34030742d</guid></item><item><title>Economist Bruce Preston appointed to RBA Board</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/economist-bruce-preston-appointed-to-rba-board/106337708</link><description>The economics professor is the second academic economist added to the board since a review recommended boosting its expertise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c0edb3495c53e1eb1dd6f353acd5bef</guid></item><item><title>More than 100 Stolen Generations survivors gather for apology anniversary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/largest-gathering-of-stolen-generations-survivors-for-apology/106322950</link><description>More than 100 Stolen Generations survivors have gathered in Canberra for the apology anniversary. The government is pledging new money to help them heal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c81bef72da28cb61fb66cddb9bf13666</guid></item><item><title>NT Australian of the Year Felix Ho volunteers thousands of hours to the community each year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/nt-australian-of-year-dr-felix-ho-thousands-of-volunteer-hours/106329556</link><description>Finding time to volunteer can be a stretch for most people, but for Darwin doctor Felix Ho, who volunteers thousands of hours every year, it's his "full-time hobby".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b99c4561a769bc93eea33549024a298</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor becomes Liberal leader after defeating Sussan Ley 34–17</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/angus-taylor-becomes-liberal-leader/106339798</link><description>Sussan Ley, the first female leader of the Liberal Party, is set to quit politics after losing a leadership vote today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fa7d372d6cff076b3d6fe902ba524d0</guid></item><item><title>Albany Woollen Mills' 101 years celebrated via shared love of blankets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/albany-woollen-mill-in-albany-celebrates-101-years/106322356</link><description>Established in 1925, Western Australia's first and only woollen mill transformed raw wool into fabric and blankets, becoming a cornerstone of Albany's industry before closing in 2002.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebfd4b3313c5a634d2a8d4ee911573eb</guid></item><item><title>Record-breaking heatwave leaves some flower farmers without Valentine's Day blooms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/flower-farmers-heatwave-victoria-losses-valentines-day/106329998</link><description>A record heatwave has destroyed a Mallee flower farm's Valentine's Day blooms, leaving its owner devastated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7db6c60336395b1e9aea3e528a183bc7</guid></item><item><title>It took 80 years for a woman to become Liberal leader, and 9 months to ditch her</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/sussan-ley-s-time-as-liberal-leader/106045934</link><description>Sussan Ley vowed to be a different opposition leader, one who consulted widely and listened to her broad church. But it left many wondering what, if anything, she stood for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05d0ee7f0ef658ce063e5a98c8024ae7</guid></item><item><title>Bangladesh Nationalist Party wins nation's first election since gen Z-led uprising toppled Sheikh Hasina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/bangladesh-nationalist-party-wins-first-election-since-uprising/106338732</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party has won a landmark parliamentary election, according to local TV stations, securing a resounding mandate in a pivotal vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cecba2d45ea708381aa812a501c1d47</guid></item><item><title>AFL Origin 2026: Are footy fans still keen on interstate football?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/afl-origin-2026-history-of-interstate-football-state-of-origin/106341464</link><description>After a break of more than a quarter of a century, AFL State of Origin returns in Perth tomorrow with a battle between two proud football states, Western Australia and Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ac0aaab0d5f3f7f1e75b164d08b3c0e</guid></item><item><title>What to know about the Year of the Horse and Lunar New Year celebrations in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/how-lunar-new-year-of-the-horse-is-celebrated-in-australia/106295942</link><description>The Year of the Horse is here and 2026 is a rare "Red Horse" year. Find out what it means, which zodiac animal you are, and how Lunar New Year is celebrated across Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3a175856e4652c5d58d63f6eaaa7e9b</guid></item><item><title>To survive, Angus Taylor's Liberals must now get over their self-obsession</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/angus-taylor-liberal-leadership-change-self-obsession/106339870</link><description>By its new leader Angus Taylor's own admission, the Liberal Party is running out of time to pull out of the nosedive that has it heading towards oblivion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6deaa2b7ef412fd41ea270749ef71894</guid></item><item><title>Sydney children's author Oliver Phommavanh jailed for sending sexually explicit messages to minors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/childrens-author-oliver-phommavanh-jailed-for-grooming-minors/106342160</link><description>Oliver Phommavanh is sentenced to six-and-a-half years in prison with a non-parole period of four years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c59431758c6b35c4dc27a1b4299ab7a8</guid></item><item><title>Coroner finds police tactic not the cause of Toowoomba Indigenous man's death in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/steven-nixon-mckellar-coronial-findings-death-in-custody/106343656</link><description>A Queensland coroner finds the cause of Indigenous man Steven Nixon-McKellar's death during an arrest was "multi-factorial".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7cece3525e620fdc4a4921898494d2a</guid></item><item><title>Ley didn't define herself by her gender but women might relate to her workplace woes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/liberal-party-women-sussan-ley-leadership-spill/106340280</link><description>The issue for the Liberal Party is not simply the toppling of a female leader. It's also about what happened to that leader while she was in the job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">596c3a295f267e6667ca697953519fbd</guid></item><item><title>From Japan to Israel, elections are reshaping global politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/elections-japan-israel-ukraine-global-politics-trump/106337028</link><description>At a time when so much of the global conversation is about the rapid decline of democracy, it is striking what a huge impact elections are having on world events just now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bcebe10dbbdf738fed5ebfaac390428</guid></item><item><title>Here's what we know about Angus Taylor's policies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/what-we-know-about-angus-taylor-policies/106342170</link><description>The new Liberal leader has signalled he will pursue a stricter immigration policy and a return to "Australian values" in his first pitch to win back voters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed198d16c5a3341a76e01f9075ac1b0f</guid></item><item><title>Michael Mohammed Ahmad confronts traumatic childhood abuse in his new novel, Bugger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/michael-mohammed-ahmad-new-book-bugger/106331764</link><description>Michael Mohammed Ahmad, author of The Lebs, marks turning 40 with the publication of his most confronting novel yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a057fc717dc6c9c31f1c40b18e69a8e</guid></item><item><title>German Chancellor Friedrich Merz eyes European nuclear shield in call for reset with US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/german-chancellor-friedrich-merz-european-nuclear-shield/106344500</link><description>German Chancellor Friedrich Merz reveals Berlin has begun confidential talks with France about a European nuclear deterrent, saying the region has to become stronger in order to reset its relationship with the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d3bd0b5935c4030a894590b302c18ab</guid></item><item><title>Traders 'excited for the future' after lengthy Jetty Road disruptions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/jetty-road-glenelg-after-roadworks/106306338</link><description>After a difficult time for many traders in Glenelg, an air of optimism is starting to emerge as the impact of major construction projects eases and the algal bloom has all but vanished from metropolitan beaches. But some businesses along Jetty Road are still hurting from the disruptions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4407a06690e2e5d3682f5d0874abac21</guid></item><item><title>Illegal tyre dump near Townsville</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/illegal-tyre-dump-near-townsville/106321156</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14f2afdb70e9bc6bec783ddedfe81c48</guid></item><item><title>Easy, tasty and nutritious recipes for sharing this Ramadan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/easy-tasty-and-nutritious-recipes-for-sharing-this-ramadan/106331120</link><description>Looking for easy, nutritious Ramadan recipes? These options will help you prepare for and break your fast well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb9d0165cd75c38640ee10f031f1d403</guid></item><item><title>Jane Hume was punished for her election slips. Now she's been crowned deputy Liberal leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/who-is-jane-hume-the-new-liberal-deputy/106340342</link><description>The Victorian senator was unceremoniously turfed from Sussan Ley's ministry after being tarred personally with much of what went wrong in the Coalition's cataclysmic loss. On Friday, she ascended to the Liberal's second-in-command.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad7db387c85c1a7f0bbbd2e940f1ffa9</guid></item><item><title>Heat of summers gone by still fresh in the memory of 98yo Clarence 'Clack' John</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/clarence-clack-john-renmark-summer-heat-history-climate-change/106292966</link><description>Clarence "Clack" John has been through 98 summers in Renmark, South Australia. But as the town sweltered through its hottest recorded day last month, he remembers hot weather before records began.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69efc479fca218e7d45b431dfe41ad19</guid></item><item><title>WA Coroner finds 'cascade of events' responsible for heart attack death of man arrested at Perth Underground Station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/joshua-van-malssen-perth-death-inquest-findings-release/106343806</link><description>A coronial inquest into the death of a 24-year-old man at a Perth train station finds the act of restraining him in a face-down position likely contributed to his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd317bb59350b4a462da42b412a3e190</guid></item><item><title>Wool price jumps ahead of industry-first Chinese New Year break</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/wool-price-rising-ahead-of-chinese-new-year-break/106339658</link><description>As wool growers enjoy their best prices since 2019, the market will now pause to respect China's request for a week off to celebrate Lunar New Year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62ad96df10ee1750f91b3b33f2f16b56</guid></item><item><title>Major construction starts on Adelaide's first skyscraper Festival Tower Two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/major-construction-starts-on-adelaide-skyscraper-festival-tower/106345112</link><description>Festival Tower Two is set to tower over South Australia's Parliament House, which the premier says will bring money and people into the city, but others remain against the $800 million project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3de9dd2f69ba1ba4dfe31d2b03269b73</guid></item><item><title>Taylor faces formidable task rebuilding Liberals' electoral fortunes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/angus-taylor-faces-big-task-rebuilding-liberal-electoral-fortune/106337012</link><description>The paralysing uncertainty that weighed on the Liberals' faces has lifted for now, but morale in politics follows results rather than reshuffles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faa611ea05322062dacd66ef69db7e11</guid></item><item><title>These mums raise other people's children to secure a future for their own</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/children-left-behind-mother-foreign-domestic-worker-abroad/106303226</link><description>A generation of children in South-East Asia are growing up without their mothers, who have to work abroad for decades to make ends meet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8878ba8d8ea10df17fab402b2241fa7d</guid></item><item><title>Woodstock Farm program helping steer troubled Queensland youth away from life of crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/woodstock-farm-program-helping-youth-avoid-life-of-crime/106337320</link><description>The rural-based social program in the shadow of Mt Tamborine has had remarkable success in rebuilding the lives of youth who have fallen through the cracks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">421b0aeae39a6049b42963e3f882f283</guid></item><item><title>Faaletino Tavana scores stunning try in NRL trial, Canterbury Bulldogs star Matt Burton limps off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/faaletino-tavana-scores-stunning-try-in-nrl-trial/106346352</link><description>Wests Tigers rookie Faaletino Tavana has laid claim to one of the best tries in 2026 during a preseason trial against the Sydney Roosters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2cfee729b56ca0f7ea35f8b101926f7</guid></item><item><title>Easy ways to help protect your hair from chlorine and saltwater damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/how-to-avoid-chlorine-and-saltwater-hair-damage-when-swimming/106334202</link><description>Regular beach days or laps at the local pool can leave our hair looking and feeling quite different.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ed59e0b1894ab058082b567c448eb32</guid></item><item><title>Forbes Inn fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/forbes-inn-fire/106335658</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f08e5a8a0559df121863a695484d9e8a</guid></item><item><title>Italian migrants who brought 'fancy cheese' to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/italian-migrants-history-of-cheesemaking-australia/106274280</link><description>When John Interlandi's father began making "fancy cheese" in Gippsland, few Australians had heard of parmesan. At 90 years old, Mr Interlandi is still perfecting it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc65fa96aa7a73e1b002718296218199</guid></item><item><title>NSW premier announces extra public holiday in April for Anzac Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/nsw-minns-government-anzac-day-extra-public-holiday/106346332</link><description>New South Wales has the fewest public holidays in Australia, observing only 11.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ffac4dfa3924b8dccdf942341a8cced</guid></item><item><title>'Took the wind out of me': Why this man tested himself for plastics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/plastic-pollution-infertility-cancer-urine-test/106340122</link><description>Kal Glanznig had his urine tested as part of an upcoming documentary exploring plastic pollution in Australia. The results left him speechless.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20a78d9083be5d5b2872c764f9c0b081</guid></item><item><title>Charlotte Mortlock quits Liberal Party following Sussan Ley leadership defeat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/charlotte-mortlock-women-liberal-party/106347176</link><description>Women were less likely to vote for the Coalition at the 2025 election than ever before, according to the Australian Election Study.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23ccff46149d64d377fec31770f5c200</guid></item><item><title>Five arrested after incident at Alice Springs Hospital, police allege weapons brandished inside</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/nt-alleged-aggravated-assault-alice-springs-hospital-arrest/106347146</link><description>Police allege an aggravated assault took place outside of Alice Springs Hospital in the early hours of this morning, where they say a group of boys and men were brandishing bladed weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">083388ec42b3102016cb4bcc81827c7f</guid></item><item><title>What is FAFO parenting and is it good for kids?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/what-is-fafo-parenting-and-is-it-good-for-kids/106321924</link><description>Is FAFO the 1980s parenting style today's generation of kids need, rebellion against gentle child-rearing, or exhausted parents just throwing their hands in the air?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27dfd8358d59f5a02bd8ef50448007a0</guid></item><item><title>ACCC takes Coles to court over 'illusory' discounts in 'case of the century'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/accc-coles-federal-court-case-discount-pricing/106294956</link><description>The "case of the century" is set to play out in the federal court this month, with the ACCC taking on supermarket giant Coles for what it claims are "illusory" discounts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a8938d5ebc9b334251e02015fddc7f9</guid></item><item><title>Whooping cough cases hit record high after 'potentially catastrophic' vaccine rate drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/whooping-cough-cases-at-record-high-level-in-australia/106332954</link><description>A "potentially catastrophic" decline in Australia's childhood vaccination rates has contributed to the sharpest increase in cases of whooping cough in 35 years, infectious diseases experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df9f56f6aeb1e16c21e2baf9475f1b0a</guid></item><item><title>How the ABC Young Performers Awards helped launch the careers of these Australian musicians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/abc-young-performers-awards-launch-australian-classical-artists/106341202</link><description>The ABC Young Performers Awards have launched the careers of some of Australia's most successful musicians. Here are some of their stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd1d1f42c12f0cd8f19af90e90ca9734</guid></item><item><title>Chalmers mocks Taylor's proposal for bipartisan budget savings taskforce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/coalition-proposes-bipartisan-budget-taskforce/106348078</link><description>Angus Taylor wrote to the prime minister pitching the plan just days after being elected leader of the Liberal Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2e1b7a17f7bbb632412e2760a78b3ec</guid></item><item><title>Senior Liberals deny involvement in draft policy to ban migrants from Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/ley-draft-migration-policy-australian-values-statement/106348870</link><description>A leaked copy of the Liberal Party's migration policy prepared before Sussan Ley was ousted included plans to "elevate" the current non-binding Australian values statement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afcbb687b8d26ea4579377278e93aa57</guid></item><item><title>'Signal sniffers' used in search for missing person Nancy Guthrie's pacemaker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/nancy-guthrie-pacemaker-signal-sniffer-suspected-kidnapping-fbi/106348848</link><description>The FBI is using "sophisticated" technology to try to locate Nancy Guthrie's pacemaker, as the search for the mother of US TV host Savannah Guthrie enters its third week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88073bf86ca64a6b89cdec55376d3d6c</guid></item><item><title>Remote WA communities isolated and roads closed after weekend deluge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/wa-kimberley-flood-warnings-roads-closed/106348986</link><description>Major roads and remote communities are cut off by floodwaters after a deluge of rain in Western Australia's far north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3830665662ad55a972cd8b43ecb6f5cd</guid></item><item><title>Aussie Walker finishes outside of medals at Milano Cortina Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/winter-olympics-2026-live-milano-cortina/106350862</link><description>Australia's Bree Walker missed a spot on the podium but still managed a top-eight placing in the monobob at the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5c159af0301712a7a70fb5924b93991</guid></item><item><title>Australian women and children with links to ISIS forced to head back to camp in Syria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/australian-families-with-isis-links-leave-camp-in-syria/106351298</link><description>A group of Australian families with links to Islamic State fighters are forced to turn around after leaving a camp in Syria to try and begin their journey home to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d35a133c23ac9abe8c930ff01e24c75</guid></item><item><title>The night snow came to Livigno, turning this surreal valley into an even greater paradise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/snow-livigno-winter-olympic-games/106351744</link><description>Livigno is an Italian outlier in more ways than one. Already known for its special tax status and fairytale quality, the town has had a phenomenal dumping of snow, causing a significant shuffling of events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74681b168ba228a59936a1522013ca77</guid></item><item><title>North Korea builds homes for families of soldiers killed fighting in Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/north-korea-housing-for-soldiers-killed-in-ukraine-war/106351754</link><description>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un unveils new housing development in the country's capital, Pyongyang, to repay the "young martyrs" killed fighting in Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fb5a467f679f84a1526c5a726d07025</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, February 17: 20 years since The Chaser's War on Everything premiered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/the-chasers-war-on-everything-20-year-anniversary/106340294</link><description>The Chaser's War on Everything didn't start the fire, but the embers from the beloved satirical current affairs show are still warm after two decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">745f78b8b02649b29035b0cec81e7085</guid></item><item><title>Ukrainian ex-minister Herman Halushchenko accused of stashing laundered millions offshore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/ukraine-herman-halushchenko-corruption-allegations/106352078</link><description>Ukraine's anti-corruption police have accused its ex-energy minister of helping launder kickbacks and stashing millions offshore, a day after he was detained trying to leave the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c3550d4ebba3d808de4e8829c8e05c9</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor bets on migration politics amid global rightward shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/migration-social-cohesion-language-support-division-policy/106348608</link><description>If migration is treated primarily as a cultural fault line, rather than an economic system embedded in national growth, the debate will remain loud. The structural reform will remain unfinished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86414a7a131a25b45dbc0a43798c1c16</guid></item><item><title>Robert Duvall, star of The Godfather and Apocalypse Now, dies at 95</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/robert-duvall-star-of-godfather-and-apocalypse-now-dies-at-95/106352132</link><description>Oscar winner Robert Duvall, known for films such as The Godfather and Apocalypse Now, has died at the age of 95.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c557714626458849acf4e2f9e4b0c251</guid></item><item><title>How to decide what type of car insurance is best for you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/how-do-i-know-what-car-insurance-is-best-for-me-/106260688</link><description>Choosing the right car insurance option can feel daunting, but it's the kind of task that it pays to get right. So, how can you decide which type is most suitable for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19c1a606228973fe803d3604b38ad3b1</guid></item><item><title>Results show high levels of lead contamination in dust around Hobart, as EPA flags further tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/nyrstar-lead-pollution-epa-tests-hobart/106339682</link><description>High levels of lead contamination have been found in dust samples taken from suburban locations close to Nyrstar's Hobart zinc smelter, documents obtained by the ABC show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df4c929be90ce6716c442950274a84e2</guid></item><item><title>Tradies consider leaving careers over lack of onsite toilets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/tradies-created-go-company-to-help-accessability/106244286</link><description>Tradies are walking out. Not over ability or aptitude but toilets — in a symbol of the sector's persistent barriers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2da70745cc00dda920be7b9032002395</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate hike worries? Here's some good news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/why-the-reserve-bank-interest-rate-hike-may-be-a-one-off/106350914</link><description>Fresh warnings of further rate rises have been enough to send shivers up the collective spine of new homeowners, but if there's any comfort to be had, it's this: Don't believe a word of the forecasts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67fb51f52c86bc4d83c2be7c7d52564e</guid></item><item><title>Anti-slavery commissioner calls for tougher laws amid forced labour concerns for Ansell and Kmart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anti-slavery-commissioner-tough-laws-dumping-ground-kmart-ansell/106349728</link><description>Australia's anti-slavery commissioner calls for tough new laws forcing companies to take slavery in their supply chains seriously, as Ansell and Kmart face scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304d8b8d78c81209b940b9f107989101</guid></item><item><title>Iran's state TV airs 'forced confessions' of 'scapegoats' whose families fear could face execution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/iran-forced-confessions-bahai-scapegoats-face-execution/106349538</link><description>Families of Baha'i youth arrested by Iran's security forces say they've been subject to "forced confessions" and fear they may face the death penalty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">820b9238cd40b32a9775d4a7f614e1f9</guid></item><item><title>News quiz: Year of the Horse traditions, zodiac facts and festive customs across Asia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/lunar-new-year-of-the-horse-quiz-china-south-korea-vietnam-asia/106348886</link><description>How much do you know about the Year of the Horse and unique Lunar New Year traditions in Asian countries? Put your knowledge to the test with these 10 questions and see if you're a true Lunar New Year expert!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">664780860b8f5a75f0169a583ee380ca</guid></item><item><title>Irish rugby to investigate racial abuse towards Test debutant Edwin Edogbo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/ireland-rugby-test-debut-edwin-edogbo-racial-abuse/106352164</link><description>The Irish Rugby Football Union has said it will launch an investigation after turning comments off a social media post that congratulated the country's newest Test debutant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">261d685409d12066905edfb9104ada79</guid></item><item><title>Mould, asbestos, collapsed ceilings plague some South Australian schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sa-schools-in-need-of-repair/106334244</link><description>Almost two years after a state government report revealed 35 per cent of all buildings within the Department for Education's portfolio were past their design life, many schools are still plagued with issues including mould, asbestos and rotting windows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fabb2b4476c5886be92e1dda09f3283</guid></item><item><title>The Carters and Sartoris mark 70 years of marriage and 70 years as next-door neighbours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/two-broken-hill-couples-mark-70-years-marriage-neighbours/106346892</link><description>A month after Ron and June Carter got married and moved in together, his sister got married and moved in next door. This year marks not just 70 years of marriage for both couples, but 70 years of being next-door neighbours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1af71fd02e8fa3cdecaf30eb2bea72c</guid></item><item><title>'Too complex': Coles lawyer says grocery prices tough to understand — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-feb-17/106352262</link><description>Coles has faced hearings at the Federal Court in Melbourne regarding accusations of misleading customers on discounts. The Australian share market was up, following Wall Street. Look back on the day's events and insights from our business reporters in the ABC News markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4304f6e9288f8ccc780a5fe7ddd3394a</guid></item><item><title>Ex-footballer shot multiple times in Western Sydney drive-by shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/nsw-greenacre-shooting-police-public-place/106352298</link><description>Police have been told Matt Utai, who played for the Tigers and Bulldogs NRL clubs, was shot outside a home on the street by the occupants of an SUV, before they fled the scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba53d12aff8db788dde0bc0c13507507</guid></item><item><title>Bushwalkers soak in near 'once-in-a-lifetime' waterfall after cyclone in WA's Pilbara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/bushwalkers-once-in-a-lifetime-waterfall-rain-pilbara/106347066</link><description>The question of whether there is water in Python Pool is often asked around the pubs and message boards of WA's Pilbara. For the moment, the answer is very much yes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bb14e13e825585b5bae41897115415a</guid></item><item><title>A waterfall gushes at Python Pool in WA's Pilbara region.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/a-waterfall-gushes-at-python-pool-in-wa-s-pilbara-region/106349636</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">604d0c1d3c020236aecb16e168ed1c29</guid></item><item><title>Pod Save America and why Australians remain obssessed with US politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/pod-save-america-why-australians-are-obssessed-with-us-politics/106327878</link><description>Huge crowds have flocked to live shows for the popular and influential Pod Save America podcast, suggesting Australia's obsession with US politics isn't going away anytime soon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29fd6077abedec21a6c24a6198c4c894</guid></item><item><title>Search for abducted Sydney man Chris Baghsarian continues, family living 'a nightmare'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/kidnapping-chris-baghsarian-cousin-hostage-negotiator-sydney/106348436</link><description>The family of Sydney man Chris Baghsarian, who was abducted in a case of mistaken identity four days ago, are awaiting "some form of closure or resolution".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6758c13f5deb62b5d208a2ff0fee9db7</guid></item><item><title>Highly sensitive Australian court data accessed by foreign entity based in India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/transcripts-federal-court-viq-solutions-e24-technologies-india/106349338</link><description>Highly sensitive Australian court files have been accessed offshore in breach of the privacy act and Commonwealth contractual obligations, an ABC investigation has revealed, raising concerns of a national security risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a37ef7306d80e256ca5ec724ed76473</guid></item><item><title>Australia leads the world in moguls skiing. This is why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/australia-winter-olympics-moguls-dominance/106346256</link><description>To the surprise of many, the "beach nation" that is Australia is the best moguls skiing nation on earth. How the team got there is no accident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edc24052fc71a153cb8523cb4c296d67</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Eileen Gu medals despite blizzard, Ilia Malinin breaks his silence — day 10 quick hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/winter-olympics-day-10-quick-hits/106351560</link><description>A Norwegian skier melts down in the Italian cold as the Canadian women's curling team hits back at cheating accusations. Here are the quick hits from day 10 of the Milano Cortina Winter Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3e902ec1235988fcd9d5cb6b4f1c4e4</guid></item><item><title>Austrian man faces terror charges over Taylor Swift concert plot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/man-charged-over-taylor-swift-concert-attack-plot/106352344</link><description>Austrian prosecutors have filed terrorism-related charges against a 21-year-old man who they say planned to carry out an Islamist militant attack at one of Taylor Swift's 2024 concerts in Vienna.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a116a72410998a2bd5cd1447607781ad</guid></item><item><title>Criminal defamation case against Australian writer Murray Hunter withdrawn from Thai court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/australian-writer-murray-hunter-thai-defamation-case-dropped/106352654</link><description>The Malaysian Communications and Multimedia Commission has dropped a criminal defamation case against Australian writer Murray Hunter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e514a70ed3352a28b7274dd1ea2b8e2</guid></item><item><title>Highly infectious 'Super-K' flu strain blamed for skyrocketing cases in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/queensland-influenza-cases-spike-super-k-strain/106350536</link><description>Increasingly low vaccination rates, more summer indoor gatherings and a new mutation of a highly infectious strain are driving the spike in flu cases, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58267ec2596bd9fdcb6c7fc3c97898d3</guid></item><item><title>Albanese says Australian government will not help ISIS-linked families leave Syria or return home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anthony-albanese-on-isis-families-trying-to-leave-syria/106352492</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese insists the federal government will not repatriate the Australian families with links to Islamic State fighters who remain in Syria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faa866e3881f2d6646422dcbe7b56295</guid></item><item><title>Brain expert recommends learning new skills, taking on new challenges for healthy aging</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/brain-expert-recommends-learning-new-skill-for-healthy-aging/106348814</link><description>A brain health expert says you're never too old to learn new skills, as Queenslanders take on fresh challenges such as Pilates, running, and even a law degree later in life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">116ce8e09c22884efa0ce73a0c1212c2</guid></item><item><title>Landmark report finds racism 'deeply embedded' in Australian universities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/racism-at-university-report-released/106352588</link><description>Federal Education Minister Jason Clare unveiled the report with Australia's Race Discrimination Commissioner Giridharan Sivaraman in Brisbane on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fd610c26e829ebc33425c156ee8fb43</guid></item><item><title>Brandan Koschel's antisemitic speech at Sydney March for Australia rally 'abhorrent', says prosecutor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/brandan-koschel-pleads-guilty-australia-day-antisemitic-speech/106353560</link><description>Brandan Koschel was arrested after he appeared on a stage for an open mic session during the anti-immigration March for Australia event in Sydney's Moore Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04cffeec705663059adc4465ec5fdbbb</guid></item><item><title>Former ACT commissioner Vanessa Turnbull-Roberts accuses public servant of sexual assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/vanessa-turnbull-roberts-alleges-sexual-assault/106352482</link><description>Vanessa Turnbull-Roberts says she stepped down as the ACT's first Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander children and young people commissioner to prioritise her safety after being subjected to sexual harassment and sexual assault by a public servant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d6b858d730eb0ebaae68c60183f36f5</guid></item><item><title>Peterborough District Council loses fifth CEO since 2024 with latest sacked after two months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/peterborough-district-council-sacks-ceo-deirdre-albrighton/106348454</link><description>Peterborough District Council has sacked its latest CEO less than two months into her role. The council in regional South Australia has gone through five CEOs in two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57fc6e2fe202b0403c55bc16dda02479</guid></item><item><title>Louvre tour guides accused of orchestrating $16m ticket fraud ring over a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/how-louvre-ticket-guides-ran-alleged-ticket-fraud-ring/106353046</link><description>Foreign tour guides and staff who were paid to remain silent orchestrated a counterfeit ticketing ring that robbed the Louvre of millions over more than a decade, Parisian prosecutors say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f41a7c8dc6c1eabf78d49897fd9c645f</guid></item><item><title>CCTV captures man on fire after firebomb attack on Thornton convenience store</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/man-on-fire-cctv-thornton-convenience-store/106353066</link><description>A man engulfed in flames is captured on CCTV after an arson attack at a Hunter Valley business.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9ee7213df91607b954f599de33584e7</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire threatens properties in central Victoria, with rising heat to be followed by gusty storms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/fire-breaks-out-ahead-of-gusty-storms-hot-dry-victoria/106350666</link><description>The fire at Trawool, south of Seymour, broke out near the Goulburn Valley Highway in central Victoria on a day when half the state was facing extreme fire danger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">108731e08685f8af2e1bce9100ec282c</guid></item><item><title>Western Australia's demersal fishing ban hits hard in coastal tourist town of Kalbarri</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/western-australia-demersal-fishing-ban-jackie-jarvis-kalbarri/106336464</link><description>People in the coastal tourist town of Kalbarri say they are already suffering the effects of WA's demersal fishing ban, less than two months after it came into force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b2b2f7a818984b5536b032082a9b2cf</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor reveals shadow ministry, elevating Andrew Hastie and Jacinta Nampijinpa Price</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/angus-taylor-preparing-to-unveil-shadow-ministry/106354092</link><description>The new Liberal leader announces his shadow ministry, elevating prominent right-faction supporters including West Australian MP Andrew Hastie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">989975fa7a8805821e114a08b60c7715</guid></item><item><title>Traditional Lunar New Year celebrations in Sydney and Melbourne ring in Year of the Horse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/lunar-chinese-new-year-horse-celebrations/106353510</link><description>Lion dances and red packets are on display in Sydney and Melbourne, as the cities' Asian communities ring in the Year of the Horse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b52f9f4faeae127bd8080e489bd89915</guid></item><item><title>Police inspect outhouse, water tank in renewed search for Gus Lamont</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sa-police-search-outhouse-where-fresh-cement-had-been-laid/106354376</link><description>SA police have inspected an outhouse where fresh cement has recently been laid and a water tank as part of the latest search for Gus Lamont in South Australia's Mid North, with no evidence so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2f75e1d79445ecd44a2de495a7beeea</guid></item><item><title>Liam Alexander Hall revealed as man charged over alleged terrorism act at Perth Invasion Day rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/invasion-day-alleged-terror-act-liam-alexander-hall/106353674</link><description>The man accused of throwing a bomb at Invasion Day protesters in an alleged terrorism act attack in Perth can be named as Liam Alexander Hall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff6d5e6a3dd2153ca8a25dcce52fcc95</guid></item><item><title>Woman tells Queensland child safety inquiry of abuse and lack of support in state care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/child-safety-commission-hearing-in-toowoomba/106350486</link><description>A Queensland woman whose adolescence was marred by sexual abuse and exploitation has described her experiences in residential care to Queensland's Child Safety Commission of Inquiry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2411de34f907744426ba49d66cc94609</guid></item><item><title>Coles downplays meaning of 'Down Down' price tags and advertising in case against ACCC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/coles-accc-federal-court-down-down-promotion/106295044</link><description>Coles downplays what shoppers understood when they saw its "Down Down" price tags, saying "not much", on the second day of a bombshell federal court case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84bff0d113546722f611e198410a65d2</guid></item><item><title>Marquee Canterbury recruit Leo Thompson to miss 10 weeks following calf injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/leo-thompson-calf-injury-canterbury-bulldogs-update/106354494</link><description>Canterbury are dealt a hammer blow for their Las Vegas trip and beyond with prop Leo Thompson ruled out for 10 weeks due to a calf injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036cfbbaa4ce64c8f213ea7592a8ab1a</guid></item><item><title>Fire crews battle blaze south of Launceston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/bushfire-warning-for-area-south-of-launceston/106355122</link><description>The Tasmania Fire Service has downgraded an emergency bushfire warning for an area south of Launceston, with helicopters and ground crews in attendance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00134fdf7a0cde3533cca8bcab9042fa</guid></item><item><title>Balonne Shire Council faces $3.8m fine due to unauthorised fires at Dirranbandi Waste Facility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/balonne-shire-council-fine-unauthorised-dump-fires-dirranbandi/106337656</link><description>There have been several unauthorised fires lit at the waste facility of a rural Queensland council, with the Department of the Environment warning it could lead to a hefty fine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d64f0f9e1312bb5d98c6ac899038849e</guid></item><item><title>Kyneton women's football players greenlit to join Central Victorian Football League</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/kyneton-womens-football-riddell-update-central-league/106354024</link><description>A long-running saga in country women's football is set to close as a central Victorian team that had been left without a competition will now be allowed to play in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54f16d5c55e8c9bba00d01c3d6d165d3</guid></item><item><title>WAAPA buildings to be re-purposed for creative industries as part of ECU Mount Lawley redevelopment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/ecu-mount-lawley-redevelopment-masterplan-released/106354086</link><description>A "creative industries hub" and around 1,000 new homes will be built on the former Edith Cowan University (ECU) campus in Mount Lawley — but the site's makeover will take 10 to 15 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e23effbb987fb36c3584e0aaa73d1119</guid></item><item><title>Mobil Oil Australia to pay $16m fine for misleading claims about fuel sold in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/mobil-oil-australia-federal-court-fine-fuel/106354140</link><description>The ACCC said Mobil advertised its Mobil Synergy fuel but did not actually supply the product at the time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c4d1c10dddccaa2bbfc1015123368aa</guid></item><item><title>SA government open to swim safety signs at airport as foreign-born drownings increase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/airport-swim-safety-signage-foreign-born-drownings/106350030</link><description>The number of drownings in Australia has surged in recent times, but with nearly a third of victims being foreign-born, the ABC has asked if installing airport signage about the rips, waves and powerful currents at our beaches could help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c04ac5fb80c325b0992d5ba32252627</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds attend state funeral for Ted Egan, former NT administrator, folk musician and land rights champion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/ted-egan-remembered-at-nt-state-funeral-alice-springs/106353076</link><description>Hundreds of people have gathered to remember former NT administrator, musician and Indigenous land rights advocate Ted Egan, at a state funeral held in Alice Springs today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb170c9933a743e4d6d8b8f39d33f45c</guid></item><item><title>Why Brisbane's fuel prices have been cheaper than usual</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/brisbane-low-fuel-prices/106352918</link><description>A combination of economic factors means Brisbane motorists have experienced below-average fuel prices for an extended period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef48273deb7b161b6d398813e4c55c16</guid></item><item><title>French Polynesia drug haul hits $2.4 billion in a month as third shipment intercepted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/french-polynesia-third-drug-shipment-cocaine/106352864</link><description>French authorities seized a 2.4-tonne drug shipment near French Polynesia during a joint operation with the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8b05b9703fd79abe25cc2318a523413</guid></item><item><title>TAFE chief executive resigns as Charles Darwin University reveals impact of course errors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/charles-darwin-university-tafe-ceo-resigns-amid-course-errors/106352750</link><description>The number of carpentry apprentices impacted by a Charles Darwin University blunder that will force them back to school has grown to more than 130 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39a23bbabc3951d8e026f52a3505de2e</guid></item><item><title>Iran launches military drill as US deploys aircraft carrier on eve of nuclear talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/iran-us-military-drill-trump-geneva-nuclear-talks/106353940</link><description>Representatives from the two nations are set to meet in Geneva on Tuesday, local time, as US President Donald Trump tries to curb Tehran's nuclear program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94646181af842a5e1c582c59df894657</guid></item><item><title>High-pitched anti-homeless noise devices switched off and labelled 'hostile' by WA government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anti-homelessness-noise-devices-perth-bridge-removed/106354270</link><description>High-pitched noise devices installed under a bridge to deter rough sleepers are labelled "unnecessary" and "humiliating" by housing campaigners and condemned by the WA government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">735727b3767fc5e8a557f1dd188af0e9</guid></item><item><title>Internal review finds almost half of all Queensland Health doctors at risk of burnout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/queensland-health-survey-doctors-clinicians-wellbeing-burnout/106355086</link><description>More than 2,000 doctors responded to the Medical Workforce Wellbeing Survey last year, which polled the wellbeing of medical clinicians state-wide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb62a16d53c341e3190fe492799a2d17</guid></item><item><title>Australian production company Matchbox Pictures to be closed by Universal International Studios</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/matchbox-pictures-closed-universal-international-studios/106355260</link><description>Matchbox Pictures, the local production house behind Dog Park, The Survivors and Secret City, will be closed by its international parent company, Universal International Studios.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78b9d935e059c11895c3efac8807b716</guid></item><item><title>The Missing number in the hundreds of thousands in Syria, where mass graves of torture victims are found weekly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/the-missing-are-syrias-victims-of-the-assad-regime/106131984</link><description>Victims of Syria's brutal Assad regime were tortured to death in completely horrible and inhumane ways. The relatives of "The Missing" are still searching for them as their numbers continue to explode.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d2157091f7eea84ecb078810305485b</guid></item><item><title>Addin Fonua-Blake and Briton Nikora embrace chance to play State of Origin following eligibility changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/addin-fonua-blake-briton-nikora-state-of-origin/106355576</link><description>Cronulla duo Briton Nikora and Addin Fonua-Blake have both praised the rule changes that will give the pair a chance at State of Origin football they thought had long passed them by.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ec581ac1f034662bed78ff674c00b7</guid></item><item><title>Private health premiums to rise at fastest rate in almost a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/private-health-premiums-increase/106355550</link><description>Private health insurance premiums will rise at their fastest rate in almost a decade, after the federal government approved a 4.41 per cent average increase from April.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cf53e80cc9f8f5821a0c50d3aa7dd87</guid></item><item><title>Jury shown footage of alleged attack on Strathmerton postmaster John Burke</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/maskell-manslaughter-john-burke-strathmerton-service-station/106352992</link><description>A jury in the trial of Troy Maskell, accused of the manslaughter death of 73-year-old John Burke, has watched CCTV footage of the alleged incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41a1f3b7026ae81ae32623b92f63131e</guid></item><item><title>Police drop charges against WIM Resource employee accused of falsifying documents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/wim-resource-murray-wilson-fraud-charges-dropped/106355362</link><description>Victoria Police has dropped all charges against WIM Resource employee Murray Wilson, who worked on the controversial Avonbank Mineral Sands Project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e46ef3f04400c724cf57f4b12383ce25</guid></item><item><title>Mother of former Manly player Keith Titmuss breaks silence on lawsuit against NRL club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/keith-titmuss-mother-speaks-on-manly-sea-eagles-lawsuit/106354504</link><description>The mother of Manly player Keith Titmuss, who died of exertional heat stroke following a 2020 Sea Eagles training session, breaks her silence on her family's multi-million-dollar lawsuit against the NRL club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0be5af7a65024f5d1249c96c36ab639d</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested after fatal Merrylands stabbing escaped care 10 days before attack, health authorities say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/man-arrested-after-merrylands-stabbing-escaped-hospital-care/106356218</link><description>A man who was arrested after a fatal stabbing in Merrylands escaped from mental health care while being transferred between hospitals more than a week ago, health authorities say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac37a20a68838d5f1d8ead99df730433</guid></item><item><title>Father whose son died in house fire accuses lawyer at coronial inquiry of 'degrading him'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/qld-fatal-fire-inquest-father-outburst/106354862</link><description>The father, in an emotional outburst, told the inquest he had spent thousands of dollars on psychiatrist and hypnotherapy appointments so he could move on from the tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2817eed5da4210d086772b41a3286cb6</guid></item><item><title>ABC to move Adelaide office to new Tapangka site in CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/abc-adelaide-to-move-to-new-cbd-arts-hub/106355280</link><description>The ABC has announced a new location for its Adelaide operations, moving to a new arts and media hub alongside other government arts organisation in the CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304f07af147679233a1ce91d82d122b7</guid></item><item><title>Grammy-winning songwriter and hitmaker Billy Steinberg dies aged 75</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/grammy-winning-songwriter-billy-steinberg-dies-aged-75/106356348</link><description>Award-winning US songwriter Billy Steinberg, who wrote several top hit songs including Madonna's Like a Virgin, died on Monday aged 75, according to media reports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb0f5e86348cae84a5923360286fcd40</guid></item><item><title>Jail term increased for Roma man who stabbed police officer during call-out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/jail-term-increased-roma-man-stabbed-police-officer/106356242</link><description>A man who stabbed a police officer with a pair of scissors during a domestic violence call-out in regional Queensland has had his jail sentence increased.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb9dc470037d273fcec3966d6535d26a</guid></item><item><title>Live: Aerials action to kick off day 11 at Milano Cortina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/winter-olympics-day-11-live-blog/106354466</link><description>Australia's men's and women's aerials are up in qualification on day 11 at the Winter Olympics and later on, 16-year-old Ally Hickman will chase a medal in the women's slopestyle final. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05560894f8728623208d380b16b46a1a</guid></item></channel></rss>