<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 21:00:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Barbeques Galore enters receivership as debt burns into bottom line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/barbeques-galore-enters-receivership/106337962</link><description>Barbeques Galore has plunged into receivership, leaving question marks for nearly 100 stores that employ about 500 staff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69523934e505732dbc33d0c34030742d</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106337290</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d261cc973fdb20ab56fe51470b7d321c</guid></item><item><title>Gardener accused of killing Darwin mum in yard deemed 'unfit' to face trial, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/joerg-kloepper-deemed-unfit-to-stand-trial/106337636</link><description>A gardener accused of murdering a Darwin mum in her backyard in 2022 has been deemed 'unfit' to face trial. The case has been delayed while investigations into Joerg Kloepper's mental state and ability to plead were conducted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69d49df12217bf283b02e8c644cb4ffd</guid></item><item><title>Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit to implement recommendations for workplace culture overhaul</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/toowoomba-hospital-maternity-unit-workplace-culture-findings/106338238</link><description>Staff at the Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit will be implementing recommended changes to their workplace culture following an independent review.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fffb7e8031442fc89790d85b110ac64c</guid></item><item><title>Teen bounces back from nasty crash to snatch gold from American great</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/winter-olympics-2026-live-milano-cortina-cooper-woods/106338490</link><description>Two-time Winter Olympic champion Chloe Kim is pipped for first place by 17-year-old Gaon Choi late in the women's snowboard halfpipe final at the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77fd8c878e9a3a73529932cf9fb473c2</guid></item><item><title>Children prescribed puberty blockers without proper assessment at Cairns health service, review finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/qld-puberty-blockers-cairns-health-service/106336756</link><description>The review of the Cairns paediatric gender health service found that children as young as 12 were given puberty blockers inconsistently and without formal consent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">239aa031616658a4122734a07b49c2df</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor to challenge for Liberal leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/angus-taylor-to-challenge-for-liberal-leadership/106337940</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">868bbbd6de942f7fd80a9a7d018a148b</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Woods wins Australia's first gold of 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/cooper-woods-wins-winter-olympic-gold-moguls/106338772</link><description>Cooper Woods has stunned the moguls field to win a maiden career title at the 2026 Winter Olympic Games at Milano Cortina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b63e0dd3c0b2886d37f6baecb4e90bc</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Woods welcomed to the Winter Olympic 'gold medal club' by Alisa Camplin-Warner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cooper-woods-gold-medal-club-alisa-camplin/106338996</link><description>Only seven Australian athletes have ever felt the weight of a Winter Olympic gold medal being hung around their necks. And one of the first, Alisa Camplin-Warner, was thrilled to welcome the most recent, Cooper Woods, to the club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00bcbc79601b776b4d7b20f266d65169</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's border tsar Tom Homan announces ICE withdrawal from Minnesota</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/ice-withdrawal-minnesota-homan-trump-tsar/106339228</link><description>An immigration crackdown in the Midwestern state has been marred by protests and public anger after the shooting of two US citizens by federal agents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebad345af8d5ae5ca9b449aeb32b47bb</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party poised to dump first female federal leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/liberal-party-poised-to-dump-first-female-leader/106338452</link><description>The Liberal Party is poised to dump its first federal female leader, with Sussan Ley's supporters acknowledging her rival, Angus Taylor, is in the "ascendancy".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6149b17b767527046bc7170e8b43226a</guid></item><item><title>3,100 aged care patients stranded in hospitals as states again press Commonwealth for action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/aged-care-hospital-funding-bed-block/106336820</link><description>With the ink still wet on a new hospital deal, state and territory health ministers will today use a meeting with their federal counterpart to call for urgent action on stranded patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db2af93a0e38f039ffeb1e1ccf5f3042</guid></item><item><title>Water utility 'confident' Hobart drinking water is antibiotic-free after salmon disease outbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/salmon-disease-outbreak-antibiotics-river-derwent/106330724</link><description>Tasmania's water provider says there is no risk of antibiotics entering Hobart's water supply, following Huon Aquaculture's use of oxytetracycline in the River Derwent to treat a disease outbreak.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1dee99594bcccdd9569ae25d5806d21</guid></item><item><title>Italy wins first T20 Cricket World Cup match as Australian-born players shine in 10-wicket win over Nepal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/italy-wins-first-t20-cricket-world-cup-match/106339406</link><description>Sydney-born brothers Justin and Anthony Mosca have guided T20 World Cup debutants Italy to their first win in the tournament, as their unbeaten half-centuries secured a dominant 10-wicket victory over Nepal on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3c6d0fe17105b65b0990f4c481c3845</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Woods, Australia's unexpected Winter Olympic champion, finds his purpose</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cooper-woods-australias-unexpected-champion-winter-olympics/106339106</link><description>Cooper Woods came into the 2026 Winter Olympic Games ranked 22nd in the World Cup rankings in moguls. But in finding his purpose, he roared to a glorious gold medal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ca54a379cdb065db55986946103d8e3</guid></item><item><title>ASX boss to depart as another controversy unfolds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/asx-boss-to-depart-as-another-controversy-unfolds/106336322</link><description>A decade of technology failures, unplanned outages, management upheaval, irate investors and the torching of hundreds of millions of dollars has left the ASX's reputation in shreds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d1cb6399c00e87f8a119dacdf9976aa</guid></item><item><title>Epstein survivor says release of files was 're-traumatising' and falls short of transparency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/epstein-survivor-says-release-of-files-retraumatising/106317616</link><description>Lisa Phillips says the publication of the "Epstein" files was meant to deliver long-promised transparency but has instead exposed victims, deepened trauma and continued to shield powerful men.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">702d35e388b86c7214a684bca057a62f</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor is the new leader of the Liberal Party. Who is he?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/who-is-liberal-party-leader-hopeful-angus-taylor/105268090</link><description>After months of speculation, Liberals hope Angus Taylor can bring the Liberals back from what many in the party fear is the edge of obscurity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da8415b8432271ddc8217b42ad3a877c</guid></item><item><title>Economist Bruce Preston appointed to RBA Board</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/economist-bruce-preston-appointed-to-rba-board/106337708</link><description>The economics professor is the second academic economist added to the board since a review recommended boosting its expertise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c0edb3495c53e1eb1dd6f353acd5bef</guid></item><item><title>The Christchurch terrorist changed New Zealand, now he is testing its legal system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/christchurch-terrorst-testing-nz-legal-system/106336320</link><description>It may be months before New Zealand finds out if the Christchurch terrorist will be granted an application to have his guilty pleas vacated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ffbd3cb1612c1e71fa5e4924f4f9071</guid></item><item><title>More than 100 Stolen Generations survivors gather for apology anniversary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/largest-gathering-of-stolen-generations-survivors-for-apology/106322950</link><description>More than 100 Stolen Generations survivors have gathered in Canberra for the apology anniversary. The government is pledging new money to help them heal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c81bef72da28cb61fb66cddb9bf13666</guid></item><item><title>Marine biologists fight to save endangered seagrass species in Sydney Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/science-key-to-saving-endangered-seagrass-population/106337120</link><description>A centuries-old nautical technique is being redesigned within a small Sydney cove in a bid to save a tiny remnant population of a dying species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c23125b58cdf591c3340528784e5fcd</guid></item><item><title>The 'farm-fluencers' taking agriculture online to bridge the rural divide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/farmer-influencers-sharing-rural-lives-online-content-creators/106326048</link><description>Farmers and agricultural workers are taking to social media to educate a new audience while building a community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed4626a80b6a8b07114590acfaf1a595</guid></item><item><title>Cost-of-living crisis sees more young women neglecting health and basic needs, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/young-women-cost-of-living-crisis-basic-needs/106300314</link><description>A study from Deakin University has found many young women admit skipping meals or forgoing medical attention to save money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5cd45054bcabb5c8fa618e72defa4a5</guid></item><item><title>Openly gay men in elite sport are rare, leaving women to lead the way for queer inclusion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/queer-lgbtiqa-inclusion-womens-sport-anneli-maley-wnbl-pride-cup/106149906</link><description>While high profile instances of homophobia in elite men's sport continue, leading female athletes are hoping to help create more inclusive spaces for all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70321d6613ab8607cbaea120ca706e88</guid></item><item><title>Consumers back call for country-of-origin labels on timber sold in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/calls-for-timber-wood-product-country-origin-labels/106335698</link><description>Consumer advocates and the wood products industry say it is time the origin of timber was made clear, as imports grow year-on-year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e45cbaa92971f939d0856d9c106483b</guid></item><item><title>What a 566yo coolabah tree in the Gwydir Wetlands could tell us about climate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/gwydir-wetlands-566-year-old-coolabah-tree-climate-history/106325412</link><description>New research shows some of the coolabahs and river red gums in the Gwydir Wetlands, New South Wales are hundreds of years old, and hold important climate history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a88c850ac8f236466b63627c9ffafc9e</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley to quit politics after losing spill, setting up by-election — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/federal-politics-live-blog-liberal-spill/106339480</link><description>Sussan Ley announces she will quit the parliament after losing her leadership to Angus Taylor, setting up a by-election in her seat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e54c956be73e4b8996ca621b91910220</guid></item><item><title>NT Australian of the Year Felix Ho volunteers thousands of hours to the community each year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/nt-australian-of-year-dr-felix-ho-thousands-of-volunteer-hours/106329556</link><description>Finding time to volunteer can be a stretch for most people, but for Darwin doctor Felix Ho, who volunteers thousands of hours every year, it's his "full-time hobby".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b99c4561a769bc93eea33549024a298</guid></item><item><title>Share market tumbles on 'traditional Friday 13 meltdown' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/asx-markets-business-live-news-feb-13-2026/106339608</link><description>Market analysts have blamed a share market sell-off on an increasing trend that is resulting in heavy stock selling as investors fear a meltdown on Wall Street's last day of trade for the week. Look back on the day's business developments in our blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18fef90dc73d15c4a2fdb264a54d455d</guid></item><item><title>Thai raid finds Cambodian scam centre had personal details of 300 Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/australians-targeted-by-cambodian-scam-compound/106335866</link><description>Australia's National Anti-Scam Centre says documents seized in a raid on a Cambodian scam compound contained the phone numbers, names and addresses of 300 Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08f7a75e42a1578ec6ae98632dc8210b</guid></item><item><title>From new life to grief, Ella Macens's music for the Melbourne Symphony Orchestra is rooted in love</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/music-by-australian-ella-macens-premiered-by-melbourne-symphony/106323262</link><description>After experiencing the Bondi terror attack in December, this composer's new music grew to encompass love's power to heal us from hate and harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bbfdad77654f3b7445bd689a1085326</guid></item><item><title>The key factor that will define your NRL team's chances in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/2026-nrl-season-preview-key-stats/106334724</link><description>With the preseason challenge well underway and the season-opening matches in Las Vegas on the horizon, find out the key numbers that will make or break your team's NRL chances for 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdbd63c61f95bb7099a8f344adfd200e</guid></item><item><title>Trump repeals power to fight climate change, axes vehicle emissions rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/trump-revokes-basis-of-us-climate-regulation-ends-vehicle-emissi/106339598</link><description>President Donald Trump's administration has revoked a scientific determination that has been the central basis for US action to fight climate change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14587c3b8bd37c5943c0d33c136fd2f9</guid></item><item><title>Keen to declutter this year? Here's how to start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/simple-ways-to-start-decluttering-at-home/106300708</link><description>Experts say you don't need to pull out the entire contents of a cupboard, beginning with one bag is best.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a8e041b72c037976f8eb5cb64a4f2a3</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor becomes Liberal leader after defeating Sussan Ley 34–17</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/angus-taylor-becomes-liberal-leader/106339798</link><description>Sussan Ley, the first female leader of the Liberal Party, is set to quit politics after losing a leadership vote today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fa7d372d6cff076b3d6fe902ba524d0</guid></item><item><title>Former Tottenham manager Ange Postecoglou says Spurs 'not a big club' in wake of Thomas Frank sacking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/former-tottenham-manager-ange-postecoglou-on-club-issues/106339490</link><description>Tottenham Hotspur are "not a big club" because of their policy in the transfer market, former manager Ange Postecoglou has said in the wake of the London club's sacking of head coach Thomas Frank on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ce56a4955c12cf141f86e6540834b3a</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Woods' mum reacts after stunning gold medal win in Men’'s Moguls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cooper-woods-mum-reacts-after-stunning-gold-medal-win-/106339924</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9330246f2d9b13f2b20e5765e9270dc4</guid></item><item><title>Norway's former PM, Thorbjoern Jagland, accused of aggravated corruption over Epstein links</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/norway-former-prime-minister-ties-with-jeffrey-epstein/106339852</link><description>The files indicate that Thorbjoern Jagland and Jeffrey Epstein's assistants made detailed plans in 2014 for the politician to visit the American in Palm Beach, Florida.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3b70dba55d4ba770182042e51ba2176</guid></item><item><title>Albany Woollen Mills' 101 years celebrated via shared love of blankets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/albany-woollen-mill-in-albany-celebrates-101-years/106322356</link><description>Established in 1925, Western Australia's first and only woollen mill transformed raw wool into fabric and blankets, becoming a cornerstone of Albany's industry before closing in 2002.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebfd4b3313c5a634d2a8d4ee911573eb</guid></item><item><title>Record-breaking heatwave leaves some flower farmers without Valentine's Day blooms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/flower-farmers-heatwave-victoria-losses-valentines-day/106329998</link><description>A record heatwave has destroyed a Mallee flower farm's Valentine's Day blooms, leaving its owner devastated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7db6c60336395b1e9aea3e528a183bc7</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Australian snowboard cross riders struggle after Cam Bolton's injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/winter-olympics-snowboard-cross-emotional-toll-cam-bolton/106338726</link><description>Cam Bolton's broken neck hangs heavily over the Australian snowboard cross team, with his late replacement Jimmy Johnstone vowing his appearance was "all for him".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">108a118275afba78a9d56fcdc5b77bdd</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs woman survives 12-hour flood ordeal on Todd River</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/alice-springs-todd-river-flood-rescue/106338710</link><description>When her mother was swept into the flooding Todd River this week, Alice Springs woman Latarne Wayne went in after her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a0d92e3f4e0d139f91767b2f3eb420c</guid></item><item><title>It took 80 years for a woman to become Liberal leader, and 9 months to ditch her</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/sussan-ley-s-time-as-liberal-leader/106045934</link><description>Sussan Ley vowed to be a different opposition leader, one who consulted widely and listened to her broad church. But it left many wondering what, if anything, she stood for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05d0ee7f0ef658ce063e5a98c8024ae7</guid></item><item><title>Organisations branch out to help men's mental health in regional NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/organisations-branch-out-help-mens-mental-health-rural-nsw/106332542</link><description>Keith Cowen was alone on his farm in regional NSW when he had a heart attack. It made him realise how much he needed mates around him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f33d23d5d6f337a5fe04f7b32b849b2f</guid></item><item><title>Ley leaves Taylor an immediate electoral test with Farrer by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/farrer-byelection-sussan-ley-angus-taylor/106341236</link><description>Within two hours of being elected Liberal leader, Angus Taylor has already been delivered his first big electoral test, and it has come from the woman he deposed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a9957d8828440921d19f5f6180a2356</guid></item><item><title>Adolescence writer Jack Thorne on his new TV adaptation of castaway novel Lord of the Flies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/lord-of-the-flies-tv-show-jack-thorne-adolescence/106295874</link><description>After winning an Emmy for writing Adolescence, Jack Thorne's latest project, a TV adaptation of Lord of the Flies, also sits at the intersection of vulnerability, masculinity and violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd85640874e64ee279c21abb06ec290e</guid></item><item><title>Bangladesh Nationalist Party wins nation's first election since gen Z-led uprising toppled Sheikh Hasina</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/bangladesh-nationalist-party-wins-first-election-since-uprising/106338732</link><description>The Bangladesh Nationalist Party has won a landmark parliamentary election, according to local TV stations, securing a resounding mandate in a pivotal vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cecba2d45ea708381aa812a501c1d47</guid></item><item><title>Katie Holmes pays tribute to Dawson's Creek co-star James Van Der Beek in handwritten letter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/katie-holmes-pays-tribute-to-james-van-der-beek/106340686</link><description>In a handwritten letter posted to social media, actor Katie Holmes has paid tribute to her Dawson's Creek co-star James Van Der Beek, who has died. He was 48.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a28511573104b49c927e99586c21dea6</guid></item><item><title>Scotty James's snowboard halfpipe gold medal hopes in judges' hands at Milano Cortina Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/snowboard-halfpipe-judging-2026-winter-olympics/106333290</link><description>Scotty James is about to face the biggest competition of his life — so what will he need to do to impress those who will decide his Olympic fate?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e9a8c5e104a8050ed2a66b0efe0a3e1</guid></item><item><title>AFL Origin 2026: Are footy fans still keen on interstate football?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/afl-origin-2026-history-of-interstate-football-state-of-origin/106341464</link><description>After a break of more than a quarter of a century, AFL State of Origin returns in Perth tomorrow with a battle between two proud football states, Western Australia and Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ac0aaab0d5f3f7f1e75b164d08b3c0e</guid></item><item><title>Bald Archy satirical art prize highlights political victories, a murder trial and protest movements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/bald-archy-prize-reveals-politics-crime-and-bob-irwin/106340644</link><description>From the trial of Erin Patterson to the landslide election victory, 2025 is pilloried in this year's satirical art prize, the Bald Archy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e360d2786aee3a4fd31acfa42d11981</guid></item><item><title>Maugean skate's endangered status not changing, Environment Minister Murray Watt says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/maugean-skate-endangered-listing-not-changing-murray-watt-says/106342278</link><description>Environment Minister Murray Watt says his decision to keep the status of a rare Tasmanian skate species as endangered rather than change it to critically endangered is based on scientific advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e900785b0c8d8f08f1f99a4eaf01e576</guid></item><item><title>Kitchen hand charged with attempted murder, stalking over alleged stabbing at Brisbane leagues club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/stabbing-charge-easts-leagues-club-coorparoo/106341498</link><description>Cameron William Leslie Clark, 33, remains in hospital after the alleged incident at Easts Leagues Club in the inner-city Brisbane suburb of Coorparoo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55690bfd7d349d8f65709a25ca26e37d</guid></item><item><title>Drug vessel MV Raider heading towards Sydney after being stripped of cocaine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/drug-vessel-mv-raider-sydney-bound-after-cocaine-seized/106337382</link><description>A ship caught carrying five tonnes of cocaine is making its way towards Sydney after being stripped of its cargo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62c02ce422ef3bc47452cda0114ef3d5</guid></item><item><title>Detective Inspector Donna Hoffmeier talks about a homemade explosive device found detonated in south Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/detonated-homemade-explosive-found-on-oval-in-south-canberra/106342084</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">818d0aa6cc06c931938555e4dfaf1fa5</guid></item><item><title>Flower industry peak body pushes for country of origin labelling amid Valentine's Day rush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/flower-industry-peak-body-seeks-country-of-origin-labelling/106340602</link><description>Millions of red roses will fly off florists' shelves this weekend, but the flower industry says there is not much to tell customers where the flowers are from.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85ad6e4fc8075f48a7b72dcf0b7c7234</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley to quit politics after losing Liberal leadership spill.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/sussan-ley-quits-politics-after-losing-leadership-spill-/106341296</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">489da7b06a51dd2c888d653c7a1a0ef8</guid></item><item><title>To survive, Angus Taylor's Liberals must now get over their self-obsession</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/angus-taylor-liberal-leadership-change-self-obsession/106339870</link><description>By its new leader Angus Taylor's own admission, the Liberal Party is running out of time to pull out of the nosedive that has it heading towards oblivion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6deaa2b7ef412fd41ea270749ef71894</guid></item><item><title>Sunshine Coast environmentalists outraged by Comiskey Group Coochin Creek site approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/environmentalists-oppose-comiskey-group-coochin-creek-sites/106342062</link><description>The Queensland government has approved a massive music festival and event site despite environmentalists saying it's "disgraceful" to put tourism before sustainability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">513c3220a4dbf0da3778dbee7016daee</guid></item><item><title>Australia in danger of World Cup elimination after 'unbelievable' loss to Zimbabwe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cricket-australia-zimbabwe-t20-world-cup-live-blog-scores/106327068</link><description>Australia's hopes of advancing out of Group B are dealt an almighty blow as Zimbabwe claims one of the biggest upset wins in T20 World Cup history in Colombo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">476ca6531e7d6c07f466b52971129dba</guid></item><item><title>How do you find modern dating? Share your highs and lows with us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/audience-callout-modern-dating-love-stories/106287262</link><description>Whether you've shed tears of joy, sadness or even laughter in the process, we want to hear it all — but keep it under 150 words.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e85c8d73dd7cdf15e05f480eb2c663e8</guid></item><item><title>Support for all-ages performances among changes proposed for NSW's live music scene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/changes-proposed-for-nsw-live-music-industry/106342426</link><description>The state government introduces what it describes as a "world first" bill to support the live music scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f2148b3c35f403dc6e9467efc37b781</guid></item><item><title>Out of 38,000 people fined for non-voting in NT local government elections just 3 per cent have paid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/-38-000-fined-for-non-voting-in-the-nt-3-per-cent-have-paid/106342158</link><description>Just 3 per cent of voters fined for not voting in last year’s Northern Territory local government elections have paid the penalty. Debate is growing over whether the system is working — or unfair to voters in remote areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7e516b49aab0aa22c5101d34c71fe0d</guid></item><item><title>Tim Picton's accused killer Brodie Dewar says Labor identity made unwanted advances on cousin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/tim-picton-accused-killer-brodie-dewar-paramount-nightclub-/106340252</link><description>A man who allegedly killed Tim Picton in a one-punch attack outside a Perth nightclub claims the Labor identity had repeatedly approached his female cousin before being escorted out of the venue because he was intoxicated, a Perth court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83536e93561ec71286007899af12d406</guid></item><item><title>Sydney children's author Oliver Phommavanh jailed for sending sexually explicit messages to minors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/childrens-author-oliver-phommavanh-jailed-for-grooming-minors/106342160</link><description>Oliver Phommavanh is sentenced to six-and-a-half years in prison with a non-parole period of four years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c59431758c6b35c4dc27a1b4299ab7a8</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106342580</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76c17c42326e19ea7822ebf9dbd9ff19</guid></item><item><title>Tony Abbott says Australia is Judaeo-Christian but warns Angus Taylor about being One Nation-lite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/tony-abbott-on-angus-taylor-one-nation-immigration-assimilation/106342458</link><description>As Angus Taylor takes the Liberal leadership via a spill motion, a former leader with plenty of experience offers up some advice on dealing with One Nation and immigration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b9b39f5ae9e1a7e6d5811e0c79cc190</guid></item><item><title>Gold and silver added to Aussie tally on thrilling day of Winter Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/winter-olympics-2026-live-milano-cortina-scotty-james/106340876</link><description>Josie Baff stormed to a famous gold medal in the women's snowboard cross, as Scotty James narrowly missed out in the men's halfpipe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4daa0023116b48b35965b2688e4f5173</guid></item><item><title>Coroner finds police tactic not the cause of Toowoomba Indigenous man's death in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/steven-nixon-mckellar-coronial-findings-death-in-custody/106343656</link><description>A Queensland coroner finds the cause of Indigenous man Steven Nixon-McKellar's death during an arrest was "multi-factorial".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7cece3525e620fdc4a4921898494d2a</guid></item><item><title>SpaceX launches new crew to International Space Station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/new-crew-launch-towards-international-space-tation/106343980</link><description>The US, French and Russian astronauts are expected to complete the mission in eight to nine months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0a6a4db3cafb9ff7c38ec675923180f</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Josie Baff claims Australia's second gold with stunning snowboard cross triumph</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/josie-baff-wins-winter-olympics-gold-australia/106343706</link><description>Josie Baff has become Australia's second gold medallist at the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics, claiming victory in the women's snowboard cross.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f7032bae169f89a7f2c743d729ef218</guid></item><item><title>Ley didn't define herself by her gender but women might relate to her workplace woes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/liberal-party-women-sussan-ley-leadership-spill/106340280</link><description>The issue for the Liberal Party is not simply the toppling of a female leader. It's also about what happened to that leader while she was in the job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">596c3a295f267e6667ca697953519fbd</guid></item><item><title>From Japan to Israel, elections are reshaping global politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/elections-japan-israel-ukraine-global-politics-trump/106337028</link><description>At a time when so much of the global conversation is about the rapid decline of democracy, it is striking what a huge impact elections are having on world events just now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bcebe10dbbdf738fed5ebfaac390428</guid></item><item><title>Josie Baff wins 2026 Winter Olympic gold, a testament to the power of self-belief</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/josie-baff-winter-olympics-snowboard-cross-gold-belief/106344394</link><description>Self-belief is the most powerful tool at an athlete's disposal, and Josie Baff utilised it to its fullest extent with a magical run to gold in the 2026 Winter Olympics snowboard cross.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">416a081074ebb50e93862255aaeab98d</guid></item><item><title>Here's what we know about Angus Taylor's policies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/what-we-know-about-angus-taylor-policies/106342170</link><description>The new Liberal leader has signalled he will pursue a stricter immigration policy and a return to "Australian values" in his first pitch to win back voters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed198d16c5a3341a76e01f9075ac1b0f</guid></item><item><title>Michael Mohammed Ahmad confronts traumatic childhood abuse in his new novel, Bugger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/michael-mohammed-ahmad-new-book-bugger/106331764</link><description>Michael Mohammed Ahmad, author of The Lebs, marks turning 40 with the publication of his most confronting novel yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a057fc717dc6c9c31f1c40b18e69a8e</guid></item><item><title>The very unusual factor in the Nancy Guthrie missing person case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/the-very-unusual-factor-in-the-nancy-guthrie-case/106333408</link><description>What initially seemed like a high-profile kidnapping that might be resolved with a multi-million-dollar bank transfer has now morphed into something else.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">222ae663ab434f1882ae7341a539cce3</guid></item><item><title>Latest Jeffrey Epstein documents reveal his deep ties to the entertainment world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/entertainment-celebrities-in-epstein-files/106317858</link><description>Some of the celebrities mentioned maintained friendships with Epstein even after his 2008 conviction for soliciting underage sex.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f9f190f049d08f567a5d801c809362e</guid></item><item><title>Courtney's doctor operated seven times to treat severe endometriosis experts say she didn't have</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/patients-endometriosis-surgery-by-simon-gordon-unnecessary-/106330214</link><description>Pathology from Courtney's seven surgeries with Dr Simon Gordon repeatedly showed no signs of endometriosis. The surgeries left her medically infertile.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90601ca8df1941d7b839eb10b0d9c070</guid></item><item><title>Residents in conservative Farrer eye future without Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/farrer-constituents-react-sussan-ley-resignation/106341264</link><description>Just minutes after deposed Liberal leader Sussan Ley announced her resignation, constituents in her electorate of Farrer began murmuring about change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fb441729e4c0e9cf72189a9fbcbb0fd</guid></item><item><title>The Allan government is under fire over corruption, but the premier is sticking to her guns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/cfmeu-labor-jacinta-allan-politics-analysis/106335648</link><description>Pressure is mounting on Premier Jacinta Allan, as she challenges claims that billions in taxpayer dollars were funnelled to criminals via the CFMEU under her watch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">609e26a14dab2997ed20b25f562d0259</guid></item><item><title>Scotty James wins silver medal in snowboard halfpipe at 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/scotty-james-snowboard-halfpipe-2026-winter-olympics/106343718</link><description>Scotty James has fallen short of an elusive Olympic gold, instead claiming a second silver medal in the snowboard halfpipe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65e53752a406915b71a1222aadf23263</guid></item><item><title>DNA genealogy is changing the way NSW Police investigate cold cases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/geneology-dna-websites-assist-cold-case-crime-investigations/106335552</link><description>Australians looking to learn more about their heritage through commercial ancestry websites could be helping police solve cold cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">497e17634b523aaf832fdd8eb43431d8</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm accused by Parramatta Eels of asking NRL to intervene in Zac Lomax contract saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/nrl-zac-lomax-storm-eels-court-battle/106344514</link><description>Melbourne has been accused of asking NRL chief executive Andrew Abdo to "apply a blowtorch" to Parramatta as part of a desperate bid to sign Zac Lomax to the Storm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd8ae2aedf1ce47d254962dc1ec3d13c</guid></item><item><title>NSW Waratahs defeat Queensland Reds 36-12 in opening round of Super Rugby Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/nsw-waratahs-defeat-queensland-reds-super-rugby-pacific/106340136</link><description>The NSW Waratahs are in celebration mode after breaking the shackles to open the Super Rugby Pacific season with a rousing 36-12 derby win over the Queensland Reds in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88c0ddda0aba1b94926b4769e6f967a4</guid></item><item><title>Musical Matches: Harpist Emily Granger and composer Tristan Coelho</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/musical-matches-harpist-emily-granger-composer-tristan-coelho/106343946</link><description>For Valentine's Day, this Australian composer wrote his wife a harp concerto. She's about to premiere it with the Queensland Symphony Orchestra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbefcaa905952815c641d386942fa2af</guid></item><item><title>Sturla Holm Lægreid's well-intentioned display left a prince looking froggy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/sturla-holm-laegreid-winter-olympics-confession/106337204</link><description>It was a new high, or low, in performative relationship management for a generation who believe a flipped screen and a full-face confession of "accountability" can solve any problem.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e325181ff4b846c2d575b4f6f1a09da</guid></item><item><title>GPS collars, camera traps to see if foxes are swimming into Booderee National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/fox-research-in-booderee-uses-gps-and-dna-testing/106145948</link><description>Camera traps, GPS collars and DNA testing are being used on foxes at Booderee National Park as efforts to control the pests intensify.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7073be4abb9810854ed3c8db8cb9ebff</guid></item><item><title>Illegal tyre dump near Townsville</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/illegal-tyre-dump-near-townsville/106321156</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14f2afdb70e9bc6bec783ddedfe81c48</guid></item><item><title>What chickens can teach us about socialising.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/what-chickens-can-teach-us-about-socialising/106310344</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2649f1ee118f6ad2700c1b6be9107f2c</guid></item><item><title>Chickens help autistic teen Summer Farrelly make sense of humans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/chickens-help-summer-farrelly-understand-humans-autism-book/106308084</link><description>While growing up, people didn't make much sense to Summer, but chickens always did. Now, Summer is using what they learnt to help other children with autism understand human interactions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69b349a86894794e632c23899a5e2185</guid></item><item><title>Man, 18, in custody over alleged carjacking attempt in Hobart CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/man-18-in-custody-over-alleged-carjacking-in-hobart-cbd/106344636</link><description>An 18-year-old man who allegedly used a screwdriver in an attempt to carjack a car with a woman and her two children inside in the middle of Hobart was overpowered by onlookers, Tasmania Police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdb1d41b8c36f54fd14019086a627874</guid></item><item><title>How Indonesians are fighting plummeting marriage rates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/indonesian-marriage-rate-plummets-despite-demand/106334832</link><description>Marriage is still a life goal in Indonesia, but the number of marriages has plummeted over the past decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf7f86f3eb467573433dccaf9d647ae0</guid></item><item><title>Ad for decimal currency 1966</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/ad-for-decimal-currency-1966/106343402</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2c162c024ca73f593cd3e2be5284d4b</guid></item><item><title>Parents fail to return consent forms as Far North Queensland HPV vaccination rate drops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/hpv-school-vaccination-rates-fall-far-north-qld/106341850</link><description>Cairns Public Health Unit says students are increasingly missing their school HPV vaccinations because they do not have parental consent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">692f4f5d7a21816cb5d9023a61a3d590</guid></item><item><title>Ready-to-go breakfast sandwiches that will get you through the day - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/omelette-breakfast-sandwiches-for-suhoor/106327796</link><description>Want a prepped breakfast with plenty of protein? These omelette sandwiches keep for three days in the fridge, ready to pop in a sandwich press in the morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd7793f3c6483227561611b8108abfc6</guid></item><item><title>Solo diver recounts brush with mako sharks off Tasmanian coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/diver-recounts-experience-with-mako-sharks-pulfers-reef/106307276</link><description>Phillip Ellis Wells was solo diving roughly 7 kilometres off the east coast of Tasmania when he noticed a shadow pass overhead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bf60fbc295b53fac0d5390d1a2f6c7f</guid></item><item><title>Innovative cattle loading ramp puts animal welfare at centre of design</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/wide-cattle-loading-ramp-reduces-transport-stress/106305408</link><description>A retired truck driver has developed a wide, steel, cattle-loading ramp that allows animals to walk side by side, mimicking natural herd behaviour and reducing noise, agitation and the risk of injury during transport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae83b1c62371e347cfe86622f6a1efe5</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Injured Australians return home from Games, skating union defends controversial scoring — quick hits from day seven</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/sport-winter-olympics-day-seven-australia-injury-skating-judges/106344140</link><description>A petition to investigate the judging of the ice dance competition has been dismissed by the sport's governing body, as two injured Australians are forced home from the Games. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99d7941e7445155e3d607955e0214b29</guid></item><item><title>Scotty James left numb by the tragedy of 'almost' at 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/scotty-james-silver-2026-milano-cortina-winter-olympics/106344652</link><description>Scotty James has sought what resides at the end of the Olympic rainbow his whole career. But for the third time, he's had to settle for the numbing pain of almost being an Olympic champion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b9d2b4c351a9eac108e331cfff92101</guid></item><item><title>Jane Hume was punished for her election slips. Now she's been crowned deputy Liberal leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/who-is-jane-hume-the-new-liberal-deputy/106340342</link><description>The Victorian senator was unceremoniously turfed from Sussan Ley's ministry after being tarred personally with much of what went wrong in the Coalition's cataclysmic loss. On Friday, she ascended to the Liberal's second-in-command.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad7db387c85c1a7f0bbbd2e940f1ffa9</guid></item><item><title>Heat of summers gone by still fresh in the memory of 98yo Clarence 'Clack' John</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/clarence-clack-john-renmark-summer-heat-history-climate-change/106292966</link><description>Clarence "Clack" John has been through 98 summers in Renmark, South Australia. But as the town sweltered through its hottest recorded day last month, he remembers hot weather before records began.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69efc479fca218e7d45b431dfe41ad19</guid></item><item><title>ECU opens in Perth CBD, with WA Academy of Performing Arts as its centrepiece</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/ecu-opens-first-university-in-perth-cbd/106341816</link><description>Thousands of students will inject vibrancy and life into Perth's CBD with the opening of the new Edith Cowan University. But how will the city cope with influx of people?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">deda1ef8e54b8ed26a19399a19941acd</guid></item><item><title>Police appeal for help after 'priceless' Egyptian artefacts stolen from Caboolture museum north of Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/caboolture-museum-egyptian-artefacts-stolen/106344626</link><description>An ancient burial mask, cat figurine and jewellery are among the "priceless" Egyptian artefacts stolen from the Abbey Museum of Art and Archaeology yesterday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21fe33170f6143c51214679bafe3258e</guid></item><item><title>Australia and EU set to ink landmark free trade agreement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/australia-and-eu-sign-landmark-free-trade-agreement/106344826</link><description>Australia and the European Union are on the cusp of finally reaching a free trade agreement after years of sometimes fraught negotiations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2f93e456b2c17b3158f607d7dd04dcb</guid></item><item><title>Broome man had to wait for someone to die to access dialysis in his hometown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/kimberley-dialysis-crisis-patient-stranded-perth/106327570</link><description>Kimberley resident David Lawford had to wait in Perth until someone in his hometown died before he could get access to dialysis on his return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8a4c51d77f29ef59bb0c8465327154d</guid></item><item><title>Roads, homes, cars damaged as Alice Springs starts flash flood clean-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/alice-springs-flood-warning-cancelled-clean-up-underway/106343242</link><description>With Alice Springs homes, businesses and roads damaged by flash flooding this week, the government is facing pressure to improve local flood mitigation measures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9e006b90247c86d9b81b9b2c0f9e819</guid></item><item><title>Former AFL captain Dyson Heppell speaks about unhealthy relationship with food during playing career</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/former-afl-captain-dyson-heppell-disordered-eating/106344044</link><description>Former Essendon captain Dyson Heppell has spoken about the unhealthy relationship he had with food early in his career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1c46dc0b0fdb0805ca8c10bdd23d02e</guid></item><item><title>Pair who plotted Islamic State-inspired attack on Jews in UK jailed for life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/men-who-plotted-gun-attack-on-uk-jews-jailed-for-life/106344876</link><description>A UK court jails two men for life for planning an Islamic State-inspired gun attack on a Jewish gathering in northern England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad2e618d32a162c0728475a8968813c3</guid></item><item><title>Cam Bolton sent message of support to Josie Baff before she won gold at the 2026 Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/cam-bolton-josie-baff-2026-winter-olympic-games-message/106344458</link><description>The injury-ravaged Australian snowboard cross team earned an enormous boost with Josie Baff's Winter Olympic gold medal, with injured teammate Cam Bolton urging his teammate to keep the faith.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c04f348253a32f6e427f09f7e84714aa</guid></item><item><title>Valentino Guseli thought he saw an 'omen from the shred gods' during the 2026 Winter Olympics halfpipe final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/valentino-guseli-shred-gods-scotty-james-olympics/106344742</link><description>As Valentino Guseli watched his teammate Scotty James "tearing" the halfpipe apart, he thought an "omen from the shred gods" would deliver him an elusive Olympic gold medal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2615b781a8e9d50765e8888e1bbcaa7</guid></item><item><title>Wool price jumps ahead of industry-first Chinese New Year break</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/wool-price-rising-ahead-of-chinese-new-year-break/106339658</link><description>As wool growers enjoy their best prices since 2019, the market will now pause to respect China's request for a week off to celebrate Lunar New Year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62ad96df10ee1750f91b3b33f2f16b56</guid></item><item><title>New Liberal leader Angus Taylor says he wants to focus on housing affordability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/angus-taylor-housing-affordability-cost-of-living/106344998</link><description>New Liberal Party leader Angus Taylor says restoring voter confidence in the Liberal party will be challenging.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9973fffb17dd8a6414f3d3b92d14ac5</guid></item><item><title>Major construction starts on Adelaide's first skyscraper Festival Tower Two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/major-construction-starts-on-adelaide-skyscraper-festival-tower/106345112</link><description>Festival Tower Two is set to tower over South Australia's Parliament House, which the premier says will bring money and people into the city, but others remain against the $800 million project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3de9dd2f69ba1ba4dfe31d2b03269b73</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds hit New South Wales beach for Valentine's Day Pride Paddle out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/pride-paddle-out-attempts-to-break-world-record-port-macquarie/106345156</link><description>Disability groups, nippers and members of the LGBTQIA+ community are among thousands celebrating love and inclusion on Aussie beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6dd63d46b008505f3e4dafcd11cdffc</guid></item><item><title>US police set up roadblock in Arizona in search for Nancy Guthrie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/us-police-set-up-roadblock-in-arizona/106345442</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf3ed932847a0b42123fbd873e967f76</guid></item><item><title>Carlton star taken to hospital as Victoria holds off WA in AFL Origin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/afl-state-of-origin-wa-victoria-live-blog/106345370</link><description>Victoria holds off a spirited WA side to win the first Aussie rules State of Origin clash for 27 years, though the game is marred by a serious injury to Carlton star Jacob Weitering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">654d718df060bf5c09e6ff92eed7385c</guid></item><item><title>Laura Peel's Olympic journey ends before even stepping onto snow at 2026 Milano Cortina Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/laura-peel-milano-cortina-2026-winter-olympics-injury/106302402</link><description>Instead of the glint of gold, Laura Peel's lasting Olympic memory will be the glittering diamonds of despair in Zhangjiakou, with the 36-year-old ruled out of the 2026 Winter Olympics in Milano Cortina after suffering a knee injury on the eve of the Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3140d1283fc197f70e6fa234813f8fe</guid></item><item><title>Jakara Anthony wins dual moguls gold at 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-jakara-anthony-gold/106345576</link><description>Jakara Anthony achieves Winter Olympic redemption, claiming a stunning gold medal in the women's dual moguls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff9575e19683a16ded7e383fad0b9232</guid></item><item><title>Taylor faces formidable task rebuilding Liberals' electoral fortunes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/angus-taylor-faces-big-task-rebuilding-liberal-electoral-fortune/106337012</link><description>The paralysing uncertainty that weighed on the Liberals' faces has lifted for now, but morale in politics follows results rather than reshuffles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faa611ea05322062dacd66ef69db7e11</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Think you know the answers? That confidence won't last long</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106298688</link><description>I admire your courage for giving the quiz another go. Just kidding, I never feel that way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">678c4063da9fed065dd80b3c61605c60</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Jakara Anthony responds to adversity and delivers a golden reply she sorely deserved</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/jakara-anthony-dual-moguls-gold-winter-olympics-adversity/106345850</link><description>Jakara Anthony stared down adversity, swallowed back her pain, and delivered a performance for the ages to become Australia's greatest Winter Olympian.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c1f5e61f8f54a8f772ce615bad28c1c</guid></item><item><title>What we know (and don't) about One Nation's rapid rise in the polls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/story-lab-one-nation-polling/106322978</link><description>Pauline Hanson's One Nation has seen the fastest polling rise in modern Australian politics. What is going on?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9026b02ac3a42175a15e4a5cfec77565</guid></item><item><title>Sophie Hyde’s dad came out when she was a baby. It shaped three generations.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/sophie-hyde-on-au/106331496</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca1fb452419ef69e21e13da5994832be</guid></item><item><title>Director Sophie Hyde unpacks long-held family secrets in her latest film Jimpa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/director-sophie-hyde-unpacks-long-held-family-secrets-jimpa/106098238</link><description>Sophie Hyde's films have won awards at Sundance and Berlin, but she has more riding on her latest release. She's turned the lens on the long-held secrets of her unconventional family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb5be1a6253a0862e0c51599f572b0a7</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians say Israel's new plans for the West Bank kill statehood hopes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/palestinians-reflect-on-israeli-measures-in-west-bank/106340318</link><description>As Israel's security cabinet agreed on a plan that would pave the way for future settlements in the occupied West Bank, Palestinians say the pressure from Israeli settlers is relentless.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e17573848593a71cdf6f6042be1acbce</guid></item><item><title>Rise of Australia's public economy is comparable to the mining boom of the 2000s, analyst says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/rise-of-australias-public-economy-is-as-big-as-mining-boom/106340550</link><description>Long-term structural shifts have gravitational forces that are hard to escape, says a Westpac economist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb00edbe0efd9fd241fcf6f329001b35</guid></item><item><title>A drunk purchase, a battling Macclesfield club, and a Crystal Palace football upset for the ages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/macclesfield-fc-plot-second-major-fa-cup-upset-against-brentford/106339326</link><description>Rob Smethurst was in the throes of a four-day drunken bender when a friend called and told him his local football team was for sale. Now his tiny English club is making global headlines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">200028f966f16baf1f7f7072648a2495</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics legend Eugenio Monti, the Italian sledder who helped his rivals win gold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/winter-olympics-bobsled-legend-eugenio-monti-selfless-act/106188248</link><description>As Bree Walker aims to create Olympic history in the women's monobob, she will do so on a track named after a man who made history of his own through one of the Winter Games' most selfless acts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">566e18af3700ee4520cd6ec878191199</guid></item><item><title>These mums raise other people's children to secure a future for their own</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/children-left-behind-mother-foreign-domestic-worker-abroad/106303226</link><description>A generation of children in South-East Asia are growing up without their mothers, who have to work abroad for decades to make ends meet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8878ba8d8ea10df17fab402b2241fa7d</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur through to ATP Rotterdam Open final with win over Ugo Humbert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/alex-de-minaur-through-to-atp-rotterdam-final/106346226</link><description>Alex de Minaur becomes the first man to reach three consecutive finals at the Rotterdam Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">841d065eed7395b080396f3f24d0b9bf</guid></item><item><title>Researchers warn climate-linked disease leptospirosis spreading south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/climate-change-linked-to-increasing-leptospirosis-disease-risk/106312420</link><description>Researchers say leptospirosis is emerging as a climate‑driven health threat in Australia, with frequent storms, floods and heatwaves pushing the disease further south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95178a5e8a4125d287e499ebfde48707</guid></item><item><title>ACT Brumbies defeat Western Force 56-24 in Super Rugby Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/act-brumbies-defeat-western-force-56-24-super-rugby/106346216</link><description>The ACT Brumbies have turned up the heat to blitz the Western Force 56-24 in a sapping season-opening Super Rugby Pacific clash in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10ef6f23013268c37706ceee148b7b16</guid></item><item><title>Dry January hits southern Australia as east coast lows drop off the radar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/dry-january-southern-australia-east-coast-lows-decline/106340260</link><description>Rainfall was below average for most of Australia's south-east, far-west and central regions in the first month of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35e0de73fc86cfd94960467f03e96dec</guid></item><item><title>How a pocket of Sydney's inner west went from Australia's deepest coal mine to waterfront houses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/sydney-houses-now-on-former-balmain-coal-mine-birchgrove-history/106219352</link><description>What was once a working class, coal-fuelled borough is now a sought-after suburb in Sydney's inner west, with houses selling for millions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e20c293730315f4a0bd560d285cffe27</guid></item><item><title>Sharing emergency resources becoming more complicated as fire and flood seasons overlap</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/emergency-resources-bushfires/106340108</link><description>With fires and floods occurring simultaneously, and overlapping with international deployments, sharing critical resources is becoming an increasingly complex task.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5be04f47974abf20f48cfef1f3b2e012</guid></item><item><title>Police block road near Nancy Guthrie's home during investigation into her disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/police-block-road-near-nancy-guthrie-home-during-investigation/106346284</link><description>Authorities investigating the disappearance of American morning show host Savannah Guthrie's mother seal off a road near Nancy Guthrie's Arizona home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5cbee59ee059fc655449045cc1bf385</guid></item><item><title>Destanee Aiava announces retirement, calls out online trolls and 'racist' tennis culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/destanee-aiava-announces-tennis-retirement/106346282</link><description>Australian tennis player Destanee Aiava says 2026 will be her last year in professional tennis, announcing her impending retirement in an expletive-laden statement on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e49fc707471384a3f7c79ab4b00b492a</guid></item><item><title>Canberra Broulee Nippers Club is helping landlocked city kids become aspiring lifesavers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/canberra-nippers-club-aspiring-lifesavers-no-beach/106327452</link><description>Young nippers are sprinting for flags, paddle boards and practising CPR despite the nearest beach being 150 kilometres away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9d53f299e3783fd74dff9fe506b6cf0</guid></item><item><title>South Molle's damaged jetty restricts access to island, with abandoned resort's future unclear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/south-molle-island-waits-on-damaged-jetty-fix-abandoned-resort/106329774</link><description>South Molle Island's former resort has been abandoned since it was damaged by a cyclone in 2017. Now, public access to the island is restricted after Cyclone Koji wreaked havoc on its jetty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c65114749dd72f64d417d81761a454d</guid></item><item><title>Woodstock Farm program helping steer troubled Queensland youth away from life of crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/woodstock-farm-program-helping-youth-avoid-life-of-crime/106337320</link><description>The rural-based social program in the shadow of Mt Tamborine has had remarkable success in rebuilding the lives of youth who have fallen through the cracks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">421b0aeae39a6049b42963e3f882f283</guid></item><item><title>Faaletino Tavana scores stunning try in NRL trial, Canterbury Bulldogs star Matt Burton limps off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/faaletino-tavana-scores-stunning-try-in-nrl-trial/106346352</link><description>Wests Tigers rookie Faaletino Tavana has laid claim to one of the best tries in 2026 during a preseason trial against the Sydney Roosters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2cfee729b56ca0f7ea35f8b101926f7</guid></item><item><title>Easy ways to help protect your hair from chlorine and saltwater damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/how-to-avoid-chlorine-and-saltwater-hair-damage-when-swimming/106334202</link><description>Regular beach days or laps at the local pool can leave our hair looking and feeling quite different.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ed59e0b1894ab058082b567c448eb32</guid></item><item><title>Forbes Inn fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/forbes-inn-fire/106335658</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f08e5a8a0559df121863a695484d9e8a</guid></item><item><title>Unscrupulous NDIS providers using inducements to recruit remote NT participants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/unscrupulous-ndis-providers-inducements-remote-nt-communities/106338736</link><description>People with disabilities in remote Northern Territory communities are being targeted by unscrupulous NDIS providers using high-pressure sales tactics and inducements including cash, cigarettes and alcohol, an ABC investigation can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd67ded9456fcfc1b2a32fce1dd07e54</guid></item><item><title>NT film industry on national stage as Kangaroo, Top End Bub and Journey Home win AACTA Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/nt-film-industry-on-national-stage-at-aacta-awards-movies/106345258</link><description>The NT's small but mighty presence is shining on the global stage 40 years after Crocodile Dundee rocketed its film industry into the stratosphere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6b91e7462a835a8868e55cdd28f79a5</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Condoms run out at the Olympic Village as cheating chaos rocks curling — quick hits from day eight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-quick-hits-condoms-curling/106345804</link><description>Protective gear is in short supply in Italy as tensions boil over in the curling and a Norwegian-born Brazilian makes history. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a381471d7f4c7ab29aa453246d08c65</guid></item><item><title>Fortescue trials battery-electric locomotives in Pilbara as decarbonisation race tightens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/fortescue-battery-electric-locomotives-pilbara/106022632</link><description>After years of delays, the Pilbara's largest carbon emitters are testing greener ways to haul iron ore, and Andrew Forrest has now joined their ranks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c13ccfede85f47f794237a00f234b83</guid></item><item><title>Italian migrants who brought 'fancy cheese' to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/italian-migrants-history-of-cheesemaking-australia/106274280</link><description>When John Interlandi's father began making "fancy cheese" in Gippsland, few Australians had heard of parmesan. At 90 years old, Mr Interlandi is still perfecting it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc65fa96aa7a73e1b002718296218199</guid></item><item><title>AFL State of Origin coaches hail success of concept following Victoria's win over Western Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/afl-state-of-origin-coaches-hail-success-of-concept/106346486</link><description>Winning Victoria coach Chris Scott and his Western Australia counterpart Dean Cox call for State of Origin to be played every year after the concept's stunning return in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a2310e59675ad0bac9b0b865d9ebaef</guid></item><item><title>NSW premier announces extra public holiday in April for Anzac Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/nsw-minns-government-anzac-day-extra-public-holiday/106346332</link><description>New South Wales has the fewest public holidays in Australia, observing only 11.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ffac4dfa3924b8dccdf942341a8cced</guid></item><item><title>Supporting and connecting Deaf people, Olivia finds her calling more than just a job</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/olivia-supports-and-connect-deaf-community/106230034</link><description>Olivia Jackson, who lost her hearing as a child, has felt invisible for over a decade until she found her true calling to help other Deaf people achieve their goals as a support worker.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1115de95a72e65d1d9a3e54ffe517057</guid></item><item><title>WA hop growers gear up for harvest as craft beer tastes evolve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/hop-growers-gear-up-harvest-western-australia/106340116</link><description>Local brewers are experimenting with new flavours, while some farms invest in US-made machinery to modernise and streamline the harvest process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0bb847882a1ace0ae5e8db0cba3fd16</guid></item><item><title>As Jakara Anthony dealt with her singles moguls crash, her coach worked out how to pick her back up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/how-jakara-anthony-bounced-back-to-winter-olympic-gold/106346110</link><description>As Jakara Anthony dealt with the disappointment of her singles moguls crash, her coach Peter McNiel was working out how to pick her back up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6104582cfaf145ac938b3a35ff9908bb</guid></item><item><title>Gisèle Pelicot intends to visit ex-husband in prison to get answers on other allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/gis%C3%A8le-pelicot-intends-to-visit-abuser-in-prison-to-get-answers/106346438</link><description>Gisèle Pelicot, the woman at the centre of France's largest rape trial, says she intends to visit her ex-husband in jail and look her abuser "straight in the eye" to get answers to other allegations under investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c69b940995a0a4012b7c4f054573a9d</guid></item><item><title>Six mysterious deaths in the Balkan Mountains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/bulgaria-twin-peaks-balkan-mountains-murders/106336984</link><description>Six unsolved deaths in two remote parts of the Balkan Mountains become a source of conspiracy across Bulgaria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43454fb8b73c98aa463e066cf5250561</guid></item><item><title>CCTV of six people hugging before they were found deceased</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/cctv-of-six-people-hugging-before-they-were-found-deceased/106337456</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">257db1f502200c7a6f3152d0e9b8683a</guid></item><item><title>'Took the wind out of me': Why this man tested himself for plastics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/plastic-pollution-infertility-cancer-urine-test/106340122</link><description>Kal Glanznig had his urine tested as part of an upcoming documentary exploring plastic pollution in Australia. The results left him speechless.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20a78d9083be5d5b2872c764f9c0b081</guid></item><item><title>Opposition draws battlelines on nuclear and capital gains tax changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/jane-hume-nuclear-angus-taylor-capital-tax-childcare-migration/106346434</link><description>Deputy Liberal leader Jane Hume says Australia needs to be "open minded" on nuclear power if the country is to bring down emissions and make power cheaper.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e5abf1fdfcc06c797eb257ee7d43c22</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister announces $3.9 billion 'down payment' towards $30b Adelaide submarine shipyard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/down-payment-for-30b-adelaide-submarine-shipyard/106346484</link><description>The South Australian and federal government release plans for the shipyard in Adelaide that will build at least eight nuclear-powered submarines under the AUKUS pact with the US and the UK.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03adb87b99e8e2d9b576ed873829b8aa</guid></item><item><title>From succession planning to inherited debt, there's pressure and joy in taking on a family business</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/taking-on-the-family-business/106303408</link><description>Inheriting a family business comes with the weight of generations past. For these change-makers, the future is in modernising their operation and making it their own.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0347909980a4922de14658a0f900f351</guid></item><item><title>How China took over global car manufacturing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/how-china-took-over-global-car-manufacturing/106346842</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0292eac405d7d12f7c52da3c62de011</guid></item><item><title>Obama deplores lack of shame after Trump shares monkey clip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/obama-trump-racist-monkey-clip-podcast/106346866</link><description>Former US president Barack Obama has criticised a lack of shame and decorum in the country's political discourse, responding for the first time to a post on Donald Trump's social media account that depicted him and first lady Michelle as monkeys.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e75e10162bdf33f5e8cc127e8b4bbf2</guid></item><item><title>Statues of Amy Sherwin, Australia's first opera star, unveiled at Hobart's Hadley's Hotel in bid to cement legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/peter-schipperheyn-statues-of-amy-sherwin-opera-star-unveiled/106344982</link><description>An effort to bring new recognition to a Tasmanian opera star who became world famous, but who died poor, culminates in the unveiling of two statues of her in Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0073ccc352d93326f0623615a91690e2</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 9</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-matt-graham-cooper-woods/106340132</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34f3b59aefed8c788f8114ead0cbd12a</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous side overturns 14-0 deficit to down Maori in women's All Stars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/womens-all-stars-indigenous-maori-jada-taylor/106347124</link><description>The Indigenous team overturns a 14-0 deficit to score a rousing comeback win over the Maori in the Women's All Stars clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f14485169561b894f2afb767bb7402d</guid></item><item><title>Frog toxins used to poison Alexei Navalny the latest in long history of Russian chemical attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/alexei-navalny-death-russian-history-of-poisonings/106346616</link><description>Russian opposition leader Alexei Navalny was poisoned by the Kremlin with a rare and lethal toxin found in the skin of poison dart frogs, five European countries have said. It's not the first time the country has been accused of poisoning its enemies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">760fb2fcb063a9e9cd0179e29e7157ec</guid></item><item><title>Charlotte Mortlock quits Liberal Party following Sussan Ley leadership defeat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/charlotte-mortlock-women-liberal-party/106347176</link><description>Women were less likely to vote for the Coalition at the 2025 election than ever before, according to the Australian Election Study.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23ccff46149d64d377fec31770f5c200</guid></item><item><title>WA government to introduce new laws on hate speech, face coverings and protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/wa-government-introduce-new-protest-hate-speech-laws/106347042</link><description>The WA premier flags new legislation on hate speech and protests in a bid to protect "social cohesion" in the wake of "multiple threats across Australia" over the summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b17a709f2e34829ce1d9cdedb3d9175</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous and Māori All Stars play out dramatic 16-all draw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/nrl-all-stars-mens-indigenous-maori-result/106347244</link><description>It went down to the final seconds, but the Indigenous and Maori NRL All Stars could not be separated with both sides left to rue missed chances after a 16-all draw.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d01cc349479a0292d97ba58d32f2571c</guid></item><item><title>Live: Chinese star takes swipe at organisers for not accommodating her schedule</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/winter-olympics-2026-live-updates-cooper-woods-bree-walker/106346610</link><description>Chinese skiing superstar Eileen Gu says she is "disappointed" and "saddened" that Winter Olympics organisers scheduled halfpipe training at the same time as her big air final at the MIlano Cortina Games. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e126a8462b94c26b695b1006d4a1e8d</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand's North Island braces for more rain amid widespread flooding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/new-zealand-north-island-rain-flooding/106347264</link><description>Floods cause power outages, road collapses, home evacuations and are linked to the death of a man whose vehicle was submerged on a highway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0752395488c74707c656699c41a23dfa</guid></item><item><title>Matt Graham wins dual moguls bronze at the 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/dual-moguls-2026-winter-olympic-games/106346230</link><description>Matt Graham's medal is the third Australia’s moguls squad has delivered at the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cea7a03f6c1f2118b562ed308b0bcc6f</guid></item><item><title>Ukrainian drone strike sparks fires at Russian Black Sea port ahead of peace talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/ukraine-drone-strike-black-sea-taman-port-russia/106347314</link><description>Two people were wounded in the attack on the port of Taman in the Krasnodar region, ahead of US-brokered peace talks between Ukraine and Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50f8cfdd74cf21db074f8162492dbc54</guid></item><item><title>City of Melbourne quiet on plan for Southbank's 'ugly' red stairs, long after design competition announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/city-of-melbourne-southbank-red-stair-replacement-plan-stalls/106274362</link><description>A Melbourne council unveiled a lucrative competition to replace Southbank's much-derided red stairs. But a year after it was due to start, the plan appears to have gone nowhere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">074f26e344537a0ab6c98a25242c702d</guid></item><item><title>What is FAFO parenting and is it good for kids?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/what-is-fafo-parenting-and-is-it-good-for-kids/106321924</link><description>Is FAFO the 1980s parenting style today's generation of kids need, rebellion against gentle child-rearing, or exhausted parents just throwing their hands in the air?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27dfd8358d59f5a02bd8ef50448007a0</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, February 16: Steven Bradbury's Winter Olympic Games golden miracle at Salt Lake City in 2002</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/steven-bradbury-gold-2002-salt-lake-city/106187326</link><description>In 2002, Australia broke its Winter Olympics gold medal duck in the most extraordinary of ways, as Steven Bradbury put a decade of injury and bad luck behind him to claim the most thrilling of gold medals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f52a523498bfdb185898253f610cc2b4</guid></item><item><title>This week in history quiz, February 16: Can you pass the test?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/this-week-in-history-quiz/106276536</link><description>Abraham Lincoln's career advice, Karl Marx's co-author and a Hollywood star's surgery: How well do you know history?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e20daa7a7ae43d08c20f2401508d442d</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: The anxiety and joy of dual moguls bronze for Matt Graham, leader and captain of the Australian team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/matt-graham-bronze-leader-moguls-duals-winter-olympics/106347650</link><description>Matt Graham's brilliant bronze in the dual moguls, and the incredible response from his teammates, proved to everyone that he is the true leader of this Winter Olympic squad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cba69d73cf10c866f2189e3ff247f598</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party divided over future direction as Angus Taylor plots right-wing political shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/liberal-party-right-wing-division-realignment-four-corners/106331358</link><description>Angus Taylor says he will unite the Liberal Party, but a deeper rift is forming among those who want to overhaul the party's direction and those who believe doing so would mean political death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53f0561e891b7b1fdb5be75b1ca47a5a</guid></item><item><title>ACCC takes Coles to court over 'illusory' discounts in 'case of the century'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/accc-coles-federal-court-case-discount-pricing/106294956</link><description>The "case of the century" is set to play out in the federal court this month, with the ACCC taking on supermarket giant Coles for what it claims are "illusory" discounts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a8938d5ebc9b334251e02015fddc7f9</guid></item><item><title>AI is evolving fast and may bring the fourth industrial revolution with it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/ai-jobs-fake-breakthrough-resignation-chat-gpt-claude/106346440</link><description>A fake news story about me, a series of AI breakthroughs, and a resignation in the tech world show that 2026 could be pivotal for AI.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c994c99fef4c461f39302358208eb79</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur claims Rotterdam Open with impressive victory over Felix Auger-Aliassime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/de-minaur-breaks-through-for-rotterdam-open-triumph/106347904</link><description>An inspired Alex de Minaur produces one of the biggest wins of his career, lifting the Rotterdam Open title by beating red-hot Felix Auger-Aliassime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f49207b10f6c3d8998833e02ddac8d3</guid></item><item><title>Whooping cough cases hit record high after 'potentially catastrophic' vaccine rate drop, experts say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/whooping-cough-cases-at-record-high-level-in-australia/106332954</link><description>A "potentially catastrophic" decline in Australia's childhood vaccination rates has contributed to the sharpest increase in cases of whooping cough in 35 years, infectious diseases experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df9f56f6aeb1e16c21e2baf9475f1b0a</guid></item><item><title>As high-speed rail plans gather pace, Britain's HS2 offers hard lessons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/australia-high-speed-rail-uk-hs2-delays-cost-blow-outs/106075750</link><description>While the federal government considers an ambitious plan, a similar project in the UK has seen its fair share of controversies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b21278ffb6cf9d25ba94b996fb6f64c1</guid></item><item><title>Australia defeated by India in opening T20 as Sophie Molineux era gets off to wobbly start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/australia-women-beaten-in-t20/106347920</link><description>Australia slumps to a rain-affected 21-run loss to India in their opening T20 at the SCG, after selectors opted to drop vice-captain Tahlia McGrath.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1d3ad1921ec592fc795d54bc3787c1b</guid></item><item><title>From wheels to waves in Australia's queer spaces</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/sydney-queer-community-finds-safe-haven-after-dark-history/105637506</link><description>In places marked by historic violence and exclusion, queer communities are still showing up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d5670385fa0f38f2511853dd5b3eff5</guid></item><item><title>Box Hill North players' sanctions over inappropriate photos criticised as 'extremely lenient'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/box-hill-north-football-players-sanctions-inappropriate-photos/106345128</link><description>The Box Hill North Football Club players involved in inappropriate photos posted online after their "Silly Saturday" post-season celebrations have been sanctioned by the league's governing body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4aff07b1deee01cf5d4a837ee4475df0</guid></item><item><title>Cousin of Westfield Bondi Junction attack victim feels many questions were left unanswered at inquest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/cousin-of-bondi-junction-victim-jade-young-speaks-out-on-inquest/106329706</link><description>A bereaved family member of victim Jade Young feels many of his questions surrounding the deadly attack and its aftermath have been left unanswered from the inquest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8673ae286fbf88815ae5d398328cda96</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Kim's LIV Adelaide victory an inspiring chapter in one of golf's most harrowing stories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/anthony-kim-liv-adelaide-win-jon-rahm/106347960</link><description>American Anthony Kim, who has overcome alcohol and drug addiction, hopes his emotional win at LIV Golf's Adelaide tournament will inspire others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">936f3df5bbc6dba69db01928719a57d5</guid></item><item><title>Shark population may have fallen prey to algal bloom, SA ecologists fear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/port-jackson-shark-populations-algal-bloom-impact/106335834</link><description>South Australia's algal bloom could be responsible for pushing a local population of sharks to the brink of collapse, some researchers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e3cb6e84a9a4e4eba4a21a0e3320312</guid></item><item><title>AGAIR operating licence cancelled by CASA two years after fatal Cloncurry plane crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/cloncurry-plane-crash-operator-licence-cancelled/106340998</link><description>The family of one of the victims says its the first step towards justice for their son.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d337bcf3f9cd1128f992f9eb11f6a6be</guid></item><item><title>India and Pakistan refuse handshakes before and after contentious T20 World Cup clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/india-and-pakistan-refuse-handshakes-t20-world-cup-clash/106348000</link><description>India and Pakistan decline to shake hands before and after the most-anticipated game of the T20 World Cup, with India easily winning by 61 runs to secure its Super 8 spot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aec88e0f0a3416457535c8861030762d</guid></item><item><title>Cape Barren Island uses greenhouse and traditional foods to keep fridges full</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/alternative-foods-keep-pantry-full-on-cape-barren-island/105893250</link><description>A tiny island off the coast of Tasmania is embracing old and new techniques to keep food on the table.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6bcc5499da65ccb48471f2c099cdbf7</guid></item><item><title>Live: ASX set to rebound despite quiet Wall Street session</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-february-16/106345462</link><description>Ahead of a busy day of corporate results, the ASX is primed to recoup much of Friday's losses. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af003f297d74e383171ed43fca17c8d2</guid></item><item><title>Live: Angus Taylor demands PM conduct spending audit ahead of budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/federal-politics-taylor-albanese-chalmers-hume/106347964</link><description>New opposition leader Angus Taylor wants the government to set up a bipartisan taskforce to find areas to trim in the upcoming budget. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">466494421e358b8d38aebf85962a8dcb</guid></item><item><title>Dams and rivers run dry, forcing Victorian farmers to make tough decisions about their livestock</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/dams-rivers-run-dry-victoria-farmers-livestock-drought-no-rain/106334366</link><description>Victorian farmers are forced to cart water or destock as dams and rivers run dry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18d39a177a6ee9d81a317ca8e1820867</guid></item><item><title>Flood warnings across Qld as the state's north braces for heavy falls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/queensland-weather-flood-watch-north/106344864</link><description>All eyes are on the already-swollen waterways across Queensland, as the state's north braces for another drenching this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d6e4a31da94d9db00fe3c73ed0f3a17</guid></item><item><title>NT MLA Tanzil Rahman accused of bullying two female staffers on VAD committee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/vad-chair-tanzil-rahman-accused-of-bullying/106340538</link><description>A Northern Territory politician has been accused of bullying by two female staffers while leading a parliamentary committee, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8223f2e6efd46e794a1a7458594f964e</guid></item></channel></rss>