<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 21:52:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Next-generation voters call for better engagement ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-18/federal-election-rural-next-generation-voters/105173450</link><description>Young people in Albury say issues that directly affect them and their communities are not being addressed by major parties for the 2025 election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ae182892b8c9591cd9ec35e6e57fcb9</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne seat of Calwell highlights Labor woes as Gaza pain galvanises Muslim voters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-20/calwell-labor-backlash-over-gaza-islamophobia/104850500</link><description>Dissatisfaction with the Albanese government's stance on Israel-Palestine among many Arab and Muslim voters threatens to unseat Labor MPs, in some places for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63e7f9854fee5bc20e54ee2f5bd136f4</guid></item><item><title>Tiwi Islanders eager to have their say as remote voting for the federal election begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-22/early-voting-starts-in-remote-communities-tiwi-islands-aec/105201318</link><description>Voters in the small remote community of Pirlangimpi on the Tiwi Islands, north of Darwin, have become some of the first to cast their votes for the federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0c419fe3ae44debe7edf27241c0e5c1</guid></item><item><title>Health, climate and community sport: What older voters in the Tasmanian seat of Bass are talking about this election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-29/health-climate-sport-election-older-voters-bass-tasmania/105224138</link><description>The federal seat of Bass is held by a margin of just 1.4 per cent. For these older voters who live in the electorate, health, climate and community sport are the issues that will decide their vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3579db910b5a7ee8e11d2618bf798f</guid></item><item><title>US hopes to challenge China's critical minerals dominance with new trading bloc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/us-pitches-new-critical-minerals-trading-bloc/106309202</link><description>The US is urging dozens of countries to follow Australia's lead and sign on to a plan to stop relying on China for the critical minerals used in modern technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4c34d4de059770202fdc288ddc3883b</guid></item><item><title>What Israel's President Isaac Herzog has said about Gaza, and why he won't be arrested in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/herzog-will-be-aware-controversy-wont-be-arrested-in-australia/106311734</link><description>When Israel's president lands in Australia this weekend, he can expect an official red carpet treatment. But he will be all too aware of the controversy his visit is generating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ffdecd9e59cf515e239536238754ac7</guid></item><item><title>Bullying surges in ACT public schools as parents, teachers speak out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/bullying-reports-rise-in-act-public-schools/106269450</link><description>Reports of bullying in ACT public schools have risen sharply in four years. Parents and teachers say children are paying the price, and the system is not coping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7cda36cd7ac7cd9196735a6516e4323</guid></item><item><title>Backyard pods won't fix the housing crisis but they signal a shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/backyard-pods-wont-fix-the-housing-crisis/106314472</link><description>Australia's biggest hardware retailer has started selling tiny homes. Are backyard pods the answer to a national housing crisis?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dd2b8a3992ec554b10d8b236bba7c64</guid></item><item><title>More people say they'll vote One Nation. What are they voting for?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/one-nation-policy-platforms-pauline-hanson/106296838</link><description>One Nation questions if man-made climate change is real, wants to wind back access to abortion care and plans to pay the HECS debts of doctors working in the regions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed4bdf450e353d8bca00c742667777f</guid></item><item><title>Roblox on notice after 'disturbing' reports of child grooming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/government-puts-roblox-on-notice-reports-of-child-grooming/100020788</link><description>The government puts popular social gaming site Roblox on notice following media reports of children being approached and groomed by predators on the platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17bbfe956fe95675bddb65bf1b70eaed</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor faces pressure to challenge for Liberal leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/angus-taylor-pressure-to-challenge-for-liberal-leadership/106324000</link><description>Liberal leadership aspirant Angus Taylor is facing pressure from conservative supporters to challenge Sussan Ley this week and end the damaging speculation paralysing the party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d731de86ca9190f9aeabd2e20ffd4bc0</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth asks to meet Roblox following reports of child grooming. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/commonwealth-roblox-reports-of-child-grooming/106323242</link><description>Roblox has been called to an urgent meeting with the federal government in the wake of reports that children are being groomed by predators and exposed to sexually explicit material on the popular online gaming platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8186dce135dbe17f29c38ae0b2e5a4fb</guid></item><item><title>At school, I was my brother's protector. But I needed more support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/support-i-wish-i-had-at-school-while-caring-for-my-brother/106279156</link><description>I was my brother's protector at school, but the education system could have done more to support us both.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8737a14dea75637ab0e525bab21121a9</guid></item><item><title>Liberals plot resignations to pave way for leadership challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/liberals-plot-mass-resignation-to-force-leadership-spill-/106328762</link><description>Liberals are bracing for a wave of frontbench resignations as soon as Wednesday to pave the way for Angus Taylor to mount a leadership challenge against Sussan Ley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68227eb101c335608129c57bdf313d7f</guid></item><item><title>Bulk-billing rates rebound on back of government's multi-billion-dollar policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/bulk-billing-rates-rebound-after-multi-billion-dollar-investment/106327456</link><description>Bulk-billing rates have rebounded in the first clear measure of the impact of the government's multi-billion-dollar pledge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d77c00d7ce459a8883fdcf39108f49f</guid></item><item><title>Israel tightens grip over West Bank while Herzog visits Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/isaac-herzog-visit-protest-police-west-bank-annexation/106325902</link><description>While Israeli President Isaac Herzog visited Sydney, his government was taking concrete actions in the West Bank designed to "continue to kill the idea of a Palestinian state".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">728001663fca5f0a0371d55a7b3d1249</guid></item><item><title>The Epstein files are shaking Britain, but Donald Trump could still have 3 million reasons to worry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/epstein-files-shake-uk-but-white-house-could-still-be-worried/106324788</link><description>Donald Trump's enemies made no secret of their hopes the documents would contain something explosive enough to bring the president down, but right now the Epstein spotlight is on Britain's politicians and palaces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd62bb34a29f437c14df3ee1992e6c76</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia readies up to 8,000 troops for Board of Peace efforts in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/indonesia-to-send-8000-troops-to-gaza-idf-peacekeeping/106330718</link><description>The move makes Indonesia the first country to clearly commit troops to a multinational peacekeeping effort in the war-torn enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb09709ab6a43276c0ef5777b42146b8</guid></item><item><title>What to watch in February, from puppy love to Muppet hijinks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/what-to-watch-the-muppets-scrubs/106325818</link><description>Kermit, Miss Piggy and the rest of the crew are back to celebrate their 50th birthday with a one-off special that has the potential to turn into a whole new series for the beloved characters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09b335d5b372e0742b8c096839af2dff</guid></item><item><title>Mother of teenager allegedly assaulted by NSW Police at Sydney protest to press charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/nsw-police-protest-allegedly-assaulted-teenager-mother-claims/106329674</link><description>The mother of a 16-year-old who alleges he was "pushed, kicked, dragged on the ground" by officers at a Sydney protest against the Israeli president's visit says she wants to press charges against police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30d0c8531d4d566ed060274bb1773187</guid></item><item><title>US politician Ro Khanna reveals names of six 'powerful men' scrubbed from Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/ro-khanna-reveals-names-redacted-from-epstein-files/106331712</link><description>US politician Ro Khanna has publicly named six men whose identities were scrubbed from the Epstein files, including the former boss of Victoria's Secret, who the FBI suspected was a co-conspirator of the sex offender's crimes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5436a5f0bc8f114fceefe16bdeef79e9</guid></item><item><title>Supersized fatberg clogging Sydney sewer blamed for mysterious debris balls on beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/supersized-fatberg-clogging-sydney-sewer-debris-balls/106309658</link><description>The debris balls that have washed up on NSW beaches in recent years are likely to continue as Sydney Water admits a massive fatberg it cannot reach is clogging sewers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e47536114404d9c787ba564b5b869472</guid></item><item><title>US bars Palau senate president and former Marshall Islands mayor over alleged corruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/us-bars-palau-marshall-islands-officials-for-alleged-corruption/106329288</link><description>A senior Palau politician rejects accusations from the United States Department of State that he accepted bribes from "government, business, and criminal interests from China".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4c5d3311f093881fd48b21aa27d5d56</guid></item><item><title>Several Liberals considering their options as race for leadership heats up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/angus-taylor-supporters-sussan-ley-liberal-leadership-spill/106333642</link><description>Angus Taylor's decision to quit the frontbench ahead of an expected leadership spill has several Liberal considering whether to throw their hat in the ring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bba6b7e2bc707e5854d76d47b7af8765</guid></item><item><title>Australia's toxic legacy at Wilkes Station in Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/wilkes-station-in-antarctica-a-toxic-legacy/106281888</link><description>The ABC has been given rare access to an abandoned Australian base in Antarctica that continues to pose a threat to the environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86fbd4ded36d272a381c32bb0d71bd55</guid></item><item><title>Shoalhaven Council loses control over leadership appointments after Andrew Constance hire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/andrew-constance-shoalhaven-council-preformance-improvement/106329850</link><description>The NSW government is set to take control of senior leadership recruitment at Shoalhaven City Council, amid probity concerns regarding the hiring of former Liberal minister Andrew Constance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bdaa91ffe7f73c9cc7024178f88a0bc</guid></item><item><title>Possible El Niño within months raising potential for hot, dry year across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/possibe-el-nino-potential-hot-dry-year-australia/106332446</link><description>The first El Niño in three years could develop during the coming months, raising the possibility of worsening drought and extreme heat across Australia in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2184da61b7edc5c55fb541a361d2f6ad</guid></item><item><title>Animal abuse charge takes one year as RSPCA prosecutions in Queensland drastically decline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/queensland-rspca-drop-in-prosecutions-animal-cruelty/106277220</link><description>A man has been charged with animal cruelty a year after neighbours first made a complaint to the RSPCA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cd8515cd059d1ed39c4f1b8f6e3e75d</guid></item><item><title>Baker Boy talks new album Djandjay, Riverboats festival and family legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/baker-boy-djandjay-album-riverboats-festival-racism-fresh-prince/106321578</link><description>The Yolŋu artist known as the Fresh Prince of Arnhem Land is the king of feel-good bilingual bangers. But heavy is the crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a7e4fe54da381b9b3169df148ff7976</guid></item><item><title>James Van Der Beek, star of Dawson's Creek, dies aged 48 after colorectal cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/james-van-der-beek-dawsons-creek-star-obituary/105821848</link><description>The American actor was best known for his starring role as Dawson Leery in Dawson's Creek from 1998 to 2003.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0a7efc4b90b9a094e5d4af5773abbca</guid></item><item><title>Australians feel divided as Albanese asks to 'turn the temperature down'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/social-cohesion-anthony-albanese-isaac-herzog/106294752</link><description>Most Australians want greater social cohesion here, even if they don't see much of it right now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa28ba119db2dd3922f89dee680cc738</guid></item><item><title>Carers WA struggling to cope with unprecedented demand for support services</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/carers-wa-unprecedented-demand-support-services/106328164</link><description>An organisation that helps people caring for vulnerable family members in WA is experiencing unprecedented demand, with services unable to keep up with the community's needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec18c3068cc8e2883c0431ac89a4d61c</guid></item><item><title>Future of Port Hedland's West End uncertain after buyback scheme ends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/port-hedland-buyback-ends-leaving-uncertain-future/106050394</link><description>As Port Hedland's controversial dust buyback scheme winds up, Pilbara Ports quietly walks away from major plans to build a training facility and accommodation, with development plans for the area still uncertain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3587d18364662f59c0d70ef1c4dbc441</guid></item></channel></rss>