<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Feb 2026 20:58:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New Zealand knocks Sri Lanka out of Twenty20 World Cup in super eight match in Colombo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/new-zealand-knocks-sri-lanka-out-of-t20-world-cup/106389722</link><description>New Zealand knocks tournament co-hosts Sri Lanka out of the Twenty20 World Cup with a 61-run win in their super eights game in Colombo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">946bb9ae9286d5dbe9dd2e108f4073dd</guid></item><item><title>Expanded Newcastle Art Gallery finally opens after decades of turmoil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/newcastle-art-gallery-expansion-opens-after-decades-of-turmoil/106385406</link><description>It has been two decades in the making, but the troubled Newcastle Art Gallery expansion is finally opening its doors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcfca6bd1010a9aa2ce40e8b3f3a2cb2</guid></item><item><title>Guide to Listening: ABC Classic's Festival of Female Composers and International Women's Day on ABC Jazz</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/guide-to-listening-international-womens-day-abc-classic-abc-jazz/106383718</link><description>For 10 years, in the lead-up to International Women's Day, ABC Classic has celebrated classical music by women across centuries. Here's what's in store for 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b5147af3995708c9117e85ca3177439</guid></item><item><title>Prosecutor's breach of WA evidence rules triggers retrial for man accused of child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/prosecutor-breach-evidence-rules-retrial-man-sexual-abuse/106388342</link><description>A man found guilty of sexually abusing his stepdaughters wins a retrial because a "serious breach" by a prosecutor resulted in a "miscarriage of justice".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b37eaa2d3d8ee5fec2440ccb2517ab43</guid></item><item><title>Gary Foley Collection tells activism history through Aboriginal lens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/aboriginal-activism-history-foley-collection-victoria-university/106385374</link><description>The ABC gets a rare look at the Aboriginal History Archive, a little-known collection of thousands of items collected by the well-known activist Gary Foley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e237149f16ae0e60b0f75d33622d850</guid></item><item><title>Australians fear falling victim to AI-related crimes, deepfakes and hacks, research shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/australians-fear-ai-related-crime-deepfakes-hacks-study-shows/106381232</link><description>More than half of Australian adults are worried about AI being used to cause them harm, and almost as many fear falling victim to a crime enabled by the technology, a report found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7d976faa70ea67fec95df8618d826fe</guid></item><item><title>What is Shen Yun, the group named in a threat against Prime Minister Anthony Albanese?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/what-is-shen-yun-group-named-in-albanese-threat/106387128</link><description>Police are investigating a bomb threat against a Gold Coast theatre hosting a classical Chinese dance group after a threat was also made against the prime minister's official residence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb107db72e70382ec5b59cc45c2d6fb6</guid></item><item><title>Dolphin injured in suspected boat strike</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/dolphin-injured-in-suspected-boat-strike/106389198</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b18c0e7ddbd7d009a0273e097773ce12</guid></item><item><title>Mardi Gras is almost here. How well do you know Australian LGBTQIA+ history?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/queer-history-quiz/106332162</link><description>Australia's LGBTQIA+ history is full to the brim with groundbreaking art, brave protests and lots of fun along the way. Test how much you know about the queer trailblazers of our country in this quiz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30cc8079f7a8e6147a4402bf37e4ee10</guid></item><item><title>Cuba says boat from Florida opened fire at its soldiers, starting fight that killed 4</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/cuba-says-guards-killed-four-aboard-us-registered-speedboat/106389902</link><description>Cuban forces killed four people and wounded six others aboard a Florida-based speedboat that entered Cuban waters and opened fire on a Cuban patrol, the country's government says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b191f4c2fa1581fba97f2eeb72333b2</guid></item><item><title>US tariffs on Australia remain at 10 per cent — for now</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/australia-to-escape-higher-tariffs-threatened-by-trump/106390024</link><description>Trade Minister Don Farrell hopes Australia can dodge a higher tariff rate being imposed by the US, saying trade officials overnight confirmed the tariff rate on Australia would remain at 10 per cent — at least for now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce900e2d0989046389098bd767e1f8ce</guid></item><item><title>New Shanghai Chinese restaurant in Katherine rocked by pre-dawn machete attack, carjacking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/new-shanghai-restaurant-katherine-alleged-carjacking-machete-nt/106385582</link><description>A Top End Chinese restaurant manager says the eatery's staff have left town after its chef was allegedly threatened with a knife in a pre-dawn carjacking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33e1e166001f7064df661973091a7005</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: Philippines up for the fight against the Matildas in tournament opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/philippines-matildas-womens-asian-cup-preview/106365770</link><description>The last time the Filipinas faced Australia they were trounced 8-0. But they have a renewed side and spirit, and are ready to push the Matildas all the way in the first Women's Asian Cup game in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">260c4faeead5a0a6c64116506be67ecc</guid></item><item><title>RBA governor Michele Bullock calls for patience as rate decisions get harder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/rba-governor-bullock-unveils-how-cash-rate-decision-being-made/106389044</link><description>Michelle Bullock gives more details on how quickly developments affecting monetary policy have moved since the middle of last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95c9f11a6694d0a98d40e8d6013c7283</guid></item><item><title>Teenager Jeremy Webb died of meat allergy from tick bites, coroner finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/jeremy-webb-first-confirmed-red-meat-tick-allergy-death/106390088</link><description>Teenager Jeremy Webb's death in 2022 is the first documented fatal case of mammalian meat allergy in the country and second in the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d7da6aa182c61e11bf7a1fdc257a5a1</guid></item><item><title>Former Australian of the Year Grace Tame responds to Anthony Albanese's 'difficult life' apology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/albanese-apologises-for-calling-grace-tame-difficult/106389860</link><description>Grace Tame criticises Prime Minister Anthony Albanese's qualified apology after he described her as "difficult", saying "what a patronising cop-out".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c5456cedc7e1df5461328c7fb225c62</guid></item><item><title>INXS nominated for induction into Rock &amp; Roll Hall of Fame</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/inxs-nominated-for-rock-and-roll-hall-of-fame/106390218</link><description>INXS will be considered for induction into the Rock &amp; Roll Hall of Fame and is one of 10 first-time nominees on the ballot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfee5f25d80a5a69d1dfaaec1ebd3c4c</guid></item><item><title>Gas giant Arrow Energy takes Australia's biggest pork producer to court over gas pipelines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/arrow-energy-launches-legal-action-against-sunpork-in-land-court/106384552</link><description>A major energy company is taking Australia's largest pork producer to court over plans to build gas pipelines through its property on Queensland's Western Downs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">766a03eccf79e7872514ec826aa04eb0</guid></item><item><title>The AFL's ruck rule changes spark fears of an injury influx as Shannon Neale limps off in preseason</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/afl-ruck-rule-change-injury-fear-shannon-neale-max-gawn/106390750</link><description>Geelong's Shannon Neale might have escaped a serious injury, but coaches and players are beginning to voice concerns the AFL's rule changes could lead to more rucks getting hurt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">996afcf51bcb663d506e4e5dd8095e6b</guid></item><item><title>Sunset Strip residents learn water unsafe even for washing in after 66 years using it to brush teeth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/sunset-strip-residents-learn-water-unsafe-after-66-years-nsw/106375164</link><description>Residents in Sunset Strip knew their water was not safe to drink, but it came as a great shock to read a letter stating it was not safe to bathe in or wash with either.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6fbbc176affd623ab8bfde04c2c4451</guid></item><item><title>Former patient of gynaecologist Simon Gordon, Sarah Hayden speaks out about her treatment.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/simon-gordon-former-patient-sarah-hayden/106390946</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3247b769f86765b73c4f82cc84590280</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of former patients of gynaecologist Simon Gordon join support group</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/endometriosis-womens-health-gynaecologist-simon-gordon-/106390516</link><description>More former patients of Melbourne gynaecologist Simon Gordon have come forward to express distress over their treatment with many joining a newly-formed private support group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37d2dfbf266603d49c6ff41b9a8d2128</guid></item><item><title>Senator Sarah Hanson-Young calls for Triple Zero overhaul at Optus outage hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/optus-call-centre-panic-during-triple-zero-crisis/106391184</link><description>A Senate committee hears bombshell testimony about Optus's processes during an outage that led to the deaths of multiple customers who were unable to call Triple Zero.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd0236ca1fe1907ada8d8a7aee9449fe</guid></item><item><title>Debate about children of 'ISIS brides' has become hyper-politicised</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/children-isis-brides-politics-anthony-albanese-coalition-greens/106382326</link><description>The fate of the "ISIS brides" is inextricably linked to constitutional facts but the debate about their future is not taking place in a legal chamber — it is being fought in the court of public opinion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9a4b4b60f030a3b4951f9b27cc4b5ca</guid></item><item><title>Qantas shares fall more than 6 per cent after first-half profit announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/qantas-first-half-profit-2026-shares-decline/106390004</link><description>Qantas' first-half profit result has disappointed shareholders, but chief executive Vanessa Hudson says the airline's largest fleet renewal in history will pay off.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7da08d86b99e41a9921fa0921a55a00</guid></item><item><title>What is mammalian meat allergy and how do you develop it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/what-is-mammalian-meat-allergy/106390604</link><description>Jeremy Webb's death in 2022 from a tick-induced red meat allergy is the first to be recorded in Australia. Here's what we know about mammalian meat allergy and how to avoid it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe373c32057149f397d0b5aaf6ac1eba</guid></item><item><title>Coral colony discovered by mother and daughter citizen scientists could be world's largest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/citizen-scientists-discover-great-barrier-reef-coral-colony/106386786</link><description>Mother and daughter citizen scientists find what is believed to be the largest coral colony on the Great Barrier Reef and possibly in the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91fa00279ea7b18d4fa86fca3a923a8f</guid></item><item><title>Mother and daughter discover largest known coral on Great Barrier Reef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/mum-and-daughter-discover-largest-known-coral-great-barrier-reef/106383412</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3daef36d07767054d10828bf2ba66f43</guid></item><item><title>How an onstage clash between a future NT administrator and a political hopeful drew battle lines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/david-connolly-phil-scott-onstage-clash-political-fault-lines/106382028</link><description>A keynote speaker shoved an environmental activist at a conference in 2023. Now, one of them is the Northern Territory's next administrator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e75b45dd5e0004999c99eefa241bb377</guid></item><item><title>High levels of E. coli and dead fish found in River Torrens, causing a stink</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/e-coli-dead-fish-found-in-river-torrens/106390262</link><description>Rowers have had to move their training and a boat operator has held off bookings after high levels of E. coli were detected alongside dead fish on a stretch of the River Torrens in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad59d33fd1590d282aa013f1573296d</guid></item><item><title>Abattoir Beaufort River Meats halts operations as $20m in live export transition grants are rolled out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/sheep-transition-grant-funding-revealed-farmers-processors/106389306</link><description>Forty farming families and five processors have secured live sheep transition funding from more than 260 applicants, including Beaufort River Meats in the Great Southern, which has temporarily shut down amid ongoing livestock shortages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3ed5e4e0e96f265b1cdd291d0715f3b</guid></item><item><title>Cuba claims 'armed terrorist infiltration' prevented during open water speedboat shootout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/cuba-says-terrorist-infiltration-stopped-by-speedboat-shootout/106391348</link><description>Cuban coastguard troops shot dead four people and injured six others they claimed were approaching the country on a speedboat filled with weapons set to be used in an act of terror.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24bb4712029afa19a478adb89c5c09ce</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's week unravelled by one-word description of Grace Tame</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/anthony-albanese-bomb-threat-grace-tame-isis-brides/106380004</link><description>The prime minister was this week evacuated from the Lodge over a bomb threat and later got stuck in a tit-for-tat with a former Australian of the Year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0315cf7f99182f207e068ea2908c3b93</guid></item><item><title>Switzerland's Crumbling Giants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/switzerland-s-crumbling-giants/106392636</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07d4c54905d4e3033fb33d529d9e4ec8</guid></item><item><title>Dingo advocates call for end to culls and recognition of environmental and cultural value</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/wa-cc-thurs-dingo-advocates-call-for-greater-protection/106390662</link><description>A campaign to introduce protections to native dingoes has taken its fight to parliament house, arguing that treating dingoes as pests is causing deep cultural and environmental harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45fd7eaff14717b891fd17fae8140d9b</guid></item><item><title>Winegrape growers welcome the establishment of national vineyard register</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/grape-growers-welcome-national-vineyard-register-amid-oversupply/106390054</link><description>Grape growers have endured a tough few years and there are hopes that a national database will help to improve the industry's fortunes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9444becd9e08bb1b3103ab723d04ddf</guid></item><item><title>Sharp decline in tobacco sales linked to illegal sales, not people quitting, says researcher</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/sharp-decline-in-tobacco-sales-linked-to-illegal-sales/106367890</link><description>Business managers and researchers are concerned that a sharp decline in tobacco sales in Alice Springs could mean more people are taking up smoking illegal tobacco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a398206ec2b41104eded0f00a0c5343a</guid></item><item><title>Fungal infection cluster at Royal Prince Alfred Hospital linked to deaths of two patients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/nsw-rpa-fungus-cluster-two-dead/106392254</link><description>The cluster of infections at the transplant unit at the Royal Prince Alfred Hospital late last year saw two people die, health bosses say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3be2c63a8de9d2e30a48f6a420875dd8</guid></item><item><title>NT cattle stations assess flood damage, as rain in central Australia declared natural disaster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/flood-damage-cattle-stations-nt/106391070</link><description>Disaster recovery funding is activated by the NT and federal governments, as flood-affected communities begin counting the cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56b3004fc60d2b339d9c3cba1d43389c</guid></item><item><title>SPC Global scales back plans for Shepparton juice production move with Fair Dinkum deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/spc-global-move-juice-production-griffith-shepparton-mill-park/106391490</link><description>SPC Global is moving juice production away from Melbourne in a bid to save $8 million a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c020c9d7252db26c07fffba7721ad9c</guid></item><item><title>Australia to focus on basics against India in second match of ODI series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/cricket-odi-australia-india-odi-hobart-ash-gardner/106392878</link><description>Ash Gardner says mastering a simple game plan was the key to Australia's convincing six-wicket win over India in the ODI series opener Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cefb056636d5b3b4f664e3d2545d0a7e</guid></item><item><title>Former teacher Stephen Fane Noga denies allegations by former student they had sex while she was his student</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/stephen-fane-noga-gives-evidence-hobart-teacher-rape-trial/106334334</link><description>Stephen Fane Noga has denied allegations he had sex with a former student while he was one of her teachers at Hobart Matriculation College in the 1980s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc4cd3c50b93f321eaaaeaf2f8b464a9</guid></item><item><title>Thursday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106393546</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b150fb4de907d597621b793d4d355cf</guid></item><item><title>What is the future for Tennis Australia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/what-is-the-future-for-tennis-australia-/106393266</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1176dd5e009fba79f12d96c5dbbe0ddb</guid></item><item><title>Funding axe looms for nine childcare centres failing standards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-26/childcare-funding-cuts-safety-rules/106392910</link><description>Nine childcare services that have failed to lift standards will only be named if the federal government decides to cut their taxpayer funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96b01329881bbb1370099da2e2185b61</guid></item><item><title>Health, environment departments questioned 'evidence' cited in salmon antibiotic approval for florfenicol in Tasmanian waterways</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/tas-concerns-over-salmon-antibiotic-approval-process/106391438</link><description>Tasmania's health department and environment watchdog questioned the scientific rigour behind an application to use the antibiotic florfenicol in salmon farms, including a lack of evidence about its impact on humans, documents show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6791dafaccc5a00178a77268c129c24</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast couple accused of breaching freezing orders a second time amid alleged NDIS fraud investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/david-mcwilliams-laura-fullarton-asic-freezing-order-breach/106390620</link><description>It is the second time ASIC has accused David McWilliams and his wife, Laura Fullarton, of breaching freezing orders while the watchdog investigates allegations of NDIS-related fraud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ebac6856237b5f5e3e05235c77de107</guid></item><item><title>From A$AP Rocky to Megadeth — these 10 great albums got 2026 started right</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/best-new-albums-2026-asap-rocky-j-cole-megadeth-willow/106381570</link><description>This year has already given us a bounty of beautiful new records. Here are just 10 of the best we've heard so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2a4e4f793d56ceea4d1588e71a989e5</guid></item><item><title>What is the best wash cycle to use on your washing machine?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/best-wash-cycles-to-use-at-home-for-clothes-towels-linen/106361962</link><description>Eco, fast, cotton, heavy, intense cold? Experts on the most cost-effective and efficient wash cycles for your home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ded506332417d3a6ce5c5116c4dee33</guid></item><item><title>The ABC speaks to Iran's exiled crown prince Reza Pahlavi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/the-abc-speaks-to-iran-s-exiled-crown-prince-reza-pahlavi/106393904</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d28ecba24cdf789646027b28ea41295f</guid></item><item><title>How Australia's lax property tax has created a class system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/australias-lax-property-tax-has-created-a-class-system/106391788</link><description>Australian real estate now is among the world's most expensive, and that has made it a red-hot political issue as demographics shift.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a31c0c5d0a59e1d562ac1a42edfcb654</guid></item><item><title>Thousands break into property market with 5% Deposit Scheme for first home buyers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/five-pc-home-deposit-scheme-influx/106136868</link><description>The number of people buying their first home with a 5 per cent deposit surges after the federal government makes sweeping changes to the scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">055b8bde6bb91a5be7130ae021c2fd32</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar military using festivals as propaganda to hide war zone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/myanmar-festival-propaganda-hiding-war-amid-air-strikes/106382144</link><description>As Myanmar's junta celebrates Chin National Day in an effort to project control, air strikes on civilians underscore a deepening civil war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">656854e7d08816135ef808492c3d120f</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: 'Proactive' Matildas aiming for Asian Cup glory under Joe Montemurro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/proactive-matildas-2026-womens-asian-cup-sam-kerr-mary-fowler/106388102</link><description>Although filled with familiar faces, the Matildas are now a completely different side to the one that captured hearts and minds at the 2023 World Cup. This is how a "proactive" Australian side is likely to line up at the Women's Asian Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">093451dc407c262e3909ee0f0ff52e93</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous people are going to jail at a record rate — what's the solution?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/solutions-focused-courts-helping-reduce-recidivism/106391944</link><description>The number of Indigenous people behind bars is rising. But some judges are bucking the trend by taking a different approach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b32b1f3d871b83341d8e3bd141d8b73</guid></item><item><title>HungryPanda alleges blackmail, intimidation amid dispute with delivery riders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/hungrypanda-alleges-blackmail-intimidation-amid-dispute/106392560</link><description>The dispute between HungryPanda and some of its riders has taken another twist, with the food delivery company accusing some workers of intimidation and blackmail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1445c8e14cdfa8b004c9936e189292eb</guid></item><item><title>Hillary Clinton slams Epstein committee for grilling her instead of Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/hillary-clinton-gives-deposition-at-jeffrey-epstein-committee/106394500</link><description>Hillary Clinton blasts a Republican-led congressional committee for summoning her to answer questions about Jeffrey Epstein while failing to push US President Donald Trump to do the same thing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24bc3f1862f71db70614627e2bb7a2ed</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberal Party flirting with fire as One Nation preference deal looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/liberal-one-nation-potential-preferences-analysis/106391418</link><description>South Australia's embattled Liberals have openly declared their willingness to strike a preference deal with One Nation. Will it help or hurt them on election day?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e771204d6dcf2bd5343cf65a3370d3d</guid></item><item><title>Albanese celebrates his caucus unity but it comes at a cost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/labor-government-caucus-unity-anthony-albanese-left/106380394</link><description>Behind the scenes, the troops are carefully managed. Opinions are expressed at factional meetings and the prime minister meets with the factional conveners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31d1a41ec7748747a7b08a90b06f6374</guid></item><item><title>India beats Zimbabwe, South Africa beats West Indies at T20 World Cup as Proteas reach semifinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/india-south-africa-win-at-t20-world-cup/106394592</link><description>The final four at the Twenty20 World Cup is taking shape after South Africa progressed on the back of a victory over West Indies, and India's victory over Zimbabwe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d23b9ec599ecde8c0cd0ce335169eaf</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley officially resigns two weeks after being ousted as Liberal leader — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/federal-politics-live-blog-fri-feb-27/106391736</link><description>Two weeks after losing the Liberal leadership, Sussan Ley officially handed in her resignation letter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d12040c259fa0fa707e41a7a04c4d981</guid></item><item><title>Bad Bunny tour unites Sydney's Latin diaspora with Australian concerts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nsw-fans-prepare-for-bad-bunny-sydney-tour-latin-dispora/106387764</link><description>Global powerhouse Bad Bunny is bringing together Sydney’s Latin diaspora and exciting fans who cannot speak a word of Spanish.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a664ab78b523b7abf65836d23ea30a17</guid></item><item><title>ASX correction 'likely', Coles shares plummet — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/asx-markets-business-live-news-feb27-2026/106394660</link><description>Analysts say a share market correction is 'likely' as the ASX hits record high.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc00f0217d7da6178314dbb98598387</guid></item><item><title>Amy Sayer eager to represent Matildas at Asian Cup after long-term knee injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/amy-sayer-return-from-injury-asian-cup/106391934</link><description>After a long-term injury seriously derailed her career, Australian soccer player Amy Sayer is looking to leave a mark on this year's Asian Cup, which begins for the Matildas on Sunday in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cb7768dc6051a8e002e6d5db68e5b8e</guid></item><item><title>Seismologists investigate 'mysterious' earthquake swarm near Gnowangerup in southern WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/earthquake-swarm-rattles-gnowangerup-southern-wa/106382850</link><description>After a dozen earthquakes in a single day and more than 70 over the course of February, farmers in Gnowangerup are curious about what is rumbling their paddocks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c2486aa99f39f551c9d485d32ab1924</guid></item><item><title>Two new Hans Christian Andersen adaptations prove fairy tales as relevant as ever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/hans-christian-andersen-tree-of-light-meow-meow-red-shoes/106364412</link><description>Two wildly different shows, The Tree of Light by Slingsby Theatre Company and Meow Meow's The Red Shoes, re-imagine classic fairy tales by Hans Christian Andersen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ef5fdd737cde8a3a507cf76b1c72769</guid></item><item><title>Inquiry looks at why Qld has more children in residential care than other Australian states</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/qld-child-safety-commission-inquiry-wraps-in-toowoomba/106393512</link><description>Queensland's Commission of Inquiry into Child Safety spends seven months exploring the complex issues surrounding children in care and how to improve their experience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16ad067dfc1b7380c4be51b8e2ce5df2</guid></item><item><title>Police charge 25 over 'family-run drug syndicate' seizing $3m in drugs at Gladstone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/police-charge-25-people-with-drug-offences-in-gladstone/106394952</link><description>Dozens of people are charged after a raid in central Queensland seized more than $3 million worth of drugs from what people say was a "deeply entrenched drug syndicate".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">809039c034f575ef5a197af6f6d52b61</guid></item><item><title>Labor not ruling out negative gearing changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/labor-not-ruling-out-negative-gearing-changes/106395074</link><description>A government source said it would make sense to consider changes to negative gearing and capital gains tax together, but that no decision was close to being made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57ef2e8357ae14f0ed1eab92322752ec</guid></item><item><title>Judge rejects request to block Trump White House from building its $560 million ballroom project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/judge-allows-trumps-white-house-ballroom-project-to-proceed/106394882</link><description>A US judge rejects a preservationist group's request to block the Trump administration from continuing construction of a $560 million ballroom to replace the demolished East Wing of the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2da5cc859c0258e4a51f7784657bdf6b</guid></item><item><title>Hillary Clinton speaks after testifying about Epstein ties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/hillary-clinton-speaks-after-testifying-about-epstein-ties-/106395198</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">259c4844eda3097d8d620a9c8736e797</guid></item><item><title>Tens of thousands of Budget Direct customers overcharged, ASIC alleges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/asic-sues-budget-direct-misconduct-allegations/106395196</link><description>The corporate regulator is taking legal action over allegations Budget Direct customers lost online discounts they were promised and were overcharged.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7882a655ec61e37e6201c5bdb8cc0ae3</guid></item><item><title>ABC to broadcast Matildas' Women's Asian Cup games as well as knockout matches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/abc-radio-broadcast-matildas-womens-asian-cup/106395182</link><description>Just days out from the start of the Women's Asian Cup, the ABC has locked in radio broadcasting rights for the tournament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4525c54c6737ed61e3faaf1577489894</guid></item><item><title>$3 million in drugs seized in Gladstone drug trafficking operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/-3-million-in-drugs-seized-in-gladstone/106395608</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0681bcb712c55b346069a8fe45f191a1</guid></item><item><title>Deepfakes back in the headlines after a federal law was used for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/rise-in-sexualised-deepfakes-new-laws-explainer/106390940</link><description>As the first case under new anti-deepfake legislation goes before the courts, authorities and experts say the rise in the creation of the non-consensual sexually explicit material is concerning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da4118b9f6f994212728c2883b3b0bd4</guid></item><item><title>Air strikes hit Afghan capital of Kabul, hours after Taliban attacks Pakistan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/taliban-launches-retaliatory-strikes-against-pakistan/106395580</link><description>Pakistan is responding to "unprovoked fire" by Afghan forces at multiple locations along the border, the Information Ministry in Islamabad says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">723636784f9962da68e0b01185be66b9</guid></item><item><title>Protestor arrested as NT Administrator David Connolly sworn in</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nt-administrator-david-connolly-swearing-in-parliament-arrest/106393862</link><description>A protester has been arrested amid chaotic scenes outside of NT Parliament, where David Connolly has been sworn in as the new administrator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a09d17d197bc6018672c8c52798f531</guid></item><item><title>171 bodies found in mass graves in eastern Congo after withdrawal of M23 rebel group</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/congo-bodies-found-mass-graves/106395864</link><description>Mass graves with at least 171 dead bodies have been found in the eastern Democratic Republic of the Congo, in a region the M23 rebel group has recently withdrawn from.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cb8612f5f98425316681232fce5aca9</guid></item><item><title>Bendigo Swordcraft rallies around one of their own after Harcourt bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/bendigo-swordcraft-larp-henry-of-harcourt-victorian-bushfires/106352450</link><description>Michael Henry's armour and weapons survived January's bushfires, as the Swordcraft community helps him rise from the ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24d209dd01eeee8c3f01a75bb5cfd606</guid></item><item><title>Instagram to alert parents if teens 'repeatedly' search for self-harm terms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/instagram-to-alert-parents-of-teen-suicide-searches/106395120</link><description>The new feature will be rolled out in Australia from next week, but there are concerns about loopholes and limitations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">200c4245e8ca3ad7f521dff90f5a1629</guid></item><item><title>WA drivers reeling after passengers caught out by AI-powered safety cameras</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/seat-belt-cameras-catch-drivers-in-costly-mistake/106395672</link><description>WA drivers given large fines or a licence suspension after their passengers were snapped wearing seatbelts incorrectly say they are being punished for behaviour beyond their control.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f49310eb8696921b88ac0f51d3ea1c4b</guid></item><item><title>How Manly backrower Hugo Hart went from American high school football to the brink of the NRL</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nrl-manly-sea-eagles-hugo-hart-nfl-high-school-football/106392204</link><description>After some eye-catching performances in the pre-season, young Manly backrower and former American high school football linebacker Hugo Hart is edging closer to an NRL debut.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eab60549feb59ed9ffc9f61f26e689a0</guid></item><item><title>Baby rhino born in NSW wildlife park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/baby-rhino-born-in-nsw-wildlife-park/106391240</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c1a4782c0ee42eca3a3379b2ab7f6eb</guid></item><item><title>Riverina community steps up to feed baby rhino after mum abandons him at birth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/white-rhino-ck-embraced-by-community-after-rejection-at-birth/106392160</link><description>Just like "Punch" the monkey, this adorable baby was abandoned by its mother soon after birth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1cddebabeb59cc75e46df1af60d3c04</guid></item><item><title>In photos: Extreme weather sweeps across large parts of Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/extreme-weather-sweeps-across-large-parts-of-australia/106395148</link><description>At least four states are facing extreme weather and heavy rain, with some areas tipped to receive the heaviest rainfall in more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">314212cea7670e933f1a5796ad376ddc</guid></item><item><title>Serial rapist Graham Kay jailed for sexually touching Sydney schoolgirl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/sex-touch-sentence-graham-kay/106395052</link><description>A serial rapist who attacked eight women and girls in the 1990s has been jailed for four and a half years for sexually touching a teenage girl in Sydney's CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43a66d48b0952d4f3e1bd7f1aea4352d</guid></item><item><title>Terella Brewing to close amid legal battle with Sunshine Coast Council</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/teralla-brewing-to-close-its-doors-amid-legal-battle/106395960</link><description>Popular Sunshine Coast brewery and music venue Terella Brewing will close after a legal stoush with the local council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a5de76c0655eae2c97b7931d6b8c24f</guid></item><item><title>Comedian Magda Szubanski in remission after stage 4 blood cancer treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/magda-szubanski-stage-4-blood-cancer-remission/106396740</link><description>The Australian entertainer reveals she is in remission after completing chemotherapy treatment for stage 4 blood cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02c295aa806c4b19a1a7af666f1fcf8c</guid></item><item><title>Crew-11 NASA astronaut behind mission-ending medical issues identifies himself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/crew-11-nasa-astronaut-behind-mission-ending-health-issues/106395048</link><description>The 58-year-old spaceflight veteran has identified himself as the astronaut whose illness prompted NASA's first medical evacuation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd932f2d6b20c020c5606c312a535772</guid></item><item><title>Australian Electoral Commission proposes changes to Tasmanian voting boundaries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/electorate-boundary-changes-proposed-for-tasmania/106395702</link><description>Under proposed changes to Tasmania's electorates, Lyons would decrease in area while Clark would increase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a86d788ef63c809696a7a63f7bc011c9</guid></item><item><title>Coles 'Down Down' in the supermarket wars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/coles-financial-results-go-backwards-with-shares-following/106396060</link><description>Financial results for supermarket giant Coles underperform, with stocks following suite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02d38172bafbfff12219f98d41817fb0</guid></item><item><title>Mitch Brown co-hosts Sydney Gay and Lesbian Mardi Gras six months after coming out as bisexual</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/mitch-brown-hosts-mardi-gras-parade/106388108</link><description>Just six months since coming out, ex-AFL player Mitch Brown is now co-hosting Sydney's Mardi Gras parade. He hopes his journey can help other players embrace who they are.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">206fcf0d74b4b47e34764aab1b2500a2</guid></item><item><title>Health authorities reject claims Sydney hospital fungal infection outbreak covered up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/nsw-government-rejects-cover-up-claims-over-hospital-fungus/106396224</link><description>Health authorities reject claims information about a fungal infection outbreak which could have caused the death of two patients at a Sydney hospital was deliberately withheld from the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8edbf8ed64af07c418ede9750b35d09</guid></item><item><title>How young people are coping with the rising cost of living</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/how-young-people-are-coping-with-the-rising-cost-of-living/106385806</link><description>Many people are struggling with the cost of living and increasingly, young Australians say they are not just worried about the situation now, but also what it means for the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64f6e8f2391b28b8f248ff3473f09f7e</guid></item><item><title>Super Bowl winner Michael Dickson puts Matt Burton's boot up with NFL punters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/michael-dickson-matt-burton-nrl-nfl-code-switch/106396080</link><description>Australian Super Bowl winner Michael Dickson says the booming boot of Bulldogs five-eighth Matt Burton could cut it in the NFL, but not without some major adjustments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1a2746cbe842599da2b26dc6ab44583</guid></item><item><title>Perth mother blames WA's mental health systemic failures for her teen daughter's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/perth-mother-blames-systemic-failures-for-her-daughter-death/106396758</link><description>The mother of a teenage girl who took her own life a few hours after being released from a Perth mental health ward says a series of systemic failures is responsible for her daughter's death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd2adb250d2d4bf3298ec45d056b46a3</guid></item><item><title>Deputy Chief of Army delivers speech at Parliament House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/deputy-chief-of-army-delivers-speech-at-parliament-house/106397912</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0991f0c4ed27c217cab87bc6f6a653f2</guid></item><item><title>What to check out this weekend: Gorillaz, Chris Fleming and a pasta salad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/what-to-watch-read-and-listen-to-this-weekend/106376414</link><description>Looking for something diverting for the weekend? We've got you covered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64b88fb74d30e6cccd8c6fbbc63e719d</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party will not publish its internal review into the 2025 election loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/liberal-party-election-review-will-not-to-be-published/106398462</link><description>The review received hundreds of submissions and was finished months ago, but today the Liberal Party's federal executive revealed it would never be made public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c3db63f84d80a3125794937ad6fa8e5</guid></item><item><title>Parents charged with manslaughter after Gold Coast crash kills 3yo boy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/parents-charged-with-manslaughter-after-gold-coast-crash/106398698</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b679bde28339a7a7880256287eb01dbd</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Liberal MP Rory Amon denies sexual assault complainant told him he was 15</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/former-nsw-mp-rory-amon-gives-evidence-underage-sex-assailt-case/106396128</link><description>Former Liberal MP Rory Amon has told a jury the complainant in his sexual assault trial told him he was 17 before they discussed meeting up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b4446c57f1988a4c74c877541084fa4</guid></item><item><title>Ex-SA Liberal leader David Speirs says he will contest state election, 10 months after drug conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/david-speirs-announces-political-comeback-for-sa-election/106389794</link><description>Former SA Liberal leader David Speirs has confirmed he has nominated to run in his former seat of Black in the state election, 10 months after he was convicted of drug supply offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d38a917197cbbdc68d82b2dd2ac06cf</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: Katrina Gorry has done it all for the Matildas. Now she wants a trophy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/womens-asian-cup-matildas-katrina-gorry/106398594</link><description>Katrina Gorry embodies all the characteristics that are celebrated in Australian football, and the veteran midfielder wants to lead the Matildas all the way to the Asian Cup trophy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02ede07013e6f10ff3550784cc2d2253</guid></item><item><title>David Speirs's comeback attempt is a risk for everyone — including himself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/david-speirs-comeback-attempt-a-political-risk-analysis/106390998</link><description>The former opposition leader's attempt at a political comeback is a risk for both the major parties — but also himself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c920c14086d0b426fa48504f14566d2b</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Reds defeat Highlanders, Western Force beat Moana Pasifika in Super Rugby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/western-force-defeat-moana-pasifika-for-first-super-rugby-win/106399112</link><description>The Queensland Reds and Western Force have recorded their first wins of the Super Rugby Pacific season in round three.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">094d1db7cab1156c1469b611fe18bc53</guid></item><item><title>An unexpected baby boy gives hope to the all-female Akuntsu tribe in Brazil's Amazon rainforest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/amazonian-tribe-akuntsu-gives-birth-to-first-boy/106399170</link><description>As they advanced in age without a child to carry on the line, many expected the Akuntsu to vanish when the three remaining women died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7e97cd520f8aef2465852b7401719a0</guid></item><item><title>Georgia Voll blazes century as Australia defeats India by five wickets and takes 6-4 series lead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/georgia-voll-strikes-century-australia-downs-india/106399172</link><description>Georgia Voll strikes her second ODI century after being dropped on 99, as Australia cruises to a five-wicket win over India and takes a 6-4 lead in the multi-format series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3a54020baa22342ddd21f6f8d97aadf</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106397788</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">692093cbbec66533ee074a199a24c6a3</guid></item><item><title>Islamic State claims credit for Bondi massacre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-27/islamic-state-claims-credit-bondi-massacre/106399514</link><description>Islamic State has embraced Sajid and Naveed Akram as "soldiers" and urged other supporters to continue attacks on Jews and Christians, as they claimed credit for the Bondi massacre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e5e8c45aed5825daa6f1ef8f07fbffd</guid></item><item><title>Coles thinks its court battle is worth it and it's got the scars to prove it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/coles-down-down-accc-court-battle-prices/106382746</link><description>Coles decided this bruising court battle was worth it and now a federal court judge is weighing up the evidence to decide whether that decision was a masterstroke or a massive error.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">364dd6e5a81b7d5c96710313bc409515</guid></item><item><title>Best books of the summer, from Julian Barnes, Tim Ayliffe, Madeline Cash and more</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/best-books-summer-what-to-read-next-julian-barnes-tim-ayliffe/106255824</link><description>Wondering what to read next? Buzzy debuts, gripping thrillers and lyrical literary fiction are among our critics' latest recommendations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d662d4d63148a453f7ff498b9e9d47a</guid></item><item><title>ABC 50/50 quiz: This week we're testing your knowledge of Mad Men, musicals and weird punctuation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/abc-5050-quiz-feb-28/106389780</link><description>Every question has only two options: One is right and the other is wrong. You have an even chance of guessing correctly each time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c18d49b2f753212dce26b4582f17cc8a</guid></item><item><title>Bill Clinton tells congressional committee he had 'no idea' about Jeffrey Epstein's crimes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/bill-clinton-deposed-at-congress-epstein-committee/106399884</link><description>The former US president is being questioned by the House Oversight Committee, which is looking into the US government's handling of the Epstein case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53b397dffffca63baeab729b1fdeacd5</guid></item><item><title>Temporary reprieve for Gaza healthcare system as Israel's attempt to block Doctors Without Borders and other aid groups is stopped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/israel-s-top-court-allows-aid-groups-to-keep-working-in-gaza/106395150</link><description>Israel's Supreme Court on Friday temporarily blocked the government from shuttering the Gaza operations of dozens of aid organisations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d8106ebce829154edc7ead3d88f4cd3</guid></item><item><title>Deluge for SA and Victoria while Queensland, NT and WA eye triple cyclone threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/nsw-sa-vic-qld-nt-wa-weather-forecast-rain-low-cyclone/106397360</link><description>Populated regions stretching from Eyre Peninsula to western Victoria and the Murray River are at risk of dangerous flash flooding, amid growing signs three additional tropical lows will form off Australia's northern coast next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0ea5d62f6f88963a1383b124cca99aa</guid></item><item><title>Warning about financial abuse of First Nations elders as lack of digital literacy risks security</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/warning-financial-abuse-of-first-nations-elders-digital-literacy/106396092</link><description>Experts are warning elders are suffering in silence and are calling for more awareness around financial abuse to understand how it manifests within families and communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fc26cfc809fcdf89d8911517a353dca</guid></item><item><title>These Australians are saving and restoring native grasslands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/native-grasslands-victoria-endangered-restoration-seed-demand/106391114</link><description>Native grasslands across southern Australia are slowly making a comeback, driven by conservationists, farmers and a growing native seed industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7c3a1948c6b245028fc0ac26ebd688b</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: Holly McNamara in career-best form and ready for breakthrough Matildas moment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/holly-mcnamara-asian-cup-matildas/106376910</link><description>Four years on from her first Asian Cup, Holly McNamara begins her second in career-best form. The 23-year-old has her eyes on the ultimate prize.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaa536064839f25872f9c7a9172059e4</guid></item><item><title>How sound helped us create a synchronised video timeline of the Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/how-sound-helped-sync-videos-of-the-bondi-terror-attack/106282450</link><description>The ABC has gathered, verified and geolocated dozens of videos of the Bondi terror attack and compiled them into a single, synchronised timeline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92c72834a69dd2811efb5b1141e26db0</guid></item><item><title>Dozens of synced videos capture humanity amid horror of Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/synchronised-video-timeline-bondi-terror-attack/106282432</link><description>As gunshots rang out at Bondi, dozens of eyewitnesses risked their lives to film the horror. This is what they wanted you to see.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6842ed3b650eaf587ec21feca4c7db6</guid></item><item><title>Former prince Andrew's scandals pose an almighty challenge for Prince William</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/prince-william-is-set-to-inherit-the-andrew-problem-/106385970</link><description>When Prince William and Princess Catherine stepped out for their first public appearance since Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's arrest, an innocuous question was levelled at them. The candid response was perhaps more revealing than anticipated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d63fb62d0d20990cd1a6057cff850ab</guid></item><item><title>The battery that divided Narrabri: How misinformation derailed a renewable energy project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/misinformation-kills-narrabri-community-battery-project/106120264</link><description>A community battery project three years in the making, run by a local not-for-profit and backed by the council, was killed after a spark of misinformation about its fire risk was ignited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32dae321540fd913dc51081e8a4e2fd0</guid></item><item><title>Archaeologists relocate lighthouse keeper's wife's remains on remote Qld island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/low-isles-grave-relocated-rising-sea-levels-queensland/106386250</link><description>The bones of a Queensland lighthouse keeper's wife were almost lost as a result of rising sea levels nearly 150 years after her death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ee9540858c797f22d9aa32263fbced4</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan and the Taliban edge closer to 'open war' — but neither can win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/afghan-taliban-pakistan-full-scale-war-not-likely/106399784</link><description>Pakistan's declaration of an "open war" with the Afghan Taliban sounds dangerous, but analysts say neither side has the capacity to win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0ca6a6a48cd4b94617f1ae46784ba1c</guid></item><item><title>OFC Pro League launches new soccer competition across seven Oceanic nations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/ofc-pro-league-launches-new-soccer-competition/106392686</link><description>A new professional soccer league has launched across Australia, New Zealand and the Pacific, though questions remain over whether it can survive long-term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57c07edf9ab625e86fce2fda21261414</guid></item><item><title>Tennis star Destanee Aiava 'scared' to walk on court because of death threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/destanee-aiava-death-threats-tennis-retirement/106395342</link><description>Destanee Aiava was once called the best 14-year-old female tennis player in the world. Just over a decade later, she is walking away from the sport and calling out its toxic culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59261a1ab537058a040f541e555479bf</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: Where is it being played, how can I watch the Matildas, and is it a big deal?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/women-asian-cup-2026-everything-you-need-to-know/106383868</link><description>Australia is hosting the Women's Asian Cup for the first time in 20 years, and this could be the Matildas' best chance to finally add another trophy to their cabinet. Here's everything you need to know about the tournament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11682c6de16ff8294aba9bee9dd6919f</guid></item><item><title>Crunch time for Victorian farmers refusing VNI West work as forced access looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/crunch-time-farmers-block-transmission-line-vni-west-assessments/106385682</link><description>Landholders opposed to VNI West have been given 30 days to allow environmental assessments before authorised officers can enter by force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03626040d9562e4e350feee56767cb9c</guid></item><item><title>Red-hot Socceroos striker Mohamed Touré set to miss World Cup warm-ups with groin injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/mo-toure-socceroos-striker-groin-injury-world-cup/106399958</link><description>After starting in Norwich in record-breaking form, Socceroos striker Mohamed Touré will almost certainly miss Australia's crucial World Cup warm-up games in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d862e59a65b94bce260b6f78bf297f6</guid></item><item><title>Greens unfazed by polling and sticking to their guns on AUKUS ahead of SA election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/greens-unfazed-by-polling-ahead-of-sa-election/106381914</link><description>Ahead of the SA election, the Greens have made only modest gains in polling compared to rival minor parties, but party leader Robert Simms is not disappointed by the result.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46a6270d356079379b95a63c34f70a49</guid></item><item><title>America's Next Top Model's feigns accountability in new docuseries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/americas-next-top-model-documentary-netflix-tyra-banks/106380392</link><description>America's Next Top Model has aged terribly. What does accountability even mean for an era of unprecedented exploitation on screen?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2cd55205f433e51319ad2435188be00</guid></item><item><title>BOM flooding forecast as SA residents warned to batten down</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/rain-and-flash-flooding-forecast-for-sa-south/106397966</link><description>The bureau is forecasting totals of 100 millimetres of rain could fall in some parts of SA this weekend as a tropical low moves south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94716ebafdd586961616f7e248611e73</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says of Iran 'sometimes you have to' use force, as US-Tehran tensions mount</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/iran-trump-use-force/106399936</link><description>The US has amassed a huge military presence in the region after the president threatened military action if Tehran refused to forswear nuclear weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea98612409185080edb3b70d51f71f49</guid></item><item><title>Queensland shark-monitoring drone trial reveals shark sightings beyond nets and drum lines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/shark-monitoring-program-queensland-nets-and-drumlines/106314156</link><description>The results of a four-year-trial were obtained by a conservation group under right to information laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27372842aee46767ace52090362fc1e0</guid></item><item><title>US Republicans call for Australian lamb investigation as new bill proposes 30pc tariff</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/republicans-call-for-australian-lamb-tariff-investigation/106339474</link><description>Republicans write to Donald Trump's top trade officials to request an investigation into Australian lamb, as several members of Congress sponsor a bill for a 30 per cent tariff on Australian sheep products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f39fe59cc62d4d403ae9d05565b29e6</guid></item><item><title>Australian Antarctic team yields big haul of fresh produce with hydroponics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/antarctic-garden-yields-big-haul-of-fresh-produce/106385768</link><description>Antarctica is the coldest, driest and windiest continent on the planet. But at Casey Station, Australian expeditioners have grown 130 kilos of fresh produce in a year thanks to a hydroponics facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29d3acdb2f66cfb3b7166a26f7fef394</guid></item><item><title>Heavy rain easing in Western Queensland as cyclone risk monitored in north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/heavy-rain-easing-in-western-queensland-cyclone-risk-monitored/106398412</link><description>Flooded communities in outback Queensland are set for some relief, with the Bureau of Meteorology expecting heavy rain to ease over the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccaac75cfaa331e0c0ebad6e896fae83</guid></item><item><title>Launceston City Council reveals $13 million increase for Princess Theatre, Earl Arts Centre upgrade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/questions-over-budget-for-earl-arts-centre-princess-theatre/106393242</link><description>The Launceston City Council has revealed the redevelopment of a historic theatre and arts centre will cost almost 50 per cent more than expected, but the mayor insists it is "not a cost blowout".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c867c47211d71550a54c83d463a4b741</guid></item><item><title>Doctor claims 'eleventh hour' condition on state election promise could tank Launceston hospital plans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/launceston-health-hub-hospital-state-government-jerome-muir/106350148</link><description>Medical experts fear a recently revealed condition on a Tasmanian election promise could kill a new hospital proposal, amid escalating concern about health facilities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">866cfd5db73d2a76f8bc3451b99d2c98</guid></item><item><title>Deniliquin mother creates sensory cape to support neurodivergent kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/sensory-suit-developed-by-mum-for-neurodivergent-kids/106305416</link><description>Lucy Horne has spent years perfecting a "sensory suit" to help her autistic son with overwhelming situations like going to the hairdresser, and now she wants to share it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49ff6005e44ab1a53591d0726957d914</guid></item><item><title>Can tax reform fix Australia's housing crisis? | Insiders: On Background</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/bernie-fraser-capital-gains-negative-gearing/106399160</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">296d946df142abd4b330041c438b0435</guid></item><item><title>Tram derails in central Milan leaving two dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/milan-tram-derailment-two-dead/106400002</link><description>A tram derails in the heart of Milan close to the city's Central Station, killing two people and injuring around 40 others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e925b11ff6fdebd58903f91fdef48bdf</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal community, linguists revive ancient Ngaiawang language of River Murray</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/ngaiawang-language-of-river-murray-revived-indigenous/106393092</link><description>Ngaiawang language, once spoken frequently along the sweeping bend of the River Murray or the Rinta, was almost wiped out by colonisation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60a199f204cedf6d8cf654d5d717370b</guid></item><item><title>Quick and easy green ginger and miso noodles made from pantry staples - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/phoebe-thorburn-spinach-ginger-miso-noodles-/106382102</link><description>Close the delivery app and get through some kitchen staples with this easy spinach, ginger and miso noodle recipe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54c8a9905e900c361424d1fe4f90a79e</guid></item><item><title>Safety warning to Victorian farmers after four work deaths in two months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/worksafe-victoria-farm-safety-campaign-agricultural-fatalities/106385668</link><description>The recent death of a respected Victorian dairy farmer has prompted fresh warnings about workplace dangers in the agricultural sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c6e834a24d9191eaacf9d50985fba3d</guid></item><item><title>Neil Sedaka, singer of Breaking Up Is Hard To Do, dies aged 86</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/neil-sedaka-dies-aged-86/106400078</link><description>Neil Sedaka, the American singer and songwriter who sold millions of records worldwide, dies aged 86.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1962d8f736a6fc3d1c94a074027fbcad</guid></item><item><title>How the 'amazing' Pretzel will help Scott march in Sydney's iconic Mardi Gras parade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/guide-dog-helps-owner-march-mardi-gras-parade-sydney/106397574</link><description>When Scott Dixon-Smith started his career, his workplace accommodated his blindness but not his sexuality. Tonight, he will march in the pride parade with the help of his guide dog, Pretzel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c6ca74b39b85087737841065748ca6e</guid></item><item><title>Regional mobile phone users lament lost service as complaints spike</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/regional-mobile-phone-service-decline-reliability-complaints/106392192</link><description>As reliability complaints increase, regional customers say mobile phone service is declining.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f09c65bb827a1fb04ddab8618b306c94</guid></item><item><title>Bolivian plane carrying banknotes crashes, leaving 20 people dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/bolivia-plane-crash-carrying-banknotes-15-people-dead-el-alto/106400144</link><description>A Bolivian Air Force Hercules aircraft carrying new banknotes crashes into a busy avenue, leaving 20 people dead and around 30 more injured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1215c62457b6a354038a46c025ff35c</guid></item><item><title>US President Trump orders six-month phase-out of Anthropic AI technology across government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/us-president-orders-six-month-phaseout-of-anthropic-technology/106400088</link><description>The Trump administration has ordered all US agencies to stop using Anthropic's artificial intelligence technology and imposed other major penalties, culminating an unusually public clash between the government and the company over AI safeguards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e455b1289cb17057b4778c442f3d86a</guid></item><item><title>Australian documentary Floodland uncovers human toll of 2022 Lismore floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/floodland-jordan-giusti-director-lismore-floods-documentary/106374088</link><description>Four years after floodwaters peaked at 14.4 metres in Lismore, a new documentary looks at how the town moved forward — and what more needs to be done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">250daf5a8fa92c7b262c219308388272</guid></item><item><title>Calls for SA election commitment to maintain feral deer eradication funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/sa-election-call-for-deer-eradication-funding-boost/106398198</link><description>More than 28,000 feral deer have been eradicated in South Australia since a program began in 2022, but conservationists say it needs a long-term funding commitment to finish the job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aee662c443c4b79f0cf31cbb2c658ddc</guid></item><item><title>What a Paramount-owned Warner Bros Discovery means for the movies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/what-happens-to-movies-if-paramount-owns-warner-bros/106400154</link><description>The proposed takeover of Warner Bros by Paramount could reshape Hollywood, movie theatres and the wider media landscape.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2555721a13a4e68aa1dcf008b72a1f08</guid></item><item><title>Facing threats of war, Denmark turns to a new weapon: women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/denmark-female-conscription-in-face-of-russia-us-threats/106339920</link><description>Denmark is fast-tracking female conscription as it muscles up to Russia and faces threats of invasion from the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17358269058443d144971ac8ba75b733</guid></item><item><title>Bolivian military plane crash kills 15</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/bolivian-military-plane-crash-kills-15-/106400308</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6ca75350046e2e4c423fda323b51d92</guid></item><item><title>NASA shakes up Moon program with new test mission before astronaut lunar landing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/nasa-shakes-up-moon-program-with-new-test-missio/106400186</link><description>NASA shakes up its Artemis Moon exploration program, adding an extra practice flight before a crewed lunar landing planned for two years' time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb040ecf12ae12852f2b7da8dfae70d2</guid></item><item><title>Peter V'landys confirms NRL's intentions to expand internationally beyond Las Vegas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/nrl-vlandys-confirms-expansion-plans-after-vegas-success/106400294</link><description>After experiencing tremendous success in Las Vegas, Peter V'landys is planning to take the NRL to other major cities around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a42a88997457a5c0515338cc65f4b5e</guid></item><item><title>FIFO workers keep football leagues alive in Pilbara towns with transient populations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/fifo-workers-keep-football-leagues-alive-in-pilbara/106259408</link><description>Local football leagues depend on FIFO workers to boost player numbers in remote and regional WA, and the workers say getting involved makes being away from home a little more enjoyable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62323fa63e19cc6d99ee7c449a160c7a</guid></item><item><title>Australia's almond industry cracks $1.3 billion mark as Chinese demand rises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/almond-industry-record-value-china-demand-increases/106394784</link><description>Australian almonds are breaking records as the trade war between the United States and China rolls on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6580d7c48ec5c7049f988870efb200b8</guid></item><item><title>Tiny Victorian photo album provides snapshot of a bygone era</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/tiny-victorian-photo-album-little-gem-tintype-photos/105925926</link><description>While wealthy upper-class colonial families were sitting for expensive studio portraits in the 1880s, many with less money were collecting miniature portraits in tiny photo albums like this one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97c44ec944e3b12b0b87483a28e9ff42</guid></item><item><title>Liberals launch Nepean candidate's campaign ahead of by-election challenge from One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/vic-liberal-candidate-nepean-by-election/106400212</link><description>The Liberal Party launches the campaign for candidate Anthony Marsh in the Nepean by-election, following the departure of Sam Groth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">869ec32afc9d0c4a9a22539aa7eb1341</guid></item><item><title>Pride in Protest float excluded from Sydney Mardi Gras over 'offensive' comments about Jewish LGBTQ group</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/pride-in-protest-excluded-sydney-mardi-gras-jewish-posts/106400076</link><description>Mardi Gras organisers have issued a formal warning to Pride in Protest on Friday morning, stating they had breached the parade's terms and conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f82046d4cc8abd76b61aa011b0d3ddcf</guid></item><item><title>Gorillaz album The Mountain exorcises death with Indian music greats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/gorillaz-the-mountain-album-damon-albarn-grief-india-afterlife/106381294</link><description>Damon Albarn and Jamie Hewlett discuss how trips to India, grieving and A-list collaborations shaped the latest genre-defying Gorillaz album, The Mountain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">001f036c6ad742a6590c591522d16158</guid></item><item><title>Professor MaryAnn Bin-Sallik remembered as a 'trailblazer' in Aboriginal education, health and rights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/aboriginal-professor-maryann-bin-sallik-remembered/106396478</link><description>MaryAnn Bin-Sallik was the first Aboriginal nurse graduate in Darwin and the first Aboriginal person to receive a PhD at Harvard University. Following her death at age 85, the Djaru Elder is being remembered for her work in Indigenous education, health and human rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaa3845831af7ecac1f05a52c3f4330c</guid></item><item><title>Lorraine Bayly, former Play School host and star of The Sullivans, dies aged 89</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/lorraine-bayly-playschool-sullivans-actor-dies/106400388</link><description>Lorraine Bayly, star of long-running soap opera The Sullivans and a former Play School host, has died aged 89, after years of ill health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fe0ad5896953b2ec458205c4b93fbd6</guid></item><item><title>Terror charges against Liam Hall and Jayson Michaels reveal challenge of maintaining social cohesion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/wa-terror-charges-threaten-social-cohesion/106400272</link><description>The charging of two young West Australian men with terror offences show the challenges facing social cohesion, and solving the problem is not going to be easy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e448820cf6c05290302532c88848f20b</guid></item><item><title>Terror police investigate disturbance, white powder at Perth Mosque</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/perth-mosque-target-of-disturbance-terror-police-probing/106399406</link><description>Terrorism police in Perth investigate a disturbance outside a Perth mosque overnight and the discovery of a "non-suspicious substance" on the footpath outside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">031550aefff469583806fe1c9e91ffb5</guid></item><item><title>Triple Melbourne Cup winner Makybe Diva dead at 27 after sudden health battle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/horse-racing-makybe-diva-dad-after-health-battle/106400516</link><description>The champion racehorse who rose to fame after combining with Glen Boss for three-straight Melbourne Cup wins has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ddb2a0f0d676a2d35140651e7dcf887</guid></item><item><title>Cheaper, easier and less taboo: Why more gen Zs are getting cosmetic injectables such as botox</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/gen-z-driving-boost-cosmetic-injectables/106258646</link><description>The number of non-surgical cosmetic procedures such as botox has increased by more than 44 per cent worldwide in four years. What's driving the increase?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c060f6cb0c2c60d0adc1b16fc8aeb818</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberal and Labor to preference David Speirs last at state election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/sa-liberal-and-labor-to-preference-david-speirs-last-at-election/106400228</link><description>Both major parties in South Australia say they will preference former opposition leader David Speirs last at the state election, as he rules out returning to the Liberal Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">858aa0addc895a2b2f16c9582523701c</guid></item><item><title>Trump says US has launched 'major operation' against Iran, with Israel calling 'pre-emptive' attack a joint effort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/iran-israel-explosion-tehran/106400716</link><description>US-Israeli strikes on Iran have prompted a string of retaliatory attacks and travel chaos across the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08b282e975f497e6702d24fbf479c050</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Gay and Lesbian Mardi Gras Parade draws thousands with politics at forefront</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/sydney-gay-and-lesbian-mardi-gras-2026-oxford-street/106386128</link><description>Glitter, sequins and political statements have been at the centre of Sydney's Gay and Lesbian Mardi Gras Parade along Oxford Street.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c003ed5ff3a97aa2c029569f8aace144</guid></item><item><title>Explosions across Middle East as Iranian retaliation puts Israel on alert — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/israel-us-attacking-iran-live-updates-blasts-in-tehran/106222024</link><description>Israel and the US have attacked Iran, with a swift response from Tehran threatening to widen the conflict across the Middle East. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28e2c3495d0aab60defa50b96b22c569</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump: Major combat operation in Iran underway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/donald-trump-major-combat-operation-in-iran-underway/106400848</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">730b480acf65495e3c77f60a56ce015b</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr admits to doubts surrounding injury issues ahead of Matildas Asian Cup campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/football-sam-kerr-injury-doubts-matildas-asian-cup-campaign/106400764</link><description>Sam Kerr says she is still not at 100 per cent as she details her moments of self-doubt during her return to Matildas colours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">720394a3977d5b26e4bddf5d880fb862</guid></item><item><title>Power disrupted at Flinders Medical Centre during Adelaide's morning storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/power-disrupted-at-flinders-medical-centre-amid-heavy-rain-sa/106400664</link><description>A temporary power disruption has impacted surgery capacity at one of Adelaide's largest hospitals as parts of the state received record rainfall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aada3bae916473da5b9252da759d3405</guid></item><item><title>Iranian TV airs footage of the aftermath of US-Israel strikes in Tehran</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/iran-television-destruction/106401010</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">207953283f2ef4801617d0c87a7fe3f2</guid></item><item><title>Israel and US attack Iran, sparking retaliatory strikes. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/what-we-know-about-the-israel-us-iran-strikes/106400988</link><description>After weeks of anticipation, Israel fired the first shot on Iran, drawing in the US and sparking retaliatory strikes that have hit several countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1321199f078f4813240a61e56426afa2</guid></item><item><title>Albanese says Australian government 'supports US acting to prevent Iran obtaining a nuclear weapon'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-28/australian-government-responds-to-united-states-attack-on-iran/106401108</link><description>Anthony Albanese says the international community has been clear that the Iranian regime can never be allowed to develop a nuclear weapon".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c2f23b0cd2e71f7e9b9f6cbc888ee23</guid></item><item><title>This US-Israeli strike on Iran is different and could lead to a longer, deadlier war</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/us-israeli-strikes-on-iran-could-lead-to-longer-war/106401110</link><description>It was clear within hours that this conflict is different and threatens to engulf the region in a longer, deadlier war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">273f7ec3f98962cc24efe688cd7b67d7</guid></item><item><title>Travellers stranded as US-Iran conflict throws international flights into chaos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/us-iran-conflict-causes-flight-chaos-strands-travellers/106401500</link><description>Among nations closing their airspace and suspending flights are major international transit hubs connecting Australian travellers with Europe and Asia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed61425da9b1866c16d96d5df55fb15</guid></item><item><title>Live: Netanyahu says there are 'many signs' Iran's supreme leader 'is gone'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/us-israel-launches-airstrikes-in-iran-live-blog/106401380</link><description>Benjamin Netanyahu says the compound of Supreme Leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei was destroyed and "there are many signs that this dictator is gone". Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d6fbd10c4210381350cc28a80b77bfd</guid></item><item><title>Astrology vs the algorithm: Why my Indian parents are hunting for my husband</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/marriage-arranged-indian-astrology-dating-app-romance-love-match/106382436</link><description>From Tinder-style apps to astrological birth charts — how today's arranged marriages blend tech and tradition in unexpected ways.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2efc790083a43943bd3233246fccb3b7</guid></item><item><title>Punch the monkey reminds us 'we all need soft spaces'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/punch-monkey-japan-soft-spaces/106393016</link><description>There's surely a reason we all went briefly nuts about a lonely little snow monkey called Punch living in a Japanese zoo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b443c70c362af315a7938db6500270c</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Get ready trivia nuts. It's time to play, HARD!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106288026</link><description>Have you been waiting all week to give this quiz another crack? You should probably find a hobby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b745c69ce66ba561ce92a9a71c75a666</guid></item><item><title>Arrested Development's long love affair with Australia continues with a trip to WOMADelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/arrested-development-speech-interview-womadelaide-hip-hop/106358486</link><description>The pioneering hip hop group returns to Australia this week, with big ideas about the future of hip hop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c4b6da2fbbd729977da4a8498c16e81</guid></item><item><title>Cheat Sheet: Weinstein, Gaza boycotts, dead bodies and 30 years of Scream</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/scream-7-boycott-melissa-barrera-neve-campbell/106392542</link><description>Weinstein, copycat panic, leaked scripts, closed studios and departing stars — Scream's 30-year journey has been anything but smooth and the seventh edition in the cornerstone slasher series is no different.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73bb21de7b19759ac88047148fe57a61</guid></item><item><title>Women trafficked, kids taught to shoot in PNG's tribal warfare industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/modern-weapons-changing-png-tribal-warfare/106380226</link><description>The proliferation of illegal high-powered guns is fuelling tribal warfare across Papua New Guinea and warlords claim children as young as eight are being trained to carry the weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28f8428117a4428745463fe19c0bb2d8</guid></item><item><title>Former NSW prison officers say system protects abusers and silences women</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/former-prison-officers-speak-out-about-nsw-corrections-system/106398318</link><description>Current and former NSW prison officers describe what they say is a toxic workplace culture and a system that shields officers accused of serious misconduct, rather than holding them accountable. They argue it has driven younger officers out of the service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5be0483b18c80258ab18af5e93a6d50</guid></item><item><title>Seventh narco sub discovered in the Pacific as Australia's cocaine habit drives heavy traffic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/drugs-cocaine-australia-narco-subs-pacific/106390402</link><description>At least seven narco subs have been discovered in Pacific waters near Australia over the past 18 months, with experts warning that Australia's cocaine demand means more are on the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d8f98671f5b2c416d5ca85587c9a1b1</guid></item><item><title>NSW unveils sweeping foster care reforms for thousands of vulnerable children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/nsw-foster-care-reforms-for-thousands-vulnerable-children/106398894</link><description>While some child protection services will continue to be outsourced, the NSW government will play a larger role in the sector, including through the recruitment of foster carers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd068b66bee5e482846c38b6f2fa10bc</guid></item><item><title>Meet the mapmakers recording every remote road in Australia to keep travellers safer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/map-patrol-checks-remote-tracks-google-maps-cannot-cover/106259210</link><description>Google Maps has made city driving a dream, but it's putting lives at risk in the bush. Meet the mapmakers taking on Australia's roughest roads to try to change that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99176f0634c7c7b6a8b216a7e0764087</guid></item><item><title>Medical Board of Australia to appeal decision allowing Dr Dileepa Jayaweera to continue working at Ballarat clinic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/medical-board-australia-appeals-dileepa-jayaweera-vcat-decision/106375838</link><description>The Medical Board of Australia is appealing a tribunal decision that allowed a Ballarat doctor accused of digitally penetrating a female patient to continue working at the same clinic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bc0b420ffd3a0f947f7bc82026273d1</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup hopes to change women's football in Australia — again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/womens-asian-cup-hoped-to-change-womens-football-in-australia/106400994</link><description>The Matildas' run in the 2023 World Cup saw unprecedented media coverage and crowds, and a participation boom among girls and women. Can the Asian Cup do the same?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7eedc698a02dcf53314a05b0f1d9b2f4</guid></item><item><title>Tehran retaliates across Middle East after US and Israel launch strikes aimed at regime change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/iran-missiles-shake-gulf-states-after-us-israel-strike-tehran/106401498</link><description>Bahrain, Qatar, Jordan and Israel were targeted by Iran after Donald Trump said the strikes were aimed at regime change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67cfa34aa78f84889fa47788b0af65a9</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: What time do the Matildas play? How to watch and follow Australia vs the Philippines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/matildas-vs-philippines-how-to-watch/106399058</link><description>The Women's Asian Cup is finally upon us, with the Matildas beginning their quest for a second continental crown against the Philippines in Perth. This is all the need to know information, plus how to watch and follow the tournament opener.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5cfee17f0c281d226b3b73bd0621938</guid></item><item><title>Domestic violence accounts for 40pc of the more than 200 kidnappings that take place annually in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/nsw-records-more-than-200-kidnappings-40pc-due-domestic-violence/106397414</link><description>Data shows that in the year to September 2025, NSW Police received 230 abduction and kidnapping reports — up from 224 in the previous year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebd11b90588784e4e19e5eb40128237b</guid></item><item><title>Minjee Lee and Hannah Green set for all-Aussie shootout in Women's World Championship final round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/minjee-lee-hannah-green-lead-womens-world-championship/106401716</link><description>Australian duo Minjee Lee and Hannah Green share a one-shot lead in Singapore with 18 holes of the Women's World Championship to play.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7377e54378f97806cb229256f38a10a</guid></item><item><title>Growing expectations Lake Eyre could reach full capacity for first time in decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/could-lake-eyre-finally-reach-capacity-after-decades/106395774</link><description>In the centre of Australia, there are whispers that Kati Thanda-Lake Eyre is experiencing conditions strangely similar to those that set a record depth of 6 metres in 1974.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a7da95dcdc507290d245f264442922f</guid></item><item><title>Extreme rhetoric in Australia's right-wing political circles deserves more attention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-03-01/extreme-rhetoric-australia-right-wing-circles-deserves-attention/106395138</link><description>The rhetoric in Australia's right-wing political circles is getting more extreme and the media should be paying more attention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">348954e35462858407cf5ddf639ebafc</guid></item></channel></rss>