<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 10:44:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Outback ringmaster Fred Brophy takes his boxing tent to Birdsville for last time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/fred-brophy-takes-boxing-tent-to-birdsville-for-last-time/105761756</link><description>Fred Brophy will sell you a ticket, spin you a yarn and dare you into the ring, but at 73, the outback ringmaster is slowing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9c596e0ff31abe53e3cdc3f15b54fcc</guid></item><item><title>Prince Harry says he has no regrets about 2023 memoir Spare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/prince-harry-defends-his-memoir/105773344</link><description>Prince Harry has defended his tell-all autobiography Spare, insisting he has no regrets about its publication.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">822f9b8bfc9e038c4a05c240f351b362</guid></item><item><title>Man sentenced over 'shocking' assault during October 2023 Malmsbury Youth Justice Centre riot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/man-sentenced-2023-malmsbury-youth-justice-centre-assault/105773100</link><description>A former youth detainee is jailed over a violent assault that took place when a group of inmates stole a set of keys and sent the Malmsbury Youth Justice Centre into lockdown in October 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4aba14cd05a983ffcc76e432e5cf7eb0</guid></item><item><title>How is Australia affected by climate change? The National Climate Risk Assessment models the future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/national-climate-risk-assessment-and-why-it-matters-explained/105773936</link><description>For the first time, the government has modelled the threats from climate change on Australia's future. What's the point of a document like this, and can it help us avoid the worst-case scenarios?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ad84229da5de3e8a79b28e4eacc8cab</guid></item><item><title>Trial of trio accused of 2022 stabbing murder of David Wayne Jenkins hears from friends of co-accused</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/george-town-murder-trial-of-david-wayne-jenkins-day-five/105773528</link><description>A murder trial has heard one of the co-accused men was "scared", "frantic", "very, very sweaty" and "swearing to God he didn't do it" after a confrontation in which a man died of stab wounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">804572674f3c20077446202863ed024f</guid></item><item><title>Former MMA fighter Conor McGregor drops out of Irish presidential race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/conor-mcgregor-drops-out-of-irish-presidential-race-/105776960</link><description>Critics say the former MMA fighter's pre-emptive dropout was to save face in a likely knockout at the hands of Dublin City Council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60f1b0734e35fba4e5506343df9a6d2a</guid></item><item><title>Use constitutional power to raise age of criminal responsibility nationwide, lawyers tell PM</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/pm-letter-raise-the-age/105748868</link><description>Forty years ago, the federal government used the constitution to halt construction of the Franklin Dam. Now lawyers want the Albanese government to do the same to keep kids out of jails.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7b875978506038b9b93d5a66cdfdece</guid></item><item><title>What to expect from Donald Trump's state visit to the UK</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/what-to-expect-donald-trump-uk-state-visit-king-charles/105776968</link><description>The US president will arrive in London on Tuesday evening, local time, for an unprecedented second state visit to the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19d933d53256fb1c8c6c8419ba9dba94</guid></item><item><title>Fears parts of Queensland will have to 'retreat' amid predicted sea level rise and increased severe weather events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/climate-report-national-climate-risk-assessment-queensland/105775976</link><description>The warning comes amid a national report finding up to 185,000 residential buildings in Queensland could be in "very high-risk areas" if climate change is not addressed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c13eb12a1db1234d6f66dae28d2620c</guid></item><item><title>Future of Bendigo Writers Festival unclear amid calls for transparent review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/bendigo-writers-festival-future-unclear-after-boycott/105773484</link><description>A councillor is demanding answers from his own executive over the botched Bendigo Writers Festival, asking colleagues whether they want to be remembered as the council that "killed" it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a2675a41175e051c99bd70c72ebf69a</guid></item><item><title>Shire of Coolgardie awaits decision on future after giving evidence to minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/shire-of-coolgardie-show-cause-notice-response/105774072</link><description>The embattled Shire of Coolgardie waits to hear whether it will be suspended ahead of local government elections over concerns about financial and managerial mismanagement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a60af1587b72855d0965e133f66c3a65</guid></item><item><title>Lisa Reihana's exhibition, Voyager, recasts history through an Indigenous lens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/lisa-reihana-ngununggula-exhibition-voyager-indigenous-maori/105760474</link><description>The internationally renowned Maori artist's technically complex, visually mesmerising exhibition spans nearly a decade of artwork.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ed46a76298102094bcf604b8536fb9b</guid></item><item><title>Family comes first for Queensland newsreader Rob Brough after months off air</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/newsreader-rob-broughs-family-battle/105775464</link><description>The long-time nightly newsreader says it was an "instant choice" to leave work as his daughter faced a battle with cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23d10f83e00ccce3717d0f0a569d4a1c</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds announce netball squads for Test series against New Zealand, South Africa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/australia-diamonds-announce-test-netball-squads-new-zealand-sa/105779230</link><description>Goal-shooter Lucy Austin is a shock selection in the Australian netball squad to face South Africa, winning a place after initially being included as an "invitee" to their training camp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f84722b6abee542504171a8343b1b82</guid></item><item><title>Israel is committing genocide in Gaza, major United Nations report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/israel-committing-genocide-in-gaza-un-report-says/105780230</link><description>Israel has committed and is continuing to commit genocide in Gaza, according to the "most authoritative assessment" to date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e547fcd275b42fb12bbaa7d9028fd7aa</guid></item><item><title>China accuses Philippines of 'illegal' intrusion at its new nature reserve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/china-accuses-philippines-of-illegal-intrusion-at-new-reserve/105781038</link><description>China's coastguard has accused Philippine ships of illegally entering China's territorial waters at a shoal that is internationally recognised as within the Philippines' exclusive economic zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d22fae2218c2b953ce31ac500d27401e</guid></item><item><title>Man 'choked to death' on ribbons and food in Adelaide nursing home, inquest told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/sa-inquest-hears-nursing-home-resident-choked-on-ribbons/105697736</link><description>A nursing home resident known to wander and ingest foreign objects died after choking on ribbons at a facility in Adelaide’s north, an inquest has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95ba5d590939d36f5248d85d89547a6f</guid></item><item><title>Trial of trio accused of 2022 stabbing murder of David Wayne Jenkins hears from co-accused's police officer cousin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/george-town-murder-trial-david-wayne-jenkins-day-six/105778162</link><description>A man on trial for murder had a flight booked for him in another person's name hours after the event where a man was fatally stabbed 11 times, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59ab09fbda07d50324fc729005b4849f</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste protesters vow to continue rallying until plan to buy MPs 65 cars is overturned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/timor-leste-protests-over-mp-car-plan-grow/105781726</link><description>The protests nearly doubled in size on Tuesday as people continued to vent their frustrations at a plan to buy MPs 65 new SUVs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">feeb6a6ab4a2322ebf2709358b8c2353</guid></item><item><title>WA Police officers subject to restraining orders desk-bound under gun reforms, union says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/wa-police-taken-off-beat-under-gun-reforms/105743700</link><description>New firearms laws meaning WA Police officers can't carry a gun if they're subject to a restraining order are leaving them desk-bound, their union warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9778f00d409cd20aa6f59b898e30bc37</guid></item><item><title>Australia and PNG fail to clinch defence agreement, resorting to communique</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/australia-png-fail-defence-agreement-communique/105782424</link><description>A major defence treaty between Australia and Papua New Guinea has failed to get over the line today, with the countries resorting to signing a communique in lieu of the actual document.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d5916f8d88a6bb049ef9ef389165d8e</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested over alleged domestic violence-related death of Palmerston woman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/nt-police-arrest-man-over-death-of-female-partner-in-palmerston/105782526</link><description>A man has been arrested over the alleged domestic violence-related death of his female partner overnight, after she was found unresponsive in the front yard of a Palmerston home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7c47df92c73582fdc3ec37e313630f3</guid></item><item><title>Farmer asks partner to marry him with special canola crop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/farmer-asks-partner-to-marry-him-with-canola-crop/105783070</link><description>NSW farmer Will Henderson had no choice but to bide his time to pop the question. In the end his efforts were rewarded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05e5cefa73531016d6c02d243bfa85a7</guid></item><item><title>Australia refusing to panic over Pat Cummins's injury ahead of Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/ashes-cricket-australia-england-pat-cummins-injury/105785808</link><description>Australia coach Andrew McDonald is confident injured captain Pat Cummins will be fit to play a major role in the men's Ashes, even if he does not feature in all five matches of the series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3764f86fe491f37a58f6d749d3f0b446</guid></item><item><title>Hasan Piker opens up on Charlie Kirk's death, Donald Trump and Elon Musk's campaign against him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/hasan-piker-speaks-charlie-kirk-death-and-death-threats-trump/105784072</link><description>Prominent left-wing commentator Hasan Piker opens up to 7.30 on Donald Trump's left-wing crackdown, the Charlie Kirk he knew and attempts to have him deplatformed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b7081bd7a10cb144ba6685b100983fa</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout finishes third in 200m heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/gout-gout-finishes-third-in-200m-heat/105786314</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d8312214b2b9a31a74786f0c79c4763</guid></item><item><title>Man claims council bid to remove 'therapy' roosters is contrary to human rights conventions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/therapy-roosters-owner-tries-to-halt-court-proceedings/105775968</link><description>A South Australian council has taken a disability pensioner to court to remove his allegedly noisy roosters, but he has argued the council's application should not proceed because it is discriminatory and the birds are his "therapeutic" animals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12ef938f04ff77b3326d973d37ac0830</guid></item><item><title>A flowering grass tree on Andy McCoubrie's property attracted plenty of visitors.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/a-flowering-grass-tree-on-andy-mccoubries-property/105783970</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cda0bf78608d2a2e4639a2e00ba39db0</guid></item><item><title>Gaming history goes on display with Australian titles Hollow Knight Silksong and Team Fortress chronicled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/acmi-game-worlds-hollow-knight-silksong-neopets-team-fortress/105754152</link><description>An exhibition at Melbourne's ACMI will pull back the curtain on how iconic games like Hollow Knight Silksong, Team Fortress, Neopets and Sim City were made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fccda39e18804bf9590546dadaed39f</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill launches LGBTQIA+ festival Rainbow in the Outback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/broken-hill-lgbtqia-festival-rainbow-in-the-outback/105782774</link><description>The outback city of Broken Hill is no stranger to celebrating the LGBTQIA+ community, with a new festival focusing on diversity and inclusion launching last weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cca328c6d304217ca3ecde48d89cfac4</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk shooting suspect Tyler Robinson surrendered in fear of being shot by police, sheriff says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/tyler-robinson-feared-being-shot-after-charlie-kirk-killing/105787132</link><description>Tyler Robinson, the Utah man accused of killing political activist Charlie Kirk, only agreed to surrender if it was done peacefully, a sheriff involved with his arrest says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">191a6a7daacb0a8a62ab28fc38a95c90</guid></item><item><title>Brittany Higgins files last-day appeal over ex-senator Linda Reynolds's defamation win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/brittany-higgins-appeal-over-linda-reynolds-defamation-ruling/105787774</link><description>Brittany Higgins lodges an appeal against a WA Supreme Court judgement that she defamed her former boss and ex-Liberal senator Linda Reynolds in social media posts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48e1405575ae54fb34788f0c57fd4e45</guid></item><item><title>Amid Trump's biggest, best state visit ever, the king delivers a pointed message</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/trump-state-visit-king-charles-message/105788584</link><description>Amid the diamonds, whisky sours and flattery of a royal banquet for Donald Trump's state visit, tiara diplomacy was on full display.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55c7f64974504498042a988379cc1542</guid></item><item><title>Authorities urge parents to check Little Ones Nappy Pants for khapra beetle larvae</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nappy-pants-still-unaccounted-for-khapra-beetle-larvae-found/105787812</link><description>Hundreds of cartons of nappy pants remain unaccounted for after one of the biggest threats to Australia's grain industry, khapra beetle larvae, was found in the imported products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45cfd2bf95d89861ab6dc3f7a688868c</guid></item><item><title>Cats coach Chris Scott regrets run-in with AFL staffer after qualifying final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/geelong-cats-chris-scott-afl-staff-qualifying-final/105789664</link><description>Geelong coach Chris Scott says long-held frustration with the AFL was behind his regrettable post-qualifying final win outburst at a junior league employee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64f8afe41599735121373a93d14d1aff</guid></item><item><title>Hobart stadium proponent dismisses planning commission key issues as 'matters of opinion'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/tasmania-hobart-macquarie-point-stadium-tpc-report-opinions/105787276</link><description>The agency behind Hobart's Macquarie Point stadium build says it is undeterred by the three key issues raised by the recent planning commission's final report, arguing it comes down to "priorities".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95214532bc602d9fbcd7742ff8b727a4</guid></item><item><title>Family of Aboriginal man killed in Darwin hit-and-run speak out over driver's sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/family-of-man-killed-in-darwin-hit-and-run-speak-out/105787700</link><description>The family of an Aboriginal man killed in a hit-and-run in Darwin have spoken out about the sentence handed to the man who killed him, and the "racist, dehumanising" messages he sent afterwards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc87964fabc0227fe5c48880a62ad60b</guid></item><item><title>Domestic violence comments on fishing show breached classification rules: ACMA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/domestic-violence-comments-on-channel-seven-in-breach-says-acma/105789254</link><description>An exchange about domestic violence between 'Bush Cook Ranger Nick' and the host of Step Outside with Paul Burt, broadcast on 7mate, was in breach of classification rules, the watchdog has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0793754492a6a1f2c4bb7b9112a6cb41</guid></item><item><title>Henley residents advised to keep windows, doors closed amid algal bloom crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/sa-beach-residents-algal-bloom-advice/105790474</link><description>Authorities have told a group of residents living near a metropolitan Adelaide beach to close their doors and windows to prevent symptoms related to South Australia's ongoing algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">094835ce530689c0fec54c85ace98853</guid></item><item><title>The Albanese government has learned from the last major climate commitment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/2035-target-energy-debate-power-prices/105787072</link><description>The government is keenly aware that the cost of the transition is a sensitive issue, which is why the prime minister was flanked not just by his climate minister but also his treasurer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb04f44e27c2583896465cd35dce2ecb</guid></item><item><title>Bindi Magic art exhibition opens in Alice Springs as organisation celebrates 25 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/bindi-magic-art-exhibition-opens-in-alice-springs/105789908</link><description>For 25 years Bindi Mwerre Anthurre Artists has been helping people with a disability to communicate through creativity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac6f9add20cd12006d1f874f0c4e4ec</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Jimmy Kimmel off-air for 'bad ratings' as Democrats slam regulator for 'bullying' US ABC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/trump-kimmel-bad-ratings-democrats-fcc-bullying/105791856</link><description>Prominent leaders in the Democratic Party are accusing the US's communications regulator of "bullying" a network to take the long-running late night show off air.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a35d01ad79ff21536357113faa2da610</guid></item><item><title>Independent advice spells out mammoth task ahead for government to reach 2035 target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/the-task-ahead-to-reach-2035-emissions-target/105789538</link><description>Getting to even the bottom end of the government's 62 to 70 per cent emissions reduction target by 2035 will require drastic increases to solar and wind power capacity, electric vehicle take-up and an extension of the safeguard mechanism, according to the Climate Change Authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">112c61869ecf0e96b28c94212500d843</guid></item><item><title>After deadly floods in Bali, its people want answers. Many are blaming overtourism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bali-overtourism-blamed-in-wake-of-deadly-floods/105785674</link><description>Unexpected and deadly flooding rocked Bali last week at a scale many had never experienced before. In the wake of this disaster, the search for answers has begun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">744d51865bef7cb34f9b946d580e8498</guid></item><item><title>First Guardian, Shield superannuation disasters expose deep flaws in Australia's $4.3 trillion retirement system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/first-guardian-shield-collapse-asic-and-superannuation-flaws/105783328</link><description>The failed First Guardian and Shield schemes have cost about 12,000 Australians more than $1 billion in retirement savings and exposed deep flaws in how Australia's $4.3 trillion superannuation sector is regulated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b80687a0c984dcbca73fbbe0b5a3dbb7</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Albanese seizes on Ley's climate slip up — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/federal-politics-live-sept-19/105790890</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has seized on remarks made by Opposition Leader Sussan Ley about Australia's climate targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d8c53f5355ddd10031e0a3f823e1972</guid></item><item><title>AFL finals fever takes hold as fans line up to buy tickets offline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/fans-line-up-for-afl-grand-final-tickets/105783152</link><description>AFL fans fed up with the online ticketing system have opted to line up in person days in advance to secure their finals tickets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae67e6d9e7b54c457bfa6e91a30fd4f7</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout misses out on 200m final at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gout-gout-misses-out-on-200m-final-at-world-athletics-/105792462</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44814bf4d05e24efb9a86e9874126c57</guid></item><item><title>Young members bring new life to the Rural Fire Service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/rural-fire-service-brigades-seek-new-members/105778996</link><description>Nearly a quarter of all western NSW Rural Fire Service volunteers are older than 70, but some younger recruits are urging others to follow in their footsteps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a9645dec99c6b79501e9b7ecffcd0c1</guid></item><item><title>How Hawthorn can upset Geelong as the Hawks meet the Cats in 2025 AFL preliminary final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/afl-preliminary-final-preview-geelong-vs-hawthorn/105792398</link><description>With a plethora of options up forward, there's one issue the Hawks need to pay attention to out of their back half if they want to upset the Cats tonight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">690d853e61b84e53b4907310f22bd294</guid></item><item><title>RONA. weaves together country, colonialism and club music on new EP It's All Here</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/rona-its-all-here-ep-bush-beats-country-colonialism-club-music/105758094</link><description>This Kaytetye producer has a fresh take on the space race that draws from First Nations knowledge and culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f63cbfd798f6826103c82f171f571494</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police arrest seven people over stabbing deaths of two boys at Cobblebank</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/victoria-police-arrest-seven-people-over-stabbing/105794330</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40d779dc059b3fc23e9d42dade8cdefc</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann likely to face four-day hearing in Tasmania over motor vehicle stealing charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bruce-lehrmann-likely-to-face-four-day-hearing/105794304</link><description>Former Liberal staffer Bruce Lehrmann appears in the Hobart Magistrates Court after pleading not guilty to one count of motor vehicle stealing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">680bec6e2ce2b4d53ae9b27667c53e23</guid></item><item><title>Russell Vale Mine Shaft 4 to trial Green Gravity renewable energy technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/russell-vale-mine-shaft-4-to-trial-green-gravity/105780830</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89d1b1e00372ede47986a5b7fb9f02ce</guid></item><item><title>China urges Papua New Guinea not to exclude other countries after it signed 'Pukpuk' communique with Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/china-warns-papua-new-guinea-against-bilateral-deal-australia/105794018</link><description>China has urged Papua New Guinea not to sign any deal that might exclude or restrict third parties from cooperating with the Pacific nation, as Australia scrambles to clinch a landmark defence treaty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad04d0391ea73681a5f0351d55692b32</guid></item><item><title>Late-night hosts call out 'unitary intimidation' in aftermath of Jimmy Kimmel's axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/stephen-colbert-seth-meyers-jon-stewart-back-jimmy-kimmel/105794466</link><description>Jimmy Kimmel's fellow late-night stars accuse the Trump administration of overriding free speech with the indefinite axing of the ABC America host, as parent company, Walt Disney, faces growing protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2f64fab37da9ee4ace2388f587b1eab</guid></item><item><title>Hakyung Lee, mother accused of killing children, had a 'disease of the mind', defence expert tells court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/hakyung-lee-suitcase-murders-auckland-new-zealand/105781562</link><description>Hakyung Lee has been charged with murdering her children and has pleaded not guilty by reason of insanity after leaving their bodies in an Auckland storage facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">690cb00a0c2ca94e57c34909bfc58001</guid></item><item><title>Sharks vow not to taunt Raiders in sudden-death NRL semifinal as minor premiers look to bounce back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/nrl-cronulla-sharks-canberra-raiders-semi-final/105795410</link><description>Cronulla suggests it will not niggle Canberra in Saturday night's semifinal, despite the Brisbane Broncos successfully getting under the Raiders' skin in their thrilling one-point win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de811a022c87a3d1a6baef74c8c54ce6</guid></item><item><title>Patrick Dangerfield stars to send Geelong into the AFL grand final as concussion rules Tom Stewart out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/afl-preliminary-final-geelong-vs-hawthorn-live-blog/105779366</link><description>Geelong utility Tom Stewart will miss the AFL grand final, but coach Chris Scott feels his Cats are in a great position to win the premiership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dd33f956ae78d4a6741605fb30417b7</guid></item><item><title>DV support services say more women are seeking help for coercive control since new state laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/slow-but-consistent-uptake-of-new-coercive-control-laws-nsw/105795204</link><description>A snapshot of the state's recent coercive control laws suggests there has been a "slow but consistent" uptake of the new offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f6288202d81a123e07877a555f48d8</guid></item><item><title>Optus CEO apologises to customers impacted by major network outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/optus-ceo-apologises-to-customers-impacted-by/105796546</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76fd1e56e640c3fcc4ec93132683da1d</guid></item><item><title>Optus CEO confirms three deaths during network outage affecting emergency calls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/optus-ceo-confirms-three-deaths-during-network/105796530</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2616d41c37b08dbe3f6b1464bddea5b</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the Optus outage which disrupted triple-zero calls, linked to three deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/what-we-know-about-optus-network-outage/105796618</link><description>It's been two days since three people died after a devastating Optus outage caused hundreds of emergency calls to fail, but information about the incident remains scarce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81d841cfe097dc82a144e78eb4423953</guid></item><item><title>Pink Floyd's album and ode to Syd Barrett Wish You Were Here turns 50</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/pink-floyd-wish-you-were-here-turns-50/105782374</link><description>Pink Floyd looked to the past to find a way forward after the massive success of Dark Side Of The Moon in 1973. The result was Wish You Were Here, released 50 years ago this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78a552157b44e92ce3d5f5773e471f3d</guid></item><item><title>Victor Caulfield moved to Florence in his 70s and became an artists' model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/victor-caulfield-moved-to-florence-and-became-an-artists-model/105762988</link><description>Victor Caulfield packed up his Australian home and moved to Italy, where he fell into the art scene as an accidental model.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf11c6e1cc2bef7d1c59c017a7b1915d</guid></item><item><title>One-tray honey chicken wings are an easy family dinner - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/one-tray-sticky-chicken-wings/105658174</link><description>It’s easy to make these irresistibly sticky wings that will have you licking your fingers and reaching for more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b49e38fcb0cc57c3220c789ba5301301</guid></item><item><title>Eucalypt trail named after botanist Dean Nicolle opens in SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/rail-trail-forest-blyth-dean-nicolle-eucalypt-walk-sa/105779316</link><description>A unique partnership between an artist and a botanist has resulted in an old rail corridor in South Australia becoming an eucalypt forest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a634367098f7c56af4d4f383b07c47fd</guid></item><item><title>'America is not happy': ABC under fire for pulling Jimmy Kimmel Live!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/complaints-about-kimmel-axing-meant-for-us-abc-sent-to-australia/105793428</link><description>The ABC has received hundreds of complaints about US talk show Jimmy Kimmel Live! being pulled off air and threats to boycott sponsors ... but that's the problem when two broadcasters from different countries share a name!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">058463060dc5663ada42854e5496b80c</guid></item><item><title>UN says there's evidence organised crime scam centres are moving from South-East Asia into new frontier of the Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/organised-crime-scam-centres-move-into-pacific-united-nations/105775972</link><description>As scam centres run by organised crime find it harder to operate in South-East Asia, evidence emerges of them moving into the Pacific and setting up lucrative operations estimated to net billions each year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb89464594316563fc34dc56a716880e</guid></item><item><title>Transition from sheep to cropping in WA's Avon Valley leaving limited balloon landing sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/crops-to-sheep-hot-air-balloon-landing-sites/105794124</link><description>The move out of sheep by an increasing number of WA farmers is having an unexpected impact on the state's hot air balloon pilots.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c79d7f50ce8880f2a74edb7c05cab83</guid></item><item><title>Yolŋu people celebrate 50 years of the homelands movement in East Arnhem Land</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/nt-laynhapuy-homelands-movement-anniversary-indigenous-yolngu/105796404</link><description>Yolŋu children from nine Laynhapuy communities are screaming the Yothu Yindi anthem, Homeland Movement, in a ceremony celebrating the Indigenous elders who claimed back life on their country 50 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3184235034372056a06780912d5fe26e</guid></item><item><title>Minister slams 'extremist' candidates nominating for WA council elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/wa-minister-condemns-extremist-council-candidates/105739550</link><description>Local Government Minister Hannah Beazely condemns the emergence of "extremist" candidates nominating for the state's forthcoming council elections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bcdc6a1da26fcdf49227a137e3eb1f7</guid></item><item><title>What is 'Solastalgia' and how are climate-affected communities tackling it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/climate-change-anxiety-first-nations-communities-respond/105793766</link><description>If you're overwhelmed by emissions targets, climate change and environmental collapse, start small and look to First Nations practices to help your wellbeing and the world around you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bff8375209835a394c77e6936900b17</guid></item><item><title>Antinatalists say human suffering, and climate change, makes having children unethical. Are they right?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/antinatalism-child-free-climate-change-human-suffering-baby/105695328</link><description>Elon Musk believes the collapsing birth rate is humanity's biggest danger. But antinatalists argue having kids is little more than a procreational Ponzi scheme, and the risks are real.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28999cb939ddfbe63b4a8339d72f435e</guid></item><item><title>Asia's protests grew from social media where misinformation also spread</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/nepal-indonesia-gen-z-social-media-misinformation/105779038</link><description>These movements may be separated by time, distance and language, but they were all born on social media, led by a new generation of activists fed up with the old systems of corruption and nepotism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">553dda439e393b87eb7b6bc4eff754a9</guid></item><item><title>What makes China confident enough to ban microchips made by US firm Nvidia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/what-makes-china-confident-to-ban-nvdia-microchips/105795486</link><description>Beijing's decision this week to ban Chinese companies from using microchips made by US firm Nvidia indicates the country is increasingly confident about replacing them with domestically produced chips, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c451e4e0710bc1516100c22ae7e23289</guid></item><item><title>Pirate attacks and sea robberies surge in key South-East Asian shipping lane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/piracy-sea-robberies-rise-malacca-strait-asia/105736740</link><description>Piracy and sea robberies are increasing in the strategic straits of Malacca and Singapore, which could have implications for Australian imports and exports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2b3b37fb5cc2fee69c406b2aa0ccdc5</guid></item><item><title>Street artist Rone's new 90-metre mural a visual love letter to Geelong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/tyrone-rone-wright-new-mural-captures-geelong-faces/105762354</link><description>The faces of 14 people will be immortalised in an enormous mural on the side of a new building in Geelong by locally born, globally renowned artist Rone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28ac13e735d6c51ed4a4df9593e87271</guid></item><item><title>Inside Ninga Mia, a forgotten community in the shadow of Kalgoorlie the city of gold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/ninga-mia-kalgoorlie-mining-aboriginal-reserve-homelessness-gold/105774862</link><description>There's an eerie silence in Ninga Mia, a once thriving community on the edge of Kalgoorlie. The Aboriginal reserve is a microcosm of the cycle of displacement endured by many First Nations people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eafa5daeccecbae05c7c9ef093e72c5</guid></item><item><title>Government has not set 2035 renewables target, downplays 90 per cent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/government-yet-to-set-2035-renewables-target/105798906</link><description>In New York for the UN summit, Energy Minister Chris Bowen declines to offer a renewable energy target for 2035 after the Climate Change Authority projected more than 90 per cent would be needed to hit its recommended emissions target.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4880a6213f11733719ca49464957e58</guid></item><item><title>Koori Court marks 20 years in Mildura as Victoria approaches treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/twenty-years-of-koori-justice-in-mildura-victorias-north-west/105784288</link><description>Mildura marks two decades since its Koori Court opened, as Victoria sees mixed results in the push to reduce Indigenous incarceration and offending rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d57275cbeb1abf5d81f15d9fb2c32b08</guid></item><item><title>Life on Aboriginal reserve remembered by Carnarvon traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/aboriginal-reserve-memories-carnarvon-traditional-owners/105510728</link><description>In 1975, an anthropologist wrote his thesis on Carnarvon's rich Aboriginal reserve. Decades later, traditional owners revisit the work to contribute to "big truth-telling" documentary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf8bb607751e84f71648e4dfa5cd44a</guid></item><item><title>Australian-born singer drops out of Russian-hosted Intervision song contest after 'political pressure'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australian-born-singer-drops-out-of-russian-hosted-song-contest/105799020</link><description>Vassy dropped out of the contest at the last minute after coming under what Russian organisers said was "unprecedented political pressure from the government of Australia".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6f53824a2ed40b9ae66bd7ebdb25e1a</guid></item><item><title>Penola High School's agriculture program revives community and enrolments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/penola-high-school-ag-program-revives-falling-enrolments/105787042</link><description>Cory O'Connor's three-week teaching placement turned around his hometown high school. Now he's receiving an award for the agriculture program he started there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">800678cadea15a18ec482186c893d046</guid></item><item><title>Cats star Tyson Stengle desperate to win second AFL premiership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/afl-grand-final-geelong-cats-brisbane-lions-tyson-stengle/105799288</link><description>Three years after Tyson Stengle capped off his remarkable AFL career resurrection with a premiership, the Geelong forward believes a second premiership would hold greater significance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4c3712d165c2a42a93ac12de61b5a9d</guid></item><item><title>How to clean out your wardrobe as the seasons change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/how-to-spring-clean-wardobe-clean-out/105780140</link><description>It's the kind of task that can seem overwhelming, but the change of season is the perfect opportunity to review what's in your wardrobe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf9c7f0a36323b3457588962f5d0b0b0</guid></item><item><title>Optus CEO confirms further customer report calls, service outage at NSW-SA border.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/optus-ceo-confirms-further-customer-report-calls,/105799496</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99f2ad74ac543864780c38476c5a3384</guid></item><item><title>Dayne Zorko fined by AFL for targeting Mason Cox's glasses in Lions' win over Magpies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/afl-brisbane-lions-collingwood-magpies-dayne-zorko-mason-cox/105799528</link><description>Brisbane Lions stalwart Dayne Zorko is punished by the AFL after he ripped off Mason Cox's glasses during their fiery preliminary final clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34b6f6c464fdb14a9fdb5f312f87feab</guid></item><item><title>Australia formally recognises state of Palestine as Anthony Albanese arrives in US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australia-formally-recognises-state-of-palestine/105799238</link><description>The historic decision foreshadowed last month has now become a reality, as Australia moves with Canada and the United Kingdom to join the growing list of countries to recognise Palestinian sovereignty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f7f36cbe6b5b1fbaaf3e78efd2951a2</guid></item><item><title>Can recognising the state of Palestine achieve a two-state solution as Israel continues bombing Gaza?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australia-recognises-state-of-palestine-two-state-solution/105799276</link><description>While the Israel Defense Forces bomb Gaza and bulldoze the West Bank for settlements, moves to recognise Palestine in pursuit of a two-state solution may appear like something of a sick joke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfa3467335da07f9ce07cf8e87421ac9</guid></item><item><title>Brownlow Medal 2025 — when is it, how to watch and who are the favourites for AFL's best-and-fairest award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-medal-2025-explainer-how-to-watch-who-might-win/105799236</link><description>The AFL's big night is here, as the league's best and fairest player is honoured with the Brownlow Medal. Here is everything you need to know about the big event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a533b478e86cba0a5d23c3da7fd118e4</guid></item><item><title>The government says its 2035 climate targets are achievable but mathematics suggests a different story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/climate-target-2035-2050-carbon-emissions-global-warming/105799080</link><description>The problem with an emissions reduction target is that its mere existence implies it is achievable and that if we do achieve it, we will be fine. The truth is more complex.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55dd3a3450e5da05cd2e7e786ef836f8</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr earns a standing ovation in home game return as Chelsea defeats Leicester 1-0 in WSL</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/wsl-sam-kerr-returns-home-to-standing-ovation-in-chelsea/105800446</link><description>Chelsea fans stand and applaud Australian superstar Sam Kerr in her long-awaited return to Kingsmeadow in the WSL.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da70332495135e59ba3b6176d03d566d</guid></item><item><title>World leaders are meeting at the UN General Assembly this week. Here are four things to watch for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/united-nations-general-assembly-what-to-watch-for-in-new-york/105800440</link><description>World leaders are arriving in New York for the UN General Assembly — and for the first time, Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is among them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">761958b8abcd8c47c96a8d78d674b211</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage investigation underway as minister warns of 'consequences'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/optus-investigation-triple-0-outage/105800556</link><description>The Australian Media and Communications Authority begins its investigation into the Optus triple-0 outage that has been linked to multiple deaths in South Australia and Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64e8d943c326b70c38e9b095d514da19</guid></item><item><title>Easy and healthy dinner recipes for spring</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/easy-healthy-recipes-for-spring-dinners/105660408</link><description>If you're looking for light dinner ideas as the weather warms up, we have plenty of easy options. Think veggie-filled frittatas and beef taco bowls with a few healthy swaps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c28e2a7be5345c5402fc685acca89162</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast man sentenced over former partner's traumatic brain injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/man-sentenced-over-former-partners-traumatic-brain-injury/105801732</link><description>A man is sentenced over a 2023 incident in which his former partner jumped from a moving car to escape him, leaving her with a traumatic brain injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e9c37ba116765f615c221f6c4108a07</guid></item><item><title>Is AI impacting your career or life plans? Has its rapid rise got you rethinking your future? The ABC wants to hear from you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/ai-artificial-intelligence-future-job-career-impact/105762606</link><description>Whether you’re a student halfway through a degree or a mid-career manager planning the next five years, artificial intelligence (AI) is reshaping lives across the country. If you've been feeling its effects, the ABC wants to hear from you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc9fb0b057b73e053ee1ce795957b20a</guid></item><item><title>Super Netball's Sunshine Coast Lightning enters new Global Sports Fund Management Group ownership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/super-netball-sunshine-coast-lightning-new-ownership/105801344</link><description>Almost a decade after being co-founded by the Melbourne Storm and University of the Sunshine Coast, Super Netball's Lightning is entering a new era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">725e5769d7aa41a90979ec4d3e47f5bd</guid></item><item><title>Alexander O'Sachy faces Brisbane court charged with manslaughter of Angela Godwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/manslaughter-sentencing-domestic-violence-upper-mount-gravatt/105802410</link><description>The court heard the 47-year-old had a criminal history spanning more than 20 years for more than 50 offences, including the unlawful wounding of a former partner in 2008.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b4cf8d12fdea5712adde0cc2c477aae</guid></item><item><title>Brownlow Medal 2025: All the best fashion looks from AFL's night of nights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-red-carpet-wrap/105802436</link><description>Just after the fashion from this evening's Brownlow Medal? We've got you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8922390581e8430e878c1aa384dd8e2d</guid></item><item><title>Ley writes to Republicans vowing to revoke Palestine recognition ahead of Albanese's UN address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/albanese-un-palestine-address-ley-republican-letter/105803078</link><description>In an unorthodox move, Opposition Leader Sussan Ley writes to a group of Republicans reassuring the Coalition would withdraw recognition of Palestine, ahead of a major United Nations address to be delivered by the prime minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98f3481476a06e3c9782e1032f1893d8</guid></item><item><title>Multiple UK charities cut ties with Duchess of York over email to Jeffrey Epstein</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/uk-charity-dumps-sarah-duchess-of-york-epstein/105804606</link><description>The decisions come after British media reported that the Duchess had described the disgraced financier as a "steadfast, generous and supreme friend" in a 2011 letter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c20e28d80c8779c49ad3426a6872fc0</guid></item><item><title>Artificial intelligence to dominate Australia's future economy, but who will reap the benefits?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/australias-future-economy-will-be-dominated-by-ai/105802364</link><description>From robots to supercomputers, artificial intelligence is set to become an integral part of the Australian economy, with tens of billions in benefits to be gained … but for whom?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12e16358f1d06001f22c8315b12c996c</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar junta revoking citizenship of actors, singers and other celebrities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/myanmar-celebrities-left-stateless-after-criticising-junta/105787574</link><description>Myanmar's military junta is using citizenship as a weapon, targeting political opponents, activists and even celebrities who speak out against the regime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df5568a6e89118d9a0c2db08ec61854c</guid></item><item><title>Three Australians lay dead as investors of Optus's parent company Singtel were buying up its shares</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/three-australians-lay-dead-investors-buy-up-shares/105803922</link><description>The actions by Optus management in the hours following a series of failed attempts by its customers to call triple-0 raises questions about the telco's fitness to operate in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24e9f1bc9c2b8e3b2e1bdab5ae2ccb23</guid></item><item><title>Calls for long-term plan to address Tasmania's 'concerning' school attendance level</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/tasmania-school-attendance-level-concerns/105770010</link><description>Australia's school attendance levels have dropped since the pandemic but education experts are particularly concerned about Tasmania — a state with an already notoriously low literacy rate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81f75b3e7bbb3bc0d144997482f5d7c9</guid></item><item><title>The public hospital patients who ended up paying abortion clinics for miscarriage care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/qld-mater-miscarriage-care-catholic-hospital-abortion/105781022</link><description>Brisbane women have told the ABC they paid an abortion clinic for their chosen miscarriage care rather than getting it at their large public hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34accc25ffd487a2e3cb32cdcd8a582d</guid></item><item><title>Doctors concerned easily accessible illegal cigarettes are causing smoking rates to increase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/act-easy-access-to-illegal-cigarettes-seeing-high-smoking-rates/105803450</link><description>Doctors say smoking rates are at levels they haven't seen in a decade due to easy access to illegal cigarettes that are a "quarter of the price" of legal cigarettes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">150ad4af75b20ef2e67ba79a215e5c20</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel reinstated after hundreds of stars back free speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/jimmy-kimmel-back-on-air-disney-says/105805048</link><description>US comedian Jimmy Kimmel's late-night show will be reinstated after being taken off air, following remarks he made referencing right-wing activist Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">868e8a8d3b8279fa34a833b46463ee3f</guid></item><item><title>Man Ray and Max Dupain's photography on display together for the first time in new Heide exhibition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/man-ray-max-dupain-photography-exhibition-heide-melbourne/105790024</link><description>Surrealist photographer Man Ray revolutionised 20th-century visual culture. In Australia, a local photographer was exploring similar territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">318bfee371103375fcc23430352eccfd</guid></item><item><title>Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera being robbed overshadowed Matt Rowell's Brownlow Medal win, and could change the voting process forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/afl-matt-rowell-nasiah-moment-brownlow-medal-voting-analysis/105804320</link><description>It is not often that the AFL's night of nights gets hijacked by a moment not involving the winner of the Brownlow Medal. This is exactly what took place when Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera was seemingly robbed in broad daylight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dfdde5b406fc68132f52c264d89b4c9</guid></item><item><title>Experts say paracetamol safe for pregnancy, no proof for autism link made by Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/trump-administration-links-autism-to-paracetamol-tga-says-safe/105803566</link><description>Australia's medicines regulator says paracetamol remains safe to use during pregnancy despite Donald Trump's administration linking its use to an increased risk of autism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9575c0f36522e77b42eccc5329990b40</guid></item><item><title>Paddleboarder gets too close to whales to film them, gets nudged away</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/paddleboarder-gets-too-close-to-whales-to-film-them/105801626</link><description>Drone footage shows a paddleboarder getting too close to film a southern right whale mother and calf, and being nudged away by the whale, off Point Ann.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccd42678f7b40484099efe1f5126dddd</guid></item><item><title>Devonport City Council approves memorial for victims of Hillcrest jumping castle tragedy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/devonport-council-hillcrest-memorial-approval-coles-beach/105804118</link><description>A proposed memorial at Coles Beach for the child victims of the Hillcrest jumping castle tragedy has been unanimously approved by the Devonport City Council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a5663271771429de2aa53e25b1c0e8e</guid></item><item><title>Women band together to create community for rural mums feeling lonely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/women-create-community-for-rural-mums-suffering-from-loneliness/105803024</link><description>After raising biological and foster children on a farm 60 kilometres from the nearest major town, Tracey Angwin says being part of a community is essential for rural mums.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da92ce9d728ad981483651f9d4c38527</guid></item><item><title>Deeming rates have increased after a five-year freeze. Here's how that could impact pension payments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/deeming-rate-freeze-ends-impact-on-pension-payments/105798966</link><description>The changes impact people on Centrelink payments who earn an income from financial assets, but pensioners are the biggest group to be affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2a6081a58d1e888118022ad40f5fcfd</guid></item><item><title>As a doctor I'm choosing self-care over resilience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/doctor-choosing-self-care-over-resilience/105728568</link><description>As a doctor who advocates for self-care, it took me a surprisingly long time to look after myself. Now I'm trying to be a good example for my patients and other doctors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96d1bd7d0cdf02ba7b181e19ec630701</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police officer charged with assault over protest arrest of former Greens candidate Hannah Thomas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nsw-officer-charged-assault-hannah-thomas-greens-arrest/105805966</link><description>Hannah Thomas was among a group of pro-Palestinian protesters who demonstrated outside a manufacturing facility in June when she sustained a serious eye injury during her arrest for failing to comply with a move on direction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ffd2b5888a415cc414e269d4943cf29</guid></item><item><title>Experts say it is safe to use paracetamol during pregnancy and Trump's autism declaration is 'baseless'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/taking-paracetamol-during-pregnancy-does-not-cause-autism/105806092</link><description>Donald Trump's advice that pregnant women should limit the use of paracetamol in pregnancy has been criticised as "baseless". So what does it mean for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81c81571674ce6c676915af2ca81de9b</guid></item><item><title>Egyptian activist Alaa Abd el-Fattah released from prison after nearly 12 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/egyptian-activist-alaa-abd-el-fattah-released-from-prison/105805902</link><description>Pro-democracy activist Alaa Abd el-Fattah has been released from prison, following a pardon from the Egyptian president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d429202c47e43999510999e5ea936c5c</guid></item><item><title>Northern Territory CLP government is reviewing sentencing laws. But will it change anything?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/jake-danby-hit-and-run-nt-sentencing-act-changing-clp-government/105801232</link><description>The case of hit-and-run driver Jake Danby has brought renewed focus to the NT's legal system and the problems it faces. But will changing sentencing laws help?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">181ee879b9bbed91231a5952dddf97e9</guid></item><item><title>Kevin Bacon on the importance of music, philanthropy and acting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/kevin-bacon-take-5-actor-music-philanthropy-interview/105793360</link><description>He's a prolific fixture on our screens who's famously six degrees from almost anyone. But Kevin Bacon is also a passionate musician and philanthropist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45104e05b24001759cca6f2985a81b97</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu plans to sign police deal with China while Nakamal pact with Australia is left hanging</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/china-vanuatu-police-agreement-equipment-training/105806934</link><description>Vanuatu declares it will sign a new policing agreement with China as the landmark Nakamal pact between Australia and the Pacific Island nation hangs in the balance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e015a5946bffafc3e5c33cd1d8fa895e</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage tragedy: What we know and how events unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/timeline-on-optus-triple-0-outage-what-we-know/105805890</link><description>The first sign something was wrong came late on Friday afternoon. Now we have a clearer picture of how the triple-0 outage unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c548c42002e87e4dd015358e8d8279e9</guid></item><item><title>Unproven autism claims like Donald Trump's risk undoing decades of progress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/trump-unproven-autism-claims-risk-undoing-decades-of-progress/105807344</link><description>The Trump administration's rhetoric only adds to the noise around autism and will make it harder for the community to feel understood and accepted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00fa47bf5ec49c44ed4dd1852e1689f4</guid></item><item><title>Sale of Australia's biggest sheep station at Rawlinna finally gets WA government approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sale-of-australias-largest-sheep-station-at-rawlinna-station/105807106</link><description>The WA government has finally signed off on the sale of Australia's largest sheep station almost seven months after UK-based Consolidated Pastoral Company announced plans to buy Rawlinna Station.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">453798f3baadfee94d513f7ea0e7efc3</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie's spray at 'muppet', 'coward' Liberal colleagues after post bemoaning loss of Aussie car making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/andrew-hastie-car-making-coward-muppet-liberals/105808280</link><description>Senior Liberal Andrew Hastie has taken aim at colleagues who questioned a social media post where he bemoaned the loss of Australian car making, calling them "nameless cowards" and "muppets".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa8f233e21c3cb087597a2e4648810dd</guid></item><item><title>Teenage girl to stand trial for alleged Hervey Bay caravan park murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/girl-to-stand-trial-for-alleged-hervey-bay-caravan-park-murder/105805474</link><description>One of the youngest Australians ever to be charged with murder will face a jury trial over the stabbing death in a Hervey Bay caravan park of a 24-year-old man in August 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ee4913dd0bfa32590ddaa5163670af</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105809052</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2291dde89e5f6f2e800c553bd2118818</guid></item><item><title>Two teenagers sentenced to detention over attacks on Perth men lured via Grindr app</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/teenagers-detention-grindr-attacks-men-perth/105807670</link><description>Two "lawless" and "cruel" teenage boys who used social media to lure gay men to isolated locations in Perth before attacking them will remain in detention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04ac3ca89cb5b2ff893be3071e8400f4</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn's Mabior Chol has three-match ban overturned at AFL tribunal as rough conduct charge dismissed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/hawthorn-mabior-chol-afl-tribunal-hearing/105808298</link><description>The AFL tribunal quashes Mabior Chol's three-match ban for rough conduct, finding he did not act unreasonably in his tackle which left Geelong's Tom Stewart concussed and out of this weekend's grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a927a04bec9e6ad920a7713d7f32bccf</guid></item><item><title>Denmark links drones at Copenhagen airport to hybrid attacks across Europe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/denmark-investigates-drone-activity-at-copenhagen-airport/105809166</link><description>Denmark links incident involving drones over its main airport to a series of recent suspected Russian drone incursions and other hybrid attacks across Europe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebee7e7802e9046c39907e2c6a3957b7</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Ragasa lashes Taiwan, with at least 15 dead and 152 missing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/super-typhoon-ragasa-taiwan-dead-missing/105809264</link><description>The most powerful storm so far in 2025 is now heading towards the Chinese mainland, prompting widespread disruption and warnings of sea surges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e86c797982ae3107e7d7d8203132df06</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump uses United Nations speech to lay out the US's complaints with the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/united-nations-general-assembly-donald-trump-speech/105809190</link><description>Donald Trump uses a speech at the UN to criticise US allies' moves to recognise Palestine and chastise the international community over a range of other American grievances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">251d1ac533cc88fd01a9540772aff365</guid></item><item><title>Russia systematically torturing Ukrainian civilians, UN says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/russia-systematically-torturing-ukrainian-civilians-un-says/105809316</link><description>The report is based on detailed interviews with 215 former detainees captured since Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b3ec3854b230344943aa0ea9a1c50f</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese to meet Donald Trump in Washington next month, White House confirms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/trump-and-albanese-to-meet/105809460</link><description>The prime minister is expected to travel to Washington to hold talks with the US president on October 20.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c3bc2495519a8885ce870e5014596b8</guid></item><item><title>Incoming triple-0 reforms may not have helped prevent Optus failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/triple-0-reforms-may-not-have-helped-optus-failure/105807524</link><description>The federal government has yet to pass legislation to empower a new coordinator for the emergency services line, but experts say tougher conditions are needed on the telco itself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">196d665b157a51d6ce3440ca5be81bfc</guid></item><item><title>Could artificial intelligence and a universal basic income eliminate 'meaningless jobs'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/will-we-need-a-universal-basic-income-to-deal-with-ai-job-losses/105747954</link><description>COVID showed just how "fragile" our economic security is. As artificial intelligence potentially takes jobs from humans, a universal basic income might be a solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5953e2ae7f84df41d0ff5021a284652b</guid></item><item><title>Ryan Routh faces life in prison after guilty verdict in Donald Trump assassination attempt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ryan-routh-guilty-of-donald-trump-assassination-attempt/105809490</link><description>A man accused of trying to assassinate Donald Trump at his Florida golf course last year has been found guilty on all charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0214a8b817cf4108f24678a4dba1f80a</guid></item><item><title>Australians are moving to Tasmania to escape climate change, but the island state is not immune</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/australians-moving-to-tasmania-to-escape-climate-change/105785996</link><description>Jack and Anna swapped the humidity of Queensland for chilly days in Tasmania, but is Tasmania really the climate refuge many think it is?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0ff7fbad477aed99626b4746b82c14c</guid></item><item><title>How climate change impacted the 2025 snow season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/climate-change-impacted-2025-snow-season/105808698</link><description>The general sentiment is Australia's ski resorts are coming to the end of a bumper snow season — but is this evaluation accurate, or just positive spin after the dismal 2023 and 2024 seasons?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d83586cda83a6d18a50afafa5ab2f844</guid></item><item><title>Dickie Bird, former English cricket umpire, dies aged 92</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/dickie-bird-former-english-cricket-umpire-dies-aged-92/105809586</link><description>One of international cricket's most recognised umpires is being remembered for his "fairness, humour and love of the game".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ea286fdda73733b0f123adaeb2b514e</guid></item><item><title>NT government open to subdividing purpose-built State Square Art Gallery in Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nt-government-open-to-state-square-art-gallery-subdivide-darwin/105807672</link><description>A leading figure in Australia's art world has criticised the Northern Territory government for considering splitting up the lease for a building designed as a major new art gallery, describing the plan as "pure madness".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cea270549341f3bb40e1fafe548161cf</guid></item><item><title>Video record of violence and racism at Purnim Bears, Noorat country football grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/violence-racism-of-80s-country-victoria-football-grand-final/105741080</link><description>The Purnim Bears were supposed to be the feel-good story of country football — a team uniting black and white communities. But their 1987 grand final was so violent it ended with their expulsion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">231bb9fc7a4848fb3114f306c75ce3e0</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine can win back all territory lost to Russia, Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ukraine-can-win-back-all-territory-lost-to-russia-trump-says/105809578</link><description>The US president criticised Russia on the sidelines of the UN General Assembly, saying it had been fighting "aimlessly" in a war that a "real military power" would have won in less than a week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51fff57c3ffcb071ce802513857b4a30</guid></item><item><title>ASX falls ahead of inflation data, Optus to investigate triple-0 failure — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/asx-markets-business-live-news/105809708</link><description>Optus launches an independent review of last week's triple-0 failure, with chief executive Stephen Rue saying human error meant processes weren't followed during the outage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e7944a8068d04ed1894186577c1f7dc</guid></item><item><title>Purnim Bears and Noorat in the 1987 Grand Final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/lowres-hits-compile-purnim-bears/105809790</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">374e9b7e43683512d21efa87c2aa761e</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's meeting with Trump matters for AUKUS and the role of the US in the Asia-Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/anthony-albanese-donald-trump-meeting/105801298</link><description>Trump clearly disagrees with Albanese on Palestine and the reality of climate change, but it's not on the scale of the beef he has with other countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1daf71c6599467c19439c0e23875de0e</guid></item><item><title>Warragul man knocks back dream job after NDIS funding for van rejected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ndis-rejects-van-man-needs-to-drive-to-dream-job/105762830</link><description>Josh Evans, who uses a wheelchair, had to turn down a job with the Bureau of Meteorology because he was unable to get NDIS funding for a vehicle to drive himself to work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21c25c4b57843d7697e914107db94243</guid></item><item><title>Trump claims paracetamol link to autism. Five experts explain what's wrong with that statement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/what-the-experts-are-saying-about-paracetamol-use-lead-to-autism/105806230</link><description>Some leading Australian experts in medicine, autism research and obstetrics say the US president's claims are "a misreading of science," or at worst, "a misuse". Here's why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bffee58bd319bdb466db1eb8559f629b</guid></item><item><title>Why the legacy of the 2023 NRL grand final hangs over the Broncos and Panthers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/panthers-broncos-nrl-preliminary-final-grand-final-cleary/105809026</link><description>On Sunday, the Broncos and Panthers will face off in the finals for the first time since the 2023 grand final, but the memory of that night still hangs over both sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad8624f8c74a64751af52bbcd1e11c56</guid></item><item><title>ABC ordered to pay $150,000 fine for unlawfully sacking journalist and presenter Antoinette Lattouf</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/antoinette-lattouf-costs-decision-in-abc-unlawful-termination/105810052</link><description>The judge ordered ABC to pay a fine of $150,000 for unlawfully sacking journalist and presenter Antoinette Lattouf for reasons including her political opinions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dad4cb7dec36a5f662b73fe15e33939</guid></item><item><title>Sandy Brondello axed by WNBA side New York Liberty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/sandy-brondello-axed-by-wnba-side-new-york-liberty/105810534</link><description>Australian basketball coach Sandy Brondello is let go by the New York Liberty after a disappointing first-round exit from the WNBA play-offs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a4504d3bbba4c100278133bdd4d6055</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann seeks funding to pay for legal representation over raids at his home in 2024</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/bruce-lehrmann-seeks-funds-for-legal-representation-over-raids/105809920</link><description>Former Liberal staffer Bruce Lehrmann launches Federal Court action seeking funding for legal representation at a National Anti-Corruption Commission hearing after raids on his home in June last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">749a230c4ad7fe395ea22940c47b8259</guid></item><item><title>Canberra golf course redevelopments providing both much-needed housing and financial lifelines for struggling clubs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/golf-course-redevelopments-providing-housing-financial-lifelines/105799100</link><description>With the ACT government pushing for greater urban density, golf courses in inner Canberra suburbs are becoming attractive sites for redevelopment to provide much-needed housing and a way for struggling clubs to bolster their budgets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b488a99ab4311911d8fa6f87e596dc4c</guid></item><item><title>Gender-based violence services prepare for increased calls on AFL grand final weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/increased-rates-of-gender-based-violence-during-football-finals/105809996</link><description>Ahead of the AFL grand final, national violence prevention organisation Our Watch is calling for the sporting community to address the increased risk of violence facing women during football finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4d5c539ddee700b75c82661684fb340</guid></item><item><title>The forgotten Australian statesman who was key in the Israel-Palestine partition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/herbert-vere-evatt-and-the-israel-palestine-partition/105805464</link><description>Anthony Albanese formally recognised Palestinian statehood on the world stage this week, but about 78 years ago a lesser-known Australian was fighting for the creation of a Jewish state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0bebd1b1a8da5b3eef2af168ca318d3</guid></item><item><title>Optus parent company Singtel apologises for triple-0 outage linked to multiple deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-singtel-apologises-for-triple-0-outage/105810296</link><description>Optus's parent company says it will "ensure a thorough investigation of this incident to prevent any future recurrence".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4603051f8c7a42c9b44e671ff971d0d</guid></item><item><title>Sculpture by the Sea could be cancelled due to $200,000 shortfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/sculptures-by-the-sea-facing-cancellation-funding-shortfall/105810510</link><description>Australia's famed sculpture walk is facing cancellation after failing to secure funding less than a month out from this year's event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ca69999aba4ff9483322749a16b717e</guid></item><item><title>Man behind iconic ABC TV programs, Graham White, dies aged 93</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/graham-white-abc-tv-and-radio-pioneer-dies-at-93/105806806</link><description>Graham White was a pioneer of Australian radio and television and played a key role in the creation of numerous television series, including A Big Country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54c9a84115c56f73f0923751c300a0e1</guid></item><item><title>When is the 2025 AFL grand final? Here's what time it starts and where to watch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/when-is-the-afl-grand-final-time-where-to-watch-explained/105809976</link><description>Wondering what time the AFL grand final starts and how you can watch it live? We've got you covered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b35be59cc10e4e0032348864c66bd1c7</guid></item><item><title>Despite past controversy, NSW Police commissioner Mal Lanyon has a strong backing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nsw-police-commissioner-mal-lanyon-premier-chris-minns-analysis/105810774</link><description>For newly-announced Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon, Wednesday morning would have been both one of his proudest moments, and his most uncomfortable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed72f9bcc7ce20d2d722b8b43d539719</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel returns, addressing Charlie Kirk and 'un-American' axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/jimmy-kimmel-returns-thanking-supporters-speaks-to-free-speech/105808410</link><description>Despite the late-night host's return, several US ABC affiliates did not air the episode, excluding an estimated one-quarter of American households.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac8b78a8e557c0d2a91d42ed04e2eed</guid></item><item><title>Family suspects foul play in Noosa man Byron Dumschat's death in a Bali villa pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/family-suspects-foul-play-in-bali-death-noosa-man-byron-dumschat/105809846</link><description>An Australian family is asking why Indonesian police allowed three Australian witnesses to return home without being interviewed after their 23-year-old son died on the Indonesian holiday resort island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4e8e32abe23c1a44f62c5e3f023e2a2</guid></item><item><title>How #RedundancyDiaries are busting the stigma of being let go</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/busting-the-stigma-on-redundancy-by-sharing-online/105751880</link><description>Camille says being made redundant was hard, so she began sharing her experiences on TikTok hoping to help others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69e9a0930ebbcb9805519c817968e9ee</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's changed stance on Ukraine could be a challenge for Vladimir Putin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/donald-trump-ukraine-nato-comments-a-challenge-to-vladimir-putin/105810170</link><description>If Donald Trump actually means what he has just said — that NATO countries have a right to shoot down any Russian jets in their airspace — the US president may be contracting out a serious counteroffensive against Russian aggression to NATO countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c624737442bcb04137b18db123e6997</guid></item><item><title>Elon Musk's father, Errol Musk, accused of abusing five of his children over three decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/errol-musk-elon-father-abuse-allegations/105810162</link><description>Multiple police reports, social workers and family members uncover the allegations against 79-year-old Errol Musk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b128f012c363aa69849c2a916828663b</guid></item><item><title>Macron phones Trump to get around NY motorcade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/macron-phones-trump-to-get-around-ny-motorcade/105811218</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0de051b84c60d4360ea72ef967de903e</guid></item><item><title>Escalator stops operating as Donald and Melania Trump step on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/escalator-stops-operating-as-donald-and-melania-trump-step-on/105811110</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5b98bfb1abe65dbbbc5d0927519eed6</guid></item><item><title>Why did the UN escalator stop after Donald and Melania Trump stepped on it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/donald-melania-trump-escalator-teleprompter-un-marcon-call/105810256</link><description>Footage of the US president and his wife's reactions to the mishap was shared widely on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87fdb12fe7af401b7964018acf19bc5f</guid></item><item><title>Doctor who lost daughter to brain cancer receives grant in race to clinical trials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/doctor-receives-grant-to-continue-brain-cancer-research/105810368</link><description>A professor who lost his daughter to brain cancer in 2018 is hopeful the research to find a cure in children is just five years away from clinical trials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc0272343034af8958b1ec9f51c4c20f</guid></item><item><title>Optus admits procedural failure before outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-admits-procedural%C2%A0failure-before-outage%C2%A0/105811978</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b84c417046bbfc3acea16532e90a47cf</guid></item><item><title>What Hollywood gets wrong about music teachers on screen and how this impacts Australian teachers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/hollywood-portrayals-music-teachers-impact-australians/105803248</link><description>On-screen portrayals of music teachers like School Of Rock are full of cliches. Researchers say this might be stopping more Australians from taking up the profession.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9038906989bc595b89e85f5f95a323fd</guid></item><item><title>Optus to pay $100m fine, as crisis engulfing Australia's second biggest telco continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-fined-100-million-for-sales-misconduct/105810174</link><description>In enforcing the fine today, the Federal Court's Justice Patrick O'Sullivan described the company's conduct as "extremely serious" and "appalling".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5b8ef086dc95c25b9efd2536b1850d6</guid></item><item><title>Tesla's self-driving technology is available in Australia, but road rules differ nationwide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/tesla-self-driving-technology-rules-differ-around-australia/105808104</link><description>Owners of late model Teslas can now access the company's self-driving technology. But the rules for how drivers can use it differ around the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">191d278dfe60ecd4ddb9b581b2e3730f</guid></item><item><title>AFL boss hints at Brownlow voting shake-up after Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/afl-boss-hits-at-brownlow-voting-shake-up-after-controversy/105812086</link><description>Voting for the Brownlow Medal has been a hot topic again in the wake of Monday night's count, with the AFL open to letting umpires have access to statistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5d9c582b445942c6c11e6f1591db872</guid></item><item><title>Concerns Launceston City Council could give away Birchalls CBD site it bought for $8.8m</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/launceston-council-developer-plans-for-birchalls-building/105809796</link><description>Launceston City Council bought the historic Birchalls building for $8.8 million five years ago. A ratepayer association says it has learnt of a proposal to give it away "for nothing".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57bb6bb59e636d4105fd48c27dcdbaca</guid></item><item><title>Kindergarten cleaner who allegedly filmed children in bathroom faces more charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/kindergarten-cleaner-who-secretly-filmed-children-in-toilet/105811222</link><description>Prosecutors have flagged more potential charges for the Victorian kindergarten cleaner accused of secretly filming children in a bathroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a0e03375009bb4e55aea4b0a8b01d7e</guid></item><item><title>Missouri woman gets more than four years jail for trying to sell off Elvis' Graceland property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/missouri-woman-jailed-for-elvis-graceland-property-scam/105810930</link><description>A woman's attempt to sell off one of the most storied pieces of real estate in the US has come to naught. Here's how it happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87c9bf726b751fc3728cdd75266b9d0d</guid></item><item><title>Gambling participation and harm on the rise in Australia, new study reveals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/gambling-participation-harm-rising/105812048</link><description>New data reveals that around 3 million Australians are engaged in some form of harmful gambling, which is linked to financial stress, family violence and poor mental health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">582e5e06f9c5592583e96dc9e908fbf5</guid></item><item><title>Electric vehicle-to-grid trial in Exmouth generates promising results for state power distributor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/electric-vehicle-to-grid-v2g-trial-in-exmouth-promising/105811868</link><description>State distributor Horizon Power says a trial of bi-directional charging with electric vehicles to both supplement the grid and take up excess power, known as V2G, has proved a success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c657879091e2ce95be5b33b932b29f12</guid></item><item><title>Hockeyroos legend Katrina Powell quits as coach after two Olympic campaigns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/hockeyroos-legend-katrina-powell-quits-as-coach/105812958</link><description>Hockeyroos great Katrina Powell has quit as coach of Australia's women's team after rebuilding a criticised culture in the elite program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3362fa20010b71b5d18e66dc93b4c83</guid></item><item><title>Christopher John Sullivan sentenced for stabbing partner Pauline Mountford in Gooseberry Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/christopher-john-sullivan-domestic-violence-sentencing/105812460</link><description>A 74-year-old man who slashed his partner's throat in their Perth Hills home is sentenced to 10 years in jail over the near-fatal attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b34ba7512fda4d4c878ff84234b915f6</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's gripe-filled United Nations speech unsurprising, Foreign Minister Penny Wong says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/penny-wong-responds-to-donald-trump-un-speech-albanese-meeting/105809070</link><description>Foreign Minister Penny Wong says the speech US President Donald Trump delivered at the UN is simply more of the same from him and "consistent" with his views and actions since being elected for a second term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d44f8f03841ac14753961232f5608cf4</guid></item><item><title>Former A-League footballers Clayton Lewis and Kearyn Baccus sentenced over betting scam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/a-league-betting-clayton-lewis-kearyn-baccus-sentencing/105811400</link><description>Both players were paid $10,000 each to intentionally get themselves yellow cards while playing for Macarthur FC against Sydney FC to influence overseas bets on the game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4d047a9369284c7941aaf5cccc0a654</guid></item><item><title>Farmer Sam Bailey, who worked to be the world's first quadriplegic helicopter pilot, dies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/quadriplegic-helicopter-pilot-sam-bailey-dies/105811530</link><description>A "true blue" farmer, pilot, and pioneer for accessibility in agriculture has been honoured after his sudden death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1022bcfec676038f6c3bd27cde15e24c</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast posts record tourism spend as mayor warns of public transport 'time bomb'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/record-gold-coast-tourism-spend-prompts-public-transport-warning/105811046</link><description>International tourists are spending more than ever on the Gold Coast, but mayor Tom Tate says the city faces a public transport "time bomb" that could ruin its reputation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c6df1c0bdc0bbebd9425d3678241991</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of Australians fighting 'cruel' battle for COVID vaccine injury compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/fight-for-compensation-for-covid-19-vaccination-injuries/105808630</link><description>Thousands of Australians who were injured by COVID vaccines say they are facing a 'cruel and complex' system to get compensation from the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc0182bdb4d37c0f24454edad8263808</guid></item><item><title>Productivity Commission to review state and territory GST deal, including $60b WA windfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/australia-gst-review-under-review-wa-gst-deal/105813372</link><description>Western Australia's GST deal, expected to cost the Commonwealth $60 billion by 2029, will form part of a review by the Australian Productivity Commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b22ae8ce5ff8afaa0d867d88f15dc4f0</guid></item><item><title>WorkSafe WA drops psychological harm case against justice department</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/worksafe-wa-bunbury-prison-psychological-harm-case-dropped/105811948</link><description>A former Bunbury prison officer who alleges she was sexually harassed at work says she is disappointed that WorkSafe WA has dropped legal action against the Department of Justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2990b5c45595069196146a3173be6cc1</guid></item><item><title>Australian War Memorial updates Ben Roberts-Smith display to mention recent High Court rejection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/war-memorial-updates-ben-roberts-smith-exhibit-again/105813004</link><description>The war memorial's revised display now mentions Ben Roberts-Smith's failed bid to the High Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9edc3cc4a1fb29debf8f915faecacf6</guid></item><item><title>Former police officer Stephen Michael Calcutt pleads guilty to filming teenagers in shower and up skirt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/former-police-officer-pleads-guilty-filming-teenager/105812714</link><description>The former sergeant also filmed up another teenager's skirt and had a number of cartoons depicting children in sexual situations on a hard drive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d016f9d7ccabbb8651e7cb9fc607919e</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions trust Lachie Neale to make right call ahead of AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/brisbane-lions-lachie-neale-right-afl-grand-final-call/105813604</link><description>All eyes are on Lachie Neale's bid to make a remarkable grand final return from injury, and his teammates will back him to make the right call.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b33183c69e679601c3ad83c2c662b7b</guid></item><item><title>Uber ordered to pay lost wages in 'landmark' unfair deactivation case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/uber-unfair-deactivation-case/105812068</link><description>The Fair Work Commission has ordered Uber to repay lost wages to a driver it deemed was unfairly deactivated from the rideshare platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f3574450e42cae819f14881001f5399</guid></item><item><title>Murder trial hears final arguments from trio accused of 2022 stabbing death of David Jenkins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/trial-of-men-accused-of-david-jenkins-murder-final-arguments/105805736</link><description>The trial of two brothers and another man accused of the stabbing murder of a man in Tasmania's north in 2022 hears there is "no serious dispute" that Luke Shaw "was the person who killed" David Jenkins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">621a1d67e3bb519003eb4e577b718a6e</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105813848</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbeee129e3122b06287a24ba6aa752ed</guid></item><item><title>Senate inquiry examines federal environment department's SA algal bloom response</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/murray-watt-briefing-algal-bloom-july/105813252</link><description>Officials from the federal environment department say they were not aware of the impact of SA's algal bloom until the state government contacted them in May, two months after the bloom was first detected. Speaking at a senate inquiry, department officials say the federal environment minister was not formally briefed on the bloom until July.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47629bf3fc1342b70bb629add33dbfd9</guid></item><item><title>Men sentenced for riot amid 'pressure cooker' conditions in Alice Springs prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nt-nine-alice-springs-prisoners-sentenced-in-court-over-riot/105810344</link><description>Lawyers for nine Alice Springs prisoners who rioted at the facility last year say the unrest was akin to a "pressure cooker release valve" amid "feelings of degradation and neglect".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f4122da2e195a834f3006510b2c73ce</guid></item><item><title>Alzheimer's drug Lecanemab approved by Therapeutic Goods Administration for use in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/alzheimers-drug-lecanemab-approved-by-tga/105813710</link><description>The Therapeutic Goods Administration approves the drug Lecanemab, which can slow down cognitive decline in the early stages of Alzheimer's.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4467a4bcfcdb0b2847fe165e1550be39</guid></item></channel></rss>