<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:23:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Alex de Minaur through to ATP Rotterdam Open final with win over Ugo Humbert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/alex-de-minaur-through-to-atp-rotterdam-final/106346226</link><description>Alex de Minaur becomes the first man to reach three consecutive finals at the Rotterdam Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">841d065eed7395b080396f3f24d0b9bf</guid></item><item><title>Researchers warn climate-linked disease leptospirosis spreading south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/climate-change-linked-to-increasing-leptospirosis-disease-risk/106312420</link><description>Researchers say leptospirosis is emerging as a climate‑driven health threat in Australia, with frequent storms, floods and heatwaves pushing the disease further south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95178a5e8a4125d287e499ebfde48707</guid></item><item><title>ACT Brumbies defeat Western Force 56-24 in Super Rugby Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/act-brumbies-defeat-western-force-56-24-super-rugby/106346216</link><description>The ACT Brumbies have turned up the heat to blitz the Western Force 56-24 in a sapping season-opening Super Rugby Pacific clash in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10ef6f23013268c37706ceee148b7b16</guid></item><item><title>Dry January hits southern Australia as east coast lows drop off the radar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/dry-january-southern-australia-east-coast-lows-decline/106340260</link><description>Rainfall was below average for most of Australia's south-east, far-west and central regions in the first month of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35e0de73fc86cfd94960467f03e96dec</guid></item><item><title>How a pocket of Sydney's inner west went from Australia's deepest coal mine to waterfront houses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/sydney-houses-now-on-former-balmain-coal-mine-birchgrove-history/106219352</link><description>What was once a working class, coal-fuelled borough is now a sought-after suburb in Sydney's inner west, with houses selling for millions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e20c293730315f4a0bd560d285cffe27</guid></item><item><title>Destanee Aiava announces retirement, calls out online trolls and 'racist' tennis culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/destanee-aiava-announces-tennis-retirement/106346282</link><description>Australian tennis player Destanee Aiava says 2026 will be her last year in professional tennis, announcing her impending retirement in an expletive-laden statement on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e49fc707471384a3f7c79ab4b00b492a</guid></item><item><title>South Molle's damaged jetty restricts access to island, with abandoned resort's future unclear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/south-molle-island-waits-on-damaged-jetty-fix-abandoned-resort/106329774</link><description>South Molle Island's former resort has been abandoned since it was damaged by a cyclone in 2017. Now, public access to the island is restricted after Cyclone Koji wreaked havoc on its jetty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c65114749dd72f64d417d81761a454d</guid></item><item><title>Woodstock Farm program helping steer troubled Queensland youth away from life of crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/woodstock-farm-program-helping-youth-avoid-life-of-crime/106337320</link><description>The rural-based social program in the shadow of Mt Tamborine has had remarkable success in rebuilding the lives of youth who have fallen through the cracks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">421b0aeae39a6049b42963e3f882f283</guid></item><item><title>Faaletino Tavana scores stunning try in NRL trial, Canterbury Bulldogs star Matt Burton limps off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/faaletino-tavana-scores-stunning-try-in-nrl-trial/106346352</link><description>Wests Tigers rookie Faaletino Tavana has laid claim to one of the best tries in 2026 during a preseason trial against the Sydney Roosters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2cfee729b56ca0f7ea35f8b101926f7</guid></item><item><title>Easy ways to help protect your hair from chlorine and saltwater damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/how-to-avoid-chlorine-and-saltwater-hair-damage-when-swimming/106334202</link><description>Regular beach days or laps at the local pool can leave our hair looking and feeling quite different.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ed59e0b1894ab058082b567c448eb32</guid></item><item><title>Marco Rubio's speech to European allies takes softer tone but sticks to Trump's firm stance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/marco-rubio-addresses-european-allies-taking-softer-firmer-tone/106346338</link><description>America's top diplomat uses the Munich Security Conference to call for a renewed partnership between the United States and Europe, with Marco Rubio saying America and Europe "belong together".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e958aa2ff47d2263a34af14185a2b78f</guid></item><item><title>Forbes Inn fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/forbes-inn-fire/106335658</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f08e5a8a0559df121863a695484d9e8a</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after two women die in crash following police pursuit in Sydney's south-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/nsw-man-charged-over-critical-incident-hurstville/106346432</link><description>NSW Police say they pursued a red sedan after it was stolen from a man who was filling up his car at a petrol station.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50472c9fda3b213e7a16472dbfc2a4bc</guid></item><item><title>Unscrupulous NDIS providers using inducements to recruit remote NT participants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/unscrupulous-ndis-providers-inducements-remote-nt-communities/106338736</link><description>People with disabilities in remote Northern Territory communities are being targeted by unscrupulous NDIS providers using high-pressure sales tactics and inducements including cash, cigarettes and alcohol, an ABC investigation can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd67ded9456fcfc1b2a32fce1dd07e54</guid></item><item><title>NT film industry on national stage as Kangaroo, Top End Bub and Journey Home win AACTA Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/nt-film-industry-on-national-stage-at-aacta-awards-movies/106345258</link><description>The NT's small but mighty presence is shining on the global stage 40 years after Crocodile Dundee rocketed its film industry into the stratosphere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6b91e7462a835a8868e55cdd28f79a5</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Condoms run out at the Olympic Village as cheating chaos rocks curling — quick hits from day eight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-quick-hits-condoms-curling/106345804</link><description>Protective gear is in short supply in Italy as tensions boil over in the curling and a Norwegian-born Brazilian makes history. Here are the quick hits from the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a381471d7f4c7ab29aa453246d08c65</guid></item><item><title>Fortescue trials battery-electric locomotives in Pilbara as decarbonisation race tightens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/fortescue-battery-electric-locomotives-pilbara/106022632</link><description>After years of delays, the Pilbara's largest carbon emitters are testing greener ways to haul iron ore, and Andrew Forrest has now joined their ranks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c13ccfede85f47f794237a00f234b83</guid></item><item><title>Italian migrants who brought 'fancy cheese' to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/italian-migrants-history-of-cheesemaking-australia/106274280</link><description>When John Interlandi's father began making "fancy cheese" in Gippsland, few Australians had heard of parmesan. At 90 years old, Mr Interlandi is still perfecting it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc65fa96aa7a73e1b002718296218199</guid></item><item><title>AFL State of Origin coaches hail success of concept following Victoria's win over Western Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/afl-state-of-origin-coaches-hail-success-of-concept/106346486</link><description>Winning Victoria coach Chris Scott and his Western Australia counterpart Dean Cox call for State of Origin to be played every year after the concept's stunning return in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a2310e59675ad0bac9b0b865d9ebaef</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs childcare centre cleared of wrongdoing following police investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/nt-alice-springs-childcare-centre-cleared-police-investigation/106346494</link><description>Investigations into allegations surrounding an Alice Springs childcare centre are finalised, with no charges laid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48dc7f3e0f8ad3d6b9e1a5d6ca631e9d</guid></item><item><title>NSW premier announces extra public holiday in April for Anzac Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/nsw-minns-government-anzac-day-extra-public-holiday/106346332</link><description>New South Wales has the fewest public holidays in Australia, observing only 11.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ffac4dfa3924b8dccdf942341a8cced</guid></item><item><title>Supporting and connecting Deaf people, Olivia finds her calling more than just a job</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/olivia-supports-and-connect-deaf-community/106230034</link><description>Olivia Jackson, who lost her hearing as a child, has felt invisible for over a decade until she found her true calling to help other Deaf people achieve their goals as a support worker.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1115de95a72e65d1d9a3e54ffe517057</guid></item><item><title>WA hop growers gear up for harvest as craft beer tastes evolve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/hop-growers-gear-up-harvest-western-australia/106340116</link><description>Local brewers are experimenting with new flavours, while some farms invest in US-made machinery to modernise and streamline the harvest process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0bb847882a1ace0ae5e8db0cba3fd16</guid></item><item><title>As Jakara Anthony dealt with her singles moguls crash, her coach worked out how to pick her back up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/how-jakara-anthony-bounced-back-to-winter-olympic-gold/106346110</link><description>As Jakara Anthony dealt with the disappointment of her singles moguls crash, her coach Peter McNiel was working out how to pick her back up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6104582cfaf145ac938b3a35ff9908bb</guid></item><item><title>Man with stab wounds dies in Galiwin'ku after Elcho Island fight involving weapons, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/man-dies-after-fight-with-weapons-galiwinku-elcho-island/106346590</link><description>A 27-year-old man has died in the Northern Territory after being stabbed during an armed fight with a 19-year-old, who has since been arrested.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6ca8afe5886780e417658634b763a87</guid></item><item><title>'Took the wind out of me': Why this man tested himself for plastics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/plastic-pollution-infertility-cancer-urine-test/106340122</link><description>Kal Glanznig had his urine tested as part of an upcoming documentary exploring plastic pollution in Australia. The results left him speechless.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20a78d9083be5d5b2872c764f9c0b081</guid></item><item><title>Opposition draws battlelines on nuclear and capital gains tax changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/jane-hume-nuclear-angus-taylor-capital-tax-childcare-migration/106346434</link><description>Deputy Liberal leader Jane Hume says Australia needs to be "open minded" on nuclear power if the country is to bring down emissions and make power cheaper.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e5abf1fdfcc06c797eb257ee7d43c22</guid></item><item><title>Four boats destroyed in fire at Hillarys Boat Harbour, second blaze at marina in four months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/four-boats-destroyed-in-fire-at-hillarys-boat-harbour/106346694</link><description>Four boats are destroyed in a fire at Hillarys Boat Harbour, the second time a blaze has struck the marina in just over four months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">153cbefb9c8620f7e06cfafbf0440b78</guid></item><item><title>From succession planning to inherited debt, there's pressure and joy in taking on a family business</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/taking-on-the-family-business/106303408</link><description>Inheriting a family business comes with the weight of generations past. For these change-makers, the future is in modernising their operation and making it their own.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0347909980a4922de14658a0f900f351</guid></item><item><title>Obama deplores lack of shame after Trump shares monkey clip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/obama-trump-racist-monkey-clip-podcast/106346866</link><description>Former US president Barack Obama has criticised a lack of shame and decorum in the country's political discourse, responding for the first time to a post on Donald Trump's social media account that depicted him and first lady Michelle as monkeys.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e75e10162bdf33f5e8cc127e8b4bbf2</guid></item><item><title>Statues of Amy Sherwin, Australia's first opera star, unveiled at Hobart's Hadley's Hotel in bid to cement legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/peter-schipperheyn-statues-of-amy-sherwin-opera-star-unveiled/106344982</link><description>An effort to bring new recognition to a Tasmanian opera star who became world famous, but who died poor, culminates in the unveiling of two statues of her in Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0073ccc352d93326f0623615a91690e2</guid></item><item><title>e-bike rider suffers head injuries in crash after being followed by police in south-west Sydney as critical incident declared</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/sydney-e-bike-rider-crashes-into-pole-followed-by-police-/106346832</link><description>A critical incident investigation is underway after a 39-year-old man being followed by police hit a pole, in what has been described as a "significant impact".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f3f5ea6650c18a6d0cac1d8dcb60f69</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 9</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-matt-graham-cooper-woods/106340132</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34f3b59aefed8c788f8114ead0cbd12a</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous side overturns 14-0 deficit to down Maori in women's All Stars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/womens-all-stars-indigenous-maori-jada-taylor/106347124</link><description>The Indigenous team overturns a 14-0 deficit to score a rousing comeback win over the Maori in the Women's All Stars clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f14485169561b894f2afb767bb7402d</guid></item><item><title>Frog toxins used to poison Alexei Navalny the latest in long history of Russian chemical attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/alexei-navalny-death-russian-history-of-poisonings/106346616</link><description>Russian opposition leader Alexei Navalny was poisoned by the Kremlin with a rare and lethal toxin found in the skin of poison dart frogs, five European countries have said. It's not the first time the country has been accused of poisoning its enemies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">760fb2fcb063a9e9cd0179e29e7157ec</guid></item><item><title>Charlotte Mortlock quits Liberal Party following Sussan Ley leadership defeat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/charlotte-mortlock-women-liberal-party/106347176</link><description>Women were less likely to vote for the Coalition at the 2025 election than ever before, according to the Australian Election Study.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23ccff46149d64d377fec31770f5c200</guid></item><item><title>WA government to introduce new laws on hate speech, face coverings and protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/wa-government-introduce-new-protest-hate-speech-laws/106347042</link><description>The WA premier flags new legislation on hate speech and protests in a bid to protect "social cohesion" in the wake of "multiple threats across Australia" over the summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b17a709f2e34829ce1d9cdedb3d9175</guid></item><item><title>Five arrested after incident at Alice Springs Hospital, police allege weapons brandished inside</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/nt-alleged-aggravated-assault-alice-springs-hospital-arrest/106347146</link><description>Police allege an aggravated assault took place outside of Alice Springs Hospital in the early hours of this morning, where they say a group of boys and men were brandishing bladed weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">083388ec42b3102016cb4bcc81827c7f</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous and Māori All Stars play out dramatic 16-all draw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/nrl-all-stars-mens-indigenous-maori-result/106347244</link><description>It went down to the final seconds, but the Indigenous and Maori NRL All Stars could not be separated with both sides left to rue missed chances after a 16-all draw.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d01cc349479a0292d97ba58d32f2571c</guid></item><item><title>Chinese star takes swipe at organisers for not accommodating her schedule</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/winter-olympics-2026-live-updates-cooper-woods-bree-walker/106346610</link><description>Chinese skiing superstar Eileen Gu says she is "disappointed" and "saddened" that Winter Olympics organisers scheduled halfpipe training at the same time as her big air final at the MIlano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e126a8462b94c26b695b1006d4a1e8d</guid></item><item><title>Matt Graham wins dual moguls bronze at the 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/dual-moguls-2026-winter-olympic-games/106346230</link><description>Matt Graham's medal is the third Australia’s moguls squad has delivered at the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cea7a03f6c1f2118b562ed308b0bcc6f</guid></item><item><title>City of Melbourne quiet on plan for Southbank's 'ugly' red stairs, long after design competition announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/city-of-melbourne-southbank-red-stair-replacement-plan-stalls/106274362</link><description>A Melbourne council unveiled a lucrative competition to replace Southbank's much-derided red stairs. But a year after it was due to start, the plan appears to have gone nowhere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">074f26e344537a0ab6c98a25242c702d</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, February 16: Steven Bradbury's Winter Olympic Games golden miracle at Salt Lake City in 2002</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/steven-bradbury-gold-2002-salt-lake-city/106187326</link><description>In 2002, Australia broke its Winter Olympics gold medal duck in the most extraordinary of ways, as Steven Bradbury put a decade of injury and bad luck behind him to claim the most thrilling of gold medals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f52a523498bfdb185898253f610cc2b4</guid></item><item><title>What is FAFO parenting and is it good for kids?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/what-is-fafo-parenting-and-is-it-good-for-kids/106321924</link><description>Is FAFO the 1980s parenting style today's generation of kids need, rebellion against gentle child-rearing, or exhausted parents just throwing their hands in the air?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27dfd8358d59f5a02bd8ef50448007a0</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: The anxiety and joy of dual moguls bronze for Matt Graham, leader and captain of the Australian team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/matt-graham-bronze-leader-moguls-duals-winter-olympics/106347650</link><description>Matt Graham's brilliant bronze in the dual moguls, and the incredible response from his teammates, proved to everyone that he is the true leader of this Winter Olympic squad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cba69d73cf10c866f2189e3ff247f598</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party divided over policy direction as Angus Taylor plots right-wing political shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/liberal-party-right-wing-division-realignment-four-corners/106331358</link><description>Angus Taylor says he will unite the Liberal Party, but a deeper rift is forming between those who want to overhaul the party's direction and those who believe doing so would mean political death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53f0561e891b7b1fdb5be75b1ca47a5a</guid></item><item><title>ACCC takes Coles to court over 'illusory' discounts in 'case of the century'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/accc-coles-federal-court-case-discount-pricing/106294956</link><description>The "case of the century" is set to play out in the federal court this month, with the ACCC taking on supermarket giant Coles for what it claims are "illusory" discounts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a8938d5ebc9b334251e02015fddc7f9</guid></item><item><title>AI is evolving fast and may bring the fourth industrial revolution with it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/ai-jobs-fake-breakthrough-resignation-chat-gpt-claude/106346440</link><description>A fake news story about me, a series of AI breakthroughs and a resignation in the tech world show that 2026 could be pivotal for AI.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c994c99fef4c461f39302358208eb79</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur claims Rotterdam Open with impressive victory over Felix Auger-Aliassime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/de-minaur-breaks-through-for-rotterdam-open-triumph/106347904</link><description>An inspired Alex de Minaur produces one of the biggest wins of his career, lifting the Rotterdam Open title by beating red-hot Felix Auger-Aliassime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f49207b10f6c3d8998833e02ddac8d3</guid></item><item><title>Whooping cough cases hit record high after 'potentially catastrophic' vaccine rate drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/whooping-cough-cases-at-record-high-level-in-australia/106332954</link><description>A "potentially catastrophic" decline in Australia's childhood vaccination rates has contributed to the sharpest increase in cases of whooping cough in 35 years, infectious diseases experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df9f56f6aeb1e16c21e2baf9475f1b0a</guid></item><item><title>Australia defeated by India in opening T20 as Sophie Molineux era gets off to wobbly start</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/australia-women-beaten-in-t20/106347920</link><description>Australia slumps to a rain-affected 21-run loss to India in their opening T20 at the SCG, after selectors opted to drop vice-captain Tahlia McGrath.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1d3ad1921ec592fc795d54bc3787c1b</guid></item><item><title>Cousin of Westfield Bondi Junction attack victim feels many questions were left unanswered at inquest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/cousin-of-bondi-junction-victim-jade-young-speaks-out-on-inquest/106329706</link><description>A bereaved family member of victim Jade Young feels many of his questions surrounding the deadly attack and its aftermath have been left unanswered from the inquest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8673ae286fbf88815ae5d398328cda96</guid></item><item><title>Shark population may have fallen prey to algal bloom, SA ecologists fear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/port-jackson-shark-populations-algal-bloom-impact/106335834</link><description>South Australia's algal bloom could be responsible for pushing a local population of sharks to the brink of collapse, some researchers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e3cb6e84a9a4e4eba4a21a0e3320312</guid></item><item><title>India and Pakistan refuse handshakes before and after contentious T20 World Cup clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/india-and-pakistan-refuse-handshakes-t20-world-cup-clash/106348000</link><description>India and Pakistan decline to shake hands before and after the most-anticipated game of the T20 World Cup, with India easily winning by 61 runs to secure its Super 8 spot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aec88e0f0a3416457535c8861030762d</guid></item><item><title>Cape Barren Island uses greenhouse and traditional foods to keep fridges full</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/alternative-foods-keep-pantry-full-on-cape-barren-island/105893250</link><description>A tiny island off the coast of Tasmania is embracing old and new techniques to keep food on the table.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6bcc5499da65ccb48471f2c099cdbf7</guid></item><item><title>Dams and rivers run dry, forcing Victorian farmers to make tough decisions about their livestock</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/dams-rivers-run-dry-victoria-farmers-livestock-drought-no-rain/106334366</link><description>Victorian farmers are forced to cart water or destock as dams and rivers run dry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18d39a177a6ee9d81a317ca8e1820867</guid></item><item><title>Rescuers race to find entangled whale last seen near Wilsons Promontory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/search-continues-for-whale-entangled-off-victorian-coast/106347966</link><description>Authorities are looking for a juvenile humpback whale last seen entangled in rope off the coast near Wilsons Promontory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b0efabce5dd3fc47ee3b0e6aafbf4ff</guid></item><item><title>How the ABC Young Performers Awards helped launch the careers of these Australian musicians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/abc-young-performers-awards-launch-australian-classical-artists/106341202</link><description>The ABC Young Performers Awards have launched the careers of some of Australia's most successful musicians. Here are some of their stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd1d1f42c12f0cd8f19af90e90ca9734</guid></item><item><title>Future of fishing prosecutions unclear after multi-million-dollar abalone trafficking case collapses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/indigenous-fishing-prosecutions-future-unclear/106323308</link><description>Subpoenaed documents obtained by the ABC reveal NSW Police continued prosecuting seven men for illegally trafficking abalone despite advice that their case was likely to fail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed4fcebac968428222f50a2c0888f162</guid></item><item><title>Why Australian Adam Lambert's medal-losing crash in the final made him feel better about his Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/mixed-team-snowboard-cross-crash/106346236</link><description>Adam Lambert's crash in the mixed snowboard cross cost Australia a chance at a medal at the 2026 Winter Olympic Games, but it still makes him feel better about his campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87d56bd4dadce372512848288cae94aa</guid></item><item><title>Queensland school teacher calls for endometriosis support after fundraising for surgery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/more-surgery-for-28yo-after-hysterectomy/106340152</link><description>After years of unsuccessful endometriosis treatments, Inez Goves underwent a hysterectomy thanks to an online fundraiser. But her symptoms returned, prompting more surgery and calls for greater support for the illness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53d3116e8a2e780423f1011cc1480352</guid></item><item><title>Sydney scientist collects wild roadside apples to produce cider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/roadside-apple-cider-made-from-feral-apples-by-scientist/106321000</link><description>Lucien Alperstein has spent the past decade picking feral apples from trees along country back roads and making cider. They say their guerilla activity inspired their curiosity about the science of genetics and fermentation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">196237c7f040a77c709aab786700cd31</guid></item><item><title>Chalmers mocks Taylor's proposal for bipartisan budget savings taskforce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/coalition-proposes-bipartisan-budget-taskforce/106348078</link><description>Angus Taylor wrote to the prime minister pitching the plan just days after being elected leader of the Liberal Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2e1b7a17f7bbb632412e2760a78b3ec</guid></item><item><title>Halls Gap businesses reinventing themselves after bushfires wiped out trade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/halls-gap-pomonal-tourism-bushfire-recovery/106331718</link><description>After two consecutive summers devastated by bushfires, businesses in the region are reinventing themselves to stay afloat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60e94f2fcc4428c36c260d3a2cded9a2</guid></item><item><title>SA Police return to Oak Park Station in Gus Lamont missing person investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/police-return-to-oak-park-station-in-gus-lamont-investigation/106348336</link><description>Officers are at Oak Park Station in South Australia's north-east, where a four-year-old boy went missing almost five months ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d453cdd70ad6004f3992a05cb30806d</guid></item><item><title>Meet GayC/DC, the world's only all-gay AC/DC tribute band</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/gaycdc-interview-gay-acdc-tribute-band-australia-tour/106331786</link><description>They worship the riffs, rewrite the lyrics and win over the toughest crowds. GayC/DC is a tribute band like no other.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d75dfaf3925eb31093fd2815687fbbc</guid></item><item><title>Israeli air strikes target Gaza Palestinians just days before Board of Peace meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/israeli-air-strikes-days-before-board-of-peace-meeting/106348162</link><description>US President Donald Trump says the first meeting of his newly created Board of Peace will take place on Thursday, with over $7 billion to be pledged for reconstruction and humanitarian efforts in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88fa2f84ef68dfaf1b37d3f11b53b0d6</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners 'won't accept' handback of rehabilitated Argyle diamond mine site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/argyle-diamond-mine-closure-traditional-owner-concerns/106339850</link><description>East Kimberley traditional owners are concerned Rio Tinto's closure plan will leave them with "a giant hole in the ground forever".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">920c2b711109c2ab18519ecaf2822c30</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Matt Graham on dual moguls 'dad podium' as weather forces reschedule — quick hits from day nine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-matt-graham-weather/106347344</link><description>A trio of dads fill the dual moguls podium as an "unfavourable" forecast leaves things up in the air. Here are the quick hits from day nine of the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">728d2c63e252485fc6b6ccaa8a108ac4</guid></item><item><title>Vermilion's Wandoo gas exports halted after December oil spill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/vermilion-wandoo-oil-spill-nopsema-exports-closed/106343518</link><description>Exports from an oil field off WA's Pilbara are at a standstill after an oil spill in December. The regulator says it has identified "systemic failures" at the Canadian-owned Wandoo facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">584938c64ecc4bec962163af6788452e</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach terror attack gunman Naveed Akram appears in court for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/bondi-terror-attack-gunman-akram-appears-court-first-time/106348400</link><description>Bondi Beach gunman Naveed Akram, who is charged with 15 counts of murder, has appeared via video link for the first time in a Sydney court as a senior magistrate extended existing suppression orders in the case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">371fada7ea7308c7ecec58d7debce4fb</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic type B killer whales seen for first time near WA's Bremer Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/visiting-orcas-steal-the-feed-of-local-killer-whales-in-wa/106345466</link><description>Sightings of Antarctic orcas in Australian waters are very rare. A tour group in WA saw what appeared to be a pod of Antarctic type B killer whales muscle in and steal the meal of a local group of orcas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39f109d1374dbb8d8c0891214ddd9157</guid></item><item><title>Brett Pointing to replace Steve Gollschewski as Queensland police commissioner on 12-month interim basis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/brett-pointing-named-new-queensland-police-commissioner/106348482</link><description>Brett Pointing has been named as the interim Queensland police commissioner after Steve Gollschewski announced his retirement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a90fdd84129f7c5def763bb89f42550</guid></item><item><title>New tobacco laws proposed by WA government to target stores selling illegal cigarettes, vapes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/new-wa-tobacco-legislation-to-target-illegal-cigarettes-vapes/106348588</link><description>Western Australia could soon have some of the nation's toughest illegal tobacco penalties, including fines of up to $21 million and hefty prison terms for possessing commercial quantities of illicit products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d104e6ddf23aa26a18c6b0d065092530</guid></item><item><title>Senior Liberals deny involvement in draft policy to ban migrants from Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/ley-draft-migration-policy-australian-values-statement/106348870</link><description>A leaked copy of the Liberal Party's migration policy prepared before Sussan Ley was ousted included plans to "elevate" the current non-binding Australian values statement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afcbb687b8d26ea4579377278e93aa57</guid></item><item><title>NRL opens door for New Zealand and England internationals to play State of Origin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/nrl-announces-origin-eligibility-changes/106349066</link><description>New South Wales and Queensland can now select players who are New Zealand and England internationals after the NRL confirmed a major change to the State of Origin eligibility rules.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">022358d3cebffadc6e741dffb4f62e42</guid></item><item><title>Increased use of pepper spray, police weapons at protests alarm rights groups</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/how-police-use-pepper-spray-lrad-weapons-at-protests/106337680</link><description>Alarmed by a spike in pepper spray use and threats of sound cannons at protests, human rights groups want a review of "less lethal" weapons for crowd control.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70964e3e18a99fa04dd1b84868314748</guid></item><item><title>ACCC accuses Coles of 'planned' campaign to mislead customers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/accc-accuses-coles-of-planned-campaign-to-mislead-customers/106295046</link><description>Supermarket giant Coles is accused of a "planned" campaign to mislead customers over discounts on the first day of a bombshell Federal Court case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0f2d8fa10569b29b83a064aa52e542e</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man accused of stalking couple and leaving them notes denied bail in ACT Magistrates Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/act-man-denied-bail-for-allegedly-stalking-married-couple/106349276</link><description>The man allegedly went to the married couple's home four times in two months, seeking access while claiming to be an arborist on one occasion, and attempting to remove the home's doorbell camera on another.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c0d45496e038c1d303cc595b732ce9f</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of Caboolture museum heist allegedly believed it was his 'duty' to return artefacts to 'rightful place', court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/museum-heist-egyptian-artefact-accused-denied-bail/106348706</link><description>Miguel Simon Mungarrieta Monsalve has been charged with a range of offences after he allegedly broke into a Caboolture museum on Friday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f814a7ee415946a09d8bd68a1cb65fe3</guid></item><item><title>Maugean skate still faces 'catastrophic' risk from salmon farming, Commonwealth advice says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/maugean-skate-endangered-status-analysis/106348446</link><description>Official advice is unequivocal that salmon farming remains the main threat to the endangered Maugean skate. It remains to be seen if the federal environment minister will ask Tasmanian salmon farms to scale back their operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f16f18ad7cc496224dc41ec49e1e0093</guid></item><item><title>'Signal sniffers' used in search for missing person Nancy Guthrie's pacemaker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/nancy-guthrie-pacemaker-signal-sniffer-suspected-kidnapping-fbi/106348848</link><description>The FBI is using "sophisticated" technology to try to locate Nancy Guthrie's pacemaker, as the search for the mother of US TV host Savannah Guthrie enters its third week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88073bf86ca64a6b89cdec55376d3d6c</guid></item><item><title>Hospital boss says changes already made at child gender service criticised in review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/advocates-say-cairns-report-not-justify-gender-care-restrictions/106343356</link><description>Advocates have called for for better regional services after a Cairns children gender clinic was restricted following a scathing report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ff6c4a104086209c6800093c04c7e53</guid></item><item><title>Firearms charges laid amid search for Gus Lamont, SA Police say unrelated to disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/firearms-charges-renewed-search-for-gus-lamont/106349994</link><description>Detectives investigating the case of missing boy Gus Lamont have made an arrest during their renewed search for evidence – but say it does not relate to his disappearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac2ed28ec4fdddd7fa2ee8a9b9fe7fd9</guid></item><item><title>Protester takes to roof of Geraldton fisheries building over WA government's demersal fishing ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/demersal-fishing-ban-rooftop-protest-geraldton/106350184</link><description>A Geraldton fisherman locks himself to the roof of a government building — and says he has swallowed the key — in a protest over Cook government restrictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a4f232b4772dc60a2946f241500c3d9</guid></item><item><title>How cheating allegations have rocked the curling teams at the Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/winter-olympics-curling-cheating-allegations-explained/106349394</link><description>Controversy is swirling in curling at the Winter Olympics after the Canadian team was accused of cheating. Here's a look at the whole controversy and why it matters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">443f4b616e5ccdfab16fa6775d3ce790</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 10</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide/106348302</link><description>Find out what is on during Day 10 at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">babe139774c2ec18a2b959e9a68baa62</guid></item><item><title>Raymond Reddington murder trial hears evidence of marriage breakdown between him and Sharon Fulton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/raymond-reddington-murder-trial-accuseds-dna-on-tip-off-letter/106349940</link><description>A Perth court hears a woman who was allegedly murdered by her husband 40 years ago initiated separation proceedings in 1985, the year before she went missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20ae10cfda50a942e54160f8d61c6046</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police chases under scrutiny after two women die in crash as data shows rise in practice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/data-shows-steady-rise-in-nsw-police-pursuits-/106349778</link><description>Lee Casuscelli and Maureen Crosland died when their car was hit in Camden by an allegedly stolen car that police had been pursuing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc2be8723c08215d2574cba75631f785</guid></item><item><title>Remote WA communities isolated and roads closed after weekend deluge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/wa-kimberley-flood-warnings-roads-closed/106348986</link><description>Major roads and remote communities are cut off by floodwaters after a deluge of rain in Western Australia's far north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3830665662ad55a972cd8b43ecb6f5cd</guid></item><item><title>Canberra woman allegedly held captive for two days and raped was 'subdued with violence', court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/act-man-on-trial-for-rape-holding-woman-captive-threat-to-kill/106350432</link><description>A woman who fled naked into a Canberra street and told police she thought she was going to die had just escaped two days of alleged violent captivity, a jury has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba41758d182e8dac70a549337241f0ad</guid></item><item><title>Police renew call for information about fatal 2023 house fire in Orange</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/orange-fatal-house-fire-investigation/106349812</link><description>NSW Police renew their appeal for information about a suspicious house fire in 2023 that killed a woman and injured her two children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7ea765ca79e9edf09185a4353f6c6ad</guid></item><item><title>Stepson tells hearing terminally ill man 'wanted to be done' as wife committed to stand trial for his murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/motor-neurone-disease-alleged-murder-court-committed/106350284</link><description>Kylie Truswell-Mobbs has been committed to stand trial for the murder of her husband David Mobbs, who had motor neurone disease, after he was allegedly given a fatal dose of medication.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73730918506f1f88d77f59f8005b8578</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106351102</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fe7896067b805fba5c947881fbb6365</guid></item><item><title>CLP announces Anjan Paudel as Nightcliff by-election candidate, Phil Scott runs as independent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/nt-nightcliff-byelection-candidates-clp-independent/106350116</link><description>More candidates for the Nightcliff by-election are announced, with Phil Scott running as an independent and the Country Liberal Party preselecting Anjan Paudel, who has stumbled while answering basic policy questions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">214a6542d0a331ab8d4a1cac56b71edb</guid></item><item><title>Former FBI agents say looking closer at Nancy Guthrie's social circle may be key to finding her</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/nancy-guthrie-missing-savannah-kidnapped-arizona/106350688</link><description>As the FBI continues searching for kidnapped 84-year-old Nancy Guthrie in the United States, a former FBI negotiator says they will be focusing on the grandmother's social circle and family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7e994c9207ab9721519039b9508bc02</guid></item><item><title>Aussie Walker finishes outside of medals at Milano Cortina Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/winter-olympics-2026-live-milano-cortina/106350862</link><description>Australia's Bree Walker missed a spot on the podium but still managed a top-eight placing in the monobob at the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5c159af0301712a7a70fb5924b93991</guid></item><item><title>Australian women and children with links to ISIS forced to head back to camp in Syria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/australian-families-with-isis-links-leave-camp-in-syria/106351298</link><description>A group of Australian families with links to Islamic State fighters are forced to turn around after leaving a camp in Syria to try and begin their journey home to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d35a133c23ac9abe8c930ff01e24c75</guid></item><item><title>'Devastated' Australia on the brink of World Cup exit after Sri Lanka's record chase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/cricket-australia-sri-lanka-t20-world-cup-live-blog/106351564</link><description>Australia is on the cusp of a group stage exit from the T20 World Cup after crashing to an eight-wicket loss against tournament co-hosts Sri Lanka.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c69a6c4d3d6ed2d91ae06e9e0fd7374d</guid></item><item><title>Kremlin rejects European accusations it poisoned Alexei Navalny with dart frog toxin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/kremlin-rejects-accusations-it-poisoned-navalny-frog-toxin/106351562</link><description>The Kremlin has rejected accusations from five European countries that the Russian state had killed late Kremlin critic Alexei Navalny two years ago using toxin from poison dart frogs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39e78bdb6048b96c3d3623930d55f0f5</guid></item><item><title>The night snow came to Livigno, turning this surreal valley into an even greater paradise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/snow-livigno-winter-olympic-games/106351744</link><description>Livigno is an Italian outlier in more ways than one. Already known for its special tax status and fairytale quality, the town has had a phenomenal dumping of snow, causing a significant shuffling of events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74681b168ba228a59936a1522013ca77</guid></item><item><title>North Korea builds homes for families of soldiers killed fighting in Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/north-korea-housing-for-soldiers-killed-in-ukraine-war/106351754</link><description>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un unveils new housing development in the country's capital, Pyongyang, to repay the "young martyrs" killed fighting in Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fb5a467f679f84a1526c5a726d07025</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, February 17: 20 years since The Chaser's War on Everything premiered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/the-chasers-war-on-everything-20-year-anniversary/106340294</link><description>The Chaser's War on Everything didn't start the fire, but the embers from the beloved satirical current affairs show are still warm after two decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">745f78b8b02649b29035b0cec81e7085</guid></item><item><title>Ukrainian ex-minister Herman Halushchenko accused of stashing laundered millions offshore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/ukraine-herman-halushchenko-corruption-allegations/106352078</link><description>Ukraine's anti-corruption police have accused its ex-energy minister of helping launder kickbacks and stashing millions offshore, a day after he was detained trying to leave the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c3550d4ebba3d808de4e8829c8e05c9</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor bets on migration politics amid global rightward shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/migration-social-cohesion-language-support-division-policy/106348608</link><description>If migration is treated primarily as a cultural fault line, rather than an economic system embedded in national growth, the debate will remain loud. The structural reform will remain unfinished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86414a7a131a25b45dbc0a43798c1c16</guid></item><item><title>Robert Duvall, star of The Godfather and Apocalypse Now, dies at 95</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/robert-duvall-star-of-godfather-and-apocalypse-now-dies-at-95/106352132</link><description>Oscar winner Robert Duvall, known for films such as The Godfather and Apocalypse Now, has died at the age of 95.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c557714626458849acf4e2f9e4b0c251</guid></item><item><title>How to decide what type of car insurance is best for you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/how-do-i-know-what-car-insurance-is-best-for-me-/106260688</link><description>Choosing the right car insurance option can feel daunting, but it's the kind of task that it pays to get right. So, how can you decide which type is most suitable for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19c1a606228973fe803d3604b38ad3b1</guid></item><item><title>Results show high levels of lead contamination in dust around Hobart, as EPA flags further tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/nyrstar-lead-pollution-epa-tests-hobart/106339682</link><description>High levels of lead contamination have been found in dust samples taken from suburban locations close to Nyrstar's Hobart zinc smelter, documents obtained by the ABC show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df4c929be90ce6716c442950274a84e2</guid></item><item><title>Tradies consider leaving careers over lack of onsite toilets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/tradies-created-go-company-to-help-accessability/106244286</link><description>Tradies are walking out. Not over ability or aptitude but toilets — in a symbol of the sector's persistent barriers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2da70745cc00dda920be7b9032002395</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate hike worries? Here's some good news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/why-the-reserve-bank-interest-rate-hike-may-be-a-one-off/106350914</link><description>Fresh warnings of further rate rises have been enough to send shivers up the collective spine of new homeowners, but if there's any comfort to be had, it's this: Don't believe a word of the forecasts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67fb51f52c86bc4d83c2be7c7d52564e</guid></item><item><title>Anti-slavery commissioner calls for tougher laws amid forced labour concerns for Ansell and Kmart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anti-slavery-commissioner-tough-laws-dumping-ground-kmart-ansell/106349728</link><description>Australia's anti-slavery commissioner calls for tough new laws forcing companies to take slavery in their supply chains seriously, as Ansell and Kmart face scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304d8b8d78c81209b940b9f107989101</guid></item><item><title>Carlton's Jacob Weitering suffers rib fracture after AFL State of Origin, but cleared of other injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/carlton-jacob-weitering-afl-origin-rib-fracture/106352118</link><description>Carlton star Jacob Weitering has received some good news, with the Blues labelling their injured vice-captain as a "good chance" to feature in opening round.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0f4a31c564ffe953194ddf9d3fbcac4</guid></item><item><title>Iran's state TV airs 'forced confessions' of 'scapegoats' whose families fear could face execution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/iran-forced-confessions-bahai-scapegoats-face-execution/106349538</link><description>Families of Baha'i youth arrested by Iran's security forces say they've been subject to "forced confessions" and fear they may face the death penalty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">820b9238cd40b32a9775d4a7f614e1f9</guid></item><item><title>News quiz: Year of the Horse traditions, zodiac facts and festive customs across Asia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/lunar-new-year-of-the-horse-quiz-china-south-korea-vietnam-asia/106348886</link><description>How much do you know about the Year of the Horse and unique Lunar New Year traditions in Asian countries? Put your knowledge to the test with these 10 questions and see if you're a true Lunar New Year expert!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">664780860b8f5a75f0169a583ee380ca</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian Motor Accident Insurance Board suing Melissa Oates for $934k in damages over Jari Wise's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/maib-chasing-jari-wise-death-driver-melissa-oates-for-934k/106349758</link><description>A woman who hit and killed her partner with her car in 2020 is being pursued for almost $1 million in damages by the Tasmanian Motor Accident Insurance Board.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d18263c5f7c1d7f98b5e30fb65d32e7</guid></item><item><title>Irish rugby to investigate racial abuse towards Test debutant Edwin Edogbo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/ireland-rugby-test-debut-edwin-edogbo-racial-abuse/106352164</link><description>The Irish Rugby Football Union has said it will launch an investigation after turning comments off a social media post that congratulated the country's newest Test debutant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">261d685409d12066905edfb9104ada79</guid></item><item><title>Police likely looking for motive during renewed search for Gus Lamont, retired detective says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/gus-lamont-search-a-hunt-for-motive-criminologist-says/106350820</link><description>Police are again at remote Oak Park Station searching for evidence related to the disappearance of missing four-year-old Gus Lamont, with a retired police officer saying detectives are likely "looking for a motive".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">325eb4db0ed179729629ac1fe1c84238</guid></item><item><title>Mould, asbestos, collapsed ceilings plague some South Australian schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sa-schools-in-need-of-repair/106334244</link><description>Almost two years after a state government report revealed 35 per cent of all buildings within the Department for Education's portfolio were past their design life, many schools are still plagued with issues including mould, asbestos and rotting windows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fabb2b4476c5886be92e1dda09f3283</guid></item><item><title>The Carters and Sartoris mark 70 years of marriage and 70 years as next-door neighbours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/two-broken-hill-couples-mark-70-years-marriage-neighbours/106346892</link><description>A month after Ron and June Carter got married and moved in together, his sister got married and moved in next door. This year marks not just 70 years of marriage for both couples, but 70 years of being next-door neighbours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1af71fd02e8fa3cdecaf30eb2bea72c</guid></item><item><title>'Too complex': Coles lawyer says grocery prices tough to understand — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-feb-17/106352262</link><description>Coles has faced hearings at the Federal Court in Melbourne regarding accusations of misleading customers on discounts. The Australian share market was up, following Wall Street. Look back on the day's events and insights from our business reporters in the ABC News markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4304f6e9288f8ccc780a5fe7ddd3394a</guid></item><item><title>Juanella Donovan reflects on People's Choice win at National Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Art Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/artist-juanella-donovan-wins-natsiaa-peoples-choice-award/106350062</link><description>Juanella Donovan has taken out the People's Choice category at the National Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Art Awards for the second time, emerging as the public favourite from more than 200 entries across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">729bb7b7ed08ea9b03a622bdc521303a</guid></item><item><title>Ex-footballer shot multiple times in Western Sydney drive-by shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/nsw-greenacre-shooting-police-public-place/106352298</link><description>Police have been told Matt Utai, who played for the Tigers and Bulldogs NRL clubs, was shot outside a home on the street by the occupants of an SUV, before they fled the scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba53d12aff8db788dde0bc0c13507507</guid></item><item><title>Reducing run-off from macadamia farms improves soil but more needed to boost waterways</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/macadamia-farming-study-environmental-agricultural-benefits/106312398</link><description>A new study backs up the agricultural and environmental benefits of certain macadamia farming practices, but the industry says there is still a long way to go in improving waterway health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c45c15852872c7bf72216544f3531dec</guid></item><item><title>Illegal fishing vessels threaten Australia's agricultural sector as biosecurity concerns grow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/farmers-fear-pest-disease-outbreaks-from-illegal-foreign-boats/106349882</link><description>Australian primary producers say they are concerned about the risk of foreign pests crippling entire industries if overseas fishing boats continue to enter the nation's waters illegally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8f3a85baf70328cdbd85ce22cd6d1ae</guid></item><item><title>Bushwalkers soak in near 'once-in-a-lifetime' waterfall after cyclone in WA's Pilbara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/bushwalkers-once-in-a-lifetime-waterfall-rain-pilbara/106347066</link><description>The question of whether there is water in Python Pool is often asked around the pubs and message boards of WA's Pilbara. For the moment, the answer is very much yes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bb14e13e825585b5bae41897115415a</guid></item><item><title>A waterfall gushes at Python Pool in WA's Pilbara region.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/a-waterfall-gushes-at-python-pool-in-wa-s-pilbara-region/106349636</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">604d0c1d3c020236aecb16e168ed1c29</guid></item><item><title>Own goal ends Macclesfield's FA Cup fairytale against Brentford</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/fa-cup-macclesfield-brentford-fourth-round/106352296</link><description>Non-league English football club Macclesfield's tremendous FA Cup run has come to an end, falling to Premier League side Brentford.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ef3637794f7ad3aecb3526517be191b</guid></item><item><title>Pod Save America and why Australians remain obssessed with US politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/pod-save-america-why-australians-are-obssessed-with-us-politics/106327878</link><description>Huge crowds have flocked to live shows for the popular and influential Pod Save America podcast, suggesting Australia's obsession with US politics isn't going away anytime soon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29fd6077abedec21a6c24a6198c4c894</guid></item><item><title>Search for abducted Sydney man Chris Baghsarian continues, family living 'a nightmare'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/kidnapping-chris-baghsarian-cousin-hostage-negotiator-sydney/106348436</link><description>The family of Sydney man Chris Baghsarian, who was abducted in a case of mistaken identity four days ago, are awaiting "some form of closure or resolution".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6758c13f5deb62b5d208a2ff0fee9db7</guid></item><item><title>PM will not repatriate Australians with IS links in Syria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/pm-will-not-repatriate-australians-with-is-links-in-syria-/106352576</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5f3d7e18263c194d84cf8f194a9430a</guid></item><item><title>Highly sensitive Australian court data accessed by foreign entity based in India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/transcripts-federal-court-viq-solutions-e24-technologies-india/106349338</link><description>Highly sensitive Australian court files have been accessed offshore in breach of the privacy act and Commonwealth contractual obligations, an ABC investigation has revealed, raising concerns of a national security risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a37ef7306d80e256ca5ec724ed76473</guid></item><item><title>Australia leads the world in moguls skiing. This is why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/australia-winter-olympics-moguls-dominance/106346256</link><description>To the surprise of many, the "beach nation" that is Australia is the best moguls skiing nation on earth. How the team got there is no accident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edc24052fc71a153cb8523cb4c296d67</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Eileen Gu medals despite blizzard, Ilia Malinin breaks his silence — day 10 quick hits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/winter-olympics-day-10-quick-hits/106351560</link><description>A Norwegian skier melts down in the Italian cold as the Canadian women's curling team hits back at cheating accusations. Here are the quick hits from day 10 of the Milano Cortina Winter Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3e902ec1235988fcd9d5cb6b4f1c4e4</guid></item><item><title>Emu raids on Nannup's rubbish tip spark growing concerns for mob's health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/nannup-emus-raiding-rubbish-tip/106350754</link><description>Emus raiding Nannup's rubbish tip are ending up with rotisserie chicken bags and piping stuck around their necks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3e26c1bad7063c7a6b6bdb8b3e5b325</guid></item><item><title>Austrian man faces terror charges over Taylor Swift concert plot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/man-charged-over-taylor-swift-concert-attack-plot/106352344</link><description>Austrian prosecutors have filed terrorism-related charges against a 21-year-old man who they say planned to carry out an Islamist militant attack at one of Taylor Swift's 2024 concerts in Vienna.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a116a72410998a2bd5cd1447607781ad</guid></item><item><title>Criminal defamation case against Australian writer Murray Hunter withdrawn from Thai court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/australian-writer-murray-hunter-thai-defamation-case-dropped/106352654</link><description>The Malaysian Communications and Multimedia Commission has dropped a criminal defamation case against Australian writer Murray Hunter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e514a70ed3352a28b7274dd1ea2b8e2</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon ends post-Bondi Beach attack protest restrictions on Sydney CBD, eastern suburbs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/nsw-police-commission-mal-lanyon-pard-protest-restrictions/106352760</link><description>The controversial laws grant police the power to refuse authorisation for public protests for up to 90 days after a terrorist incident, restricting demonstrations in certain areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44328050324e442720e49d46ebbe9ccd</guid></item><item><title>Nurses vote to go on strike at Lyell McEwin Hospital as SA government gives immediate pay rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/lyell-mcewin-hospital-nurses-vote-to-strike/106351466</link><description>Nurses and midwives at the Lyell McEwin Hospital remain set to walk off the job for 24 hours on Thursday, with the union saying the government's decision to introduce an immediate 4 per cent pay rise still falls short of expectations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d59c7aa464f39cac1635d8dcebe8a148</guid></item><item><title>Hang-gliding soars as more competitors leap into the sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/hang-gliding-corryong-competitions-sport/106211454</link><description>Bruce Atkinson taught himself to fly with a textbook, but says this daredevil sport has evolved a lot since then.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">361e53d43f0e2347d48f52c72a3af2d5</guid></item><item><title>Highly infectious 'Super-K' flu strain blamed for skyrocketing cases in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/queensland-influenza-cases-spike-super-k-strain/106350536</link><description>Increasingly low vaccination rates, more summer indoor gatherings and a new mutation of a highly infectious strain are driving the spike in flu cases, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58267ec2596bd9fdcb6c7fc3c97898d3</guid></item><item><title>WA's illegal tobacco crackdown comes after less than $89,000 in fines issued last year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/wa-illegal-tobacco-enforcement-criticised-ahead-of-new-penalties/106350410</link><description>Amid moves to increase penalties for those involved in the illegal tobacco trade, Western Australian authorities are slammed for handing out just $88,100 in fines last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">533f151a81da30343f398451ee2797aa</guid></item><item><title>Albanese says Australian government will not help ISIS-linked families leave Syria or return home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anthony-albanese-on-isis-families-trying-to-leave-syria/106352492</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese insists the federal government will not repatriate the Australian families with links to Islamic State fighters who remain in Syria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faa866e3881f2d6646422dcbe7b56295</guid></item><item><title>Brain expert recommends learning new skills, taking on new challenges for healthy aging</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/brain-expert-recommends-learning-new-skill-for-healthy-aging/106348814</link><description>A brain health expert says you're never too old to learn new skills, as Queenslanders take on fresh challenges such as Pilates, running, and even a law degree later in life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">116ce8e09c22884efa0ce73a0c1212c2</guid></item><item><title>One man dead, two people critically injured in 'random' Sydney stabbing attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/nsw-one-dead-two-critical-merrylands-stabbing/106353068</link><description>Police were told on arrival at the scene in Merrylands that a man stabbed multiple people before leaving the area on foot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d9531c303b0cc4cf96abe6f3c36f0b7</guid></item><item><title>Plains-wanderer recorded for first time on outback Queensland cattle station</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/rare-plains-wanderer-bird-recorded-on-cattle-station/106350256</link><description>A project with dozens of monitoring sites across the Queensland property confirms the presence of the critically endangered plains-wanderer by analysing bird calls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fb6753c73ebbb858ac8b4791fe49656</guid></item><item><title>Nancy Guthrie's family cleared as suspects in her disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/nancy-guthrie-family-cleared-as-suspects-in-her-disappearance/106352862</link><description>Nancy Guthrie's family members, including her children and their spouses, have been cleared as possible suspects in her abduction as the case enters its third week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa68fce209fd79c67ed8093c3aa83b3c</guid></item><item><title>Landmark report finds racism 'deeply embedded' in Australian universities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/racism-at-university-report-released/106352588</link><description>Federal Education Minister Jason Clare unveiled the report with Australia's Race Discrimination Commissioner Giridharan Sivaraman in Brisbane on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fd610c26e829ebc33425c156ee8fb43</guid></item><item><title>AFL Opening Round concept is 'unbelievably important', Tom Harley says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/afl-tom-harley-says-opening-round-concept-unbelievably-important/106353492</link><description>AFL chief operating officer Tom Harley insists the league's polarising Opening Round is here to stay, declaring it crucial to the competition's growth in northern markets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f27e67960c4dd64be08957056561d2a</guid></item><item><title>Death of man whose body was found in Adelaide river not suspicious, police believe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/body-in-patawalonga-river-prompts-police-investigation/106353570</link><description>The death of a 48-year-old man whose body was found in an Adelaide river this morning is not being treated as suspicious, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">194ceadf12625b51689d25844ec1f341</guid></item><item><title>Brandan Koschel's antisemitic speech at Sydney March for Australia rally 'abhorrent', says prosecutor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/brandan-koschel-pleads-guilty-australia-day-antisemitic-speech/106353560</link><description>Brandan Koschel was arrested after he appeared on a stage for an open mic session during the anti-immigration March for Australia event in Sydney's Moore Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04cffeec705663059adc4465ec5fdbbb</guid></item><item><title>Former ACT commissioner Vanessa Turnbull-Roberts accuses public servant of sexual assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/vanessa-turnbull-roberts-alleges-sexual-assault/106352482</link><description>Vanessa Turnbull-Roberts says she stepped down as the ACT's first Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander children and young people commissioner to prioritise her safety after being subjected to sexual harassment and sexual assault by a public servant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d6b858d730eb0ebaae68c60183f36f5</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian government forging ahead with Wilkinsons Point sale to JackJumpers' owner despite advice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/tasmanian-government-forge-ahead-wilkinsons-point-sale/106352652</link><description>The Tasmanian government is pushing ahead with plans to sell 15 hectares of publicly-owned land to the owner of the JackJumpers NBL team despite receiving departmental advice to stop negotiations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">325a77a51441d8e4a9aa71d8d1eb4bbb</guid></item><item><title>Louvre tour guides accused of orchestrating $16m ticket fraud ring over a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/how-louvre-ticket-guides-ran-alleged-ticket-fraud-ring/106353046</link><description>Foreign tour guides and staff who were paid to remain silent orchestrated a counterfeit ticketing ring that robbed the Louvre of millions over more than a decade, Parisian prosecutors say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f41a7c8dc6c1eabf78d49897fd9c645f</guid></item><item><title>Suspicious fire at Thornton business</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/suspicious-fire-at-thornton-business/106353278</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a646f017208f5488ea5a8bb750ef05a</guid></item><item><title>CCTV captures man on fire after firebomb attack on Thornton convenience store</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/man-on-fire-cctv-thornton-convenience-store/106353066</link><description>A man engulfed in flames is captured on CCTV after an arson attack at a Hunter Valley business.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9ee7213df91607b954f599de33584e7</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire threatens properties in central Victoria, with rising heat to be followed by gusty storms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/fire-breaks-out-ahead-of-gusty-storms-hot-dry-victoria/106350666</link><description>The fire at Trawool, south of Seymour, broke out near the Goulburn Valley Highway in central Victoria on a day when half the state was facing extreme fire danger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">108731e08685f8af2e1bce9100ec282c</guid></item><item><title>Four men again jailed for life for killing Albanian refugee Urim Gjabri in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/adelaide-albanian-refugee-murder-resentencing/106353932</link><description>Four men who faced a retrial over the murder of Albanian refugee Urim Gjabri in Adelaide's north in 2018 are again jailed for life, with the judge saying their crime was motivated by "greed and [a] desire to rob him of the cannabis".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eafda69581afff6cb8a576417c1b7585</guid></item><item><title>Western Australia's demersal fishing ban hits hard in coastal tourist town of Kalbarri</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/western-australia-demersal-fishing-ban-jackie-jarvis-kalbarri/106336464</link><description>People in the coastal tourist town of Kalbarri say they are already suffering the effects of WA's demersal fishing ban, less than two months after it came into force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b2b2f7a818984b5536b032082a9b2cf</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor reveals shadow ministry, elevating Andrew Hastie and Jacinta Nampijinpa Price</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/angus-taylor-preparing-to-unveil-shadow-ministry/106354092</link><description>The new Liberal leader announces his shadow ministry, elevating prominent right-faction supporters including West Australian MP Andrew Hastie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">989975fa7a8805821e114a08b60c7715</guid></item><item><title>ABC Radio Perth's move to switch to FM aims for better news delivery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/abc-radio-switches-to-fm-for-better-news-delivery/106351268</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b3c4cac8b4e6d68a91fcdae9023571a</guid></item><item><title>Traditional Lunar New Year celebrations in Sydney and Melbourne ring in Year of the Horse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/lunar-chinese-new-year-horse-celebrations/106353510</link><description>Lion dances and red packets are on display in Sydney and Melbourne, as the cities' Asian communities ring in the Year of the Horse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b52f9f4faeae127bd8080e489bd89915</guid></item><item><title>Police inspect outhouse, water tank in renewed search for Gus Lamont</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sa-police-search-outhouse-where-fresh-cement-had-been-laid/106354376</link><description>SA police said they have inspected an outhouse where cement has recently been laid and a water tank as part of the latest search for Gus Lamont in South Australia's Mid North, with no evidence so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2f75e1d79445ecd44a2de495a7beeea</guid></item><item><title>Liam Alexander Hall revealed as man charged over alleged terrorism act at Perth Invasion Day rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/invasion-day-alleged-terror-act-liam-alexander-hall/106353674</link><description>The man accused of throwing a bomb at Invasion Day protesters in an alleged terrorism act attack in Perth can be named as Liam Alexander Hall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff6d5e6a3dd2153ca8a25dcce52fcc95</guid></item><item><title>Woman tells Queensland child safety inquiry of abuse and lack of support in state care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/child-safety-commission-hearing-in-toowoomba/106350486</link><description>A Queensland woman whose adolescence was marred by sexual abuse and exploitation has described her experiences in residential care to Queensland's Child Safety Commission of Inquiry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2411de34f907744426ba49d66cc94609</guid></item><item><title>Coles downplays meaning of 'Down Down' price tags and advertising in case against ACCC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/coles-accc-federal-court-down-down-promotion/106295044</link><description>Coles downplays what shoppers understood when they saw its "Down Down" price tags, saying "not much", on the second day of a bombshell federal court case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84bff0d113546722f611e198410a65d2</guid></item><item><title>Marquee Canterbury recruit Leo Thompson to miss 10 weeks following calf injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/leo-thompson-calf-injury-canterbury-bulldogs-update/106354494</link><description>Canterbury are dealt a hammer blow for their Las Vegas trip and beyond with prop Leo Thompson ruled out for 10 weeks due to a calf injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036cfbbaa4ce64c8f213ea7592a8ab1a</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of murdering Canberra grandmother Irma Palasics pleads guilty to burglary charge as trial begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/irma-palasics-trial-begins-as-two-men-face-murder-charge/106348396</link><description>Lawyers for one of two men on trial for the 1999 murder of Canberra grandmother Irma Palasics tell the ACT Supreme Court he was just the lookout, and had nothing to do with her death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3017b2fe29aed44401597cb6ab90de37</guid></item><item><title>Fire crews battle blaze south of Launceston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/bushfire-warning-for-area-south-of-launceston/106355122</link><description>The Tasmania Fire Service has downgraded an emergency bushfire warning for an area south of Launceston, with helicopters and ground crews in attendance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00134fdf7a0cde3533cca8bcab9042fa</guid></item><item><title>Kyneton women's football players greenlit to join Central Victorian Football League</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/kyneton-womens-football-riddell-update-central-league/106354024</link><description>A long-running saga in country women's football is set to close as a central Victorian team that had been left without a competition will now be allowed to play in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54f16d5c55e8c9bba00d01c3d6d165d3</guid></item><item><title>WAAPA buildings to be re-purposed for creative industries as part of ECU Mount Lawley redevelopment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/ecu-mount-lawley-redevelopment-masterplan-released/106354086</link><description>A "creative industries hub" and around 1,000 new homes will be built on the former Edith Cowan University (ECU) campus in Mount Lawley — but the site's makeover will take 10 to 15 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e23effbb987fb36c3584e0aaa73d1119</guid></item><item><title>Mobil Oil Australia to pay $16m fine for misleading claims about fuel sold in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/mobil-oil-australia-federal-court-fine-fuel/106354140</link><description>The ACCC said Mobil advertised its Mobil Synergy fuel but did not actually supply the product at the time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c4d1c10dddccaa2bbfc1015123368aa</guid></item><item><title>SA government open to swim safety signs at airport as foreign-born drownings increase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/airport-swim-safety-signage-foreign-born-drownings/106350030</link><description>The number of drownings in Australia has surged in recent times, but with nearly a third of victims being foreign-born, the ABC has asked if installing airport signage about the rips, waves and powerful currents at our beaches could help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c04ac5fb80c325b0992d5ba32252627</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds attend state funeral for Ted Egan, former NT administrator, folk musician and land rights champion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/ted-egan-remembered-at-nt-state-funeral-alice-springs/106353076</link><description>Hundreds of people have gathered to remember former NT administrator, musician and Indigenous land rights advocate Ted Egan, at a state funeral held in Alice Springs today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb170c9933a743e4d6d8b8f39d33f45c</guid></item><item><title>Why Brisbane's fuel prices have been cheaper than usual</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/brisbane-low-fuel-prices/106352918</link><description>A combination of economic factors means Brisbane motorists have experienced below-average fuel prices for an extended period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef48273deb7b161b6d398813e4c55c16</guid></item><item><title>French Polynesia drug haul hits $2.4 billion in a month as third shipment intercepted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/french-polynesia-third-drug-shipment-cocaine/106352864</link><description>French authorities seized a 2.4-tonne drug shipment near French Polynesia during a joint operation with the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8b05b9703fd79abe25cc2318a523413</guid></item><item><title>TAFE chief executive resigns as Charles Darwin University reveals impact of course errors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/charles-darwin-university-tafe-ceo-resigns-amid-course-errors/106352750</link><description>The number of carpentry apprentices impacted by a Charles Darwin University blunder that will force them back to school has grown to more than 130 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39a23bbabc3951d8e026f52a3505de2e</guid></item><item><title>Iran launches military drill as US deploys aircraft carrier on eve of nuclear talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/iran-us-military-drill-trump-geneva-nuclear-talks/106353940</link><description>Representatives from the two nations are set to meet in Geneva on Tuesday, local time, as US President Donald Trump tries to curb Tehran's nuclear program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94646181af842a5e1c582c59df894657</guid></item><item><title>VERTICAL VIDEO: Noise device installed in East Perth underpass</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/vvp-homelesssiren-1702/106354990</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7e89892cbbfde0e5d4320d949dccb3f</guid></item><item><title>High-pitched anti-homeless noise devices switched off and labelled 'hostile' by WA government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anti-homelessness-noise-devices-perth-bridge-removed/106354270</link><description>High-pitched noise devices installed under a bridge to deter rough sleepers are labelled "unnecessary" and "humiliating" by housing campaigners and condemned by the WA government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">735727b3767fc5e8a557f1dd188af0e9</guid></item><item><title>Internal review finds almost half of all Queensland Health doctors at risk of burnout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/queensland-health-survey-doctors-clinicians-wellbeing-burnout/106355086</link><description>More than 2,000 doctors responded to the Medical Workforce Wellbeing Survey last year, which polled the wellbeing of medical clinicians state-wide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb62a16d53c341e3190fe492799a2d17</guid></item><item><title>Australian production company Matchbox Pictures to be closed by Universal International Studios</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/matchbox-pictures-closed-universal-international-studios/106355260</link><description>Matchbox Pictures, the local production house behind Dog Park, The Survivors and Secret City, will be closed by its international parent company, Universal International Studios.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78b9d935e059c11895c3efac8807b716</guid></item><item><title>The Missing number in the hundreds of thousands in Syria, where mass graves of torture victims are found weekly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/the-missing-are-syrias-victims-of-the-assad-regime/106131984</link><description>Victims of Syria's brutal Assad regime were tortured to death in completely horrible and inhumane ways. The relatives of "The Missing" are still searching for them as their numbers continue to explode.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d2157091f7eea84ecb078810305485b</guid></item><item><title>Addin Fonua-Blake and Briton Nikora embrace chance to play State of Origin following eligibility changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/addin-fonua-blake-briton-nikora-state-of-origin/106355576</link><description>Cronulla duo Briton Nikora and Addin Fonua-Blake have both praised the rule changes that will give the pair a chance at State of Origin football they thought had long passed them by.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ec581ac1f034662bed78ff674c00b7</guid></item><item><title>Private health premiums to rise at fastest rate in almost a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/private-health-premiums-increase/106355550</link><description>Private health insurance premiums will rise at their fastest rate in almost a decade, after the federal government approved a 4.41 per cent average increase from April.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cf53e80cc9f8f5821a0c50d3aa7dd87</guid></item><item><title>Jury shown footage of alleged attack on Strathmerton postmaster John Burke</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/maskell-manslaughter-john-burke-strathmerton-service-station/106352992</link><description>A jury in the trial of Troy Maskell, accused of the manslaughter death of 73-year-old John Burke, has watched CCTV footage of the alleged incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41a1f3b7026ae81ae32623b92f63131e</guid></item><item><title>Police drop charges against WIM Resource employee accused of falsifying documents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/wim-resource-murray-wilson-fraud-charges-dropped/106355362</link><description>Victoria Police has dropped all charges against WIM Resource employee Murray Wilson, who worked on the controversial Avonbank Mineral Sands Project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e46ef3f04400c724cf57f4b12383ce25</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106355048</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110518261aa0e4650ee60d7c09f2b830</guid></item><item><title>Mother of former Manly player Keith Titmuss breaks silence on lawsuit against NRL club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/keith-titmuss-mother-speaks-on-manly-sea-eagles-lawsuit/106354504</link><description>The mother of Manly player Keith Titmuss, who died of exertional heat stroke following a 2020 Sea Eagles training session, breaks her silence on her family's multi-million-dollar lawsuit against the NRL club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0be5af7a65024f5d1249c96c36ab639d</guid></item><item><title>Man charged over alleged terrorism act at Perth Invasion Day rally named</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/perth-man-charged-over-alleged-terrorism-act-named/106356240</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36893b9df081d205623d5cf180d04ad7</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested after fatal Merrylands stabbing escaped care 10 days before attack, health authorities say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/man-arrested-after-merrylands-stabbing-escaped-hospital-care/106356218</link><description>A man arrested after a fatal stabbing in Merrylands escaped from mental health care while being transferred between hospitals more than a week ago, health authorities say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac37a20a68838d5f1d8ead99df730433</guid></item><item><title>Father whose son died in house fire accuses lawyer at coronial inquiry of 'degrading him'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/qld-fatal-fire-inquest-father-outburst/106354862</link><description>The father, in an emotional outburst, told the inquest he had spent thousands of dollars on psychiatric and hypnotherapy appointments so he could move on from the tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2817eed5da4210d086772b41a3286cb6</guid></item><item><title>Sydney’s great fatberg hiding in the sewers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sydney-s-great-fatberg-hiding-in-the-sewers/106355414</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d86c2192d0e5b5504b2ff2bec1bd22ef</guid></item><item><title>ABC to move Adelaide office to new Tapangka site in CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/abc-adelaide-to-move-to-new-cbd-arts-hub/106355280</link><description>The ABC has announced a new location for its Adelaide operations, moving to a new arts and media hub alongside other government arts organisation in the CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304f07af147679233a1ce91d82d122b7</guid></item><item><title>Grammy-winning songwriter and hitmaker Billy Steinberg dies aged 75</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/grammy-winning-songwriter-billy-steinberg-dies-aged-75/106356348</link><description>Award-winning US songwriter Billy Steinberg, who wrote several top hit songs including Madonna's Like a Virgin, died on Monday aged 75, according to media reports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb0f5e86348cae84a5923360286fcd40</guid></item><item><title>Jail term increased for Roma man who stabbed police officer during call-out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/jail-term-increased-roma-man-stabbed-police-officer/106356242</link><description>A man who stabbed a police officer with a pair of scissors during a domestic violence call-out in regional Queensland has had his jail sentence increased.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb9dc470037d273fcec3966d6535d26a</guid></item><item><title>Live: Weather plays havoc on day 11, with aerials, slopestyle final postponed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/winter-olympics-day-11-live-blog/106354466</link><description>Heavy snow has played havoc with the Winter Olympic schedule on day 11, with the women's slopestyle and men's and women's aerials events postponed. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05560894f8728623208d380b16b46a1a</guid></item><item><title>NSW man kept in custody for own safety after allegedly 'squandering' $270,000 of drug-trade money</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/peter-john-howlett-accused-drug-smuggler-bail-denied/106356372</link><description>Peter John Howlett, who allegedly used a fishing trawler to import illicit drugs into Australia, is refused bail by Mackay magistrate concerned for his safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc40f61151325b5ea412a6eadaf7b440</guid></item><item><title>Jesse Jackson, civil rights leader and US presidential hopeful, dead at 84</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/civil-rghts-leader-jesse-jackson-dies-age-84/106356528</link><description>The two-time Democratic presidential hopeful remembered for powerful speeches died peacefully surrounded by loved ones, his family said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bef1e4b64b56ce290b7d00444b297818</guid></item><item><title>ASIC announces review into 'lead generators' pushing superannuation switching</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/asic-announces-review-into-lead-generators-superannuation/106353740</link><description>ASIC is investigating whether lead generators are complying with their legal obligations when suggesting people switch their retirement savings into less-regulated investment schemes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28dbc5bbe96a001ebdc28eedf9e08c3f</guid></item><item><title>Australia knocked out of T20 World Cup with one game left to play</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/australia-knocked-out-of-t20-world-cup/106356754</link><description>Australia can no longer catch up with Zimbabwe after it was awarded a point from a rained out match with Ireland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dfa50a4be411761518915d4c45e5985</guid></item></channel></rss>