<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 07:57:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Anthony Albanese is forced into policy catch-up after Bondi atrocity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/anthony-albanese-jewish-community-bondi/106156698</link><description>In an extraordinary personal censure, Australia's Jewish community effectively denied Anthony Albanese the role of being the nation's chief public mourner in this week of national tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab47ad73169cf157b1c7d055826871f9</guid></item><item><title>Russell Crowe on the reappraisal of Master and Commander and its masculinity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/russell-crowe-on-master-and-commander-reappraisal/106156486</link><description>Master and Commander flopped in 2003 but is now hailed as a masterpiece. Discover why this epic is earning renewed respect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66a4d3a14b4e26b7aa93f7ae112ab387</guid></item><item><title>The University of Philippines' dragon boat athletes are unpaid, but driven by community pride</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/dragon-boat-athletes-are-unpaid-but-driven-by-community-pride/106031384</link><description>Braving 4am starts, the dragon boat team of The University of Philippines is full of dedicated athletes. But without being recognised as an official sport, they receive no pay for their time and sacrifice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ee8789625af7e4293b0bf71a6077976</guid></item><item><title>Queensland now third least-affordable state as even remote property prices rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/queensland-third-least-affordable-state-as-prices-keep-rising/106104852</link><description>The Ballini family made the move to regional Queensland where they are are paying half the mortgage they were in the south-east, but that's rapidly changing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36859b6ab934b6858364ddc5f972bfa8</guid></item><item><title>Queensland police investigating Nazi symbol and offensive words graffitied on Brisbane mosque</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/queensland-police-investigating-mosque-graffiti/106161260</link><description>Offensive words were also written on the Brisbane mosque, along with the swastika. WARNING: The following story contains an image of a Nazi symbol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4780fb654b418f545d7210716de14539</guid></item><item><title>Why a $2.5 billion surplus has created a migraine for the WA government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/wa-mid-year-budget-review-rita-saffioti/106158160</link><description>For most other governments, a $2.5 billion surplus would be news to shout from the rooftops — but in WA's case, it's a headache with little prospect of relief.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc29bb536e7d4b8d3d929920f53f6881</guid></item><item><title>Prince William and Princess Catherine release 2025 Christmas card</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/prince-and-princess-of-wales-release-christmas-card-2025/106161436</link><description>The Prince and Princess of Wales have released a new family portrait to coincide with their annual Christmas card.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f6e483127b66aa726ea6e7f1466d32</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Travis Head scores century, Alex Carey a half-ton as Australia bat England out of third Ashes Test at Adelaide Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/ashes-adelaide-test-day-three-live-blog/106161670</link><description>Travis Head scores his fourth century in a row at Adelaide Oval, and Alex Carey scores a half-ton as Australia's lead passes 350 on another dominant Ashes day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c227938b347eba082c77baa574cdfc1</guid></item><item><title>House lost near Benalla as Victoria prepares for high fire danger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/house-lost-in-grassfire-near-benalla/106161500</link><description>One house and six sheds have been lost in a fire started by farm machinery at Goomalibee, near north-east Victorian town Benalla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b483fcb3d8f0d707c6bd020919a53865</guid></item><item><title>King Edward Memorial Hospital baby death review finds multiple failures in care provided to mother in labour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/king-edward-memorial-hospital-tommy-starkie-baby-death-review/106159992</link><description>A review into the death of newborn baby Tommy Starkie reveals multiple failures in the care provided to his mother during her labour at Perth's King Edward Maternity Hospital earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cab5ceddf88a744761075768b1ae515d</guid></item><item><title>UOW 'bizarre and chaotic' governance and finances under parliamentary and ICAC scrutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/whistleblower-alleges-university-of-wollongong-corrupt-inquiry/106156988</link><description>A long-serving University of Wollongong staffer tells a NSW parliamentary inquiry she reported suspected corruption to ICAC, as concerns mount over governance, financial mismanagement and executive appointments at the university.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f18cc3a110c5e91606363e1549a17f84</guid></item><item><title>Life on Adria Downs, one of Australia's most remote cattle stations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/life-on-remote-cattle-station-adria-downs-edge-of-simpson-desert/106113634</link><description>The idea of life out on the edge of the desert has pulled in young people from across the country and overseas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30aecf0298469be8c670668321a4088e</guid></item><item><title>Life on Adria Downs, one of Australia's most remote cattle stations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/life-on-one-of-australia-s-most-remote-cattle-stations/106155078</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d7fbcf81c588959cd0e9c828a30dba9</guid></item><item><title>Polly the pony spreads Christmas cheer in Sale aged care home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/polly-pony-sale-aged-care-home/106123742</link><description>A Welsh Shetland cross pony is spreading festive cheer — and stirring memories — during visits to an aged care home in eastern Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68763151c972423b282b7963af875a56</guid></item><item><title>How to turn feelings of helplessness into support after the Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/showing-support-after-the-bondi-terror-attack/106144732</link><description>While you might be feeling a sense of helplessness after the attack at Bondi Beach, there are ways to convert those feelings into small acts of support and kindness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b80a9f2b4e6404531d9fddd5a3b2b165</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister announces 'largest' gun buyback scheme since Howard era</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/prime-minister-announces-national-gun-buyback-scheme/106162002</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has announced a national gun buyback scheme, days after a deadly terror attack on a Hanukkah celebration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c11240861c3ceb5d58dbe19f71f7daf5</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man caught with nearly 100 grams of cocaine is spared jail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/cocaine-dealing-used-car-salesman-warned-nose-clean/106162528</link><description>Nicholas Kozac pleaded guilty to possessing a trafficable amount of cocaine after he was caught with nearly 100 grams of cocaine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54a5ee3cd44fa450f7a948d34ffd7fcc</guid></item><item><title>Australian Cricketers Association calls for Snicko overhaul following Adelaide blunder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/cricket-union-snicko-adelaide-faulty/106162676</link><description>Australian Cricketers Association boss Paul Marsh has called for an investigation into Snicko, saying careers are being affected by the technology's lack of precision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ceaf99f984f811d439fa9a9313c4257</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder of his 88-year-old mother in Fern Bay, Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/man-charged-with-murder-of-his-88-year-old-mother-fern-bay-/106161282</link><description>Police say Thomas Andrew Tapley was his mother's carer and it is a tragic set of circumstances for the family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a26ea786a2b42912d0801203e8d85da4</guid></item><item><title>Long-running NT alcohol study recommends changes to costs and trading hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/alcohol-study-nt-reform-bottle-shop-costs-trading-hours-bdr/106153030</link><description>A major study into alcohol policy in the NT has recommended tightening bottle shop trading hours, raising the minimum price of alcohol and reforming the approach to individual liquor bans in the territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faf1e114544e966fb307519ec8b869d5</guid></item><item><title>Dimboola woman who told undercover police she gouged elderly man's eyes found not guilty of murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/murder-trial-jodie-hill-dimboola-supreme-court-wimmera/106135010</link><description>Jodie Hill wept as a Supreme Court jury found her not guilty of murder and manslaughter, follow a week of deliberations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c27523dda1ba63361998149b80edd8b3</guid></item><item><title>Man facing 47 charges over alleged firearms, explosives, drugs offending</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/nt-police-raids-47-charges-related-to-firearms-explosives-drugs/106162352</link><description>A licensed firearms holder has been charged with 47 offences after two NT police raids allegedly uncovered illegal explosives, unlawful weapons and illicit drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1357050631e3a3f882f0e04bf120e0f9</guid></item><item><title>Dayna Isaac's murderer Paul Sultana sentenced to 44 years in prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/dayna-isaac-murderer-paul-sultana-sentenced/106163088</link><description>A judge labelled intimate partner violence "a scourge in a civilised society" when he sentenced Paul Sultana to 44 years in jail for the murder of Dayna Isaac.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">149c5522e54856c953326759060152b2</guid></item><item><title>Man resembling Bondi gunman Naveed Akram caught on Philippines CCTV in mid-November</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/hotel-staff-id-bondi-shooter-naveed-akram-in-davao/106163036</link><description>A man resembling Bondi gunman Naveed Akram has been captured on CCTV in Davao City in mid-November, as authorities continue to investigate the movements of him and his father, Sajid Akram, in the lead-up to the attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ed32a133aaab274b4b34574138c8774</guid></item><item><title>Teen charged with rape and home invasion tried to break into the same residence earlier, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/teenager-faces-court-in-cairns-over-rape-charges/106163378</link><description>The Cairns Children's Court has heard a teenager accused of raping a woman during a Cairns home invasion attempted to break into the same property hours earlier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd513f5110f9aabd2a700ead601f524b</guid></item><item><title>Sydney man Danny Zayat jailed for 24 years over DV murder of ex-partner Tatiana Dokhotaru</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/danny-zayat-dv-killer-tatiana-dokhotaru-liverpool-jail-24-years/106163710</link><description>The stepfather of Tatiana Dokhotaru, killed by her ex-partner Danny Zayat, tells a court of her remarkable courage as Zayat is jailed for 24 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bab71281470ccfa3c7f935142c842e5c</guid></item><item><title>Driver charged with murdering young woman walking on Sunshine Coast footpath</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/guilherme-dal-bo-charged-with-murdering-mallee-smith/106161606</link><description>A Brazilian-born man living in Queensland is charged with murdering a 24-year-old NSW woman after an alleged hit and run that injured seven others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25158a86a4427ddbd0fcae8e461c82e5</guid></item><item><title>Family demands probe into NSW Police use of force after video of Dubbo arrest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/family-seeks-investigation-into-nsw-police-arrest/106144022</link><description>An Aboriginal man who was known by NSW Police to have mental health issues was hospitalised after his arrest over a traffic stop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e251acd9086df2e30c92e78447a28001</guid></item><item><title>Communities rally to battle tragic fires near Ongerup and support each other in wake of tragedy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/communities-rally-to-battle-tragic-fires-near-ongerup/106158088</link><description>Following fatal fires in Western Australia's south earlier this week, stories are emerging of how homes were saved and communities rallied in the wake of tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98001542e748a825278a6c3b287c006e</guid></item><item><title>Bedford creditors vote to hand over reins to The Disability Trust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/bedford-creditors-vote-in-favour-of-new-operator/105943028</link><description>Creditors have voted to support the sale of Bedford to NDIS provider The Disability Trust, which would guarantee the jobs of 1,100 workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9a922696cb7e31d90763393c14da8bb</guid></item><item><title>Chris Scott re-signs as Geelong coach until the end of the 2029 AFL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/chris-scott-re-signs-with-geelong/106164740</link><description>Already the longest serving coach in Geelong history, Chris Scott's new deal with the club will put him in the company of some of the AFL's greatest ever mentors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4b20efa127af39d99150577e3a53ae1</guid></item><item><title>Ben Stokes slows down and blows up, Travis Head makes Harry Brook pay for his drop — quick hits from day three of third Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/ashes-test-england-australia-travis-head-harry-brook-quick-hits/106161810</link><description>Harry Brook drops Travis Head on 99, which would have only soured the mood of his captain, who started the day already pretty ticked off. Here are the quick hits from day three of the third Ashes Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17abe94dd547033d54d230dc18710d01</guid></item><item><title>Travis Head, the last of Australia's larrikins, revels in his Ashes summer of love</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/travis-head-summer-of-love-ashes-adelaide-day-three/106163328</link><description>Travis Head has become Australia's most beloved cricketer, and as another glorious Ashes century guided his team ever closer to the urn, he was eager to return the love.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09216a2fa13a29eff00df344ef2e870a</guid></item><item><title>The 'heroic' couple in twin coffins, a 'gifted musician' and a 'woman of integrity' laid to rest across Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/bondi-victims-funerals-sydney/106161406</link><description>A couple hailed as "heroes in every sense of the word", a "gifted musician" and a "woman of integrity" have been farewelled in ceremonies across Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45c9d9967cc59224e9c66194b5fe4bf3</guid></item><item><title>Marlinyu Ghoorlie native title group in Goldfields celebrates recognition as traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/marlinyu-ghoorlie-recogised-traditional-owners-kalgoorlie/106158324</link><description>The result comes eight years after the native title claimant group first registered for native title, with a counterclaim by another group dismissed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7a64fcf1e4c5ed61e4447ce811ebbca</guid></item><item><title>Teens sentenced over deadly Wollongong street brawl fuelled by social media group chat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/wollongong-teens-sentenced-over-social-media-fuelled-brawl/106160012</link><description>A social media feud between teenage girls in Wollongong in 2023 erupted into a deadly street fight, leaving Kristie McBride dead and several teens now sentenced for her manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef38daa94195dd83aea57329916011ee</guid></item><item><title>Former Neighbours actor Damien Richardson avoids jail over Nazi gesture conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/neighbours-actor-damien-richardson-sentenced-nazi-gesture/106164336</link><description>Damien Richardson agreed to a restorative justice program, which will require him to apologise to the Jewish community and attend therapy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acd76bd4352d3ad78662b44f86f0287b</guid></item><item><title>Search suspended for deep-sea diver Timothy Bennett in Coral Sea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/search-suspended-for-deep-sea-diver-timothy-bennett-coral-sea/106164760</link><description>A professional deep-sea diver, with several fish species named in his honour, is remembered as a loving father and well-respected in the science community for his contributions to the study of fish species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cff240e4360bb7f080d72c372b643e3</guid></item><item><title>ABC News - Trusted Source of Latest News &amp; Headlines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/106165092</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf4dd05a8663342dc61f114f5c066608</guid></item><item><title>Smashed windscreen in remote SA unlikely caused by meteorite, museum says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/smashed-windscreen-unlikely-caused-by-a-meteorite/106163728</link><description>Scientists were hoping an object that smashed the windscreen of a self-driving car in October was a meteorite, but SA Museum's investigation says it remains a mystery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6fa23fca3359f35b6d3b27db2fa12d50</guid></item><item><title>Taipei Metro stabbing attack leaves at least three people dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/taipei-metro-stabbing-attack-leaves-at-least-three-people-dead/106165504</link><description>The suspect is also dead after falling from a building during a police chase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e69855cddd6e5cd5b274931d0967afa2</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese faces primary test of his prime ministership in Bondi response</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/anthony-albanese-bondi-terror-attack-jewish-community-safety/106156710</link><description>While the prime minister will forever struggle to shed the perception that he was too slow to recognise the threat to Australia's Jewish community, he is taking action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cd87a798462fffe818491a4a089e35b</guid></item><item><title>Today in history: Picasso painting worth millions stolen in daring art heist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/today-in-history-picasso-art-heist-brazil-2007/106143440</link><description>The 2007 Brazilian heist was not the last time a nimble thief made off with a Picasso. And as many Melburnians know, it certainly wasn't the first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdf9b392c5353c4783705b64fcc9f41d</guid></item><item><title>Jewish man Gaby Silver never felt unsafe in Australia, then October 7 and Bondi happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/jewish-mans-life-after-october-7-and-rise-of-antisemitism/106163426</link><description>The rise in antisemitism in Australia since October 7 has reshaped the way Gaby Silver's family lives. After the Bondi attack, they're even more on edge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9851d21b89dc8f7cccb89b841ec74de</guid></item><item><title>The teacher, driver and host who helped strangers take refuge during the Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/nsw-bondi-beach-cafe-households-help-strangers-terror-attack/106154094</link><description>These are the stories of everyday people who stepped up during dark times, and of a community coming together when two gunmen sought to tear them apart on December 14.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34c2994bb9893ffb4129bdf4c7f89f1b</guid></item><item><title>How the Bondi shooters got access to now-banned guns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/how-the-bondi-shooters-got-access-to-now-banned-guns/106165084</link><description>With Australia's strict gun laws, how was Sajid Akram able to legally own the gun he was using to slaughter innocent people in Bondi on December 14?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">327eaa363877743b6d9ce2546bb346d0</guid></item><item><title>BOM Christmas weather forecast shows cool day in the east, searing heat in the west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/bom-christmas-weather-forecast/106163070</link><description>Australia is experiencing a smorgasbord of wild weather in the lead-up to Christmas, featuring extreme heat, humidity, severe thunderstorms, and tropical storms all on the cards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">504f34082ff519e7f1eba368acf1bc86</guid></item><item><title>Grace Tame demands law reform after Diocese of Ballarat cleared of vicarious liability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/grace-tame-campaign-to-change-vicarious-liability-laws/106049438</link><description>In every Australian state and the NT, churches cannot be held vicariously liable for historical child sexual abuse perpetrated by their priests. Grace Tame is leading the charge for change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e23edcbb74ce54f9058cc6c8c40fe844</guid></item><item><title>Coronial inquest into deaths of cultural leaders Big Brother and Little Brother recommends spit hood ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/australian-aboriginal-men-coronial-alice-springs-hospital/106163524</link><description>The NT coroner makes nine recommendations following an inquest into the deaths of two disabled Aboriginal brothers who spent a number of years homeless in Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4b688369100d2435e0a0d0e1020a9c3</guid></item><item><title>Environmental experts, detection dogs team up to protect native freshwater turtles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/environmental-experts-fight-for-freshwater-turtle-conservation/106091598</link><description>A team of environmental experts, Indigenous rangers and conservation detection dogs is working on recovering the population of native freshwater turtles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b061a8b99e175b4f025e0503dbe8a7f8</guid></item><item><title>Records tumble as Matt Renshaw leads Brisbane Heat to stunning BBL victory over Perth Scorchers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/bbl-cricket-brisbane-heat-beat-perth-scorchers-in-stunning-chase/106165678</link><description>Matt Renshaw and Jack Wildermuth pull off one of the greatest run chases in T20 history in a stunning Big Bash match at the Gabba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce2ab05b0c2e1d363771da0f51caac1b</guid></item><item><title>Oxford evolutionary researcher says humans may have been kissing Neanderthals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/why-do-humans-kiss-has-scientists-puzzled/106162070</link><description>Why is swapping saliva something all human societies have normalised? Turns out kissing isn't just a human thing — all sorts of species appear to kiss, and new research suggests Neanderthals did it too.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">762208e206debcd0ceb6214694d71739</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne University Women's Football Club was once a powerhouse. Now it's at risk of folding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/melbourne-university-womens-football-club-at-risk-of-folding/106098428</link><description>Melbourne University is the latest women’s Aussie Rules club fighting for survival, but it is hoping intervention from an AFL executive can turn the club’s fortunes around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3f071d8111dd0ba9981cb00395aae18</guid></item><item><title>Murgon residents 'at breaking point' during end-of-year crime spike</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/murgon-crime-spike-leaves-residents-at-breaking-point/106146606</link><description>The crime rate spikes every year around the holidays, according to the police. Tensions are rising in the Murgon community, as residents say they don't feel safe in their homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c291dafdc2bb6411078d2494857c394a</guid></item><item><title>Queensland family saves thousands of dollars after embracing the spirit of 'Thriftmas' over holiday period</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/queensland-family-prepares-for-second-hand-christmas/106155536</link><description>Rising expenses across the festive season have driven a family of five in Brisbane to set a rule to only purchase Christmas presents from second-hand stores — and they've been pleasantly surprised by the treasures they've uncovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a698b3c24a2ff86ece2dd9e31e0d9cb8</guid></item><item><title>Former patients 'left waiting for justice' after damning report into Brisbane's Wolston Park Mental Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/wolston-park-mental-hospital-review-patients/106164118</link><description>Brisbane's Wolston Park Mental Hospital closed in 2001, but a 12-month review has shed light on its history of sexual abuse and patient mistreatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35b74cdc101b0ce65c8769c1b3dea6dd</guid></item><item><title>How are Australian parents responding to the social media ban for under-16s?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/social-media-ban-teenagers-parents-respond/106163362</link><description>For some parents, the social media bans for under-16s have come as a relief. But others say they are fuelling conflict.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d0e1f980c1e1f5b8b0ab9069307bc9c</guid></item><item><title>Dreams shattered as 140 Zone RV caravan customers' worst fears realised</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/dreams-shattered-as-zone-rv-caravan-customers-fears-realised/106165022</link><description>About 140 customers of Zone RV have been told they will not be receiving their caravans after the company collapsed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df27b491d5dc0e943a3963a6dfa933a7</guid></item><item><title>Health and safety case against Tasmania's Adams gin distillery dismissed in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/adams-distillery-fire-health-and-safety-case-dismissed/105728508</link><description>A work health and safety case against a distillery in Perth, northern Tasmania, is dismissed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">576053b0239b5830d97cc46b4dd6a6fe</guid></item><item><title>Mourners and support services gather in Bondi as Anthony Albanese calls for unity — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/bondi-beach-shooting-terrorist-attack-live-blog-december-20/106165292</link><description>Hundreds of surf lifesavers have gathered on Bondi Beach to pay tribute to the victims of last Sunday's terrorist attack. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49576f64cb345b8d0f5d965367e8aeb1</guid></item><item><title>WA researchers find 'alarming number' of children with strep A</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/west-australian-study-strep-a-findings-kimberley-broome-derby/106149204</link><description>An infectious disease study hopes to see faster and earlier diagnosis of strep A to prevent chronic diseases in high-risk communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15ec0e83dcd9ac966c1d7c09d456e909</guid></item><item><title>Islamic State made headlines after being linked to the Bondi attack. Here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/why-islamic-state-back-in-news-link-to-bondi-2026-attack/106165328</link><description>What is this group, which once ruled a territorial "caliphate" and inspired attacks all over the world?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23a7781fd5ac752147430590cdd9699f</guid></item><item><title>Grace Lillian Lee weaves a path from the Torres Strait to Paris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/grace-lillian-lee-weaves-a-path-from-the-torres-strait-to-paris/106158378</link><description>Lee's woven, wearable art creations have catapulted her from Cairns and the Torres Strait to Paris, a bustling textile mecca more than 15,000 kilometres away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f035e8cd3c98ce09e384b45807dd935</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Nathan Lyon's massive wickets end England hopes of record run chase in third Test at Adelaide Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/ashes-third-test-day-four-live-blog/106165808</link><description>Three enormous wickets from Nathan Lyon leave Australia four wickets away from winning the Ashes after day four of the third Test at the Adelaide Oval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">369d9bef32c3e34602e80558d280f4e0</guid></item><item><title>How a Queensland family is pushing for change after a devastating loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/tyler-pask-firefighter-mens-mental-health-suicide-prevention-qld/106154520</link><description>Tyler Pask devoted his life to being an incredible father, selfless brother and a diligent emergency service worker for the Queensland Fire Department. Now his family is transforming their grief into encouraging other young men to access support for their mental health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e043b9ab1cce3b514337e5e776c53588</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian government faces questions over Pulse advertising spend after it asked for an election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/tasmanian-government-pulse-advertising-spend-questioned/106165120</link><description>The Tasmanian premier's department authorised more than $13,000 of taxpayer money to be spent with a local media organisation to promote the budget after the government asked for an election to be held, documents show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c34711e08607faed47b6a2b2c70d843</guid></item><item><title>Ambitious plan to share Carnarvon's food bowl both locally and statewide faces hurdles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/ambitious-plan-to-share-carnarvon-food-bowl-for-those-in-need/106122230</link><description>Carnarvon's fresh produce could help Western Australia's food insecurity crisis, but there is concern not enough is being done to address the issue locally first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e0c57d3291083607501b742a9d01829</guid></item><item><title>NT housing market continues to grow as house prices climb across cities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/nt-housing-market-growth-darwin-palmerston-house-prices-property/106163296</link><description>First home buyers are being priced out of the Darwin property market by interstate investors looking to cash in on high rental yields, with many properties sold without even being listed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">383d94edaf584b057d7a83d7f812ba72</guid></item><item><title>Kalgoorlie the glittering prize for Frenchman Bruno Vincent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/frenchman-bruno-vincent-and-his-golden-kalgoorlie-dream/106153794</link><description>Bruno Vincent has spent his life searching for gold, so there was only one Australian city on his travel bucket list.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">581076f764038e0b5f97f7a1bdb5dc64</guid></item><item><title>Why new Perth Glory coach Adam Griffiths might be Australian football's most interesting character</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/adam-griffiths-new-perth-glory-footballs-most-interesting-man/106163416</link><description>In a team struggling to retain fans, in a league battling for attention, newly appointed Perth Glory coach Adam Griffiths may just be the man with the answers for both problems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4057aeb87bd9dcb463f0d5788dd76bf2</guid></item><item><title>Rare pink platypus spotted in East Gippsland river</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/rare-pink-platypus-spotted-in-east-gippsland-river/106137316</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9501b542d7707b4027e32255d214fc5e</guid></item><item><title>Rare pink platypus spotted in East Gippsland river by Melbourne fisherman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/story-rare-albino-pink-platypus-found-in-east-gippsland-river/106106194</link><description>In a remote river in Victoria's east, a fisherman says he has encountered an ultra-rare pink platypus, one of only a handful ever sighted in the past 200 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2210570f1b72946b56f526c3f1ca81e4</guid></item><item><title>NSW Premier Chris Minns backs calls for royal commission into Bondi Beach terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/nsw-premier-backs-calls-for-royal-commission-into-bondi-attack/106165816</link><description>New South Wales Premier Chris Minns is supporting calls for a royal commission to be held into the Bondi Beach terror attack, which claimed the lives of 15 innocent people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d56d9150fa06febba672ef81d588aa64</guid></item><item><title>England slammed for sending assistant coaches to front media after 'nonsense' Ashes interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/ashes-2025-jason-gillespie-slams-england-over-nonsense-presser/106166094</link><description>Australian Test cricket great Jason Gillespie slams England after a "contradictory" interview from an assistant coach following day three in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fd678fe46c14b16834ccd4fab0f790e</guid></item><item><title>A first look through the Epstein files reveals celebrity snaps, police notes and a lot of Bill Clinton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/epstein-files-documents-reveal-celebrities-notes-and-clinton/106166006</link><description>The US Department of Justice today released thousands of files it holds on late sex offender and disgraced financier Jeffrey Epstein. Here's what's been uncovered in just a few hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4185dfc1e39e4327e8ccf55dbfe96dac</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Surf lifesavers pay tribute to Bondi victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/nsw-surf-lifesavers-pay-tribute-to-bondi-victims/106166140</link><description>Hundreds of surf lifesavers and lifeguards, many of whom responded to the Bondi terror attack, form a human chain in a moving tribute to the 15 people killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">259f9d3e9b53d11c180ca7cec88ea48d</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu continues to rebuild one year after devastating earthquake</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/vanuatu-marks-one-year-since-devastating-earthquake/106148676</link><description>Tourists are returning to Vanuatu a year on from a major catastrophe. But many demolished buildings are yet to be rebuilt and some locals are frustrated with the pace of repairs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64d21f1d0b5d95bccfdd147cae3ae0f7</guid></item><item><title>Easy last-minute baked gifts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/easy-last-minute-baked-gifts-biscuits/106121496</link><description>From super-quick shortbread to giant chocolatey cookies, your guests will be delighted to take home something they will actually use.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ef21f63074a9068dcec8a1194f63090</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files contain new photo of former prince Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/new-photo-former-prince-andrew-mountbatten-windsor-epstein-files/106166672</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor, the former prince, appears in the first tranche of the so-called Epstein files.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6eecd6194d73f15e27e79dd511e68c0</guid></item><item><title>Focus on Bill Clinton in Epstein Files raises questions about how curated the documents were</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/white-house-pointing-at-clinton-after-epstein-files-release/106166576</link><description>The thousands of photos paint a picture of a life spent with the rich and famous but little that is incriminating to anyone but Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4450710bef7e28696e746ec81cb1c8da</guid></item><item><title>Men left 'shaken' and 'overwhelmed' after arrest in Liverpool intend to sue NSW Police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/victorian-men-arrested-liverpool-to-sue-nsw-police/106166008</link><description>The group were detained on Thursday after tactical police rammed a car in Liverpool in what was characterised as a precautionary measure following the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4d45fb72a0ba497067a9170be96af11</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne takes miracle catch and Nathan Lyon breaks England's resistance — quick hits from day four of third Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/ashes-adelaide-test-quick-hits-marnus-labuschagne-nathan-lyon/106165884</link><description>Australia finishes day four needing four wickets to reclaim the Ashes thanks to Marnus Labuschagne and Nathan Lyon. Here are the quick hits from day four of the third Ashes Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">292785d1e6db9c09359cd50fe63753d6</guid></item><item><title>England abandons Bazball but is still no match for Australia with Ashes triumph imminent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/england-abandons-bazball-no-match-australia-ashes-adelaide/106166260</link><description>England's belated abandonment of Bazball gives it temporary life, but reveals a painful truth — no version of this team is a match for the soon-to-be victorious Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d308d23d201fb686a094091b31dc695b</guid></item><item><title>Former Pakistani PM Imran Khan and wife Bushra Bibi given 17-year jail sentence in new graft case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/imran-khan-bushra-bibi-sentenced-17-years-prison-graft-pakistan/106166948</link><description>The case against Imran Khan and his wife Bushra Bibi centres on the alleged misuse of luxury state gifts from Saudi Arabia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8475037508df624b19eee2f15eacd17e</guid></item><item><title>As Sydney's Jewish community reels from the Bondi attack, the path forward is unclear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/bondi-attack-sydney-jewish-community-darkness-light/106160056</link><description>As Sydney marks one week since the antisemitic Bondi attack, the Jewish community is grappling with the question of where to go from here.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a56da5b7fcfb7b6cfac78ccd5e369fe</guid></item><item><title>With heads bowed after the Bondi terror attack, now is the time to listen to the Jewish community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/bondi-massacre-time-to-listen-jewish-community-australia/106161492</link><description>If we are to inch towards unity, the more we pause to listen, the more sure-footed our path forward will be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbf74fcf2928d62907dba7bc4a5262f2</guid></item><item><title>Christmas movies quiz: How well do you know festive films?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/christmas-movies-quiz/106163774</link><description>From Home Alone to Nightmare Before Christmas, how well do you know these Christmas classics?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f41ef1d4c848a74b2e5f33310af308a3</guid></item><item><title>How Psy's billion-views trailblazer Gangnam Style presaged K-pop dominance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/psy-trailblazer-gangnam-style-presaged-k-pop-dominance/106157038</link><description>Who'd have guessed a South Korean man doing a goofy horse dance was a recipe for a global phenomenon? Thirteen years after it made YouTube history we revisit the legacy of Psy's Gangnam Style.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be097fcc494a0b907293bced095b78e9</guid></item><item><title>Bondi mass shooting shows how extreme danger can spark bravery from bystanders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/heroes-bondi-shooting-official-advice-armed-attacks/106156678</link><description>Experts advise to "escape, hide, and tell" in a terrorist attack. These men and women did otherwise and saved lives when gunmen opened fire at Bondi Beach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e5f8b93a86aa9c6bde4a275cd02bb9a</guid></item><item><title>Spain uses an algorithm to rank how safe women are. Sometimes it's wrong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/spain-viogen-algorithm-women-safety-domestic-violence/106156062</link><description>In Spain, police have developed technology to work out how at-risk women might be from domestic violence. Some people have grave concerns about how often the algorithm is wrong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6fc13e6b98001bca1859104bf7cc6197</guid></item><item><title>How 3D movie animation technology is helping injured athletes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/3d-movie-animation-technology-helping-injured-athletes-acl/106024028</link><description>The reasons for high rates of serious knee injuries among female athletes are not fully understood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">519ae2d1daec62a35b1d8f8ec17a5f91</guid></item><item><title>White and grey kangaroos to be sold to prevent overcrowding at Bordertown Wildlife Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/group-white-and-grey-kangaroos-for-sale-bordertown-wildlife-park/106134948</link><description>White western grey kangaroos are a popular sight in a small wildlife park nestled near the South Australia – Victoria border and some are now being sold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">526ef39d38fec931410601e4a5bff601</guid></item><item><title>The Hidden Line: Art of the Boyd Women uncovers the stories of the women in Arthur Boyd's family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/the-hidden-line-art-of-the-boyd-women-arthur-boyd-bundanon/106051870</link><description>A new exhibition highlights the women behind acclaimed Australian mid-century artist Arthur Boyd, bringing their overlooked stories and art practices to the fore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71460a3cf4b948690cdd46266bd10da8</guid></item><item><title>The fight to save Australia's beaches from coastal erosion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/fight-to-save-australias-beaches-from-coastal-erosion/106153088</link><description>Most Australians live by the beach, but the coastline we have built our lives around is disappearing before our eyes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bcf12c59c885cada4ace7fca8e02440</guid></item><item><title>Temporary recreational fishing restrictions eased amid SA's algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/fishing-restrictions-eased-amid-algal-bloom-improvement/106166214</link><description>Some recreational fishing restrictions initially put in place to protect fish stocks impacted by South Australia's algal bloom have now been eased.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c02df0a0eb02fb2711cc0147c75ebb36</guid></item><item><title>Automatic tipping becomes prominent due to rising cost of doing business in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/automatic-tipping-on-the-rise-amid-cost-of-business-crisis/106167380</link><description>Australia's tipping culture is in the spotlight, following reports more businesses are adding automatic tips to diners' bills in response to rising operating costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b679047b87feb9034e2a7b2fbd74ac</guid></item><item><title>Limited options for people trying to donate blood in regional NSW in wake of Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/limited-options-donate-blood-for-bondi-victims-regional-nsw/106154832</link><description>Residents in parts of regional NSW could be left waiting months to give blood, with limited donation options available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3929a1dc995a6c59683ae73624ba922</guid></item><item><title>Survivors search the Jeffrey Epstein files but find no sign of their evidence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/survivors-of-epstein-search-released-files-to-find-nothing/106167268</link><description>Despite giving an FBI interview and victim statement, Epstein survivor Jess Michaels finds no trace of her evidence in the vast trove published online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">057cbf521763d48d86c35f3684d7b9d3</guid></item><item><title>'Dead zones' prompt tour operator Pennicott to fund marine study of D'Entrecasteaux Channel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/dentrecasteaux-channel-imas-study-pennicott-tours/106097994</link><description>For more than two decades, Rob Pennicott has taken tourists to see the D'Entrecasteaux Channel. But what he describes as "dead zones" have him so worried that he is funding a study to find what is going wrong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9109da1b1f370a434a82b082068c92cf</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting: Thousands at Bondi mark a week since terror attack; Albanese booed by angry crowd — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/bondi-beach-shooting-national-day-of-reflection-live-blog/106166856</link><description>Thousands of people heard messages of defiance and resilience, along with calls for “light, love and unity”, as they gathered at Bondi Beach to mark one week since the devastating terrorist attack. Look back on how events unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a68b38061450900ece6a17570c585120</guid></item><item><title>Yerrabi Cricket Club eyeing premier status as it grows within Gungahlin community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/the-new-gungahlin-cricket-club-growing-at-an-exponential-rate-/106166592</link><description>Within five years, the junior club has grown from two teams to having close to 200 players and has plans to become Canberra's first new Premier Cricket club in decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f53008b0a6702cad6334be3e13d523ee</guid></item><item><title>Victorian stock agent retires Toyota LandCruiser after 1 million kilometres</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/toyota-landcruiser-4wd-clocks-up-one-million-kilometres/106072806</link><description>A Victorian stock agent's four-wheel drive LandCruiser has reached a rare milestone, as experts say Australians are keeping their cars longer than ever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53305ec775f24703df6d19e7a24c3cb2</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: England batter Zak Crawley says Australia 'were the favourites' in defence of series disaster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/ashes-2025-zak-crawley-says-there-is-still-plenty-to-play-or/106167428</link><description>England batter Zak Crawley says there's still plenty to play for despite Australia being on the verge of a 3-0 series lead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e6c4eacec2955c277b1a4a1fa0a9ea3</guid></item><item><title>Images removed from Epstein files less than a day after being posted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/images-removed-from-epstein-files-less-than-a-day-after-posted/106167464</link><description>At least 16 Jeffrey Epstein-related files, including a photo of US President Donald Trump, disappear from a US Department of Justice webpage within a day of being posted, with no explanation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1169e04c29c15212ffa478f90262da2</guid></item><item><title>Pilbara mining towns left out of government's battery rebate schemes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/mining-pilbara-towns-left-out-of-battery-rebate-schemes/106025508</link><description>Residents in small Pilbara towns with power grids run by mining companies are excluded from home battery rebate schemes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd12d9c00ad0b9fa1138dad056f18caf</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu nationals celebrate faith and friendship in Bundaberg under the PALM scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/vanuatu-workers-sunday-worship-in-bundaberg/106128564</link><description>Moving to another country to provide for your family is not an easy choice but singing, hugs and faith make it easier for these Pacific island workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c95e3f6e5fb06f7cab8d6e5b783370a9</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs program Bikes Mwerre marks four years of after-school riding, learning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/nt-alice-springs-youth-program-bikes-mwerre-mountain-biking/106161762</link><description>An Alice Springs teenager who grew up with cycling program Bikes Mwerre is now sharing his knowledge with the next generation. It's a full-circle moment for the outback program built on pride, skills and belonging.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67b09a29c5885577f0ff42d2c18ffd4a</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Nathan Lyon injured as Australia wins series on day five of the third Test at the Adelaide Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/ashes-third-test-day-five-live-updates/106167504</link><description>Ben Stokes laments the end of England's Ashes "dream" as Australia wins the third Test by 82 runs on a surprisingly tense final day to take an unassailable 3-0 series lead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2314dd8e46e87a2245a76c42f0c6b1e</guid></item><item><title>Salt lakes' 'unreal' rainbow of colours captured by photographer in WA's Wheatbelt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/rainbow-of-colours-of-west-australian-salt-lakes/106102272</link><description>For photographer Scott Jon McCook, seeing the unique salt lakes of WA's Wheatbelt from the air was so captivating it started a five-year passion project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72731fec6a9968a297d0ccf073903a3e</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios handed wildcard into Brisbane International as his tennis return continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/nick-kyrgios-handed-wildcard-entry-into-brisbane-international/106167614</link><description>Former Wimbledon finalist Nick Kyrgios is handed a wildcard to the Brisbane International as he sets sights on an Australian Open return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9748afa9a526c6153ea0e3409d050568</guid></item><item><title>German aerospace engineer Michaela Benthaus becomes the first wheelchair user to go to space</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/german-engineer-becomes-first-wheelchair-user-to-go-to-space/106167474</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c5777d37f36f262d74e4c4e6dd97f05</guid></item><item><title>Paraplegic engineer becomes the first wheelchair user to blast into space</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/first-paraplegic-engineer-in-space/106167430</link><description>The flight was just 10 minutes but the capsule still managed to soar 105 kilometres up, skimming into space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d68ba7a26cb7926fb817a41140a09a0</guid></item><item><title>Destructive storms pass through Melbourne with extreme fire danger in north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/wild-weather-storms-set-to-hit-victoria/106167442</link><description>Victorians faced intense rainfall, damaging winds and large hailstones after severe storms swept across parts of the state. Emergency services called on road users to drive carefully in dangerous conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">267dc57e0c90d44868dab100bf31c99d</guid></item><item><title>Approaching her 80th birthday, Joan Jeffery is still riding high</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/horse-riding-melbourne-pakenham-upper-riding-club/106167500</link><description>While many people entering their 80s are struggling with physical or mental limitations, Joan Jeffery still manages to do all the heavy lifting of caring for a horse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78b8daf211928fe0801fe1cd43341c1f</guid></item><item><title>Agnes Water Museum says it houses a 100-year-old orange in its collection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/orange-100-agnes-water-museum/106158496</link><description>Visitors question why the piece of citrus was kept in the first place, but the small town museum credits the region's weather conditions which kept it from rotting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">220bc94b35c217d84468f923330a15f6</guid></item><item><title>US strikes kill at least five IS members in Syria, monitor says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/us-strikes-killed-at-least-five-is-members-syria-monitor-says/106167704</link><description>The operation employed more than 100 precision munitions targeting known IS infrastructure and weapons sites, according to a US Centcom statement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">714332fd27498946d7b47907ae3966d8</guid></item><item><title>PM announces review of intelligence and law enforcement in wake of Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/pm-announces-review-into-intelligence-and-law-enforcement/106167788</link><description>Former top bureaucrat Dennis Richardson is appointed to lead the review, which will report in April of next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a57e65069432e4bf4c3dbdafea0a1ce3</guid></item><item><title>After the Bondi attack, the contrast between Chris Minns and Anthony Albanese has been stark</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/bondi-attacks-chris-minns-anthony-albanese/106167738</link><description>As Sydneysiders paid their respects to the Bondi terror victims, one moment captured the contrast between two Labor leaders and their perceived responses to antisemitism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66f485429fd0f2daf2205867b0dc5324</guid></item><item><title>Chris Minns says Sydney anti-immigration rally 'the last thing we need'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/chris-minns-says-sydney-anti-immigration-rally/106167712</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c377723df52a02cfd8c5835485ce80a3</guid></item><item><title>NT government pulls funding for puberty blockers, gender-affirming hormones for children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/nt-government-defunds-puberty-blockers-gender-affirming-hormones/106167676</link><description>Northern Territory Health Minister Steve Edgington announces the withdrawal of public funding for puberty blockers and hormone treatments for children, labelling them "dangerous, ideologically driven practices".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76236274e5027a99a7945e981d4f8292</guid></item><item><title>Australian 15-year-old Indra Brown claims World Cup silver in the freeski halfpipe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/indra-brown-claims-world-cup-silver-in-freeski-halfpipe/106167810</link><description>Melbourne 15-year-old Indra Brown claims her second medal in her World Cup debut in the freeski halfpipe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80954cd03e29f2a887efebdc42b4f121</guid></item><item><title>Governor-general calls for ‘national project’ of kindness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/governor-general-calls-for-national-project-of-kindness/106167882</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95100176d10b9ba1584bdb713dac5c29</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Lyon injured on fifth day of Adelaide Test as England hunt a miracle to keep Ashes series alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/nathan-lyon-out-of-ashes-third-test-adelaide-oval/106167622</link><description>The 38-year-old spinner pulls up lame after diving to save a boundary in the morning session of the fifth day of the third Ashes Test at Adelaide Oval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2a0354dce3cadefd2b89d7bb464aab4</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate alleged daylight assault of woman at Burleigh Heads National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/police-investigate-alleged-daylight-assault-of-woman/106167804</link><description>Police are appealing for information after a woman was allegedly assaulted in broad daylight on a popular Gold Coast walking track.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">039d6e9b57ae8974559f389fa30b7f0a</guid></item><item><title>How a Reddit tip proved vital for uncovering the suspect of the Brown University shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/brown-university-shooting-suspect-reddit-tipoff/106167702</link><description>On December 13 a gunman killed two Brown University students and wounded nine others, escaping by foot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0171503282c7ed1792cdaaa0707f94b9</guid></item><item><title>How staying quiet led Pluribus to be one of the most talked about shows of 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/pluribus-vince-gilligan-interview-grand-finale/106123758</link><description>Pluribus, the new show from Breaking Bad and Better Call Saul creator Vince Gilligan, presents a life of perfect harmony — all you have to do is give up your individuality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbc80d2e3833aa32532ea544467c574d</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Lyon's hamstring, Marnus Labuschagne's hands and Jamie Smith's hack — quick hits from day five of third Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/ashes-day-five-third-test-quick-hits-nathan-lyon-jamie-smith/106167606</link><description>Jamie Smith is pilloried as "a dope" after an ugly dismissal as Nathan Lyon is injured and Marnus Labuschagne creates more catching magic. Here are the quick hits from day five of the third Ashes Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">288ad302313240c6d2b0d93d3b4ab597</guid></item><item><title>One Nation MP Barnaby Joyce calls for PM to be removed from role</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/barnaby-joyce-calls-for-pm-to-be-removed-from-role/106168272</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bead7f95e6c8ecfb0bb94f8015df368</guid></item><item><title>At 6:47pm, Australia paused to remember victims of Bondi Beach shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/bondi-beach-shooting-victim-commemoration-candle/106167470</link><description>In a nationwide memorial, Australians have taken a moment to light a candle and quietly remember the 15 people killed at Bondi. Their names, stories and legacies are held close by a shaken, grieving community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7642ef50458b1e3b536e7b815b8184e5</guid></item><item><title>Australia defeats words with actions to outclass England and romp to Ashes glory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/australia-defeats-words-with-actions-win-ashes-adelaide/106167652</link><description>In the pre-series furore, with England crowing and injury concerns mounting, Australia stayed quiet. Its response has been an emphatic and quite brilliant Ashes domination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a960ab205a5a2a65332a56bc79a1d79b</guid></item><item><title>PM loudly booed at memorial to terrorist attack victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/albanese-loudly-booed-at-memorial-to-terrorist-attack-victims/106168654</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b11bd7120a5dcd98682ed705762c0e2</guid></item><item><title>'Deep vein of anti-Semitic hate': NSW Premier Minns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/-deep-vein-of-anti-semitic-hate-nsw-premier-minns/106168750</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30fdb96a07548b3f9b59f919a150d89e</guid></item><item><title>'I will not hide who I am, an Australian and a Jew': Jewish leader Alex Ryvchin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/an-australian-and-jew/106168736</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02f421a0653968e39773179b7da7b7fd</guid></item><item><title>Bondi terror attack hero's father receives standing ovation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/bondi-terror-attack-hero-s-father-receives-standing-ovation/106168676</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77e566201b3d4dfb88c68bbc7e94253d</guid></item><item><title>Jewish community gathers for Bondi Beach shooting vigil and commemoration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/nsw-bondi-massacre-vigil-commemoration-jewish-community/106168156</link><description>At 6:47pm, one week to the minute after the start of the Bondi Beach terror attack, silence fell across the dusk gathering on the final night of the Jewish festival of light.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a037cfc875a8c1ee7634303851e2b7c4</guid></item><item><title>Nine killed, 10 wounded in South African pub shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/nine-killed-10-wounded-in-south-african-pub-shooting/106168912</link><description>The incident happened just before 1am local time at a licensed tavern in Johannesburg's Bekkersdal township.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c52dce15684d31b712fe4e3345e2bf37</guid></item><item><title>Is 2025 ending with an AI bubble? We could be at a turning point in history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/ai-bubble-2025-turning-point-history/106163574</link><description>What makes the AI-driven stock market bubble unique in history is that if it's not a bubble, the impact on humanity could be far more challenging than any previous technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8899d0659203518e9ae4e1c581b2cc1e</guid></item><item><title>Here's what defined Australian politics in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/2025-australian-politics-albanese-government-/106156682</link><description>The ABC's political reporters, commentators and broadcasters reflect on what defined the year in politics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6259476eec94f8255eb2ff6f5ffb50a0</guid></item><item><title>Staff at Melbourne building company say wages went unpaid as employer threw lavish parties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/mj-harris-melbourne-builder-faces-accusations-from-staff-clients/106149104</link><description>Since 2017, Melbourne building boss Mike Harris has overseen four company collapses. Left behind are clients who have lost their life savings and staff who couldn't pay their mortgages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3af22e2da9ec3ab5b648b80574301358</guid></item><item><title>What we do and don't know about the Bondi gunmen's month in the Philippines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/bondi-gunmens-mysterious-month-in-the-philippines/106166178</link><description>The long shadow of the Bondi shooting has darkened the coastal southern Philippines, causing deep confusion and stoking long-held anxieties over terrorist groups in the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24c312dbae0516e8aad918ac8fe18323</guid></item><item><title>Calls for gun law reform clash with gun lobby resistance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/gun-lobby-mobilising-thousands-to-fight-gun-reforms/106149156</link><description>Straight-pull rapid-fire rifles, social media campaigns, and a looming buyback scheme – Australia's gun debate is reloading.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eae98d89ae2b6255447abe5841945a36</guid></item><item><title>Doctors delay surgery for patients on GLP-1 drugs like Ozempic over increased risk of pulmonary aspiration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/ozempic-drug-may-cause-surgery-complications/106123802</link><description>Doctors say they are forced to delay some procedures due to the risk of serious consequences for patients on Ozempic-like drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ece2b7f8ae8cb0f146f5022a8217aeed</guid></item><item><title>Insolvent business run by former AFL star wipes its debt of millions, and the taxpayer is left to foot the bill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/zib-digital-claims-insolvency-wipes-debt-of-millions/105626186</link><description>A digital marketing agency run by a former AFL star has wiped its millions in debt through an insolvency process, only to open under a new ABN days later. Former staff were left without a job and almost $450,000 in unpaid entitlements, but it's within the bounds of the law and leaves taxpayers footing the bill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">086c65812d6df3ff00834a37ba752962</guid></item><item><title>England's Bazballers finally admit they've got things wrong in this Ashes series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/england-admits-ashes-failings-after-losing-series-bazball/106168162</link><description>Losing an Ashes Test series in Australia is nothing new for England, but finally the Bazballers are looking inwards at their own failings after a stirring end to the Adelaide Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b1974fa26020f76b673a29709bd243f</guid></item><item><title>US says it is intercepting third Venezuelan oil tanker amid simmering tensions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/us-intercepting-third-venezuelan-oil-tanker/106169160</link><description>If successful, it would be the third oil tanker seized as Donald Trump continues his campaign on President Nicolas Maduro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4520517b71bb14bfef5baa3678fe01e4</guid></item><item><title>Long-awaited wine industry mandatory code of conduct too late for growers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/mandatory-code-or-wine-grape-purchases-too-late-for-growers/106159408</link><description>After 20 years, three senate inquiries and an independent review, the sale of wine grapes will be regulated by a mandatory code of conduct, but growers say it might be too late.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4fa6c637aae4071ca8cfc3af2e1984e</guid></item><item><title>How domestic violence offenders use the court system to inflict more pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/domestic-violence-perpetrators-abuse-court-system/106047916</link><description>Jessica Seage fought for six years for the man who raped her to be convicted. Experts say her experience is a stark example of how perpetrators abuse the system to inflict more pain on their victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f60810c44353ad6c998ba40286d3c2fa</guid></item><item><title>Given the all clear from cancer, 6yo Laylah celebrates by ringing the bell at the Queensland Children's Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/laylah-celebrates-by-ringing-the-bell-at-the-queensland-children/106159230</link><description>When six-year-old Laylah-Jane Morton rang the bell at the Queensland Children's Hospital, it marked the end of her chemotherapy treatment for blood cancer — and she had her merry band of eight siblings with her to help her celebrate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b3aaf162cbcd84c631cb58386fed818</guid></item><item><title>Christmas bonuses boost staff morale, but employers facing 'tighter margins' may struggle to give</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/christmas-bonus-boosts-staff-morale-but-employers-may-struggle/106125160</link><description>From hams to vouchers and cash, festive bonuses vary — but do they still have a place in the Australian workforce?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbc88e61740bc5a0606df5358556f313</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Thousands honour Bondi victims at emotional beachside memorial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/bondi-memorial-in-pictures/106168886</link><description>Emotional scenes and a heavy police presence are visible at Bondi Beach as the Jewish community and other locals mark one week since the Hanukkah shooting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46eb7537e742841df96f060c12591a82</guid></item><item><title>Safety fears as Embark Education launches takeover bid for childcare rival, Mayfield</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/embark-education-launches-takeover-bid-for-mayfield/106159548</link><description>Embark Education launches a takeover bid for rival early childcare company Mayfield Education, alarming experts who say providers that fail to meet baseline safety standards are being allowed to expand without oversight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d24813b255ae6b6f9221404ecc73b103</guid></item><item><title>Federal government announces 2027 gas reservation scheme, ASX rallies — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/106168826</link><description>The federal government announced its intention to start a gas reservation scheme from 2027. The ASX made a strong start to the shortened trading week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f57478d51615dff71f1b0dc56e4c8d8</guid></item><item><title>Welcome Christmas rain in the outback while south-east Queensland will be sweltering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/wet-weather-western-queensland-christmas-south-east-heatwave/106167612</link><description>A tropical low will bring heavy rain and storms to much of Queensland this week while a south-east heatwave persists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8da0370dc226a6ec40f0c1cd6db13047</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Lyon and Pat Cummins likely out of Boxing Day Ashes Test with series secured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/ashes-test-nathan-lyon-pat-cummins-boxing-day-test-injuries/106169238</link><description>Nathan Lyon's injury leaves selectors with another headache, made trickier by Pat Cummins's admission that he will almost certainly miss the Boxing Day Test now that the Ashes are won.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43362296f8e292a76395433f21d6bc73</guid></item><item><title>China Southern Airlines starts flying between Darwin and Guangzhou</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/nt-direct-flights-between-darwin-and-china-recommence-guangzhou/106158228</link><description>Direct flights between Darwin and China have resumed for the first time since the COVID-19 pandemic, bringing optimism of a tourism boom for the two countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f90208db22eaf78f6c9898e34319ab6e</guid></item><item><title>High school students forced to fight false allegations of AI cheating</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/ai-detectors-incorrectly-brand-high-school-students-ai-cheats/106138394</link><description>Pulled out of class, held back after school and forced to prove they're not AI cheats, students say NSW high schools are pitting them against faulty AI detectors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4a24246430413aacd96f53d9bc87953</guid></item><item><title>Heavily armed specialist police to patrol MCG during Boxing Day Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/victoria-police-presence-mcg-boxing-day-test/106169288</link><description>Officers from the Critical Incident Response Team armed with long-arm weapons will patrol outside the MCG during the upcoming Boxing Day Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4592de7a0de2a0247e85a2c234dc6299</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder after woman's death at Northfield</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/man-charged-with-murder-after-woman-s-death-northfield/106169300</link><description>A 42-year-old man has been charged with murder after a woman was found dead in a home in Adelaide's northern suburbs on Sunday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb60343fedbc20ed6ab2e59a36bffee0</guid></item><item><title>Migrants from Bhutan turn to archery to maintain mental wellbeing and find community in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/bhutanese-migrants-perth-turn-to-archery-for-mental-health/106166838</link><description>Transitioning from "the happiest nation on earth" to a fast-paced Western society is not without its challenges for Perth's booming Bhutanese population, some of whom have taken up archery to improve their mental health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a752e9476b4479787484fd61cb25ab42</guid></item><item><title>How your town can become a 'dementia-friendly' community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/dementia-friendly-town-of-ouyen-in-regional-victoria/105888288</link><description>The small Victorian town of Ouyen, 440 kilometres north-west of Melbourne, is known for its grain and sheep farms, but also for being "dementia friendly".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1eadce463b3822ae2b242c0fb8a6a6cf</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested for knife possession at Christmas carols event in Launceston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/knife-at-christmas-carols-in-the-park-launceston/106169174</link><description>Police charge a man after he allegedly produced a 30-centimetre knife at a Christmas carols event in Launceston.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87ae1007835aef391c15316c33cda722</guid></item><item><title>Nikhil Chaudhary hits six out of Kardinia Park in match-winning BBL half-century for Hobart Hurricanes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/nikhil-chaudhary-bbl-half-century-six-out-of-the-ground/106169312</link><description>Hobart star Nikhil Chaudhary launches a ball onto the roof of Kardinia Park in Geelong, but his 79 off 38 is still not enough to earn him player of the match honours in the win over the Renegades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18d33b45c3ffa356814489356f19fb64</guid></item><item><title>Seasonal workers claim unfair bonus cuts and poor conditions on NSW cherry orchard</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/cherry-workers-claim-bonus-withheld/105486328</link><description>Ten pickers who worked at Hallmark Cherries' orchard in NSW complain about poorly maintained accommodation and failure to pay an end-of-season bonus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5525f59b29b8c57f2f0e3650c0121f0</guid></item><item><title>James Ransone, star of The Wire and It: Chapter Two, dies at age 46</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/james-ransone-the-wire-actor-dies/106169416</link><description>James Ransone, an actor best known for playing Ziggy Sobotka in The Wire and also starring in It: Chapter Two, has died, according to LA medical authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f56976d3a1105eb20ac2875136566226</guid></item><item><title>Calls for urgent intervention to help Victorian teachers find affordable housing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/victoria-teacher-housing-shortage/106155540</link><description>Victorian teachers say they are exhausted, living almost 100 kilometres from work, as their salaries fail to sustain housing costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ce43e8dfa4d3310582ffffb53bebd64</guid></item><item><title>Jenny Croom thought Portrait Artist of the Year was a scam — then she won it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/jenny-croom-portrait-artist-of-the-year/106152930</link><description>Jenny Croom put her art on hold for her family; now the 77-year-old has been crowned Australia's 2025 Portrait Artist of the Year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cef6dfd3cddcb3debab871102e89add2</guid></item><item><title>School children have inspired art works which will be installed on wind turbines in WA's Goldfields.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/vv-wind-turbines/106163026</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3579ce773f650d6bdad31d83ac7536f2</guid></item><item><title>Seven wind turbines provide unique canvas for Indigenous artist Sara Riches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/unique-art-project-gets-big-canvas-on-wind-turbines/106157212</link><description>A renewable energy project being built at one of Western Australia's biggest gold mines has been transformed into a unique canvas for an Indigenous artist and about 200 schoolchildren.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89410c93303c702004b3098846f43da2</guid></item><item><title>NSW parliament likely to pass Australia's toughest gun laws, crackdown on protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/nsw-parliament-recalled-gun-reform-protests-debate/106169248</link><description>NSW parliament looks likely to pass what would be the strictest gun laws in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c49571e02e778c60bc473e9d396e62d</guid></item><item><title>Zdravko 'Zed' Bilic's legacy to live on through youth sport initiative</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/zed-bilic-honoured-through-youth-program/106166798</link><description>The wife of the beloved soccer coach, who died during a home invasion, wants to help break the cycle of youth crime through sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72ec54e7639cd0d115acbb543df2742b</guid></item><item><title>Former chief justice urges national Bondi terror attack royal commission</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/difference-between-federal-and-state-royal-commissions/106169708</link><description>Calls for the federal government to hold a royal commission into the Bondi terror attack continue after NSW announced intentions for a state-level royal commission, prompting some confusion about the difference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df3a55da14a863f86e8d798be63d7f55</guid></item><item><title>Thousands gather at Stonehenge to celebrate sunrise on winter solstice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/thousands-gather-for-sunrise-on-winter-solstice-at-stonehenge/106169594</link><description>Crowds make the pilgrimage to the stone circle every summer and winter for what many consider a spiritual experience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02e8aff81c12896cd99e3cdf207eaca9</guid></item><item><title>Government confirms plans for gas reservation on east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/government-confirms-gas-reservation-plans/106170082</link><description>Chris Bowen makes a long-anticipated announcement about reserving a portion of gas on the east coast for domestic use after a cabinet meeting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24f6eb3702dbe2e4c6adb29e697ec32d</guid></item><item><title>Lake George hides an earthquake fault zone, and scientists are using your road noise to see it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/lake-george-earthquake-fault-zone-anu-research-map/106119740</link><description>Almost 100 sensors beside the Federal Highway are helping build the clearest picture yet of the fault beneath the iconic lake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba2fd8b425cff8b995d984e6eba26d74</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files fallout continues with push for US Attorney-General Pam Bondi to be held in contempt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/pam-bondi-faces-contempt-push-after-epstein-files-release/106169584</link><description>Two congressmen say they will recommend United States Attorney-General Pam Bondi be held in contempt of Congress for not releasing all of the Epstein files by the legal deadline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54d4f51da39ea5d0b6ecb4eefb90d7a4</guid></item><item><title>How people across Australia and the world have reflected on the Bondi terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/bondi-shooting-memorials/106169460</link><description>Yesterday we asked our readers to tell us how they had honoured the victims of the Bondi terrorist attack, one week on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80bd43b7a592066aac20ecd84b222638</guid></item><item><title>Building a village means showing up even when it feels hard, says Esther Perel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/esther-perel-on-building-a-village/106144018</link><description>Building and maintaining a village doesn't just happen. It takes effort. It means showing up even when it feels hard or inconvenient, says psychotherapist Esther Perel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d67bf72d30394641d123ddf4f13963ad</guid></item><item><title>Batemans Bay childcare closed for three months due to serious health and safety concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/surfside-kidz-childcare-centre-approval-suspended-batemans-bay/106162988</link><description>The NSW childcare regulator has emailed families to say the Batemans Bay childcare centre will shut immediately for three months due to "immediate concerns".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">898bac91c474fb52f9145dd166bfcc1c</guid></item><item><title>Children and staff abducted from Nigerian school released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/nigerian-school-children-and-staff-released/106170280</link><description>No group has claimed responsibility for the November 21 abduction of more than 300 children and staff from a Nigerian Catholic school.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">056e4c7c7c5bf6372ae57e6b7dd24a5d</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting victim Dan Elkayam farewelled as floral tributes removed from memorial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/nsw-bondi-beach-terror-attack-funeral-dan-elkayam-tributes/106170038</link><description>French engineer Dan Elkayam has been remembered as an adventurous young man who loved travelling, meeting new people, playing soccer and celebrating his Jewish faith at his funeral.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b95574b82ddd309541a43df156d2fad</guid></item><item><title>Bondi gunmen filmed 'firearms training' and threw explosives into crowd, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/nsw-sydney-bondi-terror-attack-naveed-akram-court-police-facts/106170286</link><description>The Bondi gunman accused of killing 15 people conducted "firearms training" in a regional area with his father and recorded a video about their "justification" for the attack, according to documents released by a Sydney court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51c6c2bf2e8f1f744234679e5d92702b</guid></item><item><title>Measles cases almost triple in Australia as global outbreaks continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/measles-cases-triple-in-australia-2025-global-outbreaks-continue/106017266</link><description>The number of measles cases nationwide is now approaching triple the number of cases reported in 2024 as outbreaks continue around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82bd3ef5e517af8782bba83a8249b2d0</guid></item><item><title>Royal commission into Bondi attack appears inevitable for Albanese government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/bondi-terror-attack-anthony-albanese-royal-commission/106156706</link><description>The prime minister is undoubtedly facing tough conversations behind closed doors, but until the public gets to witness the scrutiny he will never satisfy his critics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db25d53c1beff82d36461c1213792ef4</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanians in 1971 speak about legalising cannabis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/tasmanians-in-1971-speak-about-legalising-cannabis/106092878</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e1084c0bf0b75d7237ec823e930be5e</guid></item><item><title>Why Mitchell Starc is open to playing on to the 2027 Ashes series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/mitchell-starc-ashes-2027-retirement/106170684</link><description>Mitchell Starc will be 37 by the time the 2027 Ashes kicks off in 18 months' time, but the in-form quick is open to spearheading Australia's attack in their next clash with England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eef12edca6fb499a21126506c057fe05</guid></item><item><title>Alleged racial hatred event organiser Ryder Shaw refused bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/alleged-violent-demonstration-organiser-refused-bail/106169506</link><description>A 20-year-old who allegedly tried to organise a racial hatred event at Cronulla on the same day as the Bondi Beach terrorist attack is refused bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c4a8d8c4b3e2fab6749e2e865643e7e</guid></item><item><title>Industry and musicians explore ways to make vinyl records more environmentally friendly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/vinyl-records-environment-impact-stella-donnelly-green-music/106170050</link><description>Artists like Stella Donnelly are searching for ways to cut waste and make production of their albums environmentally friendly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a59ea18d46fe6b9b07a7c95c2823ee3f</guid></item><item><title>Prince William and son George visit homelessness charity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/prince-william-and-son-george-visit-homelessness-charity-/106171302</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">764d03c1a8d8cc3ba491b17e9ac824c2</guid></item><item><title>Pittsburgh Steelers star DK Metcalf lashes out at Detroit Lions fan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/nfl-dk-metcalf-takes-swipe-at-lions-fan/106170988</link><description>Steelers wide receiver DK Metcalf is expected to face scrutiny after he attempted to strike a fan in the second quarter of Pittsburgh's win over Detroit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b422aca399aacecc18cf214d11c042fc</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese apologises for what Jewish community experienced after Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/government-proposes-offence-radicalising-children-bondi/106171326</link><description>Anthony Albanese says he is "sorry" for what Jewish Australians have experienced, while announcing a package of legislative changes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39ff9692d1249d0a39a52a4963e9c058</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government to crack down on hate speech, review gun laws following Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/victoria-government-antisemitism-hate-speech-law-reforms/106170386</link><description>In the wake of last week's terrorist attack at Bondi Beach, Premier Jacinta Allan unveils a five-point plan targeting antisemitism in Victoria and providing a "pathway to normal" for the state's Jewish community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bbdedb4aef4f351eaa8178e77673fea</guid></item><item><title>Stuart Broad still believes Australia's Ashes-winning team is their worst side in 15 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/broad-stands-by-worst-aussie-side-in-15-years-sledge/106171220</link><description>Stuart Broad has attracted plenty of criticism for his low opinion of the current Australian team but the England great stands by his harsh assessment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ed2d189c786b9d849804d57aa80ed70</guid></item><item><title>Family tells inquest young mother 'died of a broken heart' as system failed to protect her</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/inquest-death-assault-broken-heart/105999220</link><description>The NSW Coroners Court hands down findings into the 2023 death of a young Indigenous mother after a doctor gave evidence the woman may have died from "broken-heart syndrome".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0991818df236a4db3da682a3adc1ecf</guid></item><item><title>Students say degrees have been disrupted by University of Wollongong cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/uow-students-unable-to-finish-degrees-inquiry-told/106159284</link><description>A University of Wollongong student says she left the institution after being unable to complete core subjects due to course cuts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6f6358ea0f52e0b1fe36666dd7e25bb</guid></item><item><title>Prince William and Prince George help make Christmas lunch at homelessness charity in London</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/prince-william-and-george-volunteer/106171112</link><description>From America, the Duke and Duchess of Sussex have also sent out their Christmas wishes on Instagram.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7eb1ff578a59de8d44a58f2a66c7ff58</guid></item><item><title>Should I pour leftover liquids or foods down the sink?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/should-i-pour-leftover-liquids-or-foods-down-the-sink/106170720</link><description>Ever been about to pour rancid milk down the sink and thought, "Hmm, maybe I shouldn't…"? What about the tomato passata that's gone off? Or the water you washed the paint in? Or that pungent oil from a tuna can?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6924007e49f62dd2d7c58991cdf504cc</guid></item><item><title>WA Beazley medal winners in ATAR and VET dream of engineering careers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/wa-beazley-medal-winners-in-atar-and-vet/106170532</link><description>Students from public schools in Perth's southern suburbs take out Western Australia's top education awards for 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f451eaebfda2514176736c034af87ee</guid></item><item><title>Queensland man arrested following dozens of antisemitic graffiti offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/queensland-man-arrested-for-antisemitic-graffiti/106170620</link><description>A Coolum Beach man is charged with 25 counts of wilful damage following a spate of antisemitic graffiti incidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9326f118b79691be07229f59bd0ffa9a</guid></item><item><title>Racing tribunal bans greyhound trainer Gerry Orr for six years over prohibited substances</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/greyhound-trainer-gerry-orr-banned-over-performance-drugs/106167546</link><description>Victorian trainer Gerry Orr has received a six-year ban for procuring performance-enhancing drugs after he inadvertently alerted stewards by giving authorities his mobile phone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">339cb2958b016cdcd07b9067d315e80e</guid></item><item><title>City Beach fined $14m by Federal Court over button battery safety breaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/city-beach-fined-over-button-battery-safety-breaches/106171832</link><description>The Federal Court orders the fashion retailer to pay $14 million in fines after it was taken to court by the Australian Competition and Consumer Commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2071cda5c164c9599c9f0fcc18fcbfc</guid></item></channel></rss>