<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 10:15:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>From a Barossa 'baronial' background, Ashton Hurn has risen to the SA Liberal leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/ashton-hurn-explainer-following-liberal-leadership/106111804</link><description>South Australia's new opposition leader Ashton Hurn has likened the task ahead of her to climbing a mountain, but she's taking inspiration from a family background that includes a former state cricketer and an AFL premiership captain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa54cf54be49af6d3ed9ac168f41e2f2</guid></item><item><title>Why Kate chose to 'stay flat' after breast cancer surgery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/why-kate-chose-to-stay-flat-after-breast-cancer-surgery/106087348</link><description>After a cancer diagnosis, Kate Miller's doctor recommended a mastectomy on one side only. But Kate wanted both breasts gone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee9c5fda1e5f653e7df6819b46e1e433</guid></item><item><title>Beetaloo Basin gas piped north to 'keep the lights on' in NT from 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/nt-beetaloo-basin-agreement-fracked-gas/106119676</link><description>The gas-rich Beetaloo Basin in the Northern Territory has been in development for years — now, the NT government says the gas will finally flow from 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d74885298a0685ba44389d466256d0a</guid></item><item><title>Abuse survivors say Centrelink's 'couple rule' puts women in danger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/couple-rule-centrelink-income-test-concerns/106100196</link><description>Financial and domestic abuse survivors say the way Centrelink assesses benefit payments for people in a relationship makes it harder for women to leave dangerous relationships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df9ee2f41264eeace457f874b59e068c</guid></item><item><title>Rare brain illness could not stop Milly from making country netball history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/milly-brock-tongala-netball-encephalitis/106098456</link><description>A rare brain illness left Milly Brock unable to walk or speak, but eight months later, she was back leading her regional netball club on grand final day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">821bba383f0020f9d6f99b0b9a15f322</guid></item><item><title>Why Ashton Hurn may, or may not, succeed as SA Liberal leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/ashton-hurn-vs-peter-malinauskas-election/106115114</link><description>Ashton Hurn now has the job she said she didn't want. Could she be the leader the South Australian Liberal Party needs?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09d86e9573dbb3d47b5534e04b272ccf</guid></item><item><title>Iron deficiency is a challenge for many female athletes, like Super Netball's Zara Walters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/zara-walters-victorian-institute-of-sport-iron-deficiency/106108280</link><description>Zara Walters felt tired, dizzy and unable to recover from training sessions — then she found out she was low in iron. It's a condition that often goes undiagnosed, especially in female athletes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ee03bad452a9f38b43e0a5a4d93185d</guid></item><item><title>ASIO examined Bondi Beach gunman Naveed Akram in 2019 for close ties to Islamic State cell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-beach-attack-gunmen-father-and-son/106142630</link><description>Australia's domestic intelligence agency, ASIO, examined one of the Bondi Beach gunmen six years ago for his close ties to a Sydney-based Islamic State terrorism cell, the ABC understands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61d8702038585ef6be9d3817b6662640</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach gunmen's movements in Philippines under investigation by local police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/philippines-officials-investigating-bondi-gunmen-travel/106153264</link><description>Philippines National Police say they are investigating whether the father-son Bondi gunmen travelled to a region known as a hotbed for violent Islamist militants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cfdebf849791ab6273271f58a4cbc16</guid></item><item><title>Nearly 600 trees to be lost for North Adelaide's public course redevelopment for LIV Golf event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/north-adelaide-golf-course-trees/106157472</link><description>The South Australian government has released plans for North Adelaide's public golf course redevelopment confirming that nearly 600 trees will be cut down, not the thousands previously claimed by the Liberals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8b42f76b4e3a8eecb245c24fce8adc2</guid></item><item><title>How to turn feelings of helplessness into support after the Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/showing-support-after-the-bondi-terror-attack/106144732</link><description>While you might be feeling a sense of helplessness after the attack at Bondi Beach, there are ways to convert those feelings into small acts of support and kindness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b80a9f2b4e6404531d9fddd5a3b2b165</guid></item><item><title>Is 2025 ending with an AI bubble? We could be at a turning point in history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/ai-bubble-2025-turning-point-history/106163574</link><description>What makes the AI-driven stock market bubble unique in history is that if it's not a bubble, the impact on humanity could be far more challenging than any previous technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8899d0659203518e9ae4e1c581b2cc1e</guid></item><item><title>Building a village means showing up even when it feels hard, says Esther Perel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-22/esther-perel-on-building-a-village/106144018</link><description>Building and maintaining a village doesn't just happen. It takes effort. It means showing up even when it feels hard or inconvenient, says psychotherapist Esther Perel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d67bf72d30394641d123ddf4f13963ad</guid></item><item><title>WA farming community loses 500 sheep, thousands of hectares of crops in fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-24/western-australian-farming-community-loses-500-sheep-in-fires/106153256</link><description>A bushfire emergency in Warradarge is over, but farmers say the work to recover what was lost has only just begun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80cdd9268fb9fd905e22ffb4920dd350</guid></item><item><title>'Aussie' poster in Adelaide vandalised with white supremacist message</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-25/racist-vandalism-of-aussie-poster-in-adelaide/106177068</link><description>An Adelaide street artist's poster aimed at provoking thought about national identity has been vandalised with racist graffiti.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72bd030ba7fd002b69b762b1060405de</guid></item><item><title>When can you get a refund or exchange under Australian law?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-26/what-are-the-return-and-exchange-rights-in-australia/106078512</link><description>It can feel awkward asking for a refund or to exchange an item if you’re not sure what you’re entitled to. We’ve broken it down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2723be7871092c53be9590ed79e4005</guid></item><item><title>Today in History: Top-secret Manhattan Project quietly approved</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/manhattan-project-roosevelt-nuclear-bomb-oppenheimer-japan/106174568</link><description>On December 28, 1942, a US president formally approved an investment in the top-secret project to create nuclear weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b97d3cfa3d0bc0fb02cbfcc70b2cd52</guid></item><item><title>LGBTQIA+ focused boxing class combatting loneliness amid warnings about social isolation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/lgbtqia-boxing-class-tackling-loneliness/106034550</link><description>One in three adults experience social isolation in what experts say is a "dangerous" issue in society. One suburban boxing group is working to tackle the issue, focused on the LGBTQIA+ community more at risk of loneliness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be1b7e6c38093ce747c6d1f9fa059918</guid></item><item><title>South Australian MP Nick McBride to remain in custody for next seven days</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-29/nick-mcbride-remains-in-custody/106183758</link><description>South Australian independent MP Nick McBride will spend the next week in custody, after being arrested and charged over the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23cfb7d551970cb59aa18a5b3f9cb66b</guid></item><item><title>Human-operated Tokyo robot venture allows housebound people to work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/tokyo-robot-tourism-business-cafe-housebound-workers/106177054</link><description>Ory Yoshifuji's Tokyo business employs housebound individuals to operate robots as waitstaff at a cafe and as personal tour guides in the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee5510266f87235181771f4e5e3fa9b7</guid></item><item><title>Record year for Australian beef exports despite Donald Trump's tariffs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/record-year-for-aussie-beef-despite-trump-tariffs/106188120</link><description>When Donald Trump enforced a 10 per cent tariff on Australian beef, there were some concerns it would impact trade. But the opposite happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9906a7cbfa515375f6e8f5ee77ad5126</guid></item><item><title>NSW residents urged to check if they are owed share of $300m in unclaimed cash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-05/about-300-million-in-unclaimed-money-in-nsw/106199820</link><description>Almost $300 million in refunds, dividends and cheques remain unclaimed by households and businesses across New South Wales, with locals urged to take action to secure the money they are owed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7337b84bfbea19ae477d4850fbbd042f</guid></item><item><title>Assault-accused MP Nick McBride says home detention makes him 'more wedded' to electorate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/sa-assault-accused-mcbride-speaks-about-home-detention/106211188</link><description>South Australian MP Nick McBride, who has been charged with aggravated assault, says home detention will make him "more focused" on his electorate ahead of the SA election in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02f3f4438b200f30196cb731428b4151</guid></item><item><title>Nick McBride could get $100k in taxpayer funding for re-election campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/nick-mcbride-public-campaign-fund/106216122</link><description>Independent MP Nick McBride, who is currently on home detention bail for the alleged assault of his wife, could receive around $100,000 in public funding to support his re-election campaign, according to the state's electoral commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6da77d577333a78823f3d1e500ec53a8</guid></item><item><title>Supporting your child when starting child care or kindy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/supporting-your-child-when-starting-child-care-or-kindy/106115412</link><description>It's natural to feel nervous about transitioning your baby or child into early childhood education. Knowing some settling techniques, as well as what you can advocate for on behalf of your child, can help their transition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d03690a51df17649ec94389e7563f80</guid></item><item><title>How I have fun with friends without spending money</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/perspective-koren-on-free-fun-with-friends/106055938</link><description>I've kept low-cost, high-fun habits alive for years, even after returning home to a city where socialising often seems to mean shelling out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a76d75b2115ed8d249c4c6396faeda38</guid></item><item><title>Explosives used to demolish Bell Bay power station smokestack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-12/bell-bay-power-station-tower-explosives-demolition/106221046</link><description>It took just 41 kilograms of explosives and less than a minute — a remnant of the 1970s fossil fuel age is blown to bits to make way for a methanol fuel plant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">470fdb8e016ee9f2126e50adb4de7bab</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Writers' Week cancelled amid controversy over disinvitation of author Randa Abdel-Fattah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-13/adelaide-writers-week-cancelled-randa-abdel-fattah-controversy/106225170</link><description>The remaining members of the Adelaide Festival board will step down and this year's Writers' Week event has been cancelled, after days of furore regarding the decision to cancel a scheduled appearance by Palestinian Australian author Randa Abdel-Fattah.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecc9e0474f8f1c4c6278e2f2532651ca</guid></item><item><title>Writers' Week cancellation highlights SA premier's uneasy relationship with the arts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/writers-week-cancellation-hits-the-festival-state/106226674</link><description>After backing the Adelaide Festival's decision to drop a Palestinian Australian author from Writers' Week, Peter Malinauskas is now trying to distance himself from a crisis that threatens to do untold damage to South Australia's festival reputation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">666a3079a0050792b8a7daebf44a9e06</guid></item><item><title>United Employment collapse leaves disability workers $6 million short in missing pay, super and entitlements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/united-employment-ndis-labour-company-collapse-millions-owing/106148800</link><description>Up to 500 workers are fighting to recoup pay, super and entitlements after the collapse of a large disability support provider operating in New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b24742333e24e23481242e1515f727f</guid></item><item><title>Cross-cultural sharing is at the heart of Townsville's community garden</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/multiculturalism-thrives-in-townsville-community-garden/106171508</link><description>In the heart of north Queensland, Ukrainians, Fijians, Zimbabweans and Koreans gather in the dirt to help each other grow vegetables.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">747778fb8e47c03a41a45f71a8a4227f</guid></item><item><title>Have you been gifted an ancestry DNA test? The results could be 'life-altering'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/why-ancestry-dna-tests-arent-just-a-bit-of-fun/106225222</link><description>If you're thinking of taking an ancestry DNA test as "a bit of fun", experts warn there is the risk of uncovering more than you bargained for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c18adfae6ecc122d7b0786df99d29aa2</guid></item><item><title>Back-to-school budgeting a chance for kids to learn financial literacy and empathy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/how-to-involve-your-kids-in-back-to-school-budgeting/106225314</link><description>Managing back-to-school costs, especially when kids want expensive brand name items, can cause a lot of stress for families. But including children in the budgeting and decision-making process is key to helping everyone get on the same page.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b64c02787d589912788d033586f11c</guid></item><item><title>City of Perth probe lays bare workplace 'crisis', erosion of trust between Mayor and CEO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-22/city-of-perth-workplace-behaviour-probe-/106250502</link><description>The City of Perth has rapidly descended into a workplace of psychological harm, according to a secret report obtained by the ABC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64fc50ebb57a43747397b8920642f9ac</guid></item><item><title>David Speirs not entitled to public campaign funding, electoral commission says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/david-speirs-not-entitled-to-campaign-funding-commission-says/106252588</link><description>Former opposition leader David Speirs would "not fulfil the nomination requirements" if he applied to be a candidate at the upcoming state election, the state's electoral commission says, raising significant doubts about his chances of a political comeback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b51d1258f01f889f9ffa8d09f9b01925</guid></item><item><title>triple j's Hottest 100 of 2025 — when it happens, how to listen and more</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/triple-j-hottest-100-of-2025-date-start-finish-time/106255830</link><description>Australia's favourite music poll is back for another year — here's when it happens and how to listen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1040e2c0baec6105e30c997bf6a0c8f8</guid></item><item><title>As Russia's war intensifies Europe is exploring military and economic independence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/davos-donald-trump-zelenskyy-russia-war-technology/106252046</link><description>As the world's elite gathered in Davos, European leaders confronted a reality in which they might need to defend themselves, and potentially against, the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">777407f3d912131f903aabe2a0e5650c</guid></item><item><title>Quick and easy pasta with a zesty, no-cook salsa sauce - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/summer-pasta-with-no-cook-salsa-sauce/106254654</link><description>Salsa is not just for tacos. It's the perfect summer pasta sauce and makes the most of juicy summer tomatoes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1362255da12c15379673ce7cc421c41</guid></item><item><title>Hoping to start your finances afresh in 2026? These tips will help</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/how-to-set-new-year-financial-habits/106125752</link><description>It might be time to devote some of your energy and good intentions towards your finances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">408ff5b0fc52a8a653d2b98b79542e00</guid></item><item><title>Why time feels like it speeds up as we age</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-28/why-time-feels-like-it-speeds-up-as-we-age/106223834</link><description>The perception that time is flying by can sometimes make us feel stressed and anxious. So how do we slow it down?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a0daa65cbbf696213c3b66e4297bd5e</guid></item><item><title>Planning to breastfeed? Preparation can help you meet your goals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/what-to-know-about-breastfeeding-before-your-baby-arrives/106220406</link><description>While most mothers in Australia start breastfeeding, by the time babies are five months old, exclusive breastfeeding drops to 15 per cent. Knowing what to expect — before bub is born — can increase the chances of meeting your breastfeeding goals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74803b6ee63f792d44b8c092db9dbd1e</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government urged to use careful diplomacy to defuse Darwin Port row with China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/farmers-urge-careful-diplomacy-in-darwin-port-row-with-china/106288346</link><description>Industry groups that suffered three years of damaging Chinese trade tariffs on products including barley are appealing to the federal government to exercise careful diplomacy to defuse tensions with China over the ownership of Darwin Port.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d329f53011599b0e1e704d744857ffe</guid></item><item><title>Tyra Banks's 'hot ice cream' went viral. Don't expect to see it called that anymore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/hot-ice-cream-tyra-banks-sydney-food/106283144</link><description>Reviews have said it "tasted like soggy biscuits" and was "a weird sensation to sip through a straw". Taste aside, something bugged me. How can you call something ice cream if it's not iced?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3f517f5dea71c2574d23fd042540f1e</guid></item><item><title>A 'chia seed' trend on TikTok promotes a 'quick fix' to weight loss, but is it safe?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/chia-seed-trends-social-media-tiktok-explainer/106274220</link><description>The health benefits of chia seeds have been well publicised, but health and internet experts are urging people to not believe everything you see on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">323bc9928f884477c6208f8e6701bf7f</guid></item><item><title>Carlos Alcaraz has his never-before moment by beating Novak Djokovic in his own house</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/carlos-alcaraz-defeats-novak-djokovic-australian-open-final/106293160</link><description>Carlos Alcaraz has defeated Novak Djokovic in a pulsating Australian Open final, becoming the youngest man with a career Grand Slam in the process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fea8ff00f86caf09279b2d1a402cc482</guid></item><item><title>Alcaraz and Djokovic thrill Rafa and a 'boring' heckle delights Rod Laver Arena — quick hits from the Australian Open men's final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australian-open-2026-quick-hits-alcaraz-djokovic-mens-final/106293202</link><description>Rafael Nadal gives his seal of approval and Novak Djokovic collects the one trophy missing from his cabinet as his Melbourne Park fortunes flip. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">021aed1707e51a762d3e47daa401edd9</guid></item><item><title>From Sabalenka to Djokovic and 'animals in the zoo', here are the best quotes from the Australian Open 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australian-open-2026-best-quotes/106291648</link><description>From tennis stars pushing for more privacy, to Djokovic saying he feels like an old man and a Kyrgios F-bomb, there have been some funny and weird quotes at this year's Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">092b0db1619ef3d506d5e88441d9fb8c</guid></item><item><title>Back to school for Northern Territory construction workers after Charles Darwin University blunder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/back-to-school-for-territory-construction-workers/106306240</link><description>Dozens of carpentry apprentices in the Northern Territory will be forced back to TAFE after an error saw them declared qualified to work on construction projects without completing required units of study.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a9b8af3f0adf0f58a66327083cef79e</guid></item><item><title>Worker's death at Tanami gold mine in Central Australia under investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/nt-tanami-mine-newmont-confirms-worker-death-tragic-incident/106307980</link><description>A 47-year-old worker has died following an incident at the Tanami gold mine in remote Central Australia, with police and NT WorkSafe investigating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1662970481b3a89b3a77c8d22c4b591</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds defeat Jamaica in first netball Test match in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/diamonds-defeat-jamaica-in-adelaide/106311692</link><description>The Diamonds made a flying start with the initial six goals in a comprehensive 72-41 victory at the Adelaide Entertainment Centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be741f4d1fb677fd340efe1016d77511</guid></item><item><title>Today in history, February 6: The Manchester United team that perished in the Munich air disaster of 1958</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/manchester-united-munich-air-disaster-1958/106183032</link><description>On a snowy February afternoon in 1958, the football team that many were calling the greatest that Britain had ever produced stopped to refuel at Munich Airport. The plane would never take off, and the Flowers of Manchester would take years to bloom again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd269141d3e84cd66d24a4d4ebf71ed8</guid></item><item><title>What Israel's President Isaac Herzog has said about Gaza, and why he won't be arrested in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/herzog-will-be-aware-controversy-wont-be-arrested-in-australia/106311734</link><description>When Israel's president lands in Australia this weekend, he can expect an official red carpet treatment. But he will be all too aware of the controversy his visit is generating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ffdecd9e59cf515e239536238754ac7</guid></item><item><title>ATO debt continues to drive record level of calls to small business financial helpline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/debts-to-ato-drive-record-level-of-financial-helpline-calls/106308516</link><description>Financial counsellors say small businesses struggling to pay debts owed to the tax office are driving calls to Australia's Small Business Debt Helpline higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5e7106c0d32cd232b4538e4271760e1</guid></item><item><title>French authorities sink tonnes of cocaine bound for Australia, then release suspects</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/french-authorities-sink-five-tonnes-of-cocaine/106307438</link><description>French authorities intercept a ship carrying five tonnes of cocaine bound for Australia, before releasing the vessel and its crew.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9429ea7a44b7fd6eb152b561ab54a17</guid></item><item><title>Gus Lamont's grandparents 'absolutely devastated' by major crime declaration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/gus-lamont-grandparents-release-statement/106314122</link><description>The grandparents of missing four-year-old boy Gus Lamont say the family has "cooperated fully with the investigation and want nothing more than to find Gus and reunite him with his mum and dad".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61b66feeae95a94497e72683ac842ff0</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia's government directs education funds to meals program as teachers struggle on low wages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/indonesia-government-directs-education-funds-to-free-meals/106307002</link><description>Temporary teachers in Indonesia paid low wages criticise a government decision to direct one third of yearly education funding to the president's flagship free meals program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06d0ac084c483586e077bca8379edf61</guid></item><item><title>Martin Luther King III says dad's dream possible for Australia's First Nations people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/martin-luther-king-iii-says-fathers-dream-possible-first-nations/106305226</link><description>Martin Luther King Jr's son says while the US administration was "attempting to turn the clock back" on equal rights, Australia shows "potential".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be89a8331df5000ec2c3402fbc0f20ec</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Festival leader Julian Hobba reflects on Writers' Week controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/sa-adelaide-festival-director-says-writers-week-saga-preventable/106306654</link><description>As Adelaide Writers' Week went up in flames, Julian Hobba contemplated resigning as Adelaide Festival's executive director. He now says "we needed to trust the judgement" of the literary event's former leader, Louise Adler.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6512b46457dc635dd9be1ece4907ad35</guid></item><item><title>Meringandan collector sells vintage tractors, trucks, machines on Queensland farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/meringandan-collector-sells-vintage-tractors-trucks-machines-qld/106305032</link><description>As the last man standing, 78-year-old cattleman Mervyn has parted with his collection of tractors and utes, pledging his estate to charity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">467219dc24b07990a0bbb37f1d3c6d41</guid></item><item><title>The life of Eulo's opal queen Isabel Gray looms large almost 100 years on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/eulo-opal-queen-isabel-gray-legacy-looms-large/106134938</link><description>The infamous Isabel Gray was known by many names and fronted court for sly grogging and stood accused of running a brothel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">822aee18118745c5ce53f1614c586828</guid></item><item><title>Danish people using apps to help boycott American goods over Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/greenland-denmark-app-boycott-us-made-goods-donald-trump/106319620</link><description>After Donald Trump's repeated threats to acquire Greenland, many Danish people felt powerless but new apps are helping them make choices to boycott US-made products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2297548a311c1a6d4f30bc1eec67099</guid></item><item><title>'Massive' Indonesian ghost barge washes up on tiny Torres Strait island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/mystery-indonesian-ghost-barge-washed-up-in-torres-strait/106323116</link><description>The barge drifted into Australian waters from Indonesia after breaking from its moorings during bad weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08b39ef063e5e2f00075ab3cf9dbea37</guid></item><item><title>More people say they'll vote One Nation. What are they voting for?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/one-nation-policy-platforms-pauline-hanson/106296838</link><description>One Nation questions if man-made climate change is real, wants to wind back access to abortion care and plans to pay the HECS debts of doctors working in the regions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed4bdf450e353d8bca00c742667777f</guid></item><item><title>Margot Robbie and Jacob Elordi sizzle, but Wuthering Heights isn't quite the full Brontë</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/wuthering-heights-movie-review-emerald-fennell-jacob-elordi/106321718</link><description>The two Queensland "bogans" put on a show, but Emerald Fennell's Wuthering Heights is more wish fulfilment than a meaningful adaptation of the classic novel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41b2ef0ef990ef2113fe88e9541e3117</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth asks to meet Roblox following reports of child grooming. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/commonwealth-roblox-reports-of-child-grooming/106323242</link><description>Roblox has been called to an urgent meeting with the federal government in the wake of reports that children are being groomed by predators and exposed to sexually explicit material on the popular online gaming platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8186dce135dbe17f29c38ae0b2e5a4fb</guid></item><item><title>WA police investigate possible tobacco wars link to fire at Kelmscott store</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/fire-alleged-linked-to-illicit-tobacco-under-investigation/106325512</link><description>WA Police Commissioner Col Blanch confirms officers from Taskforce Maverick, which investigates crime linked to the illicit tobacco and vape trade, are involved with the investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c193a813072c7da9378b52e50d8e27c3</guid></item><item><title>How to reduce loneliness while working remotely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/how-to-reduce-loneliness-while-working-remotely/106286338</link><description>Working remotely can be a lonely experience. Here's what you can do about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07ee38b05fb1af72edee6be374ac35ed</guid></item><item><title>Australian T20 World Cup squad looks different but do not count it out, Mitch Marsh says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/injury-hit-australia-open-t20-world-cup-campaign-against-ireland/106329438</link><description>Despite a slew of key injuries leaving the Australian team unrecognisable, captain Mitch Marsh is confident about the experience left in the side.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e7e79b7afbfde0a033b919098cc0b12</guid></item><item><title>Supersized fatberg clogging Sydney sewer blamed for mysterious debris balls on beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/supersized-fatberg-clogging-sydney-sewer-debris-balls/106309658</link><description>The debris balls that have washed up on NSW beaches in recent years are likely to continue as Sydney Water admits a massive fatberg it cannot reach is clogging sewers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e47536114404d9c787ba564b5b869472</guid></item><item><title>Bondi: Path to Terror</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/bondi-path-to-terror-four-corners/106332752</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3e3ec0c11f67bf60a856adfabe308d3</guid></item><item><title>US bars Palau senate president and former Marshall Islands mayor over alleged corruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/us-bars-palau-marshall-islands-officials-for-alleged-corruption/106329288</link><description>A senior Palau politician rejects accusations from the United States Department of State that he accepted bribes from "government, business, and criminal interests from China".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4c5d3311f093881fd48b21aa27d5d56</guid></item><item><title>Britney Spears sells rights to music catalogue in reported $281m deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/britney-sells-rights-music-catalogue-primary-wave/106333696</link><description>Spears is the latest music star to sell the rights to their work, a decade after the release of her ninth and last studio album.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46d37ff06c7881b67f6362f876d81145</guid></item><item><title>South Africa beats Afghanistan at Twenty20 World Cup after two super overs at Narendra Modi Stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/south-africa-afghanistan-t20-world-cup-double-super-over/106334290</link><description>South Africa wins the most dramatic T20 World Cup group stage clash with Afghanistan, featuring two super overs and countless twists of fortune.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb1593268b4f75b9895b6ade64f0c231</guid></item><item><title>Chocolate recipes to share some love with the people in your life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/valentines-day-recipes-love-chocolate/106325802</link><description>Whether you are into Valentine's Day or not, these chocolate recipes are perfect for sharing some love.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4882faeefbbf9e3310ba059823c6008</guid></item><item><title>New video shows violent arrest of Australian filmmaker James Ricketson at Sydney's anti-Herzog protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/video-shows-arrest-filmmaker-james-ricketson-sydney-protest/106337470</link><description>New video obtained by ABC NEWS Verify shows in vivid detail the arrest of a 76-year-old man, who was later released without charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8b85f342914cc4a1db8e8f827b072c</guid></item><item><title>Italy wins first T20 Cricket World Cup match as Australian-born players shine in 10-wicket win over Nepal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/italy-wins-first-t20-cricket-world-cup-match/106339406</link><description>Sydney-born brothers Justin and Anthony Mosca have guided T20 World Cup debutants Italy to their first win in the tournament, as their unbeaten half-centuries secured a dominant 10-wicket victory over Nepal on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3c6d0fe17105b65b0990f4c481c3845</guid></item><item><title>Trump repeals power to fight climate change, axes vehicle emissions rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/trump-revokes-basis-of-us-climate-regulation-ends-vehicle-emissi/106339598</link><description>President Donald Trump's administration has revoked a scientific determination that has been the central basis for US action to fight climate change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14587c3b8bd37c5943c0d33c136fd2f9</guid></item><item><title>Albany Woollen Mills' 101 years celebrated via shared love of blankets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/albany-woollen-mill-in-albany-celebrates-101-years/106322356</link><description>Established in 1925, Western Australia's first and only woollen mill transformed raw wool into fabric and blankets, becoming a cornerstone of Albany's industry before closing in 2002.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebfd4b3313c5a634d2a8d4ee911573eb</guid></item><item><title>Australia in danger of World Cup elimination after 'unbelievable' loss to Zimbabwe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/cricket-australia-zimbabwe-t20-world-cup-live-blog-scores/106327068</link><description>Australia's hopes of advancing out of Group B are dealt an almighty blow as Zimbabwe claims one of the biggest upset wins in T20 World Cup history in Colombo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">476ca6531e7d6c07f466b52971129dba</guid></item><item><title>How do you find modern dating? Share your highs and lows with us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/audience-callout-modern-dating-love-stories/106287262</link><description>Whether you've shed tears of joy, sadness or even laughter in the process, we want to hear it all — but keep it under 150 words.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e85c8d73dd7cdf15e05f480eb2c663e8</guid></item><item><title>Omelette muffin sandwiches with cheese and turkey</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/omelette-muffin-sandwiches-with-cheese-and-turkey/106327784</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c525a9f3c897fd83b2517f5b3c4c185a</guid></item><item><title>Omelette muffin sandwiches with cheese and turkey</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-13/omelette-muffin-sandwiches-with-cheese-and-turkey/106328084</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c52c1c58ccc9b237379f659872968c83</guid></item><item><title>Here's what we know about Angus Taylor's policies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/what-we-know-about-angus-taylor-policies/106342170</link><description>The new Liberal leader has signalled he will pursue a stricter immigration policy and a return to "Australian values" in his first pitch to win back voters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed198d16c5a3341a76e01f9075ac1b0f</guid></item><item><title>Easy, tasty and nutritious recipes for sharing this Ramadan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/easy-tasty-and-nutritious-recipes-for-sharing-this-ramadan/106331120</link><description>Looking for easy, nutritious Ramadan recipes? These options will help you prepare for and break your fast well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb9d0165cd75c38640ee10f031f1d403</guid></item><item><title>Jane Hume was punished for her election slips. Now she's been crowned deputy Liberal leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/who-is-jane-hume-the-new-liberal-deputy/106340342</link><description>The Victorian senator was unceremoniously turfed from Sussan Ley's ministry after being tarred personally with much of what went wrong in the Coalition's cataclysmic loss. On Friday, she ascended to the Liberal's second-in-command.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad7db387c85c1a7f0bbbd2e940f1ffa9</guid></item><item><title>John F Kennedy Jr and Carolyn Bessette met a tragic end, but America's fascination endures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/love-story-john-f-kennedy-jr-and-carolyn-bessette-what-happened/105519010</link><description>The public's obsession with one of America's most storied political dynasties has been fuelled by tragedies, such as the doomed romance between John F Kennedy Jr and Carolyn Bessette.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b05324178d29330114d196d20b34b7ac</guid></item><item><title>Major construction starts on Adelaide's first skyscraper Festival Tower Two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-14/major-construction-starts-on-adelaide-skyscraper-festival-tower/106345112</link><description>Festival Tower Two is set to tower over South Australia's Parliament House, which the premier says will bring money and people into the city, but others remain against the $800 million project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3de9dd2f69ba1ba4dfe31d2b03269b73</guid></item><item><title>Taylor faces formidable task rebuilding Liberals' electoral fortunes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/angus-taylor-faces-big-task-rebuilding-liberal-electoral-fortune/106337012</link><description>The paralysing uncertainty that weighed on the Liberals' faces has lifted for now, but morale in politics follows results rather than reshuffles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faa611ea05322062dacd66ef69db7e11</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Think you know the answers? That confidence won't last long</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106298688</link><description>I admire your courage for giving the quiz another go. Just kidding, I never feel that way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">678c4063da9fed065dd80b3c61605c60</guid></item><item><title>Woodstock Farm program helping steer troubled Queensland youth away from life of crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/woodstock-farm-program-helping-youth-avoid-life-of-crime/106337320</link><description>The rural-based social program in the shadow of Mt Tamborine has had remarkable success in rebuilding the lives of youth who have fallen through the cracks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">421b0aeae39a6049b42963e3f882f283</guid></item><item><title>Faaletino Tavana scores stunning try in NRL trial, Canterbury Bulldogs star Matt Burton limps off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/faaletino-tavana-scores-stunning-try-in-nrl-trial/106346352</link><description>Wests Tigers rookie Faaletino Tavana has laid claim to one of the best tries in 2026 during a preseason trial against the Sydney Roosters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2cfee729b56ca0f7ea35f8b101926f7</guid></item><item><title>NT film industry on national stage as Kangaroo, Top End Bub and Journey Home win AACTA Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/nt-film-industry-on-national-stage-at-aacta-awards-movies/106345258</link><description>The NT's small but mighty presence is shining on the global stage 40 years after Crocodile Dundee rocketed its film industry into the stratosphere.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6b91e7462a835a8868e55cdd28f79a5</guid></item><item><title>AFL State of Origin coaches hail success of concept following Victoria's win over Western Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/afl-state-of-origin-coaches-hail-success-of-concept/106346486</link><description>Winning Victoria coach Chris Scott and his Western Australia counterpart Dean Cox call for State of Origin to be played every year after the concept's stunning return in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a2310e59675ad0bac9b0b865d9ebaef</guid></item><item><title>Statues of Amy Sherwin, Australia's first opera star, unveiled at Hobart's Hadley's Hotel in bid to cement legacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/peter-schipperheyn-statues-of-amy-sherwin-opera-star-unveiled/106344982</link><description>An effort to bring new recognition to a Tasmanian opera star who became world famous, but who died poor, culminates in the unveiling of two statues of her in Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0073ccc352d93326f0623615a91690e2</guid></item><item><title>What is FAFO parenting and is it good for kids?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/what-is-fafo-parenting-and-is-it-good-for-kids/106321924</link><description>Is FAFO the 1980s parenting style today's generation of kids need, rebellion against gentle child-rearing, or exhausted parents just throwing their hands in the air?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27dfd8358d59f5a02bd8ef50448007a0</guid></item><item><title>Whooping cough cases hit record high after 'potentially catastrophic' vaccine rate drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/whooping-cough-cases-at-record-high-level-in-australia/106332954</link><description>A "potentially catastrophic" decline in Australia's childhood vaccination rates has contributed to the sharpest increase in cases of whooping cough in 35 years, infectious diseases experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df9f56f6aeb1e16c21e2baf9475f1b0a</guid></item><item><title>Cape Barren Island uses greenhouse and traditional foods to keep fridges full</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/alternative-foods-keep-pantry-full-on-cape-barren-island/105893250</link><description>A tiny island off the coast of Tasmania is embracing old and new techniques to keep food on the table.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6bcc5499da65ccb48471f2c099cdbf7</guid></item><item><title>NT MLA Tanzil Rahman accused of bullying two female staffers on VAD committee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/vad-chair-tanzil-rahman-accused-of-bullying/106340538</link><description>A Northern Territory politician has been accused of bullying by two female staffers while leading a parliamentary committee, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8223f2e6efd46e794a1a7458594f964e</guid></item><item><title>How the ABC Young Performers Awards helped launch the careers of these Australian musicians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/abc-young-performers-awards-launch-australian-classical-artists/106341202</link><description>The ABC Young Performers Awards have launched the careers of some of Australia's most successful musicians. Here are some of their stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd1d1f42c12f0cd8f19af90e90ca9734</guid></item><item><title>Chalmers mocks Taylor's proposal for bipartisan budget savings taskforce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/coalition-proposes-bipartisan-budget-taskforce/106348078</link><description>Angus Taylor wrote to the prime minister pitching the plan just days after being elected leader of the Liberal Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2e1b7a17f7bbb632412e2760a78b3ec</guid></item><item><title>Senior Liberals deny involvement in draft policy to ban migrants from Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/ley-draft-migration-policy-australian-values-statement/106348870</link><description>A leaked copy of the Liberal Party's migration policy prepared before Sussan Ley was ousted included plans to "elevate" the current non-binding Australian values statement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afcbb687b8d26ea4579377278e93aa57</guid></item><item><title>Australian women and children with links to ISIS forced to head back to camp in Syria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/australian-families-with-isis-links-leave-camp-in-syria/106351298</link><description>A group of Australian families with links to Islamic State fighters are forced to turn around after leaving a camp in Syria to try and begin their journey home to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d35a133c23ac9abe8c930ff01e24c75</guid></item><item><title>North Korea builds homes for families of soldiers killed fighting in Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/north-korea-housing-for-soldiers-killed-in-ukraine-war/106351754</link><description>North Korean leader Kim Jong Un unveils new housing development in the country's capital, Pyongyang, to repay the "young martyrs" killed fighting in Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fb5a467f679f84a1526c5a726d07025</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor bets on migration politics amid global rightward shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/migration-social-cohesion-language-support-division-policy/106348608</link><description>If migration is treated primarily as a cultural fault line, rather than an economic system embedded in national growth, the debate will remain loud. The structural reform will remain unfinished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86414a7a131a25b45dbc0a43798c1c16</guid></item><item><title>Robert Duvall, star of The Godfather and Apocalypse Now, dies at 95</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/robert-duvall-star-of-godfather-and-apocalypse-now-dies-at-95/106352132</link><description>Oscar winner Robert Duvall, known for films such as The Godfather and Apocalypse Now, has died at the age of 95.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c557714626458849acf4e2f9e4b0c251</guid></item><item><title>How to decide what type of car insurance is best for you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/how-do-i-know-what-car-insurance-is-best-for-me-/106260688</link><description>Choosing the right car insurance option can feel daunting, but it's the kind of task that it pays to get right. So, how can you decide which type is most suitable for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19c1a606228973fe803d3604b38ad3b1</guid></item><item><title>Results show high levels of lead contamination in dust around Hobart, as EPA flags further tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/nyrstar-lead-pollution-epa-tests-hobart/106339682</link><description>High levels of lead contamination have been found in dust samples taken from suburban locations close to Nyrstar's Hobart zinc smelter, documents obtained by the ABC show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df4c929be90ce6716c442950274a84e2</guid></item><item><title>Tradies consider leaving careers over lack of onsite toilets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/tradies-created-go-company-to-help-accessability/106244286</link><description>Tradies are walking out. Not over ability or aptitude but toilets — in a symbol of the sector's persistent barriers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2da70745cc00dda920be7b9032002395</guid></item><item><title>News quiz: Year of the Horse traditions, zodiac facts and festive customs across Asia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/lunar-new-year-of-the-horse-quiz-china-south-korea-vietnam-asia/106348886</link><description>How much do you know about the Year of the Horse and unique Lunar New Year traditions in Asian countries? Put your knowledge to the test with these 10 questions and see if you're a true Lunar New Year expert!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">664780860b8f5a75f0169a583ee380ca</guid></item><item><title>Mould, asbestos, collapsed ceilings plague some South Australian schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sa-schools-in-need-of-repair/106334244</link><description>Almost two years after a state government report revealed 35 per cent of all buildings within the Department for Education's portfolio were past their design life, many schools are still plagued with issues including mould, asbestos and rotting windows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fabb2b4476c5886be92e1dda09f3283</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the ISIS-linked families in Syria who want to return to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/who-are-isis-linked-australian-families-in-syria-al-roj-camp/106352074</link><description>Australia has made limited progress in clearing a passage for the Australian women and their children, citing safety issues in and around the camps, and security concerns back home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b94dd1490b366423951626bba907299</guid></item><item><title>Juanella Donovan reflects on People's Choice win at National Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Art Awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/artist-juanella-donovan-wins-natsiaa-peoples-choice-award/106350062</link><description>Juanella Donovan has taken out the People's Choice category at the National Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Art Awards for the second time, emerging as the public favourite from more than 200 entries across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">729bb7b7ed08ea9b03a622bdc521303a</guid></item><item><title>A waterfall gushes at Python Pool in WA's Pilbara region.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/a-waterfall-gushes-at-python-pool-in-wa-s-pilbara-region/106349636</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">604d0c1d3c020236aecb16e168ed1c29</guid></item><item><title>WA's illegal tobacco crackdown comes after less than $89,000 in fines issued last year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/wa-illegal-tobacco-enforcement-criticised-ahead-of-new-penalties/106350410</link><description>Amid moves to increase penalties for those involved in the illegal tobacco trade, Western Australian authorities are slammed for handing out just $88,100 in fines last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">533f151a81da30343f398451ee2797aa</guid></item><item><title>Albanese says Australian government will not help ISIS-linked families leave Syria or return home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anthony-albanese-on-isis-families-trying-to-leave-syria/106352492</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese insists the federal government will not repatriate the Australian families with links to Islamic State fighters who remain in Syria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faa866e3881f2d6646422dcbe7b56295</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor reveals shadow ministry, elevating Andrew Hastie and Jacinta Nampijinpa Price</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/angus-taylor-preparing-to-unveil-shadow-ministry/106354092</link><description>The new Liberal leader announces his shadow ministry, elevating prominent right-faction supporters including West Australian MP Andrew Hastie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">989975fa7a8805821e114a08b60c7715</guid></item><item><title>Australian production company Matchbox Pictures to be closed by Universal International Studios</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/matchbox-pictures-closed-universal-international-studios/106355260</link><description>Matchbox Pictures, the local production house behind Dog Park, The Survivors and Secret City, will be closed by its international parent company, Universal International Studios.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78b9d935e059c11895c3efac8807b716</guid></item><item><title>Private health premiums to rise at fastest rate in almost a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/private-health-premiums-increase/106355550</link><description>Private health insurance premiums will rise at their fastest rate in almost a decade, after the federal government approved a 4.41 per cent average increase from April.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cf53e80cc9f8f5821a0c50d3aa7dd87</guid></item><item><title>Aussie teen forced to wait for Olympic final as heavy snow wreaks havoc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-day-11-live-blog/106354466</link><description>Australia's Ally Hickman has to wait another day for the women's snowboard slopestyle final, as a snowstorm hits Livigno and causes scheduling delays.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0610df31fc2a456d285c9d60f0eeb066</guid></item><item><title>Jesse Jackson, civil rights leader and US presidential hopeful, dead at 84</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/civil-rghts-leader-jesse-jackson-dies-age-84/106356528</link><description>The two-time Democratic presidential hopeful remembered for powerful speeches died peacefully surrounded by loved ones, his family said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bef1e4b64b56ce290b7d00444b297818</guid></item><item><title>Richard Roxburgh, Damon Herriman and Toby Schmitz star in 'wickedly funny' play Art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/art-the-play-richard-roxburgh-damon-herriman-toby-schmitz/106051888</link><description>In the 1994 French play Art, Serge spends 160,000 euros on an all-white painting, horrifying his friend Marc. It might just wreck their decades-long friendship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf94795c60e3d3af64640f380e98e6b3</guid></item><item><title>Millionaire Gary Stevenson's dire warning for Australian property market losing the 'fair go'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/economist-gary-stevenson-warns-australia-losing-the-fair-go/106342536</link><description>British economist Gary Stevenson is on a speaking tour, warning Australia will follow the path of the UK with "poverty exploding" unless politicians deal with inequality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f588e11282bda2e3e28ac0a5b4d7af5d</guid></item><item><title>HungryPanda riders say Chinese police intimidating families in China over Sydney protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/hungrypanda-riders-chinese-police-threats-sydney-australia/106353996</link><description>Riders embroiled in a dispute over pay and conditions with food delivery company HungryPanda in Sydney say Chinese police have asserted pressure back home to stop them protesting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00b78e0a081535d928622de443de63b8</guid></item><item><title>Aerials delay is not unusual, as snow causes chaos at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/aerials-delays-2026-winter-olympics/106356762</link><description>Delays are nothing new in skiing events, with weather and light a constant battle for event organisers. However, the Australian aerials team has an unusual method to handle the disruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f49e711941aae6ee00c9b528308bb80f</guid></item><item><title>Investor's bet on empty building and passionate self-starters transform Charleville CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/young-business-owners-transform-charleville-cbd/106309412</link><description>A few years ago, Charleville's main street had lost its spark, with storefronts empty and windows shuttered. So, what does it take to bring a main street back to life?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab232bf6e0ba3b688550df9ce999546d</guid></item><item><title>Hindmarsh Island bridge dispute told through Ngarrindjeri women's art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/ngarrindjeri-women-retell-hindmarsh-island-bridge-story/106282804</link><description>In the 1990s, a group of Indigenous women were accused of fabricating claims of sacred sites to stop the construction of a bridge south of Adelaide. It was a decision that has impacted a community for decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c8df9f180475c2f0cfe199f0433a284</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: Jürgen Klopp makes Milano Cortina Games cameo, ice hockey fight ban labelled a 'joke' — quick hits from day 11</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/winter-olympics-2026-milano-cortina-day-11-quick-hits/106356448</link><description>Football manager Jürgen Klopp makes an appearance at the Milano Cortina Games, while French ice hockey players are unhappy about the ban handed to a teammate for fighting. Here are the quick hits from day 11.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e6fc860b11cec670fa7d512e4c8727</guid></item><item><title>Eungella residents want an alternative exit after Cyclone Koji cuts the range road again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/call-for-road-upgrades-after-cyclone-isolates-north-qld-town/106341980</link><description>The remote mountain community of Eungella was cut off for the second time in three years after Cyclone Koji brought debris down on the range road. After years of inaction, the community want more options when severe weather strikes again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be9369955e49f53b9d4c0f229ec2db27</guid></item><item><title>Pauline Hanson issues partial apology for suggesting there are no 'good' Muslims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/pauline-hanson-partially-apologises-for-muslim-remarks/106357130</link><description>The One Nation leader qualified her earlier remarks, which had been met with condemnation, while reiterating calls for tougher vetting processes for Muslim migrants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef8666bfdfbfd0c8dffd9a0c82b5b3cd</guid></item><item><title>Actor Shia LaBeouf arrested for allegedly hitting two men at Mardi Gras in New Orleans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/shia-labeouf-arrested-for-alleged-fight-mardi-gras-new-orleans/106357346</link><description>The actor allegedly hit a man multiple times with closed fists and allegedly punched another man in the nose.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f284d1a63429f4a42321d1db2ea5e20</guid></item><item><title>Australia's most successful Winter Olympics coach Peter McNiel and how his moguls team led the Milano Cortina gold rush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/australia-winter-olympics-coach-peter-mcniel-moguls/106356920</link><description>With a background in mathematics and an enviable attention to detail, it would be tempting to think of Australian ski coach Peter McNiel as moguls' answer to Moneyball. The truth is far more detailed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">525992813f56d82643171c38d6db94ad</guid></item><item><title>Housing to play part in future of both old and new ABC sites in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/housing-plans-for-new-and-old-abc-adelaide-sites/106357376</link><description>The ABC's managing director says its current Adelaide bureau could be redeveloped in a similar way to an apartment building nearby, while the premier says affordable apartments will still be included on the new CBD site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">016a01cde2182b1aeb6e120fc901d875</guid></item><item><title>As Donald Trump's first Board of Peace meeting approaches, Indonesians are watching their own president closely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/donald-trump-first-meeting-board-of-peace-indonesian-president/106348628</link><description>Ahead of the inaugural meeting of US President Donald Trump's Board of Peace, charged with leading the way forward in Gaza, Indonesian President Prabowo Subianto faces perhaps his most significant foreign policy test yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d30635e040376ea60c805df9793c8cb</guid></item><item><title>Is it ever a good idea to stay together for the kids?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/should-you-ever-stay-together-for-the-kids/106281890</link><description>When a relationships breaks down, sometimes we think staying in the familiar discomfort is less scary — and even protective — for our kids. But is it ever a good idea to stay in an unhappy relationship for the sake of the children?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbe4bbc74caa9ba1918949fae6630fe1</guid></item><item><title>Chalmers suggests ex-RBA governor's spending critique is due to personal vendetta</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/chalmers-dismisses-criticism-from-philip-lowe/106359398</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers says Philip Lowe was critical of the government over spending because it did not re-appoint him as RBA governor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4578c9f616d6026ee0f378a69efa25e</guid></item><item><title>Mazda, Nissan, Hyundai and Subaru face multi-million-dollar penalties under NVES</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/new-vehicle-efficiency-standard-results-mazda-nissan-penalties/106358770</link><description>Major car brands are staring down the barrel of multi-million-dollar penalties for exceeding their emissions, the first results of the federal government's climate laws for new vehicles have revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45198840bd21329442d531c79bcbff0d</guid></item><item><title>Workers in cherry picker help police catch man accused of lewd acts in Goulburn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/cherry-picker-workers-help-goulburn-police-get-man-over-sex-acts/106359652</link><description>A man is accused of intimidation and carrying out a sexual act over incidents at a medical reception and childcare centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fd548b341fa35cb67993bf434034999</guid></item><item><title>Police treating spate of Western Sydney shootings and arson attacks as linked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/nsw-shootings-firebombing-st-clair-guildford/106358300</link><description>Raptor Squad detectives are treating three separate incidents as linked to a conflict between two organised criminal networks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b24aea455146642267ad7109b7c6523a</guid></item><item><title>Footage shows gunman spraying bullets into suburban home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/footage-shows-gunman-spraying-bullets-into-suburban-home/106360196</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55dab837735b4e8baac3bf3d63e92a34</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106359046</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">077e4b34cad227fccef803151960b1af</guid></item><item><title>Terrorism comes to Invasion Day rally in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/terrorism-comes-to-invasion-day-rally-in-perth/106360466</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23a0ff08c113322a2a764cf193fc15a8</guid></item><item><title>Police accused of being slow to respond to alleged homemade bomb at Perth Invasion Day rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/sisonke-picked-up-ied-thrown-at-perth-invasion-day-rally/106360508</link><description>When Sisonke picked up a device that looked like a glass jar in Perth on Australia Day, she had a sense of foreboding so she took it to police. She says they took some time to act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4484d2c8c44530667bc645d156bdc3b</guid></item><item><title>Tackling 'blatant' fake discounting, restoring consumer trust among ACCC's priorities for 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/accc-outlines-priorities-for-2026-including-fake-discounting/106359994</link><description>ACCC chair Gina Cass-Gottlieb outlines the consumer watchdog's priorities for 2026, including targeting "blatant" fake discounting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2937ff2740ca14e3dac8a4082576d74e</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine reclaims more than 200 square kilometres of territory as Elon Musk blocks Russian army's internet access</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/ukraine-reclaims-territory-as-musk-blocks-russian-army-internet/106356642</link><description>Ukraine has made its largest battlefield gains in more than two and a half years, retaking more than 200 square kilometres of its territory from Russia in just five days, according to a new analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e4eeb80452a2963e88ee75deff26d71</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic pioneer John King Davis's grave was unmarked – until now</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/unmarked-grave-of-antarctic-pioneer-john-king-davis-found/106357712</link><description>Captain John King Davis was one of Australia's greatest Antarctic explorers, but for decades, his final resting place was an unmarked grave in Melbourne. Today, that will change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f55c0796c4ce772d58aac0922060d57</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, February 19: Britpop, beats and a lust for life on Trainspotting's deathless soundtrack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/trainspotting-soundtrack-30th-anniversary-danny-boyle-britpop/106354570</link><description>Most films are lucky to get just one needle-drop moment embedded in the Zeitgeist. Trainspotting boasted several.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ab3fc2c71c82699927e06d1a58d6cf7</guid></item><item><title>Quiz: Which books are these literary quotes from?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/famous-book-quotes-quiz/106321984</link><description>Are you happiest with your nose in a book? Did you spend summer reading at the beach? This quiz is for you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93263cc459c19ed242af066f07f52020</guid></item><item><title>Government spending is creeping up and threatening Australia’s 'low-debt' status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/government-spending-threatening-australias-low-debt-status/105579046</link><description>Australia will cease to be a low-debt country and be more vulnerable in a future crisis without a combination of spending restraint and tax reform, a new report has warned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13ac01b1668865c59fb5bf518f92a919</guid></item><item><title>Senate committee features climate disinformation, the Atlas Network, and Dr Karl's clash with One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/climate-disinformation-senate-committee-dr-karl-atlas-network/106350002</link><description>The scourge of AI-slopaganda, viral disinformation campaigns and online attacks against individuals and institutions is going to get far worse before it gets better, if the latest public hearings on the topic are any indication.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc806ab7e06e7cc45d048d4f225dbed0</guid></item><item><title>Perth couple Jonathan and Amy Carr-Knox locked in international surrogacy battle to bring home daughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/battle-bring-home-sophie-after-surrogacy-red-tape-argentina/106126626</link><description>Jonathan and Amy had a child via surrogacy in Argentina. They have been stuck there for 12 months, unable to bring their daughter home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e1192412c2820ccafbe31fa94aa760c</guid></item><item><title>Could SA Liberal leader Ashton Hurn lose her seat at the next election?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/could-ashton-hurn-lose-her-seat-at-the-next-sa-election/106357818</link><description>It's an almost unthinkable scenario, but the fact it's even being discussed shows the extent of the Liberal Party's predicament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9786f949730f20ebd11b7fd76ff59c7f</guid></item><item><title>Fiji's former prime minister Frank Bainimarama charged with inciting mutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/former-fiji-prime-minister-bainimarama-arrested-charged-mutiny/106360516</link><description>Long-serving Fiji prime minister Frank Bainimarama and a former police commissioner will face court on Tuesday on charges of mutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfb056a8d72b38a8175534edc2ea18aa</guid></item><item><title>Unemployment steady, ASX just misses record close, energy stocks bounce on oil spike — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/106361544</link><description>A steady unemployment rate puts more pressure on interest rates, while solid company results and higher oil prices push the ASX to a near record close</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4078cdb537970968fcf1992614fe87b4</guid></item><item><title>Moyne Shire Council never wanted Port Fairy's pool, yet it paid $3.4m for it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/port-fairy-pool-moyne-shire-cost-belfast-aquatics/106345296</link><description>A Victorian community group promised its local shire a new pool would not cost it money once it was built. In less than three months, the promise was broken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8cfb04cc8a00decf70f2adc47081828</guid></item><item><title>James and Sophie among West Australians keen to give back as regional doctors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/kalgoorlie-students-following-dreams-medical-career/106325718</link><description>After graduating six years apart at the same high school in Kalgoorlie, both James Gent and Sophie Barton are following their dream of becoming a doctor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74f984707ff32b96a738d83a30123435</guid></item><item><title>Indian university kicked out of summit for falsely claiming credit for Chinese-made robotic dog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/chinese-robotic-dog-indian-university-kicked-out-of-ai-summit/106361756</link><description>An Indian professor has sparked ridicule after falsely suggesting a commercially available Chinese robot dog displayed at a major AI summit in New Delhi was developed by her university.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f29670d2a9fcccc5e0e68270b1dfb47f</guid></item><item><title>From crime heists to a BDSM love story, here's what's in cinemas this month</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/what-to-watch-movies-february-pillion-crime-101/106352928</link><description>Australians will also finally be able to catch Sirât and The Voice of Hind Rajab, two movies that will be vying for Best International Film at the Academy Awards next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8040a86763a5a4d748d6c02c57f6603a</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane's Lang Park concert cap almost doubles under new trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/qld-lang-park-suncorp-concert-limit-to-almost-double/106360994</link><description>A one-year trial will see the number of concerts at Brisbane's Lang Park almost double from 12 to 21 per year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e40403a7bf49eabd7e064b1ff94cddfd</guid></item><item><title>How exclusion orders could ban Australian citizens from returning home indefinitely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/australian-citizens-banned-returning-overseas-exclusion-orders/106361634</link><description>One of the Australian women being held in a Syrian refugee camp has been barred from returning home after being given a temporary exclusion order — but the ban may not be as temporary as the name implies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b69ea4e5ccbec5d9f3ed7794e281795c</guid></item><item><title>SA secures Australian MotoGP, world-first street circuit announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/sa-secures-motogp-world-first-street-circuit-announced/106361722</link><description>The South Australian government has confirmed the Australian MotoGP will move to Adelaide from 2027, bringing with it huge economic benefits, but the opposition and Greens say the state has other priorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a957e6c008c2cd348424eaa2acecad49</guid></item><item><title>Feed and water supplies dry up in NSW as drought tightens grip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/drought-tightens-grip-nsw-feed-water-supplies-dry-up/106360686</link><description>Over this season's hot and dry summer in New South Wales, farmer Ryan Staniforth has spent much of his time carting water to keep his sheep alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46db9976c248632ce753eccaa9b15e80</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Pickering on his ADHD, satire and the 'ludicrous' Trump era</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/charlie-pickering-the-weekly-interview/106307588</link><description>Political satire occasionally comes at a price, but Charlie Pickering still believes the right joke at the right time can have a huge impact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7c1acd1c8fd008196d50eecb9154256</guid></item><item><title>The heartwarming tribute to injured aerials star Laura Peel at the Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/heartwarming-aerials-tribute-laura-peel/106361392</link><description>This Winter Olympics aerials competition saw plenty of Aussies achieve lifetime goals, but they never forgot the one person who was missing — injured champion Laura Peel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837dd8955b1207595385711ea5af7ba8</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Gardner, Casey Stoner slam Victorian government over Phillip Island MotoGP loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/phillip-island-motogp-loss-wayne-gardner-casey-stoner/106361880</link><description>Australian Motorcycle Grand Prix winner Wayne Gardner has lashed out at the Victorian government over the loss of the Phillip Island MotoGP, saying he has been left "disappointed" and "sad" by the decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf3ff0ae76acea3e2fe354f880cbf507</guid></item><item><title>Police commissioner claims drones over Moree will not be used for surveillance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/drones-over-moree-not-for-surveillance/106358042</link><description>Police will control drones from more than 600 kilometres away from a rural town battling high crime rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20b610568fd73b396033918dcd0e2eb0</guid></item><item><title>Heavy rain through north Queensland leads to multiple floodwater rescues and Bruce Highway closures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/queensland-rain-bruce-highway-closure-mount-isa-rescues/106362844</link><description>Heavy rainfall across north Queensland has led to multiple rescues and the closure of several sections of the Bruce Highway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f93257abf07c3acbc49599880adb87</guid></item><item><title>Sydney businessman compiled reports for what he allegedly believed was Chinese intelligence, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/sydney-businessman-alexander-csergo-foreign-interference-trial/106363262</link><description>A LinkedIn introduction led to Australian businessman Alexander Csergo compiling reports for two people he believed worked for a Chinese intelligence agency in exchange for cash, a jury has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">651f82d577914adb4455f34dffd493c5</guid></item><item><title>In her memoir, Gisèle Pelicot reveals the secret love behind France's most infamous rape trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/secret-boyfriend-who-stood-beside-gis%C3%A8le-pelicot/106357080</link><description>The world knows Gisèle Pelicot as the woman who waived anonymity during France's most infamous rape trial. But in her new memoir she reveals an unexpected story — the boyfriend she kept hidden and the love that helped her face an open courtroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f0faacac57b0eb7bcc67090ad05c423</guid></item><item><title>Rescue team departs to the site of avalanche in California's Sierra Nevada mountains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/rescue-team-departs-after-skiers-stranded-in-california/106362636</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6af50b73ab5f3a4e333965b255538317</guid></item><item><title>An avalanche in Northern California was the worst in the US for 40 years. Here's how it unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/how-the-deadliest-avalanche-in-the-us-in-40-years-unfolded/106362394</link><description>An avalanche in California has left eight back-country skiers dead and one missing. Here's how it unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ecbef0cca72889da9fa0ce66f9c81ea</guid></item><item><title>Rugby fans furious over 2027 Rugby World Cup ticket website crashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/rugby-world-cup-tickets-website-crash/106363344</link><description>Rugby fans from around the world are furious after failing to get tickets to the 2027 Men's World Cup due technical glitches and website crashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4827688c1be1b5c4bd7a18a7c04671b5</guid></item><item><title>For salty South Australians, motorsport revenge is oh so sweet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/for-salty-south-australians-motorsport-revenge-is-oh-so-sweet/106363660</link><description>The last Grand Prix in Adelaide was held in 1995 before its move across the border to Victoria. Now, Adelaide has poached the MotoGP — but will it be enough to appease resentful SA Formula One fans?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ffda5df5fc99fb91a7d77ce30ebe2be</guid></item><item><title>Hate laws put free speech at risk, constitutional expert tells NSW extremism inquiry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/concerns-laws-targeting-antisemitism-risk-free-speech/106363916</link><description>An influx of federal and state laws trying to curb hateful rhetoric after a wave of antisemitic attacks are risking free speech and could anger the public, a constitutional law expert warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ec2ab33e6214d10bc2d82b96c8df256</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with terrorism offences after phones seized in Sydney's south-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/man-charged-with-alleged-terrorism-offences-in-south-west-sydney/106364186</link><description>A 31-year-old has been arrested a second time after police stopped and searched a vehicle in Yagoona and seized three mobile phones allegedly storing violent extremist material.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a42a7ef9a3826f7f12e11df944244901</guid></item><item><title>Free RSV flu vaccine for aged care residents to be rolled out in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/free-rsv-flu-vaccine-for-wa-aged-care-residents/106363530</link><description>After a horror flu season last year, free RSV vaccinations are being rolled out for the first time for older Western Australians living in residential aged care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fe0ef7aa592c15d4a4bc95474ee48a7</guid></item><item><title>Canberra schoolboys face drug-affected driver who struck them outside St Edmund's College</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/court-hears-st-eddies-victim-struck-stolen-car-drug-driver/106364166</link><description>Tayler Hazell is facing his victims in a sentencing hearing in the ACT Supreme Court. He struck two students in Canberra in a stolen car while high on drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a88ee09264511c3bc4d69c943a39cbf1</guid></item><item><title>Hanson digs her heels in, Taylor goes on tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/pauline-hanson-barnaby-joyce-angus-taylor-anthony-albanese/106349216</link><description>This week, the new opposition leader revealed his shadow cabinet while Pauline Hanson spun through a cycle she knows well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ea3a4f2179a8b0064925ee07ccfca6c</guid></item><item><title>Vegetable scraps to be turned into bioenergy by Scenic Rim farm as part of $291 million project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/qld-kalfresh-bioenergy-scenic-rim/106363982</link><description>A new $291 million project set to turn farm scraps to energy has begun construction in Queensland's Scenic Rim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db61a8e13ba17ab198287e56aca27dc2</guid></item><item><title>Tracking the US military build-up ahead of possible Iran attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/tracking-us-military-build-up-ahead-of-possible-iran-attack/106363224</link><description>The steady flow of military assets moving towards Europe and the Middle East appears to be a warning that the US could be ready to attack Iran.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a711fd4fcffd045e2300336404218f1</guid></item><item><title>What is Skimo? The sport preparing to steal the show at the Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/skimo-debut-winter-olympic-games/106361848</link><description>Skimo, or ski mountaineering, is coming to the 2026 Winter Olympics. But what is the sport and why is it so exciting?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cc7441c0ae245bfcfcc6c6051609c64</guid></item><item><title>Two WA childcare providers fined after high-needs children wander off from care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/samson-primary-school-after-school-care-fined-over-child-leaving/106360960</link><description>One of Australia's biggest providers of before-and-after-school care penalised after a five-year-old neurodivergent child escapes supervision unnoticed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e0decf99cf8c863e11323748cea5d84</guid></item><item><title>Court hears statement murdered woman Irma Palasics made after harrowing assault a year earlier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/act-irma-palasics-trial-hears-statement-from-prior-burglary/106361986</link><description>A statement made by murdered woman Irma Palasics after a burglary at her home a year prior is read to the ACT Supreme Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0c56923a5ad0aebab9da439119af986</guid></item><item><title>Racing NSW disqualifies stablehand and owner Brian Carey over racehorse death in Maryborough</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/brian-carey-city-limits-racing-nsw-racehorse-maryborough/106362914</link><description>Registered owner and stablehand Brian Carey is disqualified after being found guilty by Racing NSW of failing to ensure his racehorse, City Limits, had sufficient food and water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89c623d6aac3515dcfe6d5527459d333</guid></item><item><title>Long-awaited rapid bus plan fails to reveal construction timeline or routes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/tas-rapid-bus-network-for-hobart-business-case/106363452</link><description>After about a year of delays, the Tasmanian government has released its strategic business case for the Greater Hobart Rapid Bus Network, but a lot of the detail has not been included.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a15721768f97446098853eb2e67cfa6</guid></item><item><title>Salmon farm antibiotics found in native Tasmanian species kilometres away</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/salmon-farm-antibiotics-found-in-native-species/106363462</link><description>An antibiotic used by the Tasmanian salmon farming industry is detected in native species more than 10km away from the closest fish operation using it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a05dff63808936e6ea4c1dbd47b42ed5</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of 'controlling' the lives of Venezuelan youth group granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/bail-granted-over-alleged-youth-group-servitude/106363616</link><description>An alleged religious leader accused of "controlling every aspect" of the lives of a Venezuelan youth group has been granted release on strict home detention conditions by a South Australian court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91bc9f195f669d568f2a90e1fe9c2a44</guid></item><item><title>SA Premier Peter Malinauskas criticised over aged care workforce comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/malinauskas-criticised-for-comments-on-aged-care-migrant-workers/106362214</link><description>South Australia's Premier Peter Malinauskas has been criticised across the political divide for comments he made asking One Nation voters "who's going to feed you and bathe you and wipe your bum when you're 90", but a government spokesperson says the comments have been mischaracterised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89e475d7e7fb2bdb64bd8fefb2824fc5</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate stabbing of 17-year-old at Geelong shopping mall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/geelong-shopping-mall-stabbing/106365416</link><description>A 17-year-old boy has been taken to hospital with serious injuries after a suspected stabbing at the Market Square shopping centre in Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cd13547a7c5a690d71c004d6eaed927</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 13</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide/106361600</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b82fce97399d532a4a35eed6ae6a0ea9</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood apologises after asking elderly members for donations via their wills</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/collingwood-magpies-afl-will-elderly-members-donate/106364978</link><description>The Magpies have come under fire after a letter campaign asking elderly members to amend their wills to donate to the AFL club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f43cc50e873d456431eb853f09b69899</guid></item><item><title>Coles manager moved product onto 'Down Down' promotion days after price hike to be more competitive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/coles-accc-federal-court-dog-food-down-down-pricing/106358664</link><description>A second Coles manager has been grilled in the federal court over whether rushing a product onto a "Down Down" promotion could have broken internal guidelines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41ca3a7b1fd4851df375d2220574fd44</guid></item><item><title>South Korea's ex-president Yoon Suk Yeol sentenced to life in prison over insurrection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/south-korea-president-yoon-suk-yeol-sentenced-insurrection-guilt/106363456</link><description>Former South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol is sentenced to life in prison on charges of rebellion for his attempt to put the country under military rule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8145bfdf54ebbed599a2b489a9edabf6</guid></item><item><title>Rottnest Channel Swim organisers weigh cancellation as 55 kph winds forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/rottnest-channel-swim-threatened-cancellation-rough-seas/106363432</link><description>As thousands of people prepare to tackle Western Australia's iconic Rottnest Island Swim, rough weather is threatening to grind it to a halt just 48 hours before it begins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a39a33fd7de283d8a2e3ed71fb9cf4e</guid></item><item><title>Labor Opposition, crossbench call for NT MLA Tanzil Rahman to respond to bullying allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/nt-politicians-calling-tanzil-rahman-explain-bullying-claims-clp/106364054</link><description>An MLA accused of bullying by two female staffers is urged to front the public and explain what action has been taken following the claims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1fafc3445b2b59e5354fc437a4169aa</guid></item><item><title>Gas explosion kills 16 after apartment building partially collapses in southern Pakistan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/gas-explosion-kills-16-apartment-building-collapses-pakistan/106365612</link><description>Women and children are among 16 people killed after a gas explosion ripped through an apartment building in Pakistan on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bac5b7cbd5dc5905b6f47c64562d41d5</guid></item><item><title>Greg Lynn applies for bail as retrial for High Country camper murder looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/greg-lynn-applies-for-bail-court/106365580</link><description>The former Jetstar pilot awaits a retrial for the murder of Carol Clay, after his 2024 conviction was quashed in December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77a388716f1e874a2b4c47724de2d0e3</guid></item><item><title>Live: Aussies among first competitors in newest Olympic sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/winter-olympics-milano-cortina-live-blog-day-13/106363160</link><description>Skimo, the newest sport at the Winter Olympics, makes its grand arrival in Milan Cortina, while Australia's teenage sensation Indra Brown hits the half-pipe. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16a288ead26f05bf91abbf1233f20917</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds commemorate the Bombing of Darwin on 84th anniversary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/bombing-of-darwin-commemorations-84-year-anniversary-esplanade/106362662</link><description>Eighty-four years after Darwin was bombed in the largest single foreign attack on Australian soil, hundreds have gathered to remember.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e51b581d2300e82c60871dc1ae74895</guid></item><item><title>Employees of Albany lolly shop fined for illegal tobacco sales say they were never paid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/illegal-tobacco-fines-albany-lolly-shop/106364808</link><description>"Vulnerable" staff at a smoke shop disguised as a candy store in Albany say they were never paid by the shop's mystery operators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">504a81865723b70dcc8bc16fa3cc618b</guid></item><item><title>Coles’ Down Down’ pricing in the spotlight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/coles-down-down-pricing-in-the-spotlight/106365338</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a28ccc3bfab237bb17dd661b462d31b</guid></item></channel></rss>