<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:48:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Social media's impact on Australian teenagers' wellbeing isn't black and white, new study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/new-report-social-media-on-teens-mental-health/106224780</link><description>The findings of a newly released study have challenged one-size-fits-all rules and blanket bans, as the Australian government's social media ban for children under 16 has been in effect for over a month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2ce908ee6431741a4f8cc1ce996fb2e</guid></item><item><title>Police say 10 tennis courts' worth of poppies stolen in recent theft</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/large-scale-poppy-theft-tasmania-police-investigating/106231170</link><description>Investigations are continuing into the theft of a large quantity of poppy capsules from a Tasmanian farm. Police have confirmed the harvested area equates to 10 tennis courts, or 2,500 square metres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e446c9678535b4be64f2f18a079d211e</guid></item><item><title>These epaulette sharks are breaking the rules of biology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/epaulette-sharks-are-breaking-the-rules-of-biology/106229708</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcb0cdfb6fe2c17e2820b055802fb9f3</guid></item><item><title>These 'walking' epaulette sharks can make and lay eggs without spending extra energy, scientists say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/captive-epaulette-sharks-make-lay-eggs-using-no-extra-energy-jcu/106231990</link><description>Known best for their ability to "walk" on the sand and coral where they usually live, new research shows epaulette sharks could also defy assumptions in other ways.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b075420a6a431e7245c6cc42b46824c6</guid></item><item><title>Queenaland Maroons captain Ali Brigginshaw calls time on Origin career to focus on Brisbane Broncos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/ali-brigginshaw-retires-state-of-origin-brisbane-broncos/106238298</link><description>Ali Brigginshaw announces she has played her last State of Origin game for Queensland as she looks to focus on one final NRLW season with Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e0933c27558f92c46db864e2a88c3a5</guid></item><item><title>Amy Bowden's mother calls for SA to introduce penalties for not calling emergency services</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/amy-bowden-mother-wants-penalties-failing-to-call-triple-zero/106238080</link><description>The mother of a woman who died of "mixed drug toxicity" is pushing for South Australia to implement penalties for those who do not call emergency services in a medical emergency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">921aea86a1019a6938f01a195a9cfbec</guid></item><item><title>No inquest to be held into deaths of workers killed by concrete slab at Eagle Farm racecourse in 2016</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/no-inquest-eagle-farm-racecourse-deaths-2016/106237948</link><description>The family of the two men killed when a wall crushed them at the racecourse are disappointed there will be no inquiry into the events of the "terrible day".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8daafc46c699b59e676c943f4f13156</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers defends 'professional' Fed boss Jerome Powell in face of Trump attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/jim-chalmers-defends-federal-boss-jerome-powell-as-trump-attacks/106238258</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers defends US central bank boss Jerome Powell as professional and diligent after the Trump administration launched a criminal investigation into the Federal Reserve chair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bb45703942b5dd53badf54783cd96ea</guid></item><item><title>How climate change is making extreme rainfall events like the Great Ocean Road flooding more frequent and intense</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/victoria-floods-climate-change-and-extreme-rainfall/106237516</link><description>When it comes to extreme rainfall, it's hard for climate scientists to say what's natural and what's caused by climate change, but they do know the most extreme events are dropping more rain, more often. This is why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fd2e0d2674eeb2b04eb9157146b56cd</guid></item><item><title>Huge 40-litre European wasp nest found in Albany suburb</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/european-wasps-found-in-wa/106237180</link><description>An enormous 40-litre nest of European wasps is discovered on the south coast of WA — the last frontier for the invasive species in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ccd67dc177b55a7ae19daf37a86da6c</guid></item><item><title>Huge European wasp nest found in Albany</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/huge-european-wasp-nest-found-in-albany/106238542</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">973dd9926c8227d4fc3ae503fedffbf5</guid></item><item><title>Construction worker 'seriously injured' by falling excavator bucket at Darwin Civic Centre development site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/darwin-construction-worker-injured-falling-excavator-bucket/106237966</link><description>A Darwin construction worker has been "seriously injured" after an excavator bucket fell and hit him, with paramedics transporting the man to hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4779c5e3f505d0904044a761f18cb4e</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106239186</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">014123baf9c94a7204824cf9ccb43485</guid></item><item><title>Death of Filipino worker in NSW referred to AFP after coronial inquest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/jerwin-royupa-coronial-inquest-findings-afp-referral/106202932</link><description>A NSW coroner has referred the death of a young worker to the AFP for further investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3133af62b6c72c3fac1f3bfa1a97ca1</guid></item><item><title>Family members charged after AFP arrests over alleged links to illegal tobacco, vapes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/family-members-arrested-by-afp-after-alleged-illegal-tobacco/106239172</link><description>A 47-year-old woman, her son-in-law and her father are granted bail after the AFP charges them, claiming they are allegedly involved in supplying illicit tobacco and vapes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f50cda4b1938101195eca004353caf96</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump threatens tariffs on countries that oppose US Greenland takeover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/donald-trump-threatens-greenland-tariffs/106239964</link><description>The US president insists America needs to acquire the territory of NATO partner Denmark for national security reasons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efb92949671aaba2ea86cdfa38916e42</guid></item><item><title>From Xinjiang to Tehran: Iran's unrest is shaping China's view of power and world order</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/china-iran-internet-blackout-xi-jinping-trade-xinjiang-tehran/106232712</link><description>Xi Jinping's ambition is to occupy a central position in a reshaped international system, not to lead a permanent grouping of sanctioned or crisis-prone states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb1773dec8b3903a3d288c3bdb7f5a7b</guid></item><item><title>Iran, Israel and the US play rapidly shifting roles in the Middle East</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/iran-israel-united-states-strike-gulf-states-donald-trump/106232766</link><description>Israel joining with other countries in the Middle East to press Donald Trump not to launch a military strike against a weakened Iran is something that would have seemed incomprehensible even a couple of years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c2cb52d7a42b236bd1a5d022b71a89d</guid></item><item><title>Natimuk fire offers a glimpse into a new kind of bushfire fuelled by our changing climate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/natimuk-fire-shows-new-climate-driven-faster-kind-of-bushfire/106225970</link><description>The anatomy of the Natimuk fire offers a glimpse into a new and faster kind of bushfire — and the growing vulnerability of communities as climate change fuels dangerous conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cc0e20806842cd62a7ed92da6ada48a</guid></item><item><title>British passport changes disrupt plans for reunions, sick relative visits and business trips</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/british-passport-rule-change-affects-family-business-travel/106238368</link><description>From February 25, dual citizens of the UK and Ireland will be required to enter the UK using a valid British or Irish passport, a change causing major headaches for dual citizens with imminent travel plans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">588cdd1bb29e74afc598ec2d1f52569d</guid></item><item><title>Allegations against author Craig Silvey should spark conversations with children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/how-to-talk-to-children-about-craig-silvey-allegations/106237832</link><description>A prominent parenting expert says serious allegations made against one of Australia’s most renowned authors should spark difficult but important conversations in households across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfc0dffbaa8b980f712a0691d2f4bae3</guid></item><item><title>Khalid Abdalla brings 'anti-biography' Nowhere about grief and the Arab Spring to Sydney Festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/khalid-abdalla-nowhere-sydney-festival-the-crown-egyptian-crisis/106234002</link><description>The Crown star Khalid Abdalla is in Australia to perform his play Nowhere at Sydney Festival, exploring his experience on the frontline of the Arab Spring in Egypt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e43c947130e33bfe4abf843385bc325</guid></item><item><title>Olympic climber Campbell Harrison happy to carry weight of being an LGBTQI+ role model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/olympian-campbell-harrison-proud-to-be-gay-role-model/106132328</link><description>Campbell Harrison was homophobically trolled in the lead-up to the Paris Olympics. It strengthened his conviction about the importance of visible queer role models in sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8b0815662be65c813bfbc7ba6f548c7</guid></item><item><title>Iran's young people have 'nostalgia for an era that they didn't live in'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/irans-youth-have-nostalgia-for-an-era-they-did-not-live-in/106224024</link><description>As protests shake Iran, massive crowds rising up against the hard-line mullahs and their supporters have been bolstered by the country's younger generations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fed36988f611ddb21d5f39cd8a992a45</guid></item><item><title>Victim-survivor of child sexual abuse reveals identity in hopes it will give strength to others</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/child-sexual-abuse-victim-survivor-reflects-on-bid-for-justice/106147740</link><description>Nicholas Taylor told a court last year that he was abused as a student at a Hobart Catholic school in the 1970s and 1980s. One of his alleged abusers was former Test cricket umpire Stephen Randell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b49b6b8d16d9304cc91173ab1c1e9bf</guid></item><item><title>Final bow for Tamworth Country Music Festival coordinator Barry Harley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/barry-harley-tamworth-country-music-festival/106199142</link><description>After 54 years coordinating the Tamworth Country Music Festival, Barry Harley explains it wasn't the drawling tunes that hooked him — but the "family" he made along the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6639cc8abd5de3d5645628fdcb7499bf</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith and David Warner trade centuries as Babar Azam fumes in Sixers win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/steve-smith-david-warner-score-bbl-centuries/106239560</link><description>Steve Smith smashes 32 runs from a single over after denying Babar Azam the strike, leaving the star Pakistan recruit less than impressed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5221cc01f1cb077323d65deaee1cb00a</guid></item><item><title>The SA premier faced one of his most bruising weeks yet. Will it matter come election time?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/bruising-week-for-peter-malinauskas-election-time/106238076</link><description>The dramatic cancellation of Adelaide Writers' Week spiralled the news cycle out of Premier Peter Malinauskas's control. But will the saga actually mean anything come the March state election?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a70314211ca6c804fd0adab2034ab48</guid></item><item><title>Unauthorised ski race planned for Lake Bonney despite national suspension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/unauthorised-ski-event-organised-without-government-aprroval/106223480</link><description>A water ski racing group has planned an alleged unsanctioned racing event in South Australia, which the state's Department for Infrastructure and Transport says it has not approved. It comes as the peak body for the sport has nationally suspended racing due to safety concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7adaa05341e1e5e92d5c17266efff6a1</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane residents swap apartments for boats as the cost of housing continues to rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/brisbane-boat-living-marina-housing-costs/106224448</link><description>Living at Brisbane’s Kangaroo Point overlooking the river would typically come with a hefty price tag, but some residents have found an alternative.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">573dc0ddebce8a5ce92970edb5d57888</guid></item><item><title>Nelson Asofa-Solomona announces plans to 'clean up the whole NRL division' after successful boxing debut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/boxing-nelson-asofa-solomona-calls-out-nrl-rivals/106240134</link><description>Nelson Asofa-Solomona calls out his former rugby league competitors after making a successful transition to the fight game by knocking out Jeremy Latimore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06dea109ef3a0a57ec1334d3709b5729</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Aboriginal inmate's connection to country stays strong through art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/sydney-aboriginal-inmates-connection-to-country-through-art/106189742</link><description>With each paint stroke and dot placement, art gives John the opportunity to express his culture, with some of his fellow Aboriginal inmates joining him in creating artworks while incarcerated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7b5839fd6a30d886691909f21ba0d06</guid></item><item><title>Tasty one-tray lemon garlic chicken with green beans and potatoes - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/lemon-garlic-chicken-with-green-beans-and-potatoes/106232614</link><description>This bright and flavourful chicken tray bake take just 15 minutes to prep and bakes in one tray.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a73c160b2a519f90a88a4f5dff57b6cc</guid></item><item><title>These 'seats of knowledge' offer daily connection and a few laughs.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/seat-of-knowledge-offers-daily-connection-and-public-life/106203248</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">704c811d8cc24ed90b6cf8f173f3c1ed</guid></item><item><title>Age-old 'seat of knowledge' tradition alive and well in North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/seat-of-knowledge-tradition-lives-on-in-north-queensland/105088332</link><description>Every day in these North Queensland towns, familiar faces gather to have a yarn in public spaces — just as people have done for centuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">325869c7d1ae1830039386227e137093</guid></item><item><title>Outback NSW lake home to hundreds of turtles set to run dry in 130-year first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/imperial-lakes-broken-hill-drying-up-water-emergency-wildlife-sa/106231978</link><description>Imperial Lakes Nature Park may soon dry out for the first time in over a century, creating an environmental crisis for the region and the hundreds of native animals that call the lakes home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d7d3b7026a65c01e693993a1ed3446a</guid></item><item><title>Darwin midwife banned from working unsupervised handed $1.1 million NT government contract</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/midwives-in-darwin-private-practice-contract-nt-government/106228974</link><description>Darwin midwife Claire Marks, who has been placed under a number of conditions by Australia's medical regulator, will continue to run the Northern Territory government's new private practice midwifery service, it's been confirmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">898f33552c4b6b06b8287c8c6b52eadb</guid></item><item><title>Developers propose demolition of Mount Gambier's flour mill walls for new commercial precinct</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/heritage-wall-demolition-mount-gambier-old-flour-mill/106232796</link><description>As the wrecking ball looms, a community battle is brewing over whether historic flour mill walls need to fall to make way for development.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab0c6542a993b0a61741e83c6dbcb596</guid></item><item><title>Matteo Berrettini fighting illness ahead of Australian Open clash against Alex de Minaur</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/matteo-berrettini-illness-australian-open-tennis-alex-de-minaur/106240240</link><description>Alex de Minaur's first-round opponent, Matteo Berrettini, faces a race against time to be fit for the start of the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">add7f046c505e63ba5a21535ac437487</guid></item><item><title>Linguists and First Nations community work together to 'awaken' Bunurong language</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/bunurong-languages-dictionary-spoken-100-years/106159478</link><description>After more than a century of silence, the Bunurong language is being brought back to life by elders, linguists and community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">515aff92716327e8e9d519b3d139b14c</guid></item><item><title>Taking paracetamol during pregnancy not linked to autism or ADHD in children, Lancet study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/lancet-rejects-trump-paracetamol-pregnancy-autism-claims/106236278</link><description>Just months after US President Donald Trump warned women about taking paracetamol during pregnancy, a new study finds there is no evidence linking the painkiller to autism in children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de1a4dfed93e58310a9ec2b4600e8f0</guid></item><item><title>Albany's heritage-listed skate park 'The Snake Run' celebrates its 50th birthday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/australia-oldest-skate-park-in-abany-turns-50/106224280</link><description>Australia is home to one of the world's oldest surviving skate parks, which is as much a product of surfing culture as it is a time capsule of skating history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47b5980a45d588d61f2a37b9449ac09c</guid></item><item><title>Greek tourist Ioannis Vidiniotis flooded with support after tragic accident at Cottesloe Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/greek-tourist-ioannis-vidiniotis-injured-at-cottesloe-beach/106237774</link><description>A young Greek tourist is flooded with donations and support after a tragic accident at Perth's most iconic beach left him with life-changing injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a1dd2bb32494b5c19fd59882ebd35a2</guid></item><item><title>White House names leaders who will oversee Donald Trump's plan for Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/us-white-house-gaza-board-of-peace-leaders/106240316</link><description>The White House has released the names of leaders who will play a role in overseeing the next steps in Gaza, under the so-called "Board of Peace".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67e4cbcabe0e125a443d912dab92d70f</guid></item><item><title>Fishers and authorities in WA's Gascoyne fear overfishing after demersal ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/fishers-authorities-fear-overfishing-gascoyne-demersal-ban/106150920</link><description>Fishing stocks have rebounded in WA's Gascoyne with authorities hoping it will model recovery efforts statewide. But that success could be undone by fishers fleeing restrictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f38c6332fb3d32cad83360ed57de96c</guid></item><item><title>Geraldton's Horizon Ball sculpture draws large crowds as international visitor numbers rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/horizon-ball-geraldton-sculpture-tourism/105874130</link><description>Geraldton's Horizon Ball sculpture is drawing huge crowds of tourists after the spot gained international attention on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eba3cf9d89c6c4bef13d23466afa00e</guid></item><item><title>US Justice Department opens criminal investigation into Minnesota officials</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/us-justice-department-probing-minnesota-governor-walz-jacob-frey/106240436</link><description>Minnesota Governor Tim Walz says the federal justice system is being weaponised to intimidate Donald Trump's perceived political enemies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9385bd2ca60ba61c7534e0dc0e342f55</guid></item><item><title>Labor separates gun control laws from hate speech reforms after bill turned down by Coalition and Greens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/greens-wont-support-labor-hate-speech-reforms/106240440</link><description>The Albanese government will separate laws tightening gun control from its proposed hate speech reforms after the omnibus bill failed to secure the support of the Coalition and the Greens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc1166e4fe21c76da4e4699368b3a6e1</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar denies deadly Rohingya campaign amounts to genocide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/myanmar-denies-deadly-rohingya-campaign-amounts-to-genocide/106240468</link><description>The South-East Asian country's armed forces launched an offensive in 2017 that forced over 700,000 ethnic Rohingya from their homes into neighbouring Bangladesh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2aed1ec7475d01a08ff0c3e04843dca4</guid></item><item><title>Chinese debate Iran crisis as official and public views diverge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/chinese-people-debate-iran-crisis/106233150</link><description>As protests rage in Iran, Chinese netizens are openly debating freedom, repression and global power politics, even as Beijing keeps its criticism focused on Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cb409cb7ff6c28214b6ec8d97672506</guid></item><item><title>Michael Zerafa has been accused of quitting against Nikita Tszyu. There is no more heinous crime in boxing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/michael-zerafa-quit-nikita-tszyu-boxing-brisbane/106240558</link><description>To be called a quitter is the lowest insult in boxing. But whether Michael Zerafa was guilty of this or not, he has successfully ostracised himself from the sport's fraternity for the second time in his career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">666c36595d1ab5ab540ee320d55b3322</guid></item><item><title>Machado's peace prize gift shows she's betting on a future with Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/machado-strategy-to-gift-peace-prize-to-trump/106239946</link><description>Lacking leverage with the United States, María Machado makes a calculated move to gift her Nobel Peace Prize to President Donald Trump. It underscores her willingness to think long-term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11c8be1d662313f0f85301fdd66bfac2</guid></item><item><title>Woman dies after tree falls on her car south of Wollongong as winds and rain lash NSW coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/woman-dies-tree-hits-car-at-macquarie-pass-winds-rain-lash-nsw/106240346</link><description>Emergency services were called to the Illawarra Highway near Clover Hill Road just before 4pm after a tree branch fell onto a passing vehicle on a busy road.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">787443ac31c67f6ad25ac254b1fe21d8</guid></item><item><title>Why the chase for the grand slam record is not a burden for Novak Djokovic ahead of Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/novak-djokovic-australian-open-grand-slam-record-wins/106240934</link><description>After two years stuck one shy of the all-time grand slam titles record, Novak Djokovic believes the Australian Open is as good a place as any to make his greatest piece of history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a317a3b7e35d5a435b5869ec5fe052ec</guid></item><item><title>'I'm back!' Australian cricket great Damien Martyn shares heartfelt update on remarkable recovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-17/damien-martyn-shares-heartfelt-health-update/106240912</link><description>Australian cricket great Damien Martyn has paid tribute to the support he has received during his remarkable recovery from meningitis, while revealing he was given a "50:50 chance" of surviving the illness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eca2cb00c8f48fd37b04e0f5eb7d1a03</guid></item><item><title>Thousands protest in Denmark, chanting 'Greenland is not for sale' in response to Trump's threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/denmark-protests-greenland-not-for-sale-response-trump-threats/106241056</link><description>Chanting "Greenland is not for sale" and carrying banners saying "Hands off Greenland", thousands of people have marched in Denmark, responding to US President Donald Trump's ambitions to acquire the Artic island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fb36f57e47d7a23fba89b80e8d5dc68</guid></item><item><title>Iran Supreme Leader Ali Khamenei blames Donald Trump for inciting deadly protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/irans-leader-blames-trump-for-inciting-deadly-protests/106241068</link><description>Iran's Supreme Leader, Ali Khamenei, has labelled Donald Trump a criminal, blaming him for the deaths of thousands of demonstrators and security forces.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4609b61d85c74da59ee23b5437955fd9</guid></item><item><title>How charging board or rent to adult children can help them and you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/what-is-fair-when-charging-young-adult-children-board-or-rent/105913086</link><description>Experts on the benefit of charging board and expenses if you’re sharing a home with young adults, and how to calculate it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f013049216634a8617431620cd4371e3</guid></item><item><title>Russian President Vladimir Putin wants to 'make a different world' and Iran is vital to his plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/putin-wants-to-reshape-world-and-iran-is-vital-to-his-plan/106235534</link><description>Tehran is the epicentre of the nightly protests shaking Iran's regime, but the reverberations are being felt loud and clear in Moscow, too.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd497b3f576d298b64f3e57ea045a281</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party election autopsy delayed after Peter Dutton suggests report defames him and his staff</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/peter-dutton-election-loss-liberal-party-report-delayed/106240876</link><description>The report, co-authored by Liberal grandees Pru Goward and Nick Minchin, has now been sent to a legal team to ensure it is watertight while the party decides what step to take next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b60e19eca9f7586a8f4206ba63ebeffd</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump announces tariffs for eight countries as Greenland stand-off continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/trump-tariffs-eight-nations-greenland-standoff/106241574</link><description>Donald Trump announces the escalating tariffs for Denmark, Norway, Sweden, France, Germany, the United Kingdom, the Netherlands and Finland as a row over Greenland continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">894977a440f65d320d5a7ab9e37e119b</guid></item><item><title>BHP gaining ground as CBA loses its shine in market power struggle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/bhp-popular-with-investors-as-cba-loses-market-favour/106238676</link><description>The year is barely underway but already there's a power struggle between our biggest corporations as they fight it out for line honours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeb0f98b47bad2c6a579105a2a0e9c3f</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Refreshed after a break and ready to flex your trivia muscle?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106220390</link><description>Wow, you really don't quit. Let's see how poorly you perform this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">497407b3cf3c86b4d01057c744d6d31d</guid></item><item><title>Australian woman documents her stint in Chinese weight loss 'prison'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/weight-loss-prisons-obesity-rising-in-china/106236242</link><description>Camps offering intensive weight loss programs are on the rise in China as the country faces skyrocketing obesity rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">874810325ae70eec5fc8bd9f0d4253f1</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr scores twice for Chelsea in Women's FA Cup, declares her best form is not far away</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/sam-kerr-comeback-continues-with-fa-cup-double-chelsea/106241588</link><description>Sam Kerr declares she is approaching her best form after scoring twice for Chelsea in a Women's FA Cup victory over Crystal Palace.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e507bcbe5096fda3243668d35e4a988</guid></item><item><title>Supreme Court case continues despite more than 200 interpreter errors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/victorian-supreme-court-case-200-language-interpretation-errors/106173346</link><description>A Victorian Supreme Court trial is forging ahead with amended transcripts after an interpreter made more than 200 translation errors during a key witness' evidence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036ee554afd22b63f6f81f5c81333097</guid></item><item><title>Grandmother's support group becomes a lifeline for Lithgow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/grandmother-led-support-group-becomes-a-lifeline-for-lithgow/106098374</link><description>It started as a Facebook page and now it is a vital charity. Here is how this group run by grandmothers is fighting loneliness in the NSW Blue Mountains.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eb9d750a3d061eaece11cc2cee617bd</guid></item><item><title>Mount Lofty Ranges koala population boom risks starvation, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/researchers-find-mount-lofty-ranges-koala-boom-risk-starvation/106156850</link><description>South Australia's Mount Lofty Ranges is experiencing a koala population boom that would likely lead to starvation and deaths, researchers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d754e13667dfb466a6f2c599b46e8f</guid></item><item><title>Forgotten tracks from the 2005 Hottest 100 you need to hear again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/forgotten-songs-from-2005-hottest-100-bloodhound-gang/106146344</link><description>We've dug out some standout tracks from the Hottest 100 of 2005 that you need to hear again. Relive the mid-2000s music that defined an era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc09e85614dc423c888ef09906b13089</guid></item><item><title>Bourke artist Jenny Greentree's career sprouted during millennium drought</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/drought-sparked-back-o-bourke-art-gallery-jenny-greentree/106175110</link><description>Jenny and Steve Greentree's young family faced losing everything in the millennium drought. Twenty years on, their thriving art gallery has helped to put Bourke on the map.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d286846e2dad00a047b8c1f2b22adfb</guid></item><item><title>Why Abbey Barrett's mum wants more federal government funding for brain cancer research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/brain-cancer-abbey-barrett-family-campaigning-for-funding/106231668</link><description>Abbey was "joy on two legs" and now she is gone, another lost to brain cancer. Somehow her family must carry on, as the fight continues for more funding to bring this horror disease to an end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ec9d9719847601eb996db80054f8f03</guid></item><item><title>The central Queensland town of Agnes Water and its surfing culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/agnes-water-surfing-culture/106078546</link><description>Former professional surfers and board makers have chosen this small coastal paradise as their home, but with smaller waves, what makes it so special?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b8aba4dba07fb14409df5310038cfba</guid></item><item><title>Flash flooding, heavy rainfall and gusty weather keeps SES busy on NSW coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/flooding-heavy-rainfall-severe-weather-nsw-coast/106241644</link><description>The State Emergency Service responds to more than 2,300 incidents and 25 flood rescues, most of which involve people driving through floodwaters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">682c9a58e4ded3172424c5883c33001a</guid></item><item><title>Torres Strait Islanders commemorate the legacy of 1936 pearl industry maritime strike</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/torres-strait-islanders-commemorate-1936-maritime-strike/106185202</link><description>Fed up with restrictions over what they earned and where they could go, pearl boat workers embarked on nine months of industrial action that would change the face of their communities forever. Ninety years on, their legacy is still felt across the Torres Strait.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bbdd6f0c5d68b167bcdb5801855febc</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026 live: Venus Williams knocked out by Olga Danilovic, Zeynep Sönmez helps ball kid after fall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/australian-open-2026-live-updates-sabalenka-alcaraz-berrettini/106238282</link><description>It was a busy day at Melbourne Park but it was the night session that saw both the men's and women's world number ones progressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4c6da1c1e570acfa84f69ab5872ca93</guid></item><item><title>Australian artist's impulsive act sparks 'magic' post box restoration crusade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/vic-letterbox-man-s-colourful-hobby/106169390</link><description>Victorian man Mick Slocum is on a quest to restore every 1800s post box in Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cecd82ea27e866919a32771a82ad039</guid></item><item><title>A deadly fire tears through a shopping centre in Pakistan.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/deadly-fire-tears-through-shopping-centre-in-pakistan/106241824</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3b4ff45bf5fce916ae300b604589a84</guid></item><item><title>Deadly Pakistan shopping plaza fire fuelled by clothes and homewares</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/pakistan-gul-shopping-centre-fire/106241742</link><description>Authorities fear the death toll from a fire in Karachi could grow, with the cause of the fire not immediately known.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3fa8b24524fedf1a2dfdcc47cf2840a</guid></item><item><title>Israel objects to US announcement of leaders who will help oversee next steps in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/israel-objects-to-us-announcement-of-leaders-who-will-help-overs/106241834</link><description>The committee announced by the White House includes no Israeli officials but has an Israeli businessperson, billionaire Yakir Gabay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4a79a8c03f5465bfe8d897d31920889</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's animal populations suffer as state is ravaged by bushfires, extreme heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/victoria-wildlife-animals-suffering-bushfires-heatwave/106219826</link><description>From animal shelters to "entire generations" of bat colonies, heartbreaking stories of the significant loss of animal life are beginning to emerge in the wake of Victoria's disastrous bushfires and severe heat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">246fa1e142bbfb8793f30a1c3d549ee0</guid></item><item><title>Status of hate laws remains uncertain as politicians converge on Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/status-of-hate-laws-uncertain-ahead-of-parliamentary-sitting/106242028</link><description>A special sitting to respond to the Bondi terror attack will begin in Canberra on Monday, but the government is no closer to landing changes to hate laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">255e439147fc4cb47e4707425c861a98</guid></item><item><title>Fire sends huge plumes above Adelaide but firefighters stop spread to batteries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/large-fire-at-croydon-park-in-suburban-adelaide/106242026</link><description>About 90 firefighters have been battling a large blaze at Croydon Park that sent a large plume of smoke above the suburbs and came close to batteries for home solar systems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d748ad797aadf51ab5e444b27216bff9</guid></item><item><title>Walpole community rallies to raise money for volunteer rubbish collector Michael Filby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/community-rallies-michael-filby-manjimup-rubbish-collector/106234004</link><description>Michael Filby has been cleaning up a remote stretch of highway on WA's south coast off his own bat for 20 years. Now community members want to raise money to help him in his self-funded mission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91ea6d47d9434e2ef290e9ff1ee41c2b</guid></item><item><title>Smoke billows from a fire at Croydon Park, Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/smoke-billows-from-a-fire-at-croydon-park-adelaide-/106242126</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4ae63b2821978b2831f45c2ff10a04a</guid></item><item><title>NBA great Allen Iverson meets hundreds of fans in Australia, including NBL star Bryce Cotton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/nba-great-allen-iverson-meets-hundreds-of-australian-fans/106241020</link><description>NBA great Allen Iverson left hundreds of fans star struck at a meet-and-greet event in Perth, none more so than one of the best NBL players of all time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b373847c5a5d4039376decd597e93c92</guid></item><item><title>Pasa Faho to screen at Sydney Opera House after creating a bit of buzz</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/pasa-faho-to-screen-at-sydney-opera-house/106219252</link><description>Pasa Faho is the story of a shoe salesman who struggles to save his small business and pass on his values to his son.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72a5355a25ce77e7fc6326115bb7b45b</guid></item><item><title>World's first legally binding treaty to protect oceans and marine life takes effect</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/high-seas-treaty-marine-protection-in-effect/106241974</link><description>The High Seas Treaty will govern about two-thirds of the planet's oceans including vast areas beyond any country's borders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">689da612d25cd88f659134fa3cc9f955</guid></item><item><title>RBA cash rate 2026: cuts or hikes coming?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/rba-cash-rate-2026-cuts-or-hikes-coming-/106242308</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff3b744611586db97731db23e9b1b989</guid></item><item><title>Talia Gibson moves through to Australian Open second round</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/australian-open-talia-gibson-wins-first-round-melbourne-park/106242036</link><description>Talia Gibson prides herself on her aggressive on-court approach, which was on full display in her convincing first-round victory at Melbourne Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43668a5df364b7db43c9c951d67baef6</guid></item><item><title>Darwin gathers for Geektacular cosplay event celebrating geek culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/geektacular-nt-darwin-is-geek-culture-cool-nerd-community/106241848</link><description>Has a surge in the popularity of hit shows like Stranger Things led to an uptick in geekiness, changing how we feel about nerd culture? The ABC attended Darwin's Geektacular event to find out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95b123f4e86653bc014839e025f23438</guid></item><item><title>Why Alex de Minaur will lean into his 'selfish' side for the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/alex-de-minaur-australian-open-draw-first-round/106242496</link><description>As the nation's great hope for the Australian Open, Alex de Minaur is ready to unleash his selfish side in an effort to secure his first grand slam title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b153f752f5b400fa206021a2a3f8dbf</guid></item><item><title>Boy, 12, in critical condition after being bitten by a large shark at Sydney Harbour beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/shark-attack-boy-suffers-critical-injuries-vaucluse-east-sydney/106242502</link><description>Emergency services were called to Hermitage Foreshore Walk near Shark Beach at Vaucluse about 4:20pm on Sunday afternoon following reports of a boy being bitten by a shark.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d4a045dd3eae0df5ada21ab4b2d9396</guid></item><item><title>Writers' Week letter shows premier backed removal of Randa Abdel-Fattah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/premier-letter-on-randa-abdel-fatah-at-writers-week-released/106241792</link><description>South Australia's premier told the Adelaide Festival board it would open itself to "accusations of hypocrisy" and "legitimate public ridicule" if it did not cancel the appearance of Randa Abdel-Fattah from Writers' Week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83b2891c320c941cac6481cb385e83d8</guid></item><item><title>Crews respond to Rose Bay shark attack.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/crews-respond-to-rose-bay-shark-attack/106242592</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">822ae7c10cb62a4c9ed5b345d9ebd531</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of WA fishers congregate to protest against ban on demersal fishing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/wa-fishing-ban-protest-dozens-gather-ozone-park/104760976</link><description>Around 200 disgruntled fishers have journeyed through the streets of Perth to protest against the state government's decision to ban demersal fishing, as the WA Premier Roger Cook confirmed he planned to meet with the industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0833f292c27266d407a9d8a7702f3963</guid></item><item><title>Body found among wreckage of Indonesian plane that lost contact mid-flight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/body-found-among-wreckage-of-plane-in-indonesia/106242700</link><description>A body has been found among the wreckage of an Indonesian plane that lost contact mid-flight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db885b01bccd5ca18317d0cde9a36a3e</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka advances to Australian Open second round at Melbourne Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/australian-open-aryna-sabalenka-first-round-melbourne-park/106242750</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka again proves she is compulsive viewing, as she moves through to the second round with a straight-sets win at the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67e6df23b1e21ab03fae823a5e8f1746</guid></item><item><title>Venus Williams lost in the first round. But she still gave fans an emotional evening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-18/venus-williams-first-round-loss-in-emotional-return/106242736</link><description>Undisputed great of the sport Venus Williams was welcomed back to Melbourne Park with multiple standing ovations but bowed out in the first round to Serbian Olga Danilovic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2896ce50a37c4ece236ddfb91dd87fd3</guid></item><item><title>NATO allies warn Trump of 'dangerous downward spiral' over Greenland threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/greenland-trump-tariff-nato-downward-spiral/106242888</link><description>The US president says European countries will be hit with tariffs until a deal is struck that would see the Danish territory become an American possession.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab488abfbc008a8298394338d995ad0b</guid></item><item><title>Trump asks Australia, Albanese to join Gaza 'Board of Peace'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australia-asked-to-join-trump-s-gaza-board-of-peace-/106242966</link><description>The US president is pushing for the board to preserve a fragile ceasefire between Hamas and Israel and progress the peace deal to the next phase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed5574cc0854e1096521ee6bea0d0b2</guid></item><item><title>Unregulated fishing keeps Seahorse World locked out of traditional Chinese medicine market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/unregulated-seahorse-trade-hampers-beauty-point-seahorse-world/106225110</link><description>A seahorse farm in Tasmania thought it was onto a sure thing; exporting dried seahorses to the Chinese market — it turned out not to be as easy as hoped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8e27a55b03ef0979521c99d06b70a2</guid></item><item><title>This week in history quiz: Can you conquer these questions?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/this-week-in-history-quiz/106239130</link><description>Trips to the moon and Mars, same-sex marriage and the first canned beer appear in this week's line-up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec0a7d90400afaadd6b8919faaeda89c</guid></item><item><title>What psychologists have to say about the seven types of rest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/what-are-the-seven-types-of-rest/106076824</link><description>Have you ever found yourself still exhausted and deflated after an eight-hour sleep? Perhaps sleep isn't the reset you need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">072209ca692c4f26d317f79697d0defa</guid></item><item><title>AI platforms like Grok are an ethical, social and economic nightmare — and we're starting to wake up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/ai-grok-ethical-social-and-economic-nightmare/106242320</link><description>As 2025 began, I thought humanity's biggest problem was climate change. In 2026, AI is more pressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0956e00f7c9111bf96801d7da3854c5</guid></item><item><title>Sam Short's small leap to ocean swimming and the prospect of more Australian success in 2032</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/sam-short-to-swim-open-water-nationals/106232346</link><description>Sam Short will take on the country's best open water swimmers at the Australian Nationals this week, with a possible new event for Brisbane 2032 opening new opportunities for Australian gold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05aff475351925220d9e9ae9bf434b24</guid></item><item><title>Life in Cuba is about to get harder as Trump threatens oil supply</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/cuba-us-venezuela-trump-economic-crisis-migration/106231474</link><description>Many experts are predicting life in Cuba is about to get even harder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0dfb58404a600734acf757e9145b0c1f</guid></item><item><title>How Melbourne became a headline-making city as home prices elsewhere soared</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/melbourne-house-prices-affordable-capital-city/106210992</link><description>Property analysts say a mix of economic conditions, policy settings and demographic shifts are among the reasons for the city's subdued dwelling price growth in the past five years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e715d7f7acf87a8cc7ba75d83480f9e</guid></item><item><title>Parents of Bondi victim Matilda pay tribute to mystery woman who saved their younger daughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/parents-bondi-terror-attack-youngest-victim-matilda-speak-out/106240460</link><description>The parents of 10-year-old Matilda, the youngest victim of the Bondi terror attack, recall the final moments leading up to the shooting, paying tribute to the woman who saved their younger daughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e98dff90e3209ea166e732cfe9883173</guid></item><item><title>What Trump has planned for 'the biggest birthday party ever' as the US turns 250</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/donald-trump-united-states-of-america-250-celebrations/106125384</link><description>The United States of America is celebrating the 250th anniversary of its union as a nation and experts say Donald Trump appears to be exploiting the events for his own political gain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fce187e0e98bb1547e662a40228f93e6</guid></item><item><title>Tribunal bans senior nurse for trying to take patient's medication, altering hospital records</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/modbury-nurse-banned-stealing-patients-adhd-medication/106229238</link><description>A senior public hospital nurse has been prohibited from working for four years for attempting to steal medication from a patient and manipulating a co-worker's Facebook account in an attempt to cover it up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a458cc28e2befbbf188f607c29e61cab</guid></item><item><title>Frustrated fans, Zverev confused and a ball kid collapses — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106242092</link><description>Fans were left queuing for hours after play started, Alexander Zverev got confused by a gate and Maria Sakkari smashed an insane shot. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8de558ff26a80cd67bd1bee03b1b19e0</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith amuses and delights, Sam Curran fires as the Sydney Sixers lock in BBL finals berth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/steve-smith-sam-curran-fire-sixers-to-bbl-finals/106242754</link><description>Steve Smith oscillates between the ridiculous and the sublime as the Sydney Sixers get the better of the Brisbane Heat in a do-or-die clash at the Gabba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1ef7e0ae732c5419057160e3a03d756</guid></item><item><title>Everything you need to know about the new $800m Sydney Fish Market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/what-to-know-about-new-sydney-fish-market/106225622</link><description>It is perhaps the most expensive seafood centre of its kind, but just what can visitors expect from the new $800 million Sydney Fish Market?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b18acb9b9843b0eca9995b5b8406ff05</guid></item><item><title>Pentagon could deploy troops to Minnesota protests, US officials say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/pentagon-readies-troops-for-minnesota-deployment/106243210</link><description>The possible deployment comes after US President Donald Trump threatened to invoke the Insurrection Act to quell anti-ICE protests in the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46877bf2ca79218893e5704e52d71d17</guid></item><item><title>Calls for an industry-standard heat policy to be implemented on worksites as summers get hotter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/calls-for-industry-standard-heat-policy-on-worksites/106234134</link><description>It has been 13 years since Jenny Newport's son died from extreme heat while on a worksite in Queensland. She believes not much has changed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60f002407b15690de7b318b7c9777c52</guid></item><item><title>ASX-listed coal mine company buries report into whistleblower allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/dartbrook-coal-mine-company-buries-whistleblower-report/106136748</link><description>An investigation into whistleblower allegations finds senior managers at a NSW coal mine were involved in a decision by the mine to award their own companies multi-million-dollar contracts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f2dc9717140a6b56475205eb5c32e49</guid></item><item><title>The highly detailed, invisible work that goes into 'near real-time' bushfire mapping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/near-real-time-fire-mapping-victoria-vicemergency/106229148</link><description>As the devastating fires in Victoria spread earlier this month, people at home could see how they were moving across the state — not just in videos on the news and social media, but on an interactive map.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">469e416c8b8bc080ac586637f311738e</guid></item><item><title>ASX closes lower as Trump trade jitters renewed, China annual economic growth hits target — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/106242752</link><description>ASX closed lower as Trump trade jitters renewed. China's GDP came in line with expectations but other data is mixed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0794a627b2f9aec538d9e0388539831b</guid></item><item><title>Meals you can get kids on board with</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/fun-and-easy-recipes-kids-can-help-with/106116250</link><description>We’ve put together four recipes that are fun and easy enough for kids to help with.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60feacb4ce01787344636e59ad880e34</guid></item><item><title>Three performers talk about bringing their clown shows to Perth Fringe World</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/perth-fringe-world-festival-clowning-comedy/106134970</link><description>Three performers at Perth Fringe World talk about why the magic of clowning is getting adults to let down their walls and embrace their inner child.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c3258a63e2472d4f0d5955909eb9d5f</guid></item><item><title>Adam Lambert breaks through for maiden snowboard cross World Cup win on eve of Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/adam-lambert-snowboard-cross-world-cup-win-china/106243394</link><description>Adam Lambert completes another tremendous weekend for Australia's Winter Olympic hopes by racing to his first snowboard cross World Cup win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14a9235f7973432fc2221d907b9c61ee</guid></item><item><title>Shark attack at Sydney Harbour beach leaves boy in intensive care with critical injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/nsw-sydney-harbour-shark-attack-boy-update-beach/106243340</link><description>Police say the boy was pulled aboard a vessel by water police officers "within minutes" of the Triple Zero call being made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">601ce151705bbedc4941c852971a37ec</guid></item><item><title>Charles Darwin University researchers investigate whether old tyres can strengthen roads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/nt-cdu-recycled-rubber-tyres-stronger-roads-heat-waste/106204858</link><description>Roads buckle under the pressure of the Northern Territory's harsh climate, but a group of researchers think repurposing discarded materials may be the solution — not only helping the environment, but government budgets too.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">313dc4fe7c3b7f9dddeda018717ab128</guid></item><item><title>Boundary Road level crossing upgrade stalls indefinitely as Transport and Main Road reneges on construction date</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/no-end-in-sight-for-derelict-government-eyesore-boundary-road/106219474</link><description>The Queensland government evicted shopkeepers in Coopers Plains to make way for construction that was due to begin in mid-2025 but is yet to happen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">041d5fd00bd0acc3ff2a5a4d906c5328</guid></item><item><title>Tooperang bushfire started by vehicle, CFS believes, as multiple structures lost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/tooperang-fire-rips-through-grass-and-scrub-near-mount-compass/106243392</link><description>A bushfire that has ripped through more than 600 hectares, destroying at least two family homes, is believed to have been started by an "accidental ignition" from a vehicle, the Country Fire Service says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffa572abe13984fd61b50488e392ecf9</guid></item><item><title>Conservationists alarmed by plan to remove rare bird habitat in Sydney's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/conservationists-alarmed-riverstone-wetland-replacement/106227536</link><description>A set of ponds built for a since-shuttered abattoir in Sydney's north-west has become a habitat for rare migratory birds from Alaska and Antarctica.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e97bf8d3994084dbcbcf0225e73b07c4</guid></item><item><title>Cross-cultural sharing is at the heart of Townsville's community garden</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/multiculturalism-thrives-in-townsville-community-garden/106171508</link><description>In the heart of north Queensland, Ukrainians, Fijians, Zimbabweans and Koreans gather in the dirt to help each other grow vegetables.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">747778fb8e47c03a41a45f71a8a4227f</guid></item><item><title>At least 39 dead after two high-speed trains derailed in Spain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/many-dead-after-high-speed-trains-derailed-in-spain/106243428</link><description>At least 39 people have died and dozens are severely injured after two high-speed trains derailed in southern Spain, local authorities say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4bfd8134627a082bb0f0a5bccab5340</guid></item><item><title>Violent crime spreading to regional towns as WA waits for strengthened tobacco laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/illegal-tobacco-vapes-violent-crime-in-regional-towns/106207292</link><description>Community leaders have called on the West Australian government to take concrete action as violence and crime associated with the illegal tobacco trade spreads to the state's Wheatbelt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7e3842f3ba51094b5b8f8d6f013ec4c</guid></item><item><title>Milan-Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics a fitting destination for Australian ice dancers Holly Harris and Jason Chan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/2026-winter-olympics-ice-dancing-holly-harris-jason-chan/105896346</link><description>Holly Harris and Jason Chan have had to go a long way to skate at a Winter Olympic Games. Soon, their sacrifices — and those of Piper the dog — will have paid off.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f4f94f342a3db15b7ea2bc811d5b13e</guid></item><item><title>Witness vision captures aftermath of high-speed train collision in Spain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/witness-vision-captures-aftermath-of-train-crash-in-spain/106243760</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2751039d2dcc5c40d218ceb4556658fc</guid></item><item><title>Explosives discovery in Kalgoorlie reno sparks memories of time when gelignite was sold in shops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/old-explosives-found-in-kalgoorlie-bring-back-gelignite-memories/106240594</link><description>A recent gelignite discovery during a Kalgoorlie renovation has brought back memories of a time when explosives were "freely available" in the mining city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64d37227f41c3e3ac11f2ee1b1eb2dce</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026 live: Djokovic 'excited' to be a centurion as he wins 100th match at Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-2026-live-alex-de-minaur-novak-djokovic/106243798</link><description>The 10-time champion joined Roger Federer at that milestone after he defeated Pedro Martinez in straight sets on day two.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b57b9ccbcf4cbb0da12d29ad9bb65e74</guid></item><item><title>Senegal storms off field in penalty protest, before returning to beat Morocco in mad AFCON final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/senegal-protests-then-wins-afcon-final-morocco/106243788</link><description>Senegal's players storm off the pitch in furious protest of a refereeing decision late in the Africa Cup of Nations final, but then return to score an extra-time winner against Morocco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">610d9d94eb36d431cac87390846e0a05</guid></item><item><title>Oxfam wants tougher tax on billionaires as wealth grows 'by half a million dollars a day'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/income-inequality-oxfam-report-calls-to-tax-billionaires/106236612</link><description>Oxfam Australia is calling on the federal government to tax the super-rich to help tackle growing inequality, as billionaires grow their wealth by more than half a million a day on average.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4724ee211a3150b0e7fdb71b1aa50dff</guid></item><item><title>Adam Walton reveals what it's like to play Carlos Alcaraz at Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-adam-walton-carlos-alcaraz-first-round/106244122</link><description>As first-round opponents go, they do not come any tougher than Carlos Alcaraz, as Australia's Adam Walton found out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4124a2c909f8f8034f2ae8a1edd2c277</guid></item><item><title>Bondi victim Matilda's parents doubt hate laws will prevent future violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/matilda-parents-bondi-beach-hate-speech-laws/106241800</link><description>In their first wide-ranging interview, the parents of 10-year-old Matilda, the youngest victim of the Bondi attack, say the federal government's hate laws offer little reassurance that another terror attack will be prevented.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">405f80b4737eaa53d8bbde13d0a4d3d0</guid></item><item><title>Randa Abdel-Fattah's lawyer serves second concerns notice to SA premier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/randa-abdel-fattahs-lawyer-serves-second-concerns-notice/106244418</link><description>Palestinian Australian author Randa Abdel-Fattah says her lawyer has served a second concerns notice for defamation on South Australian Premier Peter Malinauskas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5070a5a415b4ba1efc660416513153cb</guid></item><item><title>Homes lost as Tooperang fire rips through scrub south of Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/homes-lost-as-tooperang-fire-rips-through-scrub/106244226</link><description>Devastated residents of a bushfire ground south of Adelaide are starting to count the cost of the damage, with at least two reporting their homes have been lost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">217b426f97e2049e2d28418425bce959</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court charged with planting pipe bombs along Canberra footpaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/man-who-allegedly-made-pipe-bombs-fronts-court/106243948</link><description>Damien Paul O'Brien was arrested in Gungahlin on Saturday night after officers attached to ACT Policing allegedly found items used to assemble pipe bombs during a search of his Belconnen home earlier in the day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">996e13ccf288fcc044fbb0ff0a38074c</guid></item><item><title>'Extremely large' brief of evidence in murder case against Tanika Bromley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/large-brief-of-evidence-in-pheobe-bishop-murder-tanika-bromley/106244508</link><description>Hundreds of statements gathered in murder case against Tanika Bromley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bf0f652b576628b5c3808bcf7764382</guid></item><item><title>Labor identity Tim Picton dies three weeks after alleged Northbridge assault, family confirms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/tim-picton-dies-three-weeks-after-nightclub-assault/106244678</link><description>Former Labor strategist Tim Picton dies in hospital, weeks after he was allegedly assaulted outside a Perth nightclub.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d9df645f784d9937ec88dc8a71dd414</guid></item><item><title>Aerial vision shows extent of destruction from Chile wildfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/aerial-vision-shows-extent-of-destruction-from-chile-wildfires-/106244352</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d08bef0b4bf3af07ee7964b45038b9a2</guid></item><item><title>Deadly Chile wildfires trigger state of catastrophe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/deadly-chile-wildfires-trigger-state-of-catastrophe/106244428</link><description>Wildfires raging across central and southern Chile have left at least 18 people dead, scorched thousands of hectares of forest and destroyed hundreds of homes, local authorities say, as the South American country swelters under a heat wave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">519c96d7060e5a77953b867e9d438bb0</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open fans wait hours to enter Melbourne Park as Craig Tiley admits surprise over record crowds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/tennis-craig-tiley-surprised-australian-open-crowds-wait-times/106244434</link><description>Thousands of fans are forced to wait in queues for hours, even as Australian Open boss Craig Tiley promised extra resources to aid entry into Melbourne Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e1e9771e052990b4a23a911f74f1c67</guid></item><item><title>Perth's median house price surges through $1m million mark, new data finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/perth-s-median-house-price-surges-through-1m-mark/106244510</link><description>Domain's latest quarterly house price report has found the cost to buy a home increased by 9.9 per cent in the last quarter of 2025, to a median of $1,087,762.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b643bd9313af2e8b2963681c2ca6a582</guid></item><item><title>House flooded with raw sewage still uninhabitable six months on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/raw-sewage-repairs-six-months-after-spill/106244944</link><description>Six months on from a major sewage spill in Perth's south, one resident whose house was substantially damaged still has not been able to get the repairs he needs to move back in, blaming both the Water Corp and his insurance company for the delay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15da64016c0383c97df8ceb06c38d311</guid></item><item><title>Tensions over Greenland escalate as US threatens tariffs after European troop deployment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/us-tariff-threats-european-troops-sent-to-greenland/106243860</link><description>Tensions between the United States and Greenland's allies reach a new high, with threats of increasing tariffs after European troops were sent to the island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c499ff63787990359920d7371cdd7809</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith focuses on reclaiming Australian T20 spot for Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/steve-smith-t20-world-cup-olympics/106244980</link><description>Steve Smith has lit up the Big Bash since returning to the Sydney Sixers, but concedes the ship has sailed for him to play in next month's T20 World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">840498619d37e7667d0ac59def0a7633</guid></item><item><title>Young Sydney surfer uninjured after shark bites board at Dee Why Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/nsw-young-surfer-second-sydney-beach-shark-encounter/106245088</link><description>Surf Life Saving NSW confirms a boy is unharmed after an encounter with a shark at Dee Why Beach just before lunchtime on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d27f26f3f0945b4bf3612f160d05785d</guid></item><item><title>Roger Allers, co-director of The Lion King, dies aged 76</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/co-director-of-lion-king-roger-allers-dies/106244066</link><description>Roger Allers was known for working on various Disney films including The Lion King, The Little Mermaid and Aladdin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a0ef8a277b8d386b9b932a2c9c5d992</guid></item><item><title>Elphinstone Engineering director sentenced for interfering with Aboriginal relics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/graeme-elphinstone-allegations-interfere-with-aboriginal-sites/106243968</link><description>Graeme Elphinstone, the founder and director of Elphinstone Engineering, avoids conviction and is fined $12,000 for interfering with Aboriginal relics on his land on Tasmania's east coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ad5307c820eb3687e361788dd9c66bf</guid></item><item><title>Shooters 'anxious' as ACT government looks to reform 'outdated' gun laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/shooters-concerned-act-government-gun-law-reform/106243768</link><description>Professional and recreational shooters say they want to see extensive community consultation before any changes are made to the ACT's gun laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb86d0593e40fa8c039e0a3f4386a3cf</guid></item><item><title>Storm Hunter wins at Australian Open after thinking her career was over</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-storm-hunter-reaches-second-round/106244620</link><description>A ruptured Achilles tendon threatened to send Storm Hunter into retirement, but her perseverance pays off with a first-round victory in Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fa04a6d2e7099ffe2cd1b1e136b11dc</guid></item><item><title>Switzerland's Noemi Reugg powers home to defend Tour Down Under title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/tour-down-under-noemi-ruegg-final-result/106245676</link><description>After being dropped on the first two ascents of a pivotal section of the final stage, Switzerland's Noemi Reugg fights back brilliantly to claim back-to-back Tour Down Under victories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09f302101eab6ed8f9b48dfd7bb2b595</guid></item><item><title>Petition asks Alice Springs Public Library to extend opening hours amid outback heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/nt-petition-alice-springs-public-library-weekend-opening-hours/106244058</link><description>In one of Australia's hottest towns, the library is an important air-conditioned public space offering a no-cost respite from burning summer temperatures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48234b555f036ba2f92ff1804e8371f6</guid></item><item><title>Bondi survivor Ya'akov Tetleroyd lost his father and nearly his arm in Bondi Beach terrorism event. He forgives the gunmen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/bondi-terror-survivor-yaakov-tetleroyd-speaks-naveed-akram/106238196</link><description>Ya'akov Tetleroyd's father died in the Bondi Beach shootings. He nearly lost his arm as a result of being shot, yet he told 7.30 in an exclusive interview that he forgives the gunmen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036a2c4738ac88afd5123eda6fe48589</guid></item><item><title>WA is losing the tobacco wars as gangs target vape stores and cheap cigarettes flood market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/wa-losing-the-fight-to-control-illegal-cigarettes/106242556</link><description>Burnt out storefronts in Perth and regional cities are testament to the government's inability to control the illegal tobacco trade — and it's not clear when things will change, writes Keane Bourke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">280b53748e89776c07bee7fd574bc253</guid></item><item><title>Flooding in Kalumburu, in the Kimberley region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/flooding-in-kalumburu-in-the-kimberley-region/106244868</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecd2065eee0e20c7912c37c6bb104e1f</guid></item><item><title>Kalumburu on flood watch after heavy rain as tropical low has high chance of developing into cyclone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/wa-kimberley-kalumburu-on-flood-watch/106244930</link><description>People living in Kalumburu, one of the most remote communities in Western Australia's far north, are being warned of rising river levels and floods, after heavy rain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6621008c253fa957e1d6b3469b7b33b</guid></item><item><title>What has caused a 'smack' of jellyfish to wash up on Melbourne's eastern beaches?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/lions-mane-jellyfish-melbourne-port-phillip-bay/106244362</link><description>Visitors to Melbourne's eastern beaches over the weekend were surprised to see an influx of crimson jellyfish bobbing in the water. One expert says a "perfect storm" of factors has brought them to the coastline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e313ec9d19ef5439121c1957e9127cd9</guid></item><item><title>Weekend deluge causes flooding in far-north WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/weekend-deluge-causes-flooding-in-far-north-wa/106246064</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f57d668cd54ac57ee76274d8260c3d64</guid></item><item><title>Nicolas Cage shrine amid weird pranks at Mount Gambier deputy mayor's home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/mount-gambier-deputy-mayor-celebrity-letterbox-mystery/106245108</link><description>A Nicolas Cage-themed shrine is the latest of a series of celebrity-themed pranks that Mount Gambier's deputy mayor says have befallen his home in recent weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">613d4d6f79a342e68fef76235e90f105</guid></item><item><title>Monday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106245916</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bfd8c1fab3cd958260d324a03f7b0f3</guid></item><item><title>Investigation into fatal light plane crash near Sale finds 'irregularities' at flight training school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/atsb-triple-fatal-tinamba-gippsland-light-plane-crash-report/106245644</link><description>An investigation finds risky flying behaviour, an amateur-built aeroplane's "design deficiencies" and issues at the pilot's flight school may have contributed to a fatal light aeroplane crash in Victoria in 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62650d192b1549e1df38232a5626191d</guid></item><item><title>Teenage boy dies of injuries at bottom of cliff near Jerrabomberra Waterhole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/act-teenager-dies-at-jerrabomberra-waterhole-bottom-of-cliff/106246244</link><description>A member of the public tried to perform CPR on a teenage boy suffering serious injuries at the bottom of a cliff near Canberra, but he died at the scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e11e9a0e318dcb3d76efc7eef5c7678</guid></item><item><title>Man critical after being bitten by a shark at North Steyne Beach in third incident in two days</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/shark-attack-north-steyne-beach-nsw/106246378</link><description>A man in his 20s is in a critical condition after he sustained leg injuries in another shark attack at a Sydney beach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01ac466828db525eeb0257f91ad7b0b0</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court after 2kg of meth seized in Katherine roadside drug bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/katherine-drug-bust-meth-allegedly-bound-for-darwin/106245962</link><description>A 22-year-old man has faced court after police allegedly found 2 kilograms of methamphetamine, along with large quantities of other drugs, during a traffic stop in Katherine last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98effadd199406586f274ffc8312e87e</guid></item><item><title>Iranian official says verified deaths in Iran protests reach at least 5,000</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/iranian-official-says-verified-deaths-in-iran-protests-5000/106246384</link><description>The death toll includes about 500 security personnel and exceeds that of any other round of protest or unrest in Iran in decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1881129ec8352a4f180454980115f1f</guid></item><item><title>Helicopter at North Steyne Beach after shark attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/helicopter-at-north-steyne-beach-after-shark-attack/106246484</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">593dba8cca07aa1b05943aea09a7b2b3</guid></item><item><title>What is it like to live and work in the Antarctic?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/living-and-working-in-the-antarctic/106246052</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d13273f34a29dd8e349e41e8e456cd05</guid></item><item><title>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi to dissolve parliament and call snap election for February 8</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/japan-prime-minister-calls-snap-general-election/106246400</link><description>Japanese Prime Minister ⁠Sanae Takaichi will ​dissolve parliament ‌on ‌Friday ‌and call a snap ​election for February 8 ⁠to seek voter backing ‌for her ​spending ​plans and ‍other ⁠policies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6762019ff9f76327ee529684d85c451</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government will refuse to support federal gun buyback legislation, ABC understands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/qld-government-refuses-support-federal-gun-buyback/106246450</link><description>The ABC understands Queensland will join the Northern Territory and Tasmania in rejecting a national gun buyback scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f2a2eb7b251032b41adc9a10da8cd4</guid></item><item><title>Victim Tanya urges alleged Mullewa shooter Kenneth Giles to come home safe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/mullewa-shooting-victim-makes-public-statement/106246464</link><description>In her first statement since she was shot through the hand on January 7, Tanya says she wants Kenneth Giles to know she wants him to return home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d217f22671f03c4ca8f601a436780f7b</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump links Greenland takeover threat to Nobel Peace Prize snub, amid tariffs row with Europe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/trump-norway-prime-minister-no-longer-obligation-peace/106246538</link><description>President Donald Trump sends a text message to the Norwegian Prime Minister Jonas Gahr Støre saying he no longer feels obligated to think purely of peace.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20ba7c8762afea740f16f5db3b8abfdc</guid></item><item><title>Land council chair calls for block on appointment of incoming NT administrator David Connolly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/nlc-calls-on-nt-administrator-david-connolly-to-step-down/106244078</link><description>Former Northern Territory Cattlemen’s Association president David Connolly is set to be sworn in as NT administrator next month, but the emergence of past social media posts have led to calls for his appointment to be blocked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1c54e45e5ef104dac2cd71b7015e15a</guid></item><item><title>Philippines star Alexandra Eala sends Australian Open crowds into a frenzy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/australian-open-alexandra-eala-philippines-melbourne-park/106246520</link><description>Alexandra Eala, ranked 49 in the world, attracts a crowd that virtually brought the Australian Open to a standstill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed8e4fa5d5e748dd1e7b20e436cc5910</guid></item><item><title>Man critical after being bitten by a shark in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/man-critical-after-being-bitten-by-a-shark-in-sydney/106246594</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e136a9efd0474d1502b11b3ec4dc15a</guid></item><item><title>Prince Harry's court battle against British tabloids reaches final chapter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/prince-harry-returns-to-court-in-battle-with-british-tabloids/106246678</link><description>Prince Harry has returned to court in London in his third and final attempt to tame the British tabloids through the legal system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">370456cf33716b09f3e36a9a21e41ba5</guid></item><item><title>Deadly Pakistan shopping plaza fire death toll rises to 23</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/deadly-pakistan-shopping-plaza-fire-death-toll-rises/106246696</link><description>Pakistani firefighters began pulling bodies from the smouldering remains of a sprawling Karachi shopping mall on Monday where dozens of people remain missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e150196ed19b2ece558297a16bcff946</guid></item><item><title>What we know so far about Spain's fatal high-speed train crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/what-we-know-about-spain-deadly-high-speed-rail-train-crash/106246960</link><description>Spanish authorities have declared three days of mourning after two trains collided on a track south of Madrid, killing at least 40 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a439df12ad3524c4e55faa1833f926ca</guid></item><item><title>Italian fashion designer Valentino dies aged 93 in Rome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/italian-fashion-designer-valentino-dies-aged-93-in-rome/106247130</link><description>The fashion icon's creations were adored by Hollywood stars, royals and first ladies for his fail-safe red carpet designs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46af3ffb2731ac5d3650837108493b36</guid></item><item><title>EPA asks Victorians to check water quality before swimming in Port Phillip Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/port-phillip-bay-water-quality-summer-beach-reports-epa/106158836</link><description>Victoria's Environment Protection Authority says people wanting to cool off at Port Phillip Bay beaches this summer should stay across its regular pollution updates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea04c727cb0b034491d7cd8c93a10cc6</guid></item><item><title>Oak Tasmania issued $1.1m penalty over hundreds of NDIS compliance failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/tas-ndis-provider-1-1m-penalty-for-breaches/106246414</link><description>Oak Tasmania admits to 474 compliance and reporting failures, as well as breaches that resulted in the hospitalisation of multiple NDIS clients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9e88e8b1c262ca731e0c1c273ec6e75</guid></item><item><title>Travel quiz, January 20: Which Australian state has the most wine regions?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/travel-quiz-january-20/106245804</link><description>Do you know where Marco Polo Airport is? And which is the biggest island in Australia?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c9c978f27dccabcd2105d5892e4b823</guid></item><item><title>How lifting gave me back the power to feel good at sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/how-powerlifting-gave-me-back-the-power-to-feel-good-at-sport/106234088</link><description>As a child, Julie "wasn't one of the sporty kids". A safe gym environment and then a supportive powerlifting community helped her realise that wasn't actually true.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2abbef65f571e75069d3d1abdc6f375</guid></item><item><title>Labor and Coalition on path to deal on hate laws reform as parliament deadline looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/labor-coalition-hate-laws-deal-deadline-looms/106244300</link><description>Liberal MPs gathered to discuss the draft laws at a partyroom meeting in Canberra on Monday evening after Opposition Leader Sussan Ley and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese met to hash out an agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a2526f58a5d9b6415bdab9d0bbe190d</guid></item><item><title>China ramps up crackdown on Christians amid global political pressures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/china-ramps-up-crackdown-on-underground-christian-churches/106228908</link><description>Dozens of church leaders and members have been arrested in China in recent months, which advocates say is indicative of intensifying persecution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c54c22a63990022797415619510f9303</guid></item><item><title>China's population declines for a fourth straight year amid record low birth rates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/china-population-decline-fourth-straight-year/106245406</link><description>National data shows that in 2025, China's population shrunk by 3.39 million people, as experts warn the trend is likely to continue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5e802e05f3c7a95834eb029793b0ed4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump heading to Davos as bond market vigilantes plot against him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/donald-trump-us-federal-reserve-powell-interest-rates/106245010</link><description>There are signs Donald Trump's bold strategy to artificially lower interest rates could backfire, as a level of disquiet emerges on money markets, particularly in bonds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65e936bbb965d193d01d5df138ff1bd8</guid></item><item><title>Shark expert says it's a 'terrible idea' to swim in Sydney Harbour after heavy rain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/sydney-harbour-shark-risk-not-clear-sewage-attracts-fish/106245214</link><description>A public policy shark expert says sewage leaking into the harbour after heavy rainfall is attracting bait fish followed by sharks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">196c8da596d94bf6c88caf312ec27dc2</guid></item><item><title>First Nations employee asked by supervisor about eating ants takes transport department to court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/sa-transport-department-federal-court-case/106231982</link><description>A First Nations employee at South Australia's Department for Infrastructure and Transport (DIT) has claimed she was sexually harassed by her supervisor and racially discriminated against when asked about eating ants before a cultural training session, court documents reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7374c2347019e1b32db9a67988ee3efb</guid></item><item><title>In Iran, Elon Musk's Starlink helped citizens get messages beyond the 'digital prison'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/in-iran-starlink-helped-citizens-break-out-of-the-digital-prison/106244360</link><description>In Iran, Starlink has provided a line to the outside world, but now there are fears about such vital technology being in the hands of one company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbf024ef38c524a39f1172af74e69250</guid></item><item><title>New Trump tariffs on European allies could push EU to use 'trade bazooka'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/trump-tariffs-european-allies-trade-bazooka/106243894</link><description>Following the Trump administration's recent tariff threat on European allies, some experts warn it may push Europe closer to China, and potentially see the European Union use its anti-coercion instrument, also known as a "trade bazooka", in response.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfd83a0c8c002868f5bb1a1d952c2109</guid></item><item><title>Victorian bushfires squeeze beekeeper access to high-quality trees for bees ahead of winter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/victoria-bushfires-beekeeper-access-restrictions/106243830</link><description>Apiarists in Victoria are wondering how they will keep their bees fed during winter after bushfires two years in a row render certain areas inaccessible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53ba80cd946bb3fbcb843855ca6d35a4</guid></item><item><title>Dissecting Donald Trump's Greenland message, line by line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/donald-trump-greenland-message-analysed-line-by-line/106246964</link><description>A leaked message from the US president to Norway's prime minister has fanned the flames of a geopolitical dumpster fire engulfing Greenland. We've analysed Donald Trump's claims to see if they stack up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81dd92b61485bb709c037d07f0241a9b</guid></item><item><title>Women's captain departs football club after men's offensive Silly Saturday costumes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/box-hill-north-fc-womens-captain-leaves-club-after-men-behaviour/106190266</link><description>A women's senior football captain has stepped away from her local club after photos of the senior men's leadership team were posted online during their "Silly Saturday" post-season celebrations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ffb103fdb7886c68801e2562aeef8ca</guid></item><item><title>Stan Wawrinka's impressive win, a wheelchair exit and Alja Tomljanović tells off her dad — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/australian-open-2026-quick-hits/106243998</link><description>One player had to be wheeled off the courts in a wheelchair, while Alja Tomljanović was wishing her dad would be quiet in the crowd. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5d4a55ec566caaa313f28eb7c9913b7</guid></item><item><title>Ipswich residents frustrated as nickel waste stored near homes without council approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/ipswich-residents-nickelwaste-dumped-nearhomes-council-approval/106244714</link><description>The dumping of the waste is the latest in a series of similar events for the city which some now call "Australia’s waste capital".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">098856adadd618e6d5f95435a562ca83</guid></item><item><title>Shellharbour mayor's quick thinking during call may have saved deputy's life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/shellharbour-councillor-kellie-marsh-aneurysm-emergency/106245410</link><description>A mayor's split-second decision to answer a phone call instead of heading into the surf may well have saved the life of his deputy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d92c75f46d2dd5048aa680d5e3e2bc68</guid></item></channel></rss>