<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 04:46:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Australian FMX rider Clinton Moore lands 720 trick</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/australian-fmx-rider-clinton-moore-lands-720-trick/105748934</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b750776abb60a888ae4a0a4f4496216</guid></item><item><title>Jess Fox announces she will miss Canoe Slalom World Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/jess-fox-announces-she-will-miss-canoe-slalom/105762586</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5dc18bb88857142cc4820e1ddcca090</guid></item><item><title>Zach Merrett's meeting with Hawthorn has given Essendon a chance to become a ruthless football club once again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/afl-zach-merrett-hawthorn-meeting-essendon-culture-analysis/105757688</link><description>Essendon has gone from an AFL powerhouse to a cellar-dweller due to its inability to make tough decisions over the last two decades, and now its captain has offered the club a chance to flip the script.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8384497c62ff7a3ac09bf2775c0e31b4</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Crows boosted by Josh Rachele return for AFL semifinal against Hawthorn Hawks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/adelaide-crows-josh-rachele-returns-afl-semifinal-hawthorn-hawks/105762146</link><description>The Crows have received a major boost ahead of their knockout semifinal against the Hawks, with livewire forward Josh Rachele recalled after a knee injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dedd9f8bda2e74a1245bf93dfb7fa6ca</guid></item><item><title>Is the pink soap scum in my bathroom mould, or something else?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/why-is-the-soap-scum-in-my-bathroom-pink-and-orange-/105721212</link><description>Have you ever noticed a pink or orange-coloured substance in the tile grout or around taps in your bathroom? In most cases, it's one of two things.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9deb3308036c00d500826ba08d50f062</guid></item><item><title>What videos from the scene tell us about Charlie Kirk’s 'political assassination'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/verify-what-we-know-about-the-charlie-kirk-assassination/105761534</link><description>Verified videos taken at the scene of the shooting of high-profile right-wing activist Charlie Kirk show what appears to be a figure on the roof of a nearby building.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24160b081eec81b32cd9932baf801b0b</guid></item><item><title>A Nampijinpa Price-sized chink in Ley's armour might have given Labor a campaign edge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/jacinta-nampijinpa-price-sussan-ley-armour-election/105745506</link><description>The Jacinta Nampijinpa Price saga is a chink in Sussan Ley's armour and at the very least has handed Labor damaging material for their 2028 election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f675f2ca4f69a3fbd020a7e26196ccf0</guid></item><item><title>How Hawthorn and Gold Coast proceed to the AFL preliminary finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/how-hawthorn-and-gold-coast-get-to-prelim-finals/105762028</link><description>Hawthorn and Gold Coast go into their cut-throat semifinals with reasons for some confidence against the Crows and Lions. Cody Atkinson and Sean Lawson look into the factors driving both teams' September runs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bee6f2e0e1aee53ecd326cca279df14</guid></item><item><title>Julie Bishop says there are 'no grounds' for her to step aside following resignation of Genevieve Bell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/julie-bishop-responds-genevieve-bell-resignation/105763422</link><description>In the wake of ANU vice-chancellor Genevieve Bell's resignation, Chancellor Julie Bishop says there's no reason for her to also stand aside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87feb39c8dfe1f3ab21bb0968a8e93fc</guid></item><item><title>Exhibition of ceramic work by Purple House dialysis patients opens in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/purple-house-dialysis-patients-ceramics-exhibition-alice-springs/105762128</link><description>Between treatments, Purple House patients have been creating colourful works of ceramic art. The results are now on display in Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b06662e346a171d11fdb5732df22f736</guid></item><item><title>'Unconscionable' for Ireland to participate in Eurovision 2026 if Israel takes part, says broadcaster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/ireland-threatens-eurovision-boycott-if-isreal-takes-part/105764652</link><description>Irish national broadcaster RTE has said Ireland will not participate in Eurovision 2026 if Israel does, citing the ongoing and appalling loss of lives in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6e6c785f4a9425e849bb6220cf8b39f</guid></item><item><title>Queenslanders pay more than $4.5 million in fines after failing to vote in 2024 state election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/queensland-electoral-commission-voting-fines-state-election/105761396</link><description>Electoral Commission of Queensland data has revealed about 340,000 eligible Queenslanders failed to cast a vote at last year's state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20c10f9744349fd14e99fba7df2e4300</guid></item><item><title>Sydney live music venue embraces grant for soundproofing amid noise complaint concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/nsw-government-grants-soundproofing-sydney-live-music-venues/105748102</link><description>When the Red Rattler theatre in Sydney's inner west installed acoustic foam in the walls behind its stage, it didn't just make the venue soundproof — but future-proof.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ff16aa762f54c42d123cbb2a78c68e5</guid></item><item><title>Toni Jordan spent her childhood at the greyhound track, inspiring her new novel Tenderfoot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/toni-jordan-books-tenderfoot-interview/105754310</link><description>The acclaimed author's father was a greyhound trainer and her mother ran a TAB. Her unconventional childhood inspired her eighth book, Tenderfoot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19370cb777b009a92f1855e8361e9d09</guid></item><item><title>Northern Territory Corrections Department honours 20th anniversary of Elders Visiting Program in prisons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/aboriginal-elders-visiting-nt-prisons-program-20th-anniversary/105762476</link><description>A decades-long partnership between Indigenous elders and the Northern Territory’s prison system is helping prisoners reconnect with culture and encouraging them to turn their lives around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d147bcd5d79a00f7cbb9532900da3288</guid></item><item><title>Genevieve Bell's resignation unlikely to satisfy calls for change in ANU leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/vc-bell-resignation-unlikely-satisfy-call-anu-leadership-change/105763826</link><description>The announcement of vice-chancellor Genevieve Bell's resignation on Thursday was greeted with cheers, however the view on campus is that this alone will not reverse the erosion of trust and morale that has already occurred.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74cadc99f2b0bca0070bf30d25913213</guid></item><item><title>Netball final scoring error sparks resignation in Wimmera Football Netball League rivalry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/wimmera-netball-scoring-error-sparks-football-controversy/105753726</link><description>A botched score in a western Victorian netball league final has led to a senior official resigning and a police escort at the rival clubs' football match as tensions between the clubs remain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2cee958724691598f5102c88f167506</guid></item><item><title>Kiama by-election could signal voter mood across NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/kiama-by-election-test-for-labor-and-liberals-after-gareth-ward/105761224</link><description>The Kiama by-election this weekend is more than a fight for one seat. It could reveal how voters view the state's major party leaders after scandal and political upheaval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fc47b757caa798d67eb6d84b1a4c0fa</guid></item><item><title>Outback hairdresser a 'hero' to Wilcannia residents longing for a pampering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/outback-hairdresser-travels-1000kms-to-pamper-remote-residents/105636488</link><description>The "salon" is an op shop and the round-trip commute's a doozy, but Juliann Mutch is happy to go the extra distance to pamper her grateful Wilcannia clientele.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">078b38e392f5ace6b92b8e4e40ed7b88</guid></item><item><title>How Jamal Fogarty learned to be the hero Canberra needed for its premiership charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/jamal-fogarty-canberra-raiders-nrl-finals-broncos/105763708</link><description>Jamal Fogarty has spent a rugby league lifetime waiting to play on a team like the Raiders. Now with the NRL finals approaching, he's ready for his close-up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37ebbb2fb5d1d3bfd53ea39bbcdce144</guid></item><item><title>Voter turnout as low as 10 per cent in NT local elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/nt-local-government-council-elections-see-dip-in-voter-turnout/105760662</link><description>Two out of five of the NT's enrolled voters failed to vote in the jurisdictions recent local government elections, with experts concerned voting fatigue has taken hold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">889f1bd29f1f4d9c6b5541f52d7a7f70</guid></item><item><title>Netball Australia, players strike revenue-sharing deal in collective player agreement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/netball-australia-players-strike-landmark-revenue-sharing-deal/105765526</link><description>Netball Australia and the players' association strike a landmark revenue-sharing deal as part of a three-year collective player agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04124b57417d9814469f61aa8c909075</guid></item><item><title>The simple system I use for composting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/simple-system-use-for-composting/105648580</link><description>Koren Helbig has devised an easy and effective method of turning her food waste and plant trimmings into a nutrient-rich compost for her Adelaide/Tarntanya food gardens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79967d2cf242f317c83d0a075a76ca87</guid></item><item><title>Australia to face Belgium in Davis Cup in Sydney with Final 8 spot up for grabs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/nothing-for-granted-aussies-wary-of-belgian-davis-cup-threat/105767498</link><description>Lleyton Hewitt's Australian Davis Cup team is ready for another fierce battle with old foes Belgium as they chase a spot in this year's Final 8 in Italy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25e0a60e31cf0b026f68b6ea2239af89</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne names Geelong assistant Steven King as new senior coach as Nathan Buckley is overlooked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/afl-steven-king-named-melbourne-demons-coach/105767854</link><description>Melbourne surprises the AFL world by naming Geelong assistant Steven King as its new senior coach despite persistent links with Nathan Buckley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fea7a235f5c0090787551364ca3b7d77</guid></item><item><title>Quote Quiz: Who said it, Lachlan Murdoch or Succession's Kendall Roy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/quiz-who-said-it-lachlan-murdoch-or-kendall-roy/102946532</link><description>As Lachlan Murdoch's ascension to the head of the family business is cemented, can you tell his quotes apart from Succession's self-proclaimed "eldest boy", Kendall Roy?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cddc5ea62e8e2529ae1aade17a00dfd</guid></item><item><title>Artists and users boycotting Spotify over AI use and CEO's military tech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/spotify-boycott-daniel-ek-ai-music-military-tech-fenn-wilson/105765846</link><description>A growing number of artists and users are leaving Spotify. What's changed with the streaming giant? And what comes next?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dce4c940b969890ecfdfb4e37ad98c9</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian government consulting on public homebirth model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/tasmanian-government-consulting-on-public-homebirth-model/105767780</link><description>A proposal by the Tasmanian government to introduce a public homebirth model has been welcomed by those in the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9fdea3108a66149f4d49c462aee9cca</guid></item><item><title>British YouTube creator Yung Filly to travel home to UK on bail for sexual assault charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/youtube-creator-yung-filly-allowed-to-fly-overseas-on-bail/105094220</link><description>British YouTube content creator Yung Filly, who's facing trial in Perth on sex assault charges, is granted permission to travel home to the UK for the first time since he was arrested.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c89f9603e811b96cf1412b9f341613a</guid></item><item><title>Judge awards man $450k in damages after ex-premier's police officer son falsified evidence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/man-gets-450k-damages-for-daniel-keneally-fabricating-evidence/105767836</link><description>A Supreme Court judge has awarded NSW man Luke Moore $450,000 in damages after the disgraced police officer son of former senator Kristina Keneally falsified evidence about alleged death threats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11118a489badd08a9a50abbfccbc184e</guid></item><item><title>Disagreement over way forward for Australian National University after Genevieve Bell resigns as vice-chancellor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/anu-staff-disagree-way-forward-after-genevieve-bell-departure/105766052</link><description>The resignation of Australian National University vice-chancellor Genevieve Bell has sparked furious debate over whether it constitutes enough of a "reset" for the institution after months of controversy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b4a26c95183383a604a98eb05670027</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn ends Adelaide's season with rollicking semifinal win, setting up epic Geelong prelim final date</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/afl-adelaide-crows-vs-hawthorn-hawks-semifinal-live-blog/105767748</link><description>After dispensing of the Crows via a 34-point victory, the Hawks are licking their lips ahead of their preliminary final against the annoyingly good" Cats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dae5c2cdc7b85088bd6f6b57bce33018</guid></item><item><title>Matildas to face England Lionesses in October international window</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-12/matildas-to-face-england-in-october-international-window/105768734</link><description>The Matildas have announced an international friendly against England this October, the first time they will face the European champions since the semifinal of the 2023 FIFA Women's World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dcbfca402515a25dcb9fa30ae7dbe58</guid></item><item><title>Sushila Karki sworn in as Nepal's new prime minister after gen Z protests prompt political change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/sushila-karki-nepals-new-prime-minister-after-gen-z-protests/105769388</link><description>Sushila Karki garnered widespread support from many young Nepalese people who took to the streets in anger over government corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b14068c37ad26302453e199b0b0960b7</guid></item><item><title>Former minister Greg Hunt works for Brethren company whose owners made millions on COVID contracts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/greg-hunt-plymouth-brethren-liberal-party-four-corners/105767402</link><description>The Sydney-based church has been described by former members and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese as a "cult".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4328a557e1520bd5030668231cb9ac20</guid></item><item><title>Journey Home, David Gulpilil shows the film icon's remote homeland 'for the first time'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/new-documentary-journey-home-david-gulpilil-screens-in-darwin/105765450</link><description>Legendary Yolŋu actor David Gulpilil held an ambition throughout his career to share a part of himself and his culture that the world had never seen before. A new documentary does exactly that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d65721a64e5ebe2a1f5e94ea75d0c3b0</guid></item><item><title>More than a dozen women complain about Brisbane doctor accused of performing 'sexually motivated' checks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/complaints-against-brisbane-doctor-accused-unnecessary-checks/105761406</link><description>Dr Stan Theodoros is facing disciplinary proceedings, lodged by Queensland's health ombudsman, in the Queensland Civil and Administrative Tribunal (QCAT).</description><guid isPermaLink="false">741e87aaa3667ced3bea58af9748de48</guid></item><item><title>Cobblebank stabbing victims Dau Akueng, 15, and Chol Achiek, 12, remembered by family and friends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/chol-achiek-dau-akueng-cobblebank-stabbing-victims-remembered/105763754</link><description>Last weekend, Dau Akueng, 15, and Chol Achiek, 12, were fatally stabbed on their way home from basketball in Melbourne's western suburbs. The pair are being remembered by those who knew them for who they were, not just for how they tragically died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32e7ce5fedea82b82486cd60fcab1067</guid></item><item><title>Keio Yoshida tells queer stories differently in their new book, Pride and Prejudices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/keio-yoshida-pride-and-prejudices-queer-lives-and-the-law/105658412</link><description>In their latest book, author and human rights lawyer Keio Yoshida draws on their personal experience and legal expertise to demonstrate the importance of sharing queer stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">325fafb6f4714080b832c5a0148c1ee0</guid></item><item><title>Adrianne Lenker on Big Thief's evolution and the making of Double Infinity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/big-thief-double-infinity-adrianne-lenker-new-album-interview/105754728</link><description>At the peak of their success, Big Thief faced a major emotional rupture that reshaped the group from the inside out. Now, they've returned with their sixth album, shaped by deep creative trust and a renewed commitment to collaboration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c838f7561646302e00adf2a4fa4ff7b4</guid></item><item><title>Nourishing and easy sweet potato and lentil bowls - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/easy-roasted-sweet-potato-and-lentil-bowl/105643934</link><description>This jazzy little bowl is made from simple ingredients. The sweet potato is roasted gently with spices and tinned lentils are roasted until crisp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f14ee49334cef10b8f95233d1889d9e</guid></item><item><title>Australian men charged with allegedly trafficking firearms after international kidnapping investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/men-charged-over-alleged-trafficking-of-firearms-to-indonesia/105769796</link><description>A Queensland man and a New South Wales man have been charged over alleged links to trafficking firearms to Indonesia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2aa067d1a6a82aa8f7e601efe1b3f2b8</guid></item><item><title>Suns coach Damien Hardwick praised ahead of historic finals clash against Lions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/afl-suns-lions-damien-hardwick-alastair-lynch/105769862</link><description>Brisbane Lions great Alastair Lynch hails the impact of Damien Hardwick at the Gold Coast Suns as they look to continue their run in the finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">325e308ff45d50af4c7b44030c5cb081</guid></item><item><title>Bush band tells Aboriginal people's side of the Maralinga nuclear weapon tests story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/bush-band-song-tells-story-of-maralinga-atomic-bomb-tests/105765452</link><description>For Liam Tunkin, making music is about continuing his late father's legacy and sharing a dark part of Australia's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b898813878aa4745672fc29e28ce560b</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fall to 28-26 defeat against Argentina in The Rugby Championship in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/live-updates-wallabies-vs-argentina-the-rugby-championship/105753320</link><description>The Wallabies have fallen just short of a magical comeback against Argentina, losing 28-26 in a thrilling Rugby Championship Test in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac9963693b81c061d5a7137f7874121c</guid></item><item><title>Supreme Court gives Queensland hospital permission to terminate 12yo girl's pregnancy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/qld-hospital-gets-court-permission-for-abortion-on-12yo-girl/105770196</link><description>A 12-year-old girl in residential care in Queensland should be allowed to have an abortion, a court rules, after a judge found she was not capable of making the decision herself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86cd5589ba9855a3f68a146a74e238ad</guid></item><item><title>NRLW wrap: Brisbane Broncos thrash the Cowboys 50-4, Gold Coast grab last finals spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/upton-hat-trick-leads-broncos-to-big-nrlw-win-over-cowboys/105770416</link><description>It's a big day for Queensland sides in the NRLW, as the Broncos — led by skipper Tamika Upton — are far too good for the third-placed Cowboys, while the Titans clinch the last finals spot with a win over Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0af6a0f9bdb8ae75a28c6c7e963ce856</guid></item><item><title>WA Health issues measles warning as two more cases linked to Bali travel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/two-more-measles-cases-in-wa-linked-to-bali-travel/105770492</link><description>West Australians planning to visit South-East Asia are being urged to get vaccinated against measles, with two more cases linked with travel to Bali.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1897bbaf4493022b86af465fcc949ac6</guid></item><item><title>Labor win Kiama by-election as voters replace disgraced MP Gareth Ward</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/kiama-byelection-polls-close-votes-counting/105770414</link><description>The NSW Premier said Kiama now has the ear of the government after it claimed victory in the by-election triggered by the resignation of convicted rapist Gareth Ward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f8148eb8e329e6cf74190c6118a0a8f</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane far too good for Gold Coast in QClash semifinal, setting up Collingwood prelim date</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/afl-finals-brisbane-lions-gold-coast-suns-live-blog/105768034</link><description>Bouncing back from a resounding loss to Geelong, the Brisbane Lions comfortably dispense of the Gold Coast Suns to advance to the preliminary finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35fd90e486aa2532889961cd9ae474b8</guid></item><item><title>From Formula 1 to creating the 'world's best' croissant, how baking saved Lune founder Kate Reid's life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/cars-to-croissants-kate-reid-and-the-lune-empire/105750472</link><description>Kate Reid's Lune croissants have been called the world's best. But how did a young woman struggling with a near-fatal eating disorder end up perfecting pastry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d09b350f758690100795053d1425df1</guid></item><item><title>Children missing out on early intervention for language delays due to shortage of speech pathologists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/australias-speech-pathology-therapy-language-delay/105658306</link><description>One in four children starting school now has a speech or language delay. It can hold back their learning, affect their friendships and harm their mental health. Speech therapists are struggling to find ways to support them all, but one school is leading the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fd8643f474de3cb897a95d95769fb75</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's health chief, RFK Jr, is dividing Republicans on vaccines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/trump-health-chief-rfk-jr-divides-republicans-on-vaccines/105763060</link><description>US Health Secretary Robert F Kennedy Jr's anti-vaccination agenda is gaining ground, but resistance is coming from all sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">550382bc4a2dad860c2ebd332ba5da22</guid></item><item><title>Trump hits out at Florida's 'tough stance' on vaccines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/trump-hits-out-at-floridas-tough-stance-on-vaccines/105767070</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">411cbb4e0109999f07a638bac1bb9e45</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Think you're contestant material? Prove it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/105746846</link><description>It's time to show me your exceptional trivia knowledge. Ha!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03f61e05a2d928ef5dd5a855914f188a</guid></item><item><title>'Bone lady' who helped find Daniel Morcombe still unearthing stories of the dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/life-of-qld-police-forensic-anthropologist-donna-macgregor/105757258</link><description>From the search for Daniel Morcombe to a flaming roadside torso, Queensland's top forensics cop deals with some of the state's worst crimes — when she's not identifying fallen Australians on WWI battlefields.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">756451363a24944c71314b39d4ee9da4</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal artist Emily Kam Kngwarray becomes first Australian with solo exhibition at London's Tate Modern</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/emily-kam-kngwarray-nt-artist-solo-exhibition-tate-modern/105748722</link><description>Emily Kam Kngwarray has been recognised as "one of the world's leading artists" after becoming the first Australian whose work is the subject of a solo exhibition at the Tate Modern Gallery in London.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80742075f005deb3851d847eafa37b21</guid></item><item><title>Wallaroos' Rugby World Cup hopes dashed by dominant Canada in 46-5 loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/rugby-world-cup-wallaroos-canada-quarterfinal/105771382</link><description>The Wallaroos miss the chance to reach the Rugby World Cup semifinals, losing heavily 46-5 to Canada in Bristol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eeea51af32489f3175d1f115a728a37</guid></item><item><title>The Pacific won a stunning climate victory at the International Court of Justice. What's next?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/whats-next-after-pacific-icj-climate-victory/105747794</link><description>Pacific Island nations are weighing up how to use a historic international court ruling in their fight to bring about stronger emissions reductions and climate justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4d5352fd2872714b73915e90a078b57</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk's accused killer Tyler Robinson awaits formal charges in Utah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/tyler-robinson-awaits-formal-charges-over-charlie-kirk-murder/105771364</link><description>Tyler Robinson, jailed on suspicion of fatally shooting right-wing activist Charlie Kirk, faces formal charges in Utah early next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">388d30366d16f1bf3aebb0058cc923e8</guid></item><item><title>Parramatta Road could get up to 8,000 new homes close to Sydney CBD in rezoning plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/thousands-new-homes-could-be-built-sections-parramatta-rd-sydney/105768070</link><description>The NSW government strikes a deal with Inner West Council to move forward with a plan to rezone sections of busy Parramatta Road that could see up the construction of up to 8,000 new homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f91bfdf2fe77baed9a8e3ab75b5e6d8d</guid></item><item><title>'White-hot anger' in the bush as Victorians fight government on multiple fronts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/why-regional-victorians-are-angry-at-state-government/105761034</link><description>Rural residents and local councils are deeply unhappy with new taxes, renewable energy, bad roads and mining companies, accusing the state government of "city centric" policymaking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">975ae86896e7894f15dfe756b7e0f4f9</guid></item><item><title>Carlton AFLW side has reached a 'turning point' after challenging years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/with-a-few-added-pieces-carlton-have-flown-up-the-ladder-aflw/105770732</link><description>Inaugural Carlton player Gab Pound says the club has reached a turning point after not making the finals since the 2020 COVID-interrupted season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4746581d3adeb6ddbdb1c2e40b060a32</guid></item><item><title>Brick-pit frog recovery another win for green and gold at Sydney Olympics site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/green-and-golden-bell-frogs-thrive-at-sydney-olympics-site/105762124</link><description>Twenty-five years after the Sydney Olympics, an important Homebush planning decision has led to successful conservation efforts for a species born in the green and gold. But a deadly fungus poses a threat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7163e13b015cd649bd1282f9f989c65e</guid></item><item><title>'Where to now?' Liberals soul searching after heavy loss in Kiama by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/nsw-kiama-by-election-analysis/105768772</link><description>For a party that had just suffered a heavy defeat, the mood at the Liberals' post-election event was surprisingly upbeat on Saturday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0324f2b1e17e0afe58c8b2fdb2342585</guid></item><item><title>Wombats in Robe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/wombats-in-robe/105762994</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b3220b0971b015745735ee5063bf7e0</guid></item><item><title>The Franklin River rescue was extreme. Here's how medics prepare for the wilderness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/expedition-medicine-frontline-wilderness-rescue-tasmania/105647214</link><description>The Franklin River rescue was an extreme test for the skills of medics. In remote Tasmania, here's how they train for "chaos".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad6b3276dc3d97f9e83daaf4447dd1e</guid></item><item><title>Outback nurse transforms remote diabetes care with cans, rocks and bush tucker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/collarenebri-hosts-pilot-diabetes-and-holistic-health-program/105600544</link><description>When Rishoniy Caine arrived in a remote NSW community with one general store and no gym, she knew fixing its diabetes problem would need a different approach to what had already failed the locals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">222ba35951a8a4a1e2c0a8f063f85b5b</guid></item><item><title>How to watch the 2025 Primetime Emmys in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/how-to-watch-the-emmys-2025-primetime-awards-los-angeles/105751936</link><description>Your pocket guide to watching the Emmy awards in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec791c67cc32865ea8679b33207acf56</guid></item><item><title>Victorian farmers welcome spring forecast despite long-term climate concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/farming-faces-global-warming-challenges-bom-csiro-forecasts/105698854</link><description>As spring brings a flicker of hope, some farmers cautiously embrace optimism while others face mounting pressures and climate uncertainty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eefc8f08701a2e9f48f36a96143be8ca</guid></item><item><title>Residents in flood-affected communities want more warning technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/flood-hit-residents-call-for-more-automated-river-gauges/105724942</link><description>For generations, farmers and outback communities have relied on the bush telegraph during floods but it has fallen silent in recent years, leaving residents without up-to-date information.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c31e8ba3a792f16088d132fc493aa4e1</guid></item><item><title>All Blacks forced to re-group after 43-10 loss to Springboks in Rugby Championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/all-blacks-regroup-after-springboks-defeat/105771568</link><description>After a demoralising 43-10 loss to the Springboks on home soil, the All Blacks are looking to rebound against the Wallabies in the upcoming Bledisloe Cup Tests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14cb19776ed7e08739a74354c2afa92e</guid></item><item><title>'World's biggest' hockey game in York fundraises for cancer research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/eliza-reynolds-hockey-game-cancer-fundraiser/105763156</link><description>More than 370 people participate in a hockey game lasting more than eight hours in honour of a little girl who died from a rare form of cancer earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6940b0964bbe2ae1724b08b2a97f81f</guid></item><item><title>Police condemn 'brazen' Sydney shooting after three people escape injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/merrylands-sydney-shooting-three-people-avoid-injury/105771760</link><description>Police believe the target of a shooting in Merrylands on Sunday no longer lives at the home but allegedly has links to a splintering Sydney crime family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ba3b4dbdeada147ebf8528b70c3ee87</guid></item><item><title>How to give your indoor plants a spring clean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/how-to-spring-clean-indoor-plants/105754044</link><description>As gardens, parks and nature strips start showing signs of spring, our indoor plants might need a little help to jump into the new season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7041345f64a52b3d64fb6ac2ef82f3b</guid></item><item><title>Lachie Neale gives himself '50 per cent' chance of improbable grand final appearance after calf injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/afl-brisbane-lions-lachie-neale-50-per-cent-chance-gf/105771982</link><description>Lachie Neale admits medical professionals are not holding out much hope of him recovering from a calf injury in time for the grand final, but he is not giving up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a19957fc35f1ad280cdb57d03a33c7d3</guid></item><item><title>Ben Hunt's Golden Point field goal sends Brisbane Broncos into NRL prelims after downing Canberra Raiders in all-time classic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/nrl-live-updates-finals-canberra-raiders-brisbane-broncos/105767630</link><description>Jamal Fogarty scores a try in Golden Point to send the Raiders to a preliminary final only for it to be disallowed before Ben Hunt delivers a dagger field goal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6df4f99fbc4ba21354c9bf49bf40731</guid></item><item><title>One woman, eight men charged with child abuse offences following NSW raids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/nine-people-charged-nsw-child-abuse-offences-homes-raided/105772116</link><description>Eight men and one woman have been charged across with more than 30 online child abuse offences during a two-week child protection blitz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4bb1db6e528250a9ee913e555d290fc</guid></item><item><title>AFLW Round 5 Sunday wrap: Kangaroos claim grand final rematch against Lions as Saints and Cats record big wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/aflw-round-5-sunday-wrap-kangaroos-beat-lions-gf-rematch/105771940</link><description>North Melbourne continues its blistering start to the AFLW season as Geelong and St Kilda also record big wins in Round 5.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cee53d3f18feb5d3f6fa788a7a48b761</guid></item><item><title>Belgians break Australian hearts in Davis Cup classic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-14/tennis-de-minaur-australia-belgium-davis-cup-wrap/105772264</link><description>Beligum's Raphael Collignon wore down late stand-in Aleksandar Vukic in the deciding rubber to lead Belgium to the quarter-finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48108db3db36157632582610dcc8f4ed</guid></item><item><title>The year Australia is due to blow its carbon budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/australia-carbon-budget-2035-emissions-target/105341080</link><description>Unless Australia lifts its ambitions, its "fair share" of carbon emissions will be spent 14 years early. With the government announcing a 2035 climate target this week, there is intense debate on how high the government should aim — and whether it will be enough to help limit global warming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92c26486065559e6e68fc907f4300c31</guid></item><item><title>GIM Trading accused of defrauding millions from ordinary Australian investors with 'low risk' bonds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/gim-trading-alleged-fraud-investors-bonds/105747410</link><description>A Gold Coast musician approached by a man he knew from a local bar went on to front a trading company, later accused of defrauding millions from ordinary Australian investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef7a680d03253010b78fa5b88e06a4f0</guid></item><item><title>Dads leaving sex education to mums, report finds, with concerns young boys are missing out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/dads-leaving-sex-education-to-mums-boys-missing-out/105761172</link><description>New report finds mothers do more of the sex education at home, raising concerns that young boys are missing out on key information from their dads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09373ae607cb293f5028b7499dce7b5a</guid></item><item><title>Weather to warm up in Queensland, as more rain forecast for the north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/warmer-weather-tipped-for-much-of-queensland-as-spring-sets-in/105771650</link><description>The southern half of Queensland can expect fine weather at least for the first half of the week, while more rain is on the way for the north of the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44a26254dc8a8890086a64f319e0fce8</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic expeditioners join research project to help astronauts on space missions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/antarctic-expeditioners-join-astronaut-research-project/105767136</link><description>Expeditioners at Australia's Antarctic stations are taking part in a research project to better understand the cognitive and physiological impacts of extended deployments — which can include actual "brain shrinkage".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d57ace742d2dab72c8470091d9eea61</guid></item><item><title>Bankruptcy law reform push after paedophile protects assets in superannuation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/paedophiles-using-bankruptcy-loophole-to-avoid-payouts/105765918</link><description>Edan van Haren, a victim of child predator Maurice Van Ryn, says legal loopholes are allowing the confessed paedophile to protect his assets in superannuation to avoid paying compensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">598df1c8747bfb8132eaed82ca93974e</guid></item><item><title>Residents say former Moe Hospital could become public housing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/moe-hospital-newborough-derelict-building-social-housing/105637366</link><description>A retired nurse who worked at Moe Hospital says the closed facility could be used for housing rather than left to further rot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d6259927cc7b3ea15a9fcb2704c8b7c</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr scores 100th goal for Chelsea in long-awaited WSL return from knee injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sam-kerr-makes-wsl-chelsea-return-from-torn-acl/105772878</link><description>Matildas star Sam Kerr scores her 100th goal for Chelsea just minutes after returning to the pitch for the Blues for her first game since 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bae5f25a567be7986ec4489f569f5f25</guid></item><item><title>Road repairs after flood delayed by 'excruciating' eligibility criteria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/buloke-shire-flood-funding-pot-holes-delays-unsafe-roads/105733714</link><description>Victorian councils say they are required to provide before-and-after photos of every 100 metres of road in order to be eligible for flood recovery funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d6870a6663a3b8139b0e567866cd586</guid></item><item><title>Documents reveal unauthorised sediment releases at Blackwater Coal Mine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/blackwater-coal-mine-contamination-sediment/105769922</link><description>A report obtained by lobby group Lock The Gate under right-to-information laws reveal a mine in central Queensland was releasing sediment into environmentally sensitive areas for more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c0e5d78e0e78c7d0e25c51e02aed43f</guid></item><item><title>Fortunes change quickly in AFLW as round of upsets shakes up ladder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/round-of-upsets-shakes-up-aflw-ladder-mid-season/105772256</link><description>After a tough start to the year, Geelong sit just outside the top eight and equal on points with the reining grand finalists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a314ed873d6767758eb39088f9f9e0f6</guid></item><item><title>Traditional custodian readies for 'challenge' over North West Shelf gas project extension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/traditional-custodian-fights-north-west-shelf-approval/105770306</link><description>Environment Minister Murray Watt approved the extension of Australia's biggest gas project last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fff78b1c904abb60057a8fd295536c56</guid></item><item><title>Specialist GPs to diagnose ADHD in WA amid calls for further easing of restrictions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/wa-gps-soon-start-diagnosing-adhd/105759814</link><description>As a select cohort of WA GPs begins to diagnose ADHD in people older than 10, parents of younger children and some medical professionals have expressed concerns about the scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32f743c6d37c23f14438dac29a9eb199</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh fined for headbutt, Pat Carrigan banned for high shot in NRL finals win over Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/reece-walsh-headbutt-pat-carrigan-bans-from-broncos-raiders/105772942</link><description>Superstar Broncos fullback Reece Walsh will be free to play in the NRL preliminary finals after avoiding suspension for a headbutt on Hudson Young in Brisbane's epic win on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69bc0f4f4df315eed7d8c781e1acb538</guid></item><item><title>WA's expanded container deposit scheme to cost wineries, distilleries millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/container-for-change-wa-wine-expansion-hits-small-business/105763914</link><description>Producers in Western Australia's premier wine region say the state government's expanded bottle recycling scheme is set to cost them millions of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16ff8a6ec9140b73f0af3e85a003dec0</guid></item><item><title>Australia beats India in first of three ODIs before Women's Cricket World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/australia-beats-india-in-odi-world-cup-warm-up/105773182</link><description>Australia's Cricket World Cup preparations are in full swing as three batters score half-centuries in a big run chase in the first of three ODIs against India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a29f09f0be7bd9b554de11bd5f4906d1</guid></item><item><title>Emmy Awards 2025: The Pitt, Adolescence and The Studio win big as Owen Cooper makes history — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/emmy-awards-2025-live-blog-latest-updates/105757172</link><description>The Pitt wins Best Drama at the 77th Annual Primetime Emmy Awards, with The Studio, Adolescence and even Stephen Colbert walking away as the biggest winners of the night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f0dab0d1494400d0b01fc6483c43b32</guid></item><item><title>Port Hinchinbrook marina remains inaccessible despite dredging project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/port-hinchinbrook-marina-remains-inaccessible-after-dredging/105739106</link><description>Mud and silt continue to choke the channel connecting the controversial development to the Great Barrier Reef, once again putting industry and conservationists at odds over the fix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00377919955e2acc697f9565f436b2a9</guid></item><item><title>Outback ringmaster Fred Brophy takes his boxing tent to Birdsville for last time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/fred-brophy-takes-boxing-tent-to-birdsville-for-last-time/105761756</link><description>Fred Brophy will sell you a ticket, spin you a yarn and dare you into the ring, but at 73, the outback ringmaster is slowing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9c596e0ff31abe53e3cdc3f15b54fcc</guid></item><item><title>From Tantanoola to Essendon, Angus Clarke reflects on AFL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/angus-clarke-on-south-east-sa-breakfast/105773582</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32b5ad4ec4dbc2210f1b5997bfa6ec36</guid></item><item><title>Australian rules football and SANFL administrator Max Basheer dies aged 98</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sanfl-administrator-max-basheer-dies-aged-98/105773500</link><description>Max Basheer — the football administrator who oversaw the creation of the Adelaide Crows and the purpose-built stadium Football Park — has died aged 98.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">594325c3e747906c91d2cd8c90983d6f</guid></item><item><title>AFL State of Origin will return, with Western Australia-Victoria clash confirmed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/afl-announces-state-of-origin-return-with-wa-vic-clash-confirmed/105773392</link><description>AFL chief executive Andrew Dillon confirms Western Australia will play Victoria in Perth next February in the first State of Origin match since 1999.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d22aa23c3e429a537fcaf8a6093051d</guid></item><item><title>Prince Harry says he has no regrets about 2023 memoir Spare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/prince-harry-defends-his-memoir/105773344</link><description>Prince Harry has defended his tell-all autobiography Spare, insisting he has no regrets about its publication.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">822f9b8bfc9e038c4a05c240f351b362</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with giving Nazi salute at Brisbane Lions v Gold Coast Suns AFL game at the Gabba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/qld-man-charged-nazi-salute-at-afl-game-banned/105773522</link><description>A 39-year-old man has been charged with giving a Nazi salute at the AFL semifinal in Brisbane on Saturday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10247763ed0af9c91511f307aea12cd7</guid></item><item><title>Inquest to probe police action before Kelly Wilkinson killed by husband</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/coronial-inquest-into-death-of-gold-coast-mother-kelly-wilkinson/105767910</link><description>The actions of Queensland police will be put under the microscope at an inquest into the death of Gold Coast mother Kelly Wilkinson, who was killed by her estranged husband.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">717d0c00c1a3ba02425db620f8ba0fdd</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Roosters confirm ACL injury for Tarryn Aiken on eve of NRLW finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/sydney-roosters-confirm-tarryn-aiken-acl-injury-nrlw/105773930</link><description>Tarryn Aiken will miss the Sydney Roosters' NRLW finals campaign, with scans confirming a knee injury that will require a knee reconstruction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">880a495525ca619936ce2de16f4379d3</guid></item><item><title>Police charge man with assisting suicide while investigating 20 other deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/three-people-charged-over-alleged-assisted-suicide-on-gold-coast/105773946</link><description>Police allege the death of a man on the Gold Coast earlier this year was an assisted suicide and are investigating the deaths of other people as far back as 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f268d99b5f6b08e8bd88d36f26aadbc5</guid></item><item><title>Inquest hears prison system failed Aboriginal inmate before he died</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/inquest-examines-clinton-austin-death-loddon-prison/105735924</link><description>A coronial inquest hears the system failed First Nations prisoner Clinton Austin before his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3728f892b4b408407004793ea3dc66f</guid></item><item><title>Emmys 2025 winners: Adolescence, Severance, The Pitt and The Studio win big</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/primetime-emmy-awards-ceremony-winners-list/105752034</link><description>The 77th Primetime Emmy Awards are honouring the best and brightest in the US television industry. Here are the shows that picked up the trophies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d8d75f9c20e7825a51aab42eb0d2ca3</guid></item><item><title>Man jailed until at least 2028 for importing and producing a child-like sex doll</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/geoffrey-mew-sentence-sex-offences/105774224</link><description>The actions of a man who imported a child-like sex doll to his family home have been labelled "morally and legally repugnant" by a District Court judge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f6206491dd3bc63887246620afb01d0</guid></item><item><title>Arhab Haque sprayed fart gas at restaurants for TikTok clout, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/arhab-haque-sentenced-over-fart-gas-prank-gone-wrong/105774764</link><description>An amateur mixed martial arts fighter sprayed fart gas in a fast food restaurant so he could make TikTok prank videos, a Perth court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b3e5750b5b7883a158b5adc9cf27be0</guid></item><item><title>Starving wallabies at The Briars spark urgent Mornington Peninsula Shire council meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/the-briars-mornington-peninsula-wallaby-overpopulation-council/105773468</link><description>A study prompted by the deaths of wallabies at a beloved wildlife reserve south of Melbourne finds the population has grown five times larger than what The Briars sanctuary can sustain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">424a62aaec22ec8d6b644d8c878fed7b</guid></item><item><title>SA to roll out ChatGPT-style AI app in all high schools as tech experts urge caution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/education-chat-gpt-style-ai-app-to-roll-out-to-sa-high-schools/105772944</link><description>A ChatGPT-style app to be rolled out at all South Australian high schools next term has been welcomed by tech experts, who are also warning its use should be carefully managed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd8111de02cfad378cd6bbaeb5b75896</guid></item><item><title>How is Australia affected by climate change? The National Climate Risk Assessment models the future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/national-climate-risk-assessment-and-why-it-matters-explained/105773936</link><description>For the first time, the government has modelled the threats from climate change on Australia's future. What's the point of a document like this, and can it help us avoid the worst-case scenarios?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ad84229da5de3e8a79b28e4eacc8cab</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of pigs feared dead in fire at Dublin's Andgar piggery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/fire-dublin-andgar-piggery-animal-cruelty-sa/105775484</link><description>It has taken all day for a fire at a controversial piggery north of Adelaide to be put out. RSPCA inspectors are attending the piggery, which was already under investigation over cruelty claims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa9cf9f12e59456af1cd840c58c97688</guid></item><item><title>Cricket Tasmania seeking ways to make proposed Macquarie Point stadium 'compatible' for matches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/cricket-tasmania-support-macquarie-point-afl-stadium/105774588</link><description>After initial concerns that the roof design of the proposed Hobart AFL stadium at Macquarie Point would hinder cricket matches, sporting authorities have thrown their support behind the build, saying "we will find a way".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52fc9b1b49c5b01644f528cf1efb60b0</guid></item><item><title>Australia's richest person among hundreds of donors to NT senator's legal fund</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/gina-rinehart-jacinta-nampijinpa-price-defamation-legal-fund/105775036</link><description>Australia's richest person, Gina Rinehart, has helped fund Senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price's crowd-funded defence to a defamation action brought by the head of a Northern Territory land council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d91909126ee3a35177e1e241ad2e0c3</guid></item><item><title>Inmate tells inquest guards referred to Indigenous man who died in custody with derogatory slurs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/guards-referred-to-tj-denniss-with-derogatory-slurs-inquest-told/105775100</link><description>An inmate, who cannot be named, provided details of an Indigenous man's treatment in custody, as an inquest into the man's death continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48ae914a843526cfeb88ffed2cbfb41d</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle Knights announce Justin Holbrook as new NRL head coach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/-newcastle-knights-justin-holbrook-nrl-head-coach/105776208</link><description>Sydney Roosters assistant coach Justin Holbrook has been named the new head coach of the Newcastle Knights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1dd4d58f20f4f23adda8178a9bef8c9</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump vows national emergency in Washington DC after ICE dispute with Democrat mayor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/trump-vows-national-emergency-in-washington-dc/105776222</link><description>The US president's threat comes after Washington DC Mayor Muriel Bowser said the district's police would not cooperate with Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29a70dad39dbb57f35f5b6c01aafca9b</guid></item><item><title>Whispering Jack: The John Farnham Musical to premiere in Sydney Theatre Company's 2026 season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/whispering-jack-john-farnham-musical-sydney-theatre-company-2026/105766868</link><description>Whispering Jack: The John Farnham Musical is one of 13 plays coming to Sydney Theatre Company next year, alongside shows starring David Wenham and Miranda Otto.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ade2dd75f87979058d05fced4a9318</guid></item><item><title>NRL announces preliminary finals dates, Melbourne Storm on Friday, Brisbane Broncos play Sunday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/nrl-preliminary-finals-dates-melbourne-brisbane/105776416</link><description>The NRL has shaken up its preliminary finals weekend, electing to host one of its grand final qualifiers on a Sunday for the first time in 18 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29c35159922bc6cf9a11532627c3c244</guid></item><item><title>All the latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/all-the-latest-financial-news/105776480</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6f073c7f7020949078deb2eb0c7a85c</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste students protest government plan to buy new cars for parliamentarians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-15/timor-leste-protesters-demand-repeal-of-plan-to-buy-cars-for-mps/105776898</link><description>About 1,000 students hit the streets of the capital to rally against the plan, before police clashed with some protesters who reportedly threw rocks and damaged properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ce414e161409b0fcdd72ce826062fbc</guid></item><item><title>Former MMA fighter Conor McGregor drops out of Irish presidential race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/conor-mcgregor-drops-out-of-irish-presidential-race-/105776960</link><description>Critics say the former MMA fighter's pre-emptive dropout was to save face in a likely knockout at the hands of Dublin City Council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60f1b0734e35fba4e5506343df9a6d2a</guid></item><item><title>DNA at crime scene matches Charlie Kirk murder suspect, FBI says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/charlie-kirk-crime-scene-dna-matches-murder-suspect/105777360</link><description>Tyler Robinson, 22, was arrested last week over the death of conservative influencer Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7cf3e37a6ee22b7ae5bb477725734fa</guid></item><item><title>Fewer Aussies would need NDIS if government boosted mental health support, expert says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/psychosocial-disability-mental-health-ndis/105773308</link><description>As the Albanese government seeks to rein in the cost of the NDIS, a former Australian of the Year says money could be saved with this one shift.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5bca27cbb4ae9aab43ea5684315161e</guid></item><item><title>Use constitutional power to raise age of criminal responsibility nationwide, lawyers tell PM</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/pm-letter-raise-the-age/105748868</link><description>Forty years ago, the federal government used the constitution to halt construction of the Franklin Dam. Now lawyers want the Albanese government to do the same to keep kids out of jails.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7b875978506038b9b93d5a66cdfdece</guid></item><item><title>How Melbourne mosquitoes are being used to fight dengue fever and save lives in Laos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/melbourne-mosquitoes-fight-dengue-fever-laos-save-the-children/105773926</link><description>They are the deadliest animals in the world, and millions of them are being sent from Australia to the Laos capital Vientiane in a bid to save lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a24e6c7c32402fe5603b887c428f2552</guid></item><item><title>Pathological Demand Avoidance, a little-known profile of autism affecting kids and adults</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/pathological-demand-avoidance-awareness-of-autism-subtype/105772066</link><description>A surge of professional and personal interest in Pathological Demand Avoidance (PDA), an autism subtype — which in children can affect everything from cleaning teeth to attending school — has led to Australia's first-ever PDA conference, to be held in Perth in November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21dc9dcc25ab99ec13266f4d172f1692</guid></item><item><title>WWII-era bombs are killing and injuring thousands in PNG. Now trainees will learn how to remove them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/png-world-war-2-unexploded-ordnance-removal/105774308</link><description>Trainees in Papua New Guinea will learn to remove unexploded ordnance, as fading memories of World War II expose more people to the conflict's dangerous legacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8bf240cd5378047327fc404a9e7f897</guid></item><item><title>Will it happen? Crunch time imminent for Tasmania's proposed Macquarie Point stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/macquarie-point-stadium-planning-decision/105759040</link><description>It's not the be all and end all — but the impending delivery of the Tasmanian Planning Commission's final report is a major moment for the Macquarie Point stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b39f129ad1988ebe3b71971d4e7bb065</guid></item><item><title>Residents encouraged to attract native bees amid varroa mite spread</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/backyard-owners-encouraged-to-attract-native-bees-gardening/105767140</link><description>A pollination ecologist says it is important people play their part in preserving native bees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2de85a81cf81cdc683c925dfd059c30</guid></item><item><title>Fears parts of Queensland will have to 'retreat' amid predicted sea level rise and increased severe weather events</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/climate-report-national-climate-risk-assessment-queensland/105775976</link><description>The warning comes amid a national report finding up to 185,000 residential buildings in Queensland could be in "very high-risk areas" if climate change is not addressed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c13eb12a1db1234d6f66dae28d2620c</guid></item><item><title>The hidden impact of injuries costing AFL clubs millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/the-hidden-costs-of-injuries-costing-afl-clubs-millions/105777624</link><description>New research highlights the financial impact of injuries in the AFL, with one club losing $13 millions over six seasons, nearly 17 per cent of its total player salaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1df9a60d5e14380c28dd088a5cbf203a</guid></item><item><title>Rex Airlines apologises after wheelchair-using passenger stranded for six hours at Perth Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/rex-passenger-issues-albany-perth-wheelchair-user-/105774708</link><description>Albany woman Debby Butler says she had to ask strangers to help her to the bathroom after Rex delayed her flight home from Perth Airport and left her without a wheelchair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbfe858ddf70fc0694fbe80e02bdc22a</guid></item><item><title>Cathy Freeman and Ian Thorpe among Stadium Australia's first hall of fame inductees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/cathy-freeman-ian-thorpe-stadium-australia-hall-of-fame/105777908</link><description>The first golden group of inductees were honoured at an event that threw back to the Sydney 2000 games with Nikki Webster reproducing her iconic opening ceremony performance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdef62442b745f1023ee6848ed55f9e3</guid></item><item><title>Nikki Webster sings with her children for 25th anniversary of Sydney Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nikki-webster-sings-with-her-children-for-25th/105778014</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c83bf0274f16a9fa314e120145c3d8f</guid></item><item><title>Shire of Coolgardie awaits decision on future after giving evidence to minister</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/shire-of-coolgardie-show-cause-notice-response/105774072</link><description>The embattled Shire of Coolgardie waits to hear whether it will be suspended ahead of local government elections over concerns about financial and managerial mismanagement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a60af1587b72855d0965e133f66c3a65</guid></item><item><title>Lisa Reihana's exhibition, Voyager, recasts history through an Indigenous lens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/lisa-reihana-ngununggula-exhibition-voyager-indigenous-maori/105760474</link><description>The internationally renowned Maori artist's technically complex, visually mesmerising exhibition spans nearly a decade of artwork.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ed46a76298102094bcf604b8536fb9b</guid></item><item><title>Family comes first for Queensland newsreader Rob Brough after months off air</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/newsreader-rob-broughs-family-battle/105775464</link><description>The long-time nightly newsreader says it was an "instant choice" to leave work as his daughter faced a battle with cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23d10f83e00ccce3717d0f0a569d4a1c</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Olympics inflatable art reappears after 25 years in rural NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/sydney-olympics-reg-mombassa-inflatable-art-reappears-in-nsw/105735020</link><description>A Coonabarabran artist made a lucky find at an online auction two years ago when she recognised a Reg Mombassa art piece from the Sydney Olympics mixed in with advertising devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f4eacf145efc7f64bf56ffdaca13099</guid></item><item><title>Former Bankstown nurse who appeared in video with Israeli content creator has one charge dropped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/bankstown-nurse-in-video-israeli-content-creator-charge-dropped/105778390</link><description>Sarah Abu Lebdeh appeared in a video chat with an Israeli content creator that allegedly included threats to Israeli patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ac6ca3277f66dd115c844ff1b073096</guid></item><item><title>Victoria to push for national machete ban as amnesty sees hundreds of weapons surrendered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victoria-machete-weapon-amnesty-push-for-national-ban/105778266</link><description>The state's police minister vows to urge other states and territories to ban the weapons after more than 1,300 machetes and dangerous knives were surrendered at disposal bins during the first two weeks of his government's machete amnesty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c799d399d5ef8249c46906599105cfd</guid></item><item><title>Craig McLachlan withdraws from Cluedo stage show following backlash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/craig-mclachlan-withdraws-cluedo-the-play/105779280</link><description>Less than a week ago, Craig McLachlan was announced to play Colonel Mustard in the forthcoming national tour, making his return to the theatre after The Rocky Horror Show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2abe05c441b509ea22995eb926f87711</guid></item><item><title>Planning commission rejects bid to turn Redbank Power Station into bioenergy hub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/planning-commission-rejects-redbank-power-station-biofuel-plan/105777592</link><description>The Independent Planning Commission of NSW knocks back plans to restart Redbank Power Station in the Hunter Valley, fuelling it with biomass instead of coal tailings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">149bdcd14f72ed4787e50322861090cb</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds announce netball squads for Test series against New Zealand, South Africa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/australia-diamonds-announce-test-netball-squads-new-zealand-sa/105779230</link><description>Goal-shooter Lucy Austin is a shock selection in the Australian netball squad to face South Africa, winning a place after initially being included as an "invitee" to their training camp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f84722b6abee542504171a8343b1b82</guid></item><item><title>Central Queensland included in fire ant biosecurity zones</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/fire-ant-biosecurity-zones-introduced-in-central-queensland/105777728</link><description>New restrictions in place on moving materials into five central Queensland sites to reduce the spread of the invasive species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f62a27c6d9e79b642f55fa3dab985fb8</guid></item><item><title>Where and how to watch the 2025 Primetime Emmy award-winning shows in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/where-and-how-to-watch-the-emmy-award-winning-shows/105778142</link><description>From The Studio to The Pitt, here's how to stream the biggest winners of the 2025 Primetime Emmy Awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">243532cd9f64922ef9206ce0ccd4940d</guid></item><item><title>Perth childcare worker Robert David Reti faces court for allegedly indecently touching two girls at separate centres</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/perth-childcare-worker-robert-reti-accused-of-indecent-acts/105778920</link><description>A male childcare worker indecently touched two young girls in his care at separate childcare centres in Perth, a court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8773ffc337006c01be69dfa51723999</guid></item><item><title>Victoria delays Gippsland offshore wind auction, stalling developers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victoria-offshore-wind-auction-delay/105778708</link><description>The Victorian government pushes back its timeline for new offshore wind farms in the state's east in a blow to developers looking to move their projects to the next stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80c982b89a58ea8f9bc5c06f098af297</guid></item><item><title>Does washing your fruit and veggies remove chemicals?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/best-way-to-wash-fresh-produce-fruits-veggies-remove-chemcials-/105773664</link><description>This is what experts have to say about washing fruit and veggies, with removing chemicals and reducing the amount we consume in mind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57b4d4864180c3c11eed8be0eca03f20</guid></item><item><title>Breastfeeding Gold Coast mum says she was asked to leave Virgin Australia lounge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/virgin-australia-apologises-mother-pumping-breast-milk/105779738</link><description>Mother-of-two Elise Turner says she was asked to leave the Virgin Australia business lounge after refusing to go to a bathroom to pump breast milk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a5d01ae6ec3bc3224e376127e761ff5</guid></item><item><title>How Isabelle Kelly shook off getting her 'teeth pushed back' to return for Roosters' NRLW finals charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/isabelle-kelly-injury-jaw-teeth-roosters-nrlw-finals/105780582</link><description>Isabelle Kelly was meant to rest up for a few weeks after suffering an oral fracture that nearly cost her several teeth but the Roosters skipper missed just one match and has now returned to lead the club's premiership charge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">062a7201f7cd32cadeb54c8069a61337</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of pigs die as Andgar Proprietors piggery catches fire with two sheds burning for over 12 hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/andgar-piggery-fire-kills-200-animials-sa/105780636</link><description>The Department of Primary Industries and Regions says about 200 animals died in the blaze while another 45 pigs were euthanised by the department and RSPCA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8d637dff0fa3ce0bdf9aee2457db201</guid></item><item><title>Israeli military launches ground offensive to occupy Gaza City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/idf-launches-military-offensive-to-occupy-gaza/105777948</link><description>The Israel Defense Forces says its expanded operation in Gaza City "to destroy Hamas's military infrastructure" has begun, with residents warned to move south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80bfd937165cc59a068b4d0ad85e2045</guid></item><item><title>Queensland police release vision of pair accused of violent carjacking on Sunshine Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/qld-armed-carjacking-sunshine-coast-cctv-vision-released/105780504</link><description>Police allege the pair assaulted three people and attempted to steal multiple vehicles while armed early on Sunday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">227cbcd18812b3783432cb3061566399</guid></item><item><title>Israel is committing genocide in Gaza, major United Nations report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/israel-committing-genocide-in-gaza-un-report-says/105780230</link><description>Israel has committed and is continuing to commit genocide in Gaza, according to the "most authoritative assessment" to date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e547fcd275b42fb12bbaa7d9028fd7aa</guid></item><item><title>James O'Connor still hopeful of playing Bledisloe Cup for Wallabies against All Blacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/james-oconnor-still-hopeful-of-playing-bledisloe-cup/105780738</link><description>James O'Connor has flown to England with his Test future still up in the air, but the Wallabies playmaker has not given up on playing in his first Bledisloe Cup match in five years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fe6060cfa537dad8e49fa78e8c41f63</guid></item><item><title>Simon Lviev, the Tinder Swindler on Netflix, arrested after allegedly scamming victims out of $15 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/the-tinder-swindler-simon-lviev-arrested-in-georgia/105780320</link><description>Simon Lviev, 34, rose to notoriety after a pattern of romance fraud and financial crimes, with victims scammed out of an estimated $15 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">408e01733332e7bcef8aa275d501d586</guid></item><item><title>Bateau Bay woman thought to have died in fire may have been murdered, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/police-say-bateau-bay-woman-was-murdered-before-unit-fire/105779266</link><description>Police search for clothing connected to the death of Diane Harkess, who they now believe was murdered before her Bateau Bay unit went up in flames last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1aeeeaa342501c06160dcd087bc14d1</guid></item><item><title>Approval of $453 million battery project angers Kiewa Valley residents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/victorian-premier-approves-kiewa-valley-battery-project/105779392</link><description>The state government approves the development of a $453 million energy storage system by a Chinese company in the state's north-east, angering nearby residents who say their concerns have been ignored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0714747da477ffd0c9e429861e28643d</guid></item><item><title>NRL finals week two team lists: Canterbury Bulldogs pick new halves combination</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nrl-finals-week-two-team-lists-bulldogs-panthers-raiders-sharks/105781098</link><description>Winger Jacob Kiraz has revealed he is happy to keep playing with painkilling injections as a patched-up Canterbury turn to a barely tested halves combination of Lachlan Galvin and Toby Sexton to save their NRL season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e00963cd95ccbc1a7f4dac1f88d12452</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105781402</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e2b5a3b30f5fdf1b8c8739f00047ca8</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull wins 1,500m bronze, Peter Bol crashes out at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-jess-hull/105778240</link><description>Jess Hull claims bronze in the women's 1,500m at the World Athletics Championships, after Peter Bol was eliminated from the 800m in the heats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7250f2b7b3eaaed7b8f51092ef3fc818</guid></item><item><title>Nepal's protests estimated to have caused hundreds of millions of dollars in damage as families farewell those killed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-16/nepal-gen-z-protests-cause-millions-of-dollars-in-damage/105781578</link><description>As clean-up efforts continue and an interim government finds its feet, families have said farewell to loved ones killed in last week's violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1064109a46dbf7b37962228d9f172092</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste protesters vow to continue rallying until plan to buy MPs 65 cars is overturned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/timor-leste-protests-over-mp-car-plan-grow/105781726</link><description>The protests nearly doubled in size on Tuesday as people continued to vent their frustrations at a plan to buy MPs 65 new SUVs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">feeb6a6ab4a2322ebf2709358b8c2353</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk shooting suspect Tyler Robinson charged with murder as prosecutors seek death penalty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/alleged-charlie-kirk-shooter-tyler-robinson-charged/105781872</link><description>Utah prosecutors say they will seek the death penalty for the 22-year-old alleged shooter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87bd66a147b9d8ff76e79fdd79e8ff76</guid></item><item><title>Botox, fillers among the cosmetic injectables targeted in medical regulator's new rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/cosmetic-injectables-rules-botox-fillers/105778596</link><description>New rules have come into place aimed at better protecting patients from unsafe cosmetic procedures. Here's what it mean for your next appointment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f034dc98c168b046f196741357b091bf</guid></item><item><title>Unpaid mandatory work experience a 'significant barrier' for some NSW law students</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/plt-unpaid-placements-nsw-law-students-a-financial-difficulty/105774700</link><description>During her unpaid placement at a not-for-profit community legal centre in Sydney, Dani struggled to make ends meet. She is among some law students whose entry into the profession is fraught with financial difficulty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a77e2484c201c3b6a1ff99c5e168d5c6</guid></item><item><title>Fingal Post Office saved from closure after local farmers confirmed as new operators</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/fingal-post-office-in-tasmania-saved-by-local-pig-farmers/105779962</link><description>A rural Tasmanian community has fought to keep its post office open, fearing losing the important service could lead to their hometown disappearing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08e347abc9bfa22abeb9447ad06020ab</guid></item><item><title>Israeli military vision appears to show vehicle movement through Gaza City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/israeli-military-vision-appears-to-show-vehicle-movement/105782006</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88f2226649850cdf70cba484717babdc</guid></item><item><title>Israeli military vehicles among damaged buildings near Gaza City.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/israeli-military-vehicles-among-damaged-buildings-near-gaza-city/105782022</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdb604848ca36e54000e0b2b24d4f064</guid></item><item><title>For the Adelaide Crows, the AFL season was a matter of 'what could have been'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/adelaide-crows-reflect-on-afl-finals-exit-after-minor-premiers/105778196</link><description>After an eight-year AFL finals drought, the Adelaide Crows finished this year's home-and-away season as minor premiers — but the club's hopes were dashed by consecutive defeats that left the players and their fans wondering about what might have been.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b79b17dec6a9f9b23b4349c7283d3818</guid></item><item><title>Griffith locals push for new health district to meet needs of their community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/griffith-locals-push-for-new-health-district/105729862</link><description>Residents and medical professionals in south-western NSW are pushing to establish a new local health district in Griffith, arguing current services are not good enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">811a2f3a903585b4dace7ad758f6a3f0</guid></item><item><title>ABC reporter reflects on heated exchange with Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/abc-reporter-reflects-on-heated-exchange-with-trump/105782066</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d66c9b484df7f246f7468910b081bdfa</guid></item><item><title>New doco Signorinella: Little Miss celebrates the Italian women who shaped modern Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/signorinella-little-miss-documentary-italian-film-festival/105774428</link><description>Signorinella: Little Miss, the new documentary from the filmmakers behind Lygon St — Si Parla Italiano, celebrates the tenacity of Italian Australian women in business and beyond.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc3ea23b27aab754a73fa0319a25aee</guid></item><item><title>Sam Konstas scores Australia A century in four-day game in India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sam-konstas-scores-australia-a-century-against-india-a/105782060</link><description>Sam Konstas's push for an Ashes spot continues as he clatters a century in an extended session for Australia A in Lucknow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cec1e71dd86b61ad4d12f75e6292662</guid></item><item><title>Animal advocates want WA to 'get on board' with phasing out greyhound racing amid welfare concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/wa-greyhound-racing-parliamentary-inquiry/105781496</link><description>Animal advocates call on the WA government to follow the lead of other jurisdictions and phase out greyhound racing, as a state parliamentary inquiry examines the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d151b0111cbdf98135b0a72304ccd15</guid></item><item><title>South Australia's feral deer culling program targets eradication amid plague warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sa-deer-eradication-program-aerial-culling-reduces-population/105763068</link><description>South Australia has ramped up its feral deer aerial culling program as drought-affected farmers battle the pest on their properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62ba923682e9f4c1c2fea7cd969ab7fd</guid></item><item><title>PNG Foreign Minister questioned whether defence pact would be signed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/png-foreign-minister-questioned-whether-defence-/105782438</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">287b83c9f45bc9d9ed1ca75023d18245</guid></item><item><title>UK protesters arrested for beaming Epstein video on Windsor castle before Donald Trump's visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/protesters-beam-epstein-video-as-trump-visits-uk/105782420</link><description>The shots included Donald Trump's mugshot, portraits of Epstein, newspaper headlines, and footage of the two men dancing together.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fbdd2e588435c6e7184adb4bba39607</guid></item><item><title>Prosecutors to seek death penalty for Charlie Kirk shooting suspect Tyler Robinson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/prosecutors-to-seek-death-penalty-for-charlie-kirk/105782284</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69d841a4df7070902ccfd30a402b2bb2</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk murder suspect appears in court by video from jail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/charlie-kirk-murder-suspect-appears-in-court-by-video-from-jail/105782372</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">358bbfc5a2557ea8a273c5a8fa4648ca</guid></item><item><title>NT Police arrests man over alleged domestic violence-related death of female partner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/nt-police-arrest-man-over-death-of-female-partner-in-palmerston/105782526</link><description>A man has been arrested over the alleged domestic violence-related death of his female partner overnight, after she was found unresponsive in the front yard of a Palmerston home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7c47df92c73582fdc3ec37e313630f3</guid></item><item><title>Only social media companies know for sure how the teen ban will work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/social-media-ban-law-rules-analysis/105780188</link><description>The social media saga has produced its fair share of intrigue. But the latest big reveal on how the ban will work has left us with just another cliffhanger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81ea0e9097c27edcfe3bce09fd63b970</guid></item><item><title>Childcare worker charged with assaulting young boy near Bathurst</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/childcare-worker-charged-with-assault-near-bathurst/105782480</link><description>The female childcare worker has been accused of forcing the four-year-old boy onto a bed resulting in a 2-centimetre cut on the child's head.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a47d51a9b9641ba0db84e2c2c0c86d42</guid></item><item><title>Brett Daniel Taylor accused of unlawfully engaging in legal practice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/man-accused-assisting-suicides-allegedly-fake-lawyer/105778616</link><description>Brett Daniel Taylor is accused of trafficking veterinary drugs to Queenslanders for assisted dying. The ABC can reveal he is separately being prosecuted for engaging in legal practice when not entitled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5cadd676325107ded6a885ef5e0c143</guid></item><item><title>Khapra beetle, a threat to grains industry, discovered in imported nappy pants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/khapra-beetle-found-in-imported-nappy-pants-threatens-grains/105782306</link><description>Authorities are investigating how khapra beetle, the number-one-priority pest for the grains industry, entered Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c65ef8036bcd15cd64dcb1342bb737aa</guid></item><item><title>The campaign video proved a success.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/fingal-post-office-campaign/105783222</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc2728e5c33e9526ea0a593442e0be6c</guid></item><item><title>Images of Trump and Epstein projected onto Windsor Castle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/images-of-trump-and-epstein-projected-onto-windsor/105782518</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84048044d449fa3a73d813b2b5c53078</guid></item><item><title>Australian Army's 3rd Brigade starts heavy armoured training with a bang</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/army-3rd-brigade-townsville-new-weapons-training/105778442</link><description>The arrival of new army capabilities shook homes throughout a north Queensland city this month. Now residents can see what they felt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4969dc2bbce79a3bd864b445e0ffcafd</guid></item><item><title>Robert Redford's most notable movies with Jane Fonda, Barbra Streisand and Paul Newman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/robert-redford-movies-jane-fonda-barbra-streisand-paul-newman/105782412</link><description>The Hollywood icon leaves a legacy of classic films with a career that stretched over decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a65466a8bed654c5a2f46954d2cfb614</guid></item><item><title>Police fear missing Perth man Jayden Selfe dead as Attadale unit scoured for clues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/police-searching-perth-unit-fear-missing-man-jayden-selfe-dead/105778986</link><description>WA Police's homicide squad takes over a major investigation into the whereabouts of a missing Perth man, which has seen officers spend almost a week searching a riverside property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b25dd948fcb50a93e317eca09fb2724</guid></item><item><title>Major reforms for NSW planning system aim to curb 'maze' of current process</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/nsw-development-changes-planning-system-overhaul/105783324</link><description>The proposed centrepiece is a "single front door" authority to provide advice on development applications on behalf of all government agencies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">852e7381bb09830b61e462fd16c8e8b1</guid></item><item><title>SA parliamentary inquiry recommends short-stay accommodation registration scheme and fees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/sa-short-stay-accommodation-recommendations/105782300</link><description>A South Australian parliamentary inquiry has recommended the introduction of a registration scheme to track short-stay accommodation after finding the sector has played a role in the rental affordability crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">108f410572a6e48271c62635ee767395</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Barnes, Dave Faulkner among music industry voices in open letter urging ANU to keep School of Music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/jimmy-barnes-against-anu-school-of-music-cuts/105784002</link><description>Jimmy Barnes is among more than 40 music voices supporting an open letter to the embattled Australian National University (ANU) calling for the School of Music to be saved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c2e11e10aa99b2ef294abc946d1feaa</guid></item><item><title>Man admits he claimed to be Charlie Kirk gunman so real suspect could flee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/man-admits-he-falsely-claimed-to-be-charlie-kirk-gunman/105783512</link><description>US police have charged a 71-year-old man they say has admitted to yelling out that he shot conservative activist Charlie Kirk in order to "allow the actual suspect to flee".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de1fbb93cdf9eb43245231ba9e88c8c4</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's only large-scale private mental health clinic, the Hobart Clinic, to close inpatient site by end of October</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/tasmanian-mental-health-inpatient-site-hobart-clinic-to-close/105783678</link><description>The Hobart Clinic, which employs 100 people and has provided private mental health services for Tasmanians for 40 years, will close its inpatient site by the end of October, citing financial woes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd61d37d4e64d804e365a3ede3165983</guid></item><item><title>Hawks AFL coach Sam Mitchell reacts to speculation over Zach Merrett meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-17/afl-sam-mitchell-zach-merrett-hawthorn-hawks-essendon-bombers/105784298</link><description>As his young Hawks squad prepare for their preliminary final against the Cats, Sam Mitchell opens up about the club's pursuit of Bombers captain Zach Merrett.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">862f69660065f08d0572520ae7565aab</guid></item></channel></rss>