<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 07:44:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How to maintain Antarctica's ice runway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/wilkins-aerodrome-antarctic-runway/106376398</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f7c0416ce1043220b7ff29f053d161a</guid></item><item><title>Denmark and Greenland reject Trump's offer to send naval hospital ship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/denmark-greenland-reject-trump-offer-naval-hospital-ship/106376252</link><description>Denmark and its territory Greenland reject Donald Trump's offer to send a naval hospital ship to the Arctic island coveted by the US leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da6be898edb441a8825b6acb38f78a19</guid></item><item><title>Neighbouring farmers say overwhelming fire risk from Lake Magenta Nature Reserve in WA's south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/farmers-raise-concerns-over-lake-magenta-nature-reserve-fire/106370154</link><description>WA farmer Doug Giles has warned that parts of Lake Magenta Nature Reserve haven't been burned in 25 years, raising fears of a dangerous fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2867bfbdd2ae8c4f834614c7020a00e2</guid></item><item><title>MAGA figure tells Australian conservatives Angela Merkel did more damage to Germany's fabric than Nazis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/advance-lobby-group-conference-centre-right-mass-immigration/106371720</link><description>Benjamin Harnwell, the "international editor" of Steve Bannon's War Room podcast, says centre-right politicians have "betrayed" the West by supporting "mass immigration".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c036dfffbc94d642235a37ef1b6e3399</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Klingberg avoids jail over crash that killed his employee in rollover near Hamley Bridge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/wayne-klingberg-sentenced-for-killing-employee-in-rollover/106373394</link><description>A man has been spared jail time after his "substandard" driving resulted in a crash that caused the death of his passenger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d7bc8a2fcdc95df3c711a87a46252bb</guid></item><item><title>What experts want you to know about endometriosis, diagnosis and surgery as treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/endometriosis-surgery-treatment-explained-four-corners/106375904</link><description>Allegations about endometriosis surgery have alarmed experts and distressed women living with the condition. Here's what to know about the chronic disease that affects about one in seven Australian women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbaf9bd04ca59cd113da66ade8586963</guid></item><item><title>More details emerge after man shot dead by Secret Service at Mar-a-Lago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/mar-a-lago-trump-secret-service-shooting/106375912</link><description>Austin Tucker Martin was seen at the Mar-a-Lago resort's north gate at about 1:30am on Sunday, local time. He has been described as being from a family of "big Trump supporters".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1045783573ad7d46acaca41e63ff72fb</guid></item><item><title>Two men charged after man stabbed during confrontation in Kambalda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/two-men-charged-stabbing-kambalda-wa-goldfields/106376558</link><description>Two men are charged and another is flown to Perth with life-threatening stab wounds, after a weekend altercation in Kambalda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a765daef73dcbfd6cf5eecd71ab51d08</guid></item><item><title>Darcy Moore downplays Collingwood's injury woes, Patrick Dangerfield optimistic on Jeremy Cameron's health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/afl-darcy-moore-patrick-dangerfield-downplay-pies-cats-injuries/106376972</link><description>Several of Collingwood's defensive stalwarts have suffered interrupted preseasons, but skipper Darcy Moore isn't concerned just yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bf987fc7214ac5f9d00e1721ab4492b</guid></item><item><title>SA pastoralists receive more than 60mm of rain in 24 hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/pastoralists-rain-drought-destocking-south-australia/106375318</link><description>South Australian pastoralists are preparing to buy livestock after the weekend's downpours brought more than 60 millimetres to some areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a993832dd084d2ff3fd4c53c14abfc0b</guid></item><item><title>Cyber attack takes major chicken processor Hazeldenes offline leaving businesses without meat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/cyber-attack-takes-major-chicken-processor-hazeldenes-offline/106376184</link><description>A cyber attack at Hazeldenes chicken processing plant in central Victoria has stalled production and left butchers and pubs across the state without chicken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad7275d3ac33e822d86835f8e8ca6b93</guid></item><item><title>Death of Kelly T'Hart inspires shake up of WA driving laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/wa-new-driving-bans-for-people-charged-with-driving-offences/106376430</link><description>Tougher WA driving laws are expected to be introduced to parliament after a drunk driver, who was charged with killing a 32-year-old, was allowed to drive just two months after the incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">865da2fafb865e027a4d14fd8445adfa</guid></item><item><title>Former UK PM Gordon Brown urges police to investigate if Andrew used RAF bases to meet Epstein</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/brown-urges-andrew-police-probe-over-epstein-raf-bases/106375734</link><description>Former British prime minister Gordon Brown urges British police to investigate whether Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor used taxpayer-funded jets and Royal Air Force bases to meet with convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b76c410513462e9b98bba684536256cd</guid></item><item><title>Horse endoscopy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/horse-endoscopy/106363588</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5a63fc0b398c1847ca2bfa97d2d4097</guid></item><item><title>These four salads are tasty and substantial meals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/these-four-salads-are-tasty-and-substantial-meals/106363054</link><description>If you’re after a healthy and summery dinner, these salads are a meal in a bowl and will tempt even the salad avoiders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b43ee09ed451f0e7f6420ed3472fbdff</guid></item><item><title>Richmond forward Mykelti Lefau suspended for two matches over drink driving charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/afl-mykelti-lefau-suspended-two-matches-drink-driving-charge/106377438</link><description>Mykelti Lefau is banned for two matches after a drink driving charge that will see him miss a pre-season clash as well as round one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c4ea2f9071e3790d91763c3026a1489</guid></item><item><title>Police bodycam footage captures 'retributive' force used on St Edmund's College hit-and-run driver</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/act-tayler-hazell-police-bodycam-footage/106375728</link><description>Body-camera footage released by the ACT Supreme Court shows tactical police officers using force on a handcuffed hit-and-run driver outside St Edmund's College.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bc70d8008462d11e48f5dbd54482057</guid></item><item><title>Bodycam footage shows tactical police officers using force on a handcuffed hit-and-run driver</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/body-camera-tactical-police-force-hit-and-run-driver/106377912</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">840067a62466a8723d5a50ce3878a332</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106377930</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cd201e4cab12a1e8d9109dec7af0e4f</guid></item><item><title>Toddler found unresponsive at Sydney day care may have died from a bacterial infection, inquest hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/nsw-arianna-maragol-coronial-inquest-family-speaks-bacterial/106377282</link><description>A baby who died after being found unresponsive at a Sydney day care may have had a bacterial infection, an inquest has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfdde31cd10ef6f3a585059f10bac008</guid></item><item><title>SA Police postpone renewed search for missing Andamooka woman Trisha Graf</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/sa-police-scour-mine-shafts-search-for-missing-trisha-graf/106377578</link><description>Heavy rain has forced police to postpone a search for missing mother Trisha Graf in mine shafts near the outback South Australian town of Andamooka.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3ebd687d259d0790dfd4051686dccaa</guid></item><item><title>Arvind Ajay Singh extradited from Fiji to Sunshine Coast on rape charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/arvind-ajay-singh-returns-to-sunshine-coast-faces-rape-charge/106375712</link><description>A Fijian national charged over the alleged rape of a child four years ago returns to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3bfb5887669e3fe34e8697fcf80e78e</guid></item><item><title>Tabatha Badger angling to replace outgoing Greens senator Peter Whish-Wilson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/tabatha-badger-senate-tilt-to-replace-peter-whish-wilson/106377994</link><description>Tasmanian Greens MP Tabatha Badger is among the names vying to replace outgoing federal senator Peter Whish-Wilson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70b94d5a4e222251fa22d9491cae6035</guid></item><item><title>The Lion King musical makes its return to Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/the-lion-king-musical-makes-its-return-to-sydney/106378128</link><description>The Lion King musical makes its return to Sydney in April with the cast and crew opening its doors to rehearsals for a sneak peak.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cd895f5c24c035246533ab2c99be933</guid></item><item><title>SA Premier Peter Malinauskas speaks to 7.30</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/sa-premier-peter-malinauskas-speaks-to-7-30/106377780</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7da4917626b5efef9bdc07292edad7e</guid></item><item><title>Former youth worker Geoffrey Guest pleads not guilty to historical child sex abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/former-youth-worker-pleads-not-guilty-historical-abuse-charges/106376946</link><description>Geoffrey John Guest is standing trial in Cairns after being charged with the abuse of a child in the 1970s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be44341c902da3949f56ff003343bcbf</guid></item><item><title>Australia first Commonwealth country to back removing Mountbatten-Windsor from line of succession</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-23/australia-backs-removal-of-andrew-line-of-succession/106377738</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese tells his British counterpart, Sir Keir Starmer, that Australia would support removing Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor from the royal line of succession. New Zealand has also backed the move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">baf8c107d59d46617a9378b0644d0ffb</guid></item><item><title>Met Gala dress code announced as 'Fashion is Art' by New York's Museum of Metropolitan Art</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/met-gala-theme-announced-as-fashion-is-art/106378808</link><description>The dress code for this year's Met Gala will be "Fashion is Art", the Metropolitan Museum of Art has announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1f7e332dacb9a78ac86ae62335f8472</guid></item><item><title>Simon Burke on how 19 years of Play School fed into The Elocution of Benjamin Franklin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/simon-burke-the-elocution-of-benjamin-franklin-play-school/106295868</link><description>After five years starring in major musicals, Simon Burke returns to a much smaller stage in a one-man play, on its 50-year anniversary: The Elocution of Benjamin Franklin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4458da0549bbbebe99b63d9648eb25af</guid></item><item><title>What is the difference between a homebirth and a freebirth?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/the-difference-between-a-homebirth-and-a-freebirth/106348232</link><description>Experts say creating awareness around how homebirthing and freebirthing differ is important in helping women make informed and safe decisions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a67b6ee22205e5375e88a384d9be9f5c</guid></item><item><title>Power supply for Macquarie Point stadium not yet costed or planned as key deadlines approach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/macquarie-point-stadium-power-options-uncosted/106377676</link><description>Major upgrades to Hobart's power grid to supply the Macquarie Point stadium are yet to be finalised or costed, with the final estimate for the precinct's energy demand increasing by almost 50 per cent in a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0619a4ec6a598c4119df3c19a29dfbd9</guid></item><item><title>Trump's dispute with Denmark over Greenland 'far from over', warns intelligence expert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/us-denmark-feud-over-greenland-far-from-over-warns-analyst/106359334</link><description>A former chief analyst with the Danish Defence Intelligence Service warns diplomatic efforts to settle the Greenland dispute will fail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">caf70a88cade8101f8fcb73ba80cc069</guid></item><item><title>Could Canada and Australia form a critical minerals supergroup?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/critical-minerals-future-australia-canada-us-china/106368382</link><description>Canberra's decision to sign a bilateral agreement with Canada to join forces on everything to do with critical minerals could prove to be a forerunner of things to come.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16de728cafe7b3d7ac16ae0851dde9b8</guid></item><item><title>Australian exporters on notice as Trump tariff policy thrown into uncertainty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/australian-exporters-on-notice-as-trump-tariffs-in-chaos/106375716</link><description>Business representatives have warned all Australian exporters they will need to monitor US trade policy carefully over coming weeks and months, as one firm owner estimates tariffs have cost him $1 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0fbfe0f1b5a1ef08dac628ed21a5b5d</guid></item><item><title>Regulator 'dropped the ball' by dismissing complaints about gynaecologist's practices, expert says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/endometriosis-surgeon-simon-gordon-ahpra-complaints-four-corners/106376338</link><description>Australia's medical regulator, AHPRA, faces criticism for failing to act on complaints from patients about surgeries by Melbourne gynaecologist Simon Gordon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37e9c9955acd6273241e064c5b886efb</guid></item><item><title>Urgent care clinics ease emergency department demand but wait times unchanged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/urgent-care-clinics-not-improving-hospital-wait-times/106377942</link><description>An independent review finds Labor's urgent care clinics face workforce shortages and problems with after-hours services, with no evidence hospital waiting times have improved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75eaec4d09e07adaa39fe8f1d3901729</guid></item><item><title>Peter Mandelson arrested at residence in London</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/peter-mandelson-arrested-at-residence-in-london/106379014</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1be2bc4ac2ee1c4096077544560aebb3</guid></item><item><title>Matildas coach Joe Montemurro speaks to ABC Sport's Amanda Shalala.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/womens-asian-cup-2026-matildas-coach-joe-montemurro-interview/106372378</link><description>Sport news, live scores, features, analysis and photos from the world of sport. Comprehensive coverage of AFL, cricket, football, rugby league and rugby union. Audio interviews. News stories and highlights in video. Sports news bulletin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffdd65572a90557a39c7eced42c2e030</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: Matildas coach Joe Montemurro says 'we want to be a dominant force in Asia'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/womens-asian-cup-matildas-coach-joe-montemurro-dominant-force/106372410</link><description>Matildas coach Joe Montemurro, who has had nine months in charge leading into the Women's Asian Cup starting this week, has bold ambitions for the tournament and the future of women's football.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">353674cf248b7dd8c344aab288d0ee1c</guid></item><item><title>Regional Victoria among the worst areas for meth use police say after Shepparton bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/shepparton-meth-bust/106378988</link><description>Police say methylamphetamine trafficking is "insidious" in regional Victoria, with almost one trafficker a week charged over the past year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c15262d03dacfd37831e0185811140b</guid></item><item><title>DV attacker photographed victim giving evidence, found guilty of contempt of court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/dv-attacker-found-guilty-of-contempt-of-court/106355262</link><description>A man standing trial for domestic violence charges took an image of the victim while she was giving evidence and recorded the prosecutor inside the court building, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea7ddb1679b1f9ccf535d4316d5e3bc0</guid></item><item><title>Solomon Islands denies China will run new police station in the heart of the capital Honiara</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/chinese-police-establish-temporary-post-solomon-islands/106376922</link><description>Authorities in Solomon Islands deny claims that Chinese police will run a new police post in Honiara's Chinatown district, but say Chinese police will instead "visit" the site.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa910e93601c07e2ab8d53a1e98a85f8</guid></item><item><title>Hope south-east Queensland koala population can recover but advocates remain wary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/qld-koala-recovery-redlands-coast/106310380</link><description>Urbanisation has decimated south east Queensland's koala population, but new analysis suggests the decline has slowed in some areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c368680b2f2c0b62737c0f0724110feb</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Cleary's ban overturned as father acts as counsel at NRL judiciary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/nrl-nathan-cleary-ban-overturned-ivan-cleary-judiciary-counsel/106379116</link><description>Ivan Cleary's legal prowess comes in handy as his son, Panthers star Nathan Cleary, sees his two-match suspension overturned at the NRL judiciary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">124f69f96041c4e00733fb309dc8d7cb</guid></item><item><title>Crimes against humanity hearings against former Philippine leader Rodrigo Duterte open in The Hague</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/rodrigo-duterte-hearings-open-at-international-criminal-court/106379020</link><description>An International Criminal Court prosecutor tells judges that former Philippines president Rodrigo Duterte personally instructed members of a death squad to kill suspected criminals and drug users.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2f5a4bd5434cb405720414cefc68fca</guid></item><item><title>Inspection reveals substandard housing for PALM scheme workers in Gippsland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/warragul-substandard-palm-housing/106331606</link><description>Migrant workers in Victoria's east were made to pay $190 a week to their employer for overcrowded, mouldy accommodation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">325b531c1d1e9a8e4a20fedfc3e837c1</guid></item><item><title>Nick Reiner pleads not guilty to murder of parents Rob and Michele Singer Reiner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/nick-reiner-pleads-not-guility-to-first-degree-murder/106379080</link><description>Nick Reiner has pleaded not guilty to two counts of first-degree murder in the fatal stabbing of his parents in December last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72c8efa2b22a2976ca629282d76fd3be</guid></item><item><title>Economist warns rural NSW shires are on the verge of financial ruin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/rural-nsw-councils-warn-of-financial-sustainability-crisis/106358104</link><description>Huge areas, spiralling costs and a small revenue base do not add up for a growing number of councils in NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f098cb9486b6e942d9b878225f901016</guid></item><item><title>William Barton on blending the ancient First Nations instrument, the yidaki, with classical music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/william-barton-yidaki-meet-classical-music-brodsky-quartet/106369492</link><description>Virtuoso William Barton, renowned for bringing together First Nations culture and European classical music, reflects on heritage and the lifelong pull of the yidaki.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18cd76c9661a9eaf25275f3a6f719215</guid></item><item><title>SA wildlife carers help animals hurt in Deep Creek fires as they emerge from refuges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/deep-creek-fire-wildlife-response-animals-south-australia/106334650</link><description>As the firefighters packed up and went home from the recent Deep Creek fires, other volunteers were just starting weeks of work finding injured wildlife in the charred landscape.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3dbf571a4cecf4cc8240f7815633a5d</guid></item><item><title>Carney plans Australia trip to tighten trade and defence ties after warning of world order 'rupture'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/mark-carney-seeks-stronger-defence-trade-ties-australia-visit/106379182</link><description>The Canadian government confirms details of Prime Minister Mark Carney's trip to Australia, where he hopes to deepen ties on trade, defence and critical minerals as his country looks to reduce reliance on the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b349508ea74849874271cf35fb0c90d</guid></item><item><title>Alcoa under investigation for alleged breaches of state mining agreement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/alcoa-under-investigation-alleged-breach-state-mining-agreement/106376898</link><description>Just days after being forced to pay $55 million for unlawfully clearing land in the world's only jarrah forest, it is revealed Alcoa is under investigation for alleged breaches of its agreement with the WA government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eedb4193560a4bf3688ea7232bdda222</guid></item><item><title>BAFTA and BBC apologise for racial slur during awards show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/bafta-bbc-apology-racial-slur-awards/106379194</link><description>Tourette syndrome advocate John Davidson, who shouted the slur, says it is not a reflection of his personal beliefs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a7fad65bac06602f873108e4ab20230</guid></item><item><title>Homeless mother refused social housing after Centrelink payments deemed too high</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/homeless-mother-denied-social-housing-queensland/106376802</link><description>Welfare payments are Rissa Blakeley's only source of income, but she and her kids have been left with no choice but to live in a park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98537414ca6a771d738c2f0e9535e226</guid></item><item><title>Shimron Hetmyer blasts West Indies to record T20 World Cup score in win over Zimbabwe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/cricket-t20-world-cup-shimron-hetmyer-creates-west-indies-record/106379260</link><description>Shimron Hetmyer takes advantage of a dropped chance to blast his way to 85 as the West Indies maintain their unbeaten record at this year's T20 World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30debec237ed46aaceb6c212f28eafee</guid></item><item><title>Volunteer firefighters wasting hours 'babysitting' pole-top fires waiting for Western Power crews</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/pole-top-fires-firefighter-concern-western-power/106358052</link><description>Volunteer firefighters in regional Western Australia say fatigued crews are frustrated over time spent monitoring pole-top fires before Western Power crews travel to the scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5678f237dd6bc39a06f510c82496e39</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberal Party indicates One Nation preference as Alex Antic meets with Cory Bernardi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/sa-liberals-may-preference-one-nation-over-labor-greens/106379200</link><description>The South Australian Liberal Party has indicated it may direct preferences to One Nation ahead of Labor and the Greens. It comes as prominent Liberal senator Alex Antic was spotted having drinks with One Nation's lead SA candidate Cory Bernardi, amid speculation over a possible defection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72c419cb0694688644a18c3c1afcf669</guid></item><item><title>Security screening at Burnie Airport could drive airlines away, airport boss warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/burnie-airport-security-screening-cost-regional-airports/106376586</link><description>Burnie Airport has been told it will need to introduce security screening, but the airport's director says the cost of doing so will make some services commercially unviable and threaten the airport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e096398ae89c37494a16cb56174f1b7f</guid></item><item><title>Victorian premier refers surgeon Simon Gordon allegations to police after Four Corners revelations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/simon-gordon-four-corners-allegations-premier-police-referral/106379430</link><description>Victorian Premier Jacinta Allan has referred allegations against gynaecologist Simon Gordon to police, but the government will not conduct its own investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbc42ddc66916a74d2eb01978ef31910</guid></item><item><title>Sunshine Coast's iconic venue Solbar to close after more than 20 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/sunshine-coast-solbar-closing-maroochydore/106379262</link><description>The Sunshine Coast's longest-running live music venue will close this weekend, after more than 20 years of hosting artists and performers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61ff7be6a3afe0bdc03cf355d504cfa6</guid></item><item><title>Bunbury backpacker hostels ordered to close after asbestos, safety warnings ignored</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/bunbury-backpackers-closed-after-asbestos-found/106377416</link><description>Two backpacker hostels in Western Australia's largest regional city have been ordered to shut due to serious health and safety concerns, including asbestos exposure risks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af5120aee3df7d826ba36674e3c73e11</guid></item><item><title>The 'first-night effect': Why it's hard to sleep when you're somewhere new</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/why-its-hard-to-sleep-when-you-are-somewhere-new/106377794</link><description>It's night-time and you're exhausted. But the hotel bed feels wrong. The mini fridge won't stop making that low, irritating hum. The power outlet lights feel brighter than the sun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31c70a83ae2e841ba9faf3f83b43af1f</guid></item><item><title>Farmers rally against 96 million litres per year Southern Downs water extraction and bottling facility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/farmers-rally-water-extraction-bottling-cherrabah-southern-downs/106358124</link><description>A developer has lodged an application with a rural Queensland council to build a water bottling, storage and export facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">696c203be2eb87f4287a5969556c6e3a</guid></item><item><title>More than 70 dead after Mexico's biggest drug lord 'El Mencho' killed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/people-dead-in-mexico-after-drug-leader-el-mencho-death/106379184</link><description>At least 73 people have died in the attempt to capture cartel leader Nemesio Oseguera Cervantes and in the aftermath of his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d6e8bdec46001b4377710d416e49c9c</guid></item><item><title>Police suspect human remains to be abducted Sydney man</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/human-remains-found-in-search-for-sydney-man-chris-baghsarian/106350124</link><description>Eighty-five-year-old Chris Baghsarian was mistakenly snatched from his North Ryde property about 5am on February 13.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb560b2fcf4c45dbcccfe29cfb5b416a</guid></item><item><title>Opposition leader to boycott swearing-in of controversial new NT administrator David Connolly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/new-nt-administrator-david-connolly-swearing-in-boycott/106376176</link><description>Northern Territory Opposition Leader Selena Uibo says she will boycott the swearing-in of incoming administrator David Connolly, whose appointment has been embroiled in controversy due to a series of past social media posts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e17c784876f317725a0f6fdc31f88d6f</guid></item><item><title>Sam Walsh's eight-year contract extension the biggest deal in Carlton's history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/afl-sam-walsh-record-carlton-contract-extension/106379858</link><description>Carlton locks down Sam Walsh to a massive eight-year contract extension as he turns down the lure of free agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3b2ac1e0ee2244745260bab311e3d2a</guid></item><item><title>Is couples counselling right for me and will the therapist take sides? An expert explains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/is-couples-counselling-right-for-me/106377918</link><description>Many people seek out couples counselling when going through a rough patch, or wondering how to improve their relationship. So, how do you decide if it's right for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4be6f26e0de6326cf36d9c3115b73ad1</guid></item><item><title>Grace Tame abuser Nicolaas Bester unfit to stand trial over alleged 'menacing' social media posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/grace-tame-abuser-nicolaas-bester-unfit-to-stand-trial/105640758</link><description>Nicolaas Ockert Bester has been deemed unfit to stand trial in the Hobart Magistrates Court over three counts of using a carriage service to menace, harass or cause offence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beada0a8927ee572636c12af002e6bba</guid></item><item><title>Trump Tower developer Altus Property Group's David Young has twice gone bankrupt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/trump-tower-developer-went-bankrupt-twice/106379446</link><description>A search by the ABC of federal insolvency records reveals the developer has had personal financial scrapes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1cf983d1575d549dda1cde43880b004</guid></item><item><title>Australia confirms first full men's tour of South Africa since 2018 ball-tampering scandal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/cricket-australia-south-africa-2026-mens-tour-fixtures-confirmed/106380536</link><description>Steve Smith will be one of five Australian players from the infamous 2018 tour to return to South Africa later this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83339d68b9905f2e5b6c4db966984801</guid></item><item><title>For some families, the social media ban has made things harder. Here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/social-media-ban-choices-for-families/106334598</link><description>We spoke with three parents about how it has impacted their family and the different choices they are making around the ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9396f5068ed4179cc5d3622cc647caf3</guid></item><item><title>Kash Patel and US men's hockey team under fire after Donald Trump makes joke about women's team</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/trump-us-mens-hockey-team-under-fire-mocking-womens-team/106380212</link><description>Viral video of Trump's White House invitation to the US men's hockey team sparks backlash online after the president jokes he would be 'impeached' if he did not also include the gold-medal winning women's team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f9e2ca77739ded4fef9d2c039565d60</guid></item><item><title>TasWater continues to push for higher water bills, despite regulator knock back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/taswater-argues-its-case-for-higher-water-bills/106379690</link><description>TasWater has continued to press its case for a steep water bill hike, despite the economic regulator's decision to halve its proposed price earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef5aff82a0977148ce84dae0cae1f60d</guid></item><item><title>Farmers are sick of being called 'resilient' and researchers say it's causing real harm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/why-calling-farmers-resilient-is-causing-real-harm/106380598</link><description>Farmers and mental health experts say it is time to stop calling farmers "resilient", with concerns it is making it harder for people to ask for, or be offered, help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8262c8df577b48206152fb3633b1c7b</guid></item><item><title>Blizzard hits US Northeast bringing cities to standstill, closing schools and disrupting flights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/new-york-blizzard-shuts-down-city/106380000</link><description>A record-breaking snowstorm pummels the north-eastern United States, bringing cities to a near-standstill for millions of residents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e189929376eb6370b3de7af3a9595cc</guid></item><item><title>WA Parliament to debate institutional child sex abuse laws in wake of 'retrograde' High Court decision</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/political-fight-brewing-over-wa-child-sex-abuse-laws/106378266</link><description>A tense political fight is brewing over the future of laws to compensate survivors of institutional child sexual abuse, as the government faces pressure to expand its scope beyond just churches and religious institutions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ebc9f878ee9aa4c53cfa620788901c2</guid></item><item><title>Former Matildas label new Football Australia membership program a 'silencing mechanism'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/football-matildas-alumni-silencing-mechanism/106380898</link><description>A new membership program launched by Football Australia puts former Matildas players in a difficult position if they want to criticise the governing body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12ab1a1fc7933a240faf717139d7e352</guid></item><item><title>Police identify Katherine Sanowski as woman found dead at Bellbird Park house as they launch murder investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/katherine-sanowski-found-at-bellbird-park-house/106380702</link><description>A 34-year-old found nearby, known to the victim, is receiving a medical assessment and is yet to speak to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16f9da380f80e397c36c347f7829c85e</guid></item><item><title>Globetrotting ancient marine amphibians uncovered in lucky Kimberley fossil rediscovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/globetrotting-marine-amphibian-kimberley-fossil/106378096</link><description>A salamander-crocodile type predator survived five extinction events and travelled from waters off Norway to WA's Kimberley coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74546bf755e86634e833775195d5a28f</guid></item><item><title>Former RBA governor Bernie Fraser calls for capital gains tax discount to be scrapped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/former-rba-governor-bernie-fraser-calls-out-toxic-tax-debate-cgt/106381176</link><description>Bernie Fraser tells a Senate committee hearing on capital gains tax that, if it were up to him, he would abolish the discount, as he warns younger Australians are watching the unaffordable housing market in "dismay".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e2e581ae18667dd719881ee26af70c3</guid></item><item><title>Thousands without power as intense storms sweep across Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/storms-heavy-rain-create-flash-flooding-risk-melbourne-victoria/106381904</link><description>Storms dumped 50 millimetres of rain on parts of Victoria on Tuesday and cut power to thousands of homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd921bd2b66d090c85c4290ac02e432d</guid></item><item><title>Woman allegedly attempts to snatch hijab from teenage girl in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/police-investigate-alleged-hijab-snatching-brisbane/106377108</link><description>Queensland Police launch an investigation after a woman allegedly attempted to snatch a hijab from a teenage girl on the Brisbane bayside.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf3abd205bed7da3b3acea07677024e</guid></item><item><title>Could Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor be removed from the line of succession?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/could-andrew-mountbatten-windsor-be-removed-succession/106379724</link><description>Is it possible to remove him? The short answer is yes — but it would most likely be a time-consuming process involving many parliaments passing legislation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc7b6cf1265cee96550e880ac1189d24</guid></item><item><title>Australia has been waiting more than 40 years for a high-speed train</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/high-speed-rail-timeline/106380200</link><description>It has been more than 40 years since the idea of high-speed rail was first floated in Australia, but is it finally about to become a reality?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b871f60ea4b939b39299867329db2d65</guid></item><item><title>Rodney Wayne Williams fails appeal to overturn conviction for murdering pregnant teenager</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/rodney-wayne-williams-fails-murder-appeal-again/106381496</link><description>Rodney Wayne Williams is serving life in jail for the murder of 16-year-old, pregnant Tiffany Taylor in Waterford West in July 2015.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ae0393e00ac7837b97eba078297d636</guid></item><item><title>AI body suddenly scrapped after 15 months spent finding experts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/ai-body-scrapped-15-months-spent-experts/106381560</link><description>It took 15 months to narrow a field of 270 AI experts to 12 appointees for an AI authority, at a cost of almost $200,000, before it was suddenly scrapped by the federal government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4d4a8e5bb2f4cb7d4740af807977d6a</guid></item><item><title>Gus Lamont's parents release public statement saying their lives have been 'shattered'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/gus-lamont-parents-release-statement-and-video/106382060</link><description>The parents of missing four-year-old Gus Lamont have released a public statement, saying "every moment without him is unbearable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d3e5c997663dc92e3421d5bad20eb45</guid></item><item><title>Australia's women's team wins first ODI against India by six wickets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/australia-rocked-by-injuries-for-odi-against-india/106382088</link><description>Half-centuries to Alyssa Healy and Beth Mooney help lead Australia to a six-wicket win over India in the first ODI.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ffe49e1fc9fac5bc4872e11ab263f28</guid></item><item><title>Explosive detection dog Flo Joe posthumously awarded for military service in Afghanistan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/explosive-detection-dog-honoured-for-afghanistan-service/106381612</link><description>In July 2007, explosive detection dog Flo Joe became the first Australian service dog to locate an improvised explosive device in Afghanistan. Today, she was posthumously recognised for her military service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a025209051ae4b48cc916b0eff99763</guid></item><item><title>Popular WA outback tourist property Wooleen Station to be sold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/wooleen-station-to-go-on-the-market/106380032</link><description>A pastoral station in WA's Murchison region which has become a high-profile example of conservation is to be sold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2629129ee45ba4e948d4323c0b0f54ca</guid></item><item><title>Half the country on flood watch as summer storms bring deluge of rain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/flood-watch-severe-summer-storms-rain-deluge/106380770</link><description>There are widespread warnings for intense rain and potential flooding, as summer storms hit southern states and an unusually slow-moving system soaks central Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cf44965fc7c5761beae2aa89fa43be8</guid></item><item><title>Geoffrey John Guest to face fresh trial after Cairns District Court jury discharged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/geoffrey-john-guest-cairns-district-court-mistrial/106381884</link><description>The judge decided a witness's "inadmissible" response under cross-examination in the trial of Geoffrey John Guest left her with no choice but to discharge the jury the day after it had been empanelled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d12e78f860c14d96031e44bd3fbd4b</guid></item><item><title>WA government announces $140m plan to prevent repeat of record-breaking flu season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/funding-announced-to-prevent-repeat-of-worst-wa-flu-season/106381138</link><description>Creating more beds and boosting immunisation are key features of a $140 million "winter strategy" aimed at avoiding a repeat of WA's worst-ever flu season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cdf32025a3e240599546afd0cac4a75</guid></item><item><title>Fire ant authority considers penalties for business that spread nests to central Qld</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/fire-ant-authority-considers-business-penalties-central-qld/106381870</link><description>The National Fire Ant Eradication Program is considering "enforcement actions" for a business accused of spreading nests to Queensland mine sites via a shipment of bricks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b7e49e3c8b3f0115d47c00005c53b9b</guid></item><item><title>Most flu deaths this century were recorded in 2025, ABS finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/most-flu-deaths-this-century-were-recorded-in-2025/106380626</link><description>There were more deaths associated with influenza last year than any other year this century, according to the Australia Bureau of Statistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e3386c5443b969a614212741434003a</guid></item><item><title>New ACT firearms laws would allow police to search property of 'high-risk' individuals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/new-act-laws-to-target-high-risk-firearms-licence-holders/106379570</link><description>The ACT government's plan to strengthen firearms laws could raise human rights issues by interfering with the right to privacy, a lawyer has warned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1f4939ac3ca9f4d10abc422d74b3fcc</guid></item><item><title>Perth obstetrician Rhys Bellinge jailed over drunken high-speed crash that killed Elizabeth Pearce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/rhys-bellinge-dash-cam-vision-shown-at-manslaughter-hearing/106379994</link><description>A Perth obstetrician who killed a 24-year-old woman after smashing his high performance luxury car into the small hatchback she was a passenger in is sentenced to 10 years and six months in jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67f3bc7237cf123c2e550b516eb79a62</guid></item><item><title>Banning transgender women from lesbian group could 'undermine their dignity', court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/trans-women-ban-could-undermine-dignity-court-hears/106379566</link><description>Transgender women will have their dignity "undermined" and could be made to feel "inferior" if a lesbian group is allowed to ban them from events, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fff4a589cb54ef441b0031aadaecd259</guid></item><item><title>Trans-Tasman Yacht Race from Sydney to Auckland postponed after withdrawal of most entries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/inaugural-trans-tasman-yacht-race-postponed/106382816</link><description>The first running of the Trans-Tasman Yacht Race between Sydney and Auckland is called off days out from the start, after the withdrawal of the majority of entries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">439fd74ff186d18c86d500c7cbe2cae1</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106381704</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39e60231a17d7a495fddc0419a39ae3a</guid></item><item><title>Torres Strait Island men jailed over 110kg cocaine bust at top of Australian mainland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/torres-strait-island-men-jailed-110-kg-cocaine-bust/106381388</link><description>One of three men who used a dinghy to haul 110 kilograms of cocaine onto the Australian mainland has been jailed after telling a court he was helping a friend in exchange for a free boat trip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">541a6f2b789102f306eb4615606528d2</guid></item><item><title>Ash Barty to return to golf, as three-time tennis grand slam winner ready to play NZ Open pro-am</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/barty-to-dust-cobwebs-off-golf-clubs-at-nz-open/106383366</link><description>Ash Barty, Kelly Slater and Ricky Ponting are among the multi-talented sports stars in action in the pro-am component of the NZ Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">691e478bd06ca170a02cb11cd8010379</guid></item><item><title>Inquest into Aboriginal woman's death in custody hears of daughters' grief from losing 'loving mother'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/inquiry-into-tammy-shipley-indigenous-death-in-custody-underway/106375872</link><description>Tammy Shipley died in a NSW prison cell in December 2022 after consuming excessive water, a complication of schizoaffective disorder known as polydipsia. Today her children told a coronial inquest that "if love could have saved her, she could have lived forever".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ea20def3d0cef5ce9691ef8a1913353</guid></item><item><title>Sunshine Coast man Riccardo Valenza charged with 31 offences, including 11 counts of rape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/sunshine-coast-riccardo-valenza-rape-sex-offence-charges/106383282</link><description>Sunshine Coast man Riccardo Valenza, 31, has been remanded in custody after police charged him with 31 offences relating to 11 alleged victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2a0eaed5b17d352f1a7fa52c740a38c</guid></item><item><title>Gynaecologist referred to police after Four Corners report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/gynaecologist-referred-to-police-after-four-corners-report/106383070</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af5fa80a27c13ce749c4abd8cbf9c859</guid></item><item><title>This video shows Rhys Bellinge's erratic behaviour and driving in the lead-up to the fatal accident.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/rhys-bellinge-dashcam/106383724</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56edceffc1a1d0498e77c5721b86cb57</guid></item><item><title>WIN Network acquires Nine Darwin, expanding broadcast operations into the NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/win-network-expands-to-nt-acquires-nine-darwin-broadcast-licence/106381370</link><description>Regional news broadcaster WIN has announced it will acquire Nine Darwin, just over a year after the Nine Network suddenly axed its Darwin TV news bulletin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8baa7469fabfac9c6ed288c3f74508b5</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese evacuated from The Lodge following security incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/anthony-albanese-security-incident-at-lodge-police-canberra/106383816</link><description>The incident at Mr Albanese's Canberra residence led to the prime minister being taken to another location for several hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72b50206545d3ac787b1d543ef05a0cb</guid></item><item><title>Russell Brand pleads not guilty to further rape, sex assault charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/russell-brand-pleads-not-guilty-to-rape-sex-assault-charges/106383904</link><description>British actor and comedian Russell Brand pleads not guilty in a London court to two additional charges of rape and sexual assault nearly two decades ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b747accab501f137c5c60f8fc3286c92</guid></item><item><title>Reawakening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-24/investigating-the-return-of-the-islamic-state-terrorist-group/106154258</link><description>The Bondi Beach terrorist attack signalled the resurgence of the Islamic State terrorist group in Australia. For the past two years, ABC Investigations has tracked the group's revival, identifying key figures, mapping the network and raising questions about the response of police, intelligence agencies and governments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ed875261411710cd5d9b1a2ae992a69</guid></item><item><title>Former Philippine leader Rodrigo Duterte drew up 'death lists' and boasted about murders, ICC prosecutors say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/rodrigo-duterte-drew-up-death-lists-icc-prosecutor-says/106383930</link><description>Former Philippines president Rodrigo Duterte personally drew up "death lists" and boasted about murders committed during his "war on drugs", an International Criminal Court prosecutor alleges at a crimes against humanity hearing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d06ac48619d2547d4416c2e55b69aa52</guid></item><item><title>Savannah Guthrie's family offers $1.42m reward to bring home missing mother Nancy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/brk-savannah-guthrie-million-dollar-reward-nancy/106384088</link><description>US TV host Savannah Guthrie has posted a video to Instagram offering a $US1 million ($1.42 million) reward for information leading to the recovery of her missing mother Nancy Guthrie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53947568c5673b9c16079b2e53f0b890</guid></item><item><title>Travel quiz, February 25: Can you win our race around the world?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/travel-quiz/106251072</link><description>Which European city is home to the Rijksmuseum? And which dance style is Argentina best known for?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12547cb9e33e987e219d6bc7abf94e46</guid></item><item><title>Salmon Tasmania fighting proposal by regulator to revoke its licence to use antibiotic florfenicol</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/salmon-tasmania-fighting-to-keep-florfenicol-licence/106379754</link><description>Tasmania's salmon industry is arguing the case to keep using an antibiotic being used to combat bacterial infection in fish stocks, as a possible ban on the drug's usage looms because of it being found in "non-target" species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e1bfed478e6d5edcba7362c9b4986f5</guid></item><item><title>Gay and bisexual Sydney teenagers lured and bashed on camera in IS-inspired attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/lgbtq-sydney-teenagers-bashed-on-camera-in-is-inspired-attacks/106381614</link><description>An ABC investigation has obtained distressing videos and victims' accounts of IS sympathisers hunting and bashing gay and bisexual boys on camera in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02cf66c55ec69f880e3809e1ee0429a4</guid></item><item><title>WARNING: DISTRESSING FOOTAGE Young men attack a teenager in Strathfield Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/teenager-attacked-in-park/106383850</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d97f351a771d70f5f9300be9f2b656e0</guid></item><item><title>Endometriosis sufferers fear progress could be undone by one surgeon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/simon-gordon-actions-undo-decades-endometriosis-advocacy/106380210</link><description>Endometriosis sufferers have been left "sick" and reeling over the findings of a months-long ABC investigation into a Melbourne gynaecologist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb137f5b8e49938c0ab7401b57e03c07</guid></item><item><title>Russia casts net wide for mercenary recruits: fmr presidential adviser</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/fional-hill-iv-russia-recruits/106383740</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e046e0fde8c37bc2af5d53ee49ca9eee</guid></item><item><title>Four years of war in Ukraine leaves Russia a 'spent force' with diminished influence, analyst says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/russia-military-reputation-economy-after-ukraine-war-years/106382378</link><description>For the first time since its invasion of Ukraine, Russia has lost troops faster than it can replace them. It's one of many grim milestones of a bloody war that has now been going for four years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bced11945eb48f8283eac8c53bd02cf8</guid></item><item><title>Aiva Anagnostiadis looks to future after breaking leg during F1 Academy rookie year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/aiva-anagnostiadis-motor-sport-f1-academy-broken-leg/106380728</link><description>Armed with a strengthened determination to succeed on the race track, Aiva Anagnostiadis is ready to put her injury woes in the rear-view mirror.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77c674fd515793cfabe6c37ff1482519</guid></item><item><title>Women's Asian Cup 2026: The uneven roads that lead to the trophy, from the intriguing North Korea, to favourite Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/matildas-women-asian-cup-uneven-roads-lead-to-trophy/106359648</link><description>The Women's Asian Cup in Australia provides a chance for the Matildas and visiting nations to create history, bring attention to their countries like never before, and seek respect and investment. But each have had varied paths to get here.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aacf7cdc0ca08ec21e067171a144021a</guid></item><item><title>Antisemitism royal commission underway, but does it have time to deliver effective change?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/antisemitism-royal-commission-takeaways-bell-under-pressure/106382176</link><description>The antisemitism royal commission is underway, but it faces some real tests in delivering justice to those impacted in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e594d0b66d135cb84779076f40a5e4d</guid></item><item><title>Sir Donald Bradman died a quarter century ago but will 'always be 99.94 not out'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/sir-donald-bradman-died-25-years-ago-but-his-legacy-endures/106380826</link><description>Sir Donald Bradman was a towering figure in Australian cricket and culture, and some of the game's commentators have paused to reflect on his ongoing significance to the sport 25 years after his death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">975906e8b1e84eeb203f6986ecaf9129</guid></item><item><title>SA Labor's stamp duty policy appears at odds with former treasurer Stephen Mullighan's views</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/sa-labor-stamp-duty-policy-at-odds-with-former-treasurer/106378424</link><description>SA Labor has announced a plan to abolish stamp duty for those aged over 60 and planning to downsize at the party's election campaign launch, in what seems to be a major policy shift from the position detailed by the state's former treasurer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b27db3455f09fb4d6806cfb7711d05</guid></item><item><title>Armidale community rallies to welcome refugees from Democratic Republic of Congo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/congolese-refugees-welcomed-in-armidale-nsw/105972890</link><description>Churches and families rally around Congolese refugee arrivals in a NSW town known as a welcome zone for those fleeing crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f543759c3159899de0b556d015bc0898</guid></item><item><title>Irma Palasics's husband recounts her brutal murder in violent home invasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/irma-palasics-husband-gregor-recounts-brutal-murder/106383678</link><description>A jury has watched hospital footage of Irma Palasics's husband describing the night she was killed in 1999, as two men stand trial over her death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b228934b08a6e5492eb7b74281967e33</guid></item><item><title>Australian Chamber Orchestra welcomes 416yo Italian viola into its collection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/416yo-maggini-viola-now-in-aco-golden-age-instrument-collection/106379198</link><description>The instrument is believed to be one of the finest tenor violas in existence and the only surviving example of its kind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1687be523fb662e38112f9e215a95c24</guid></item><item><title>UK government supports release of Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's trade envoy documents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/uk-supports-release-andrew-trade-envoy-documents/106384154</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor was arrested last week on suspicion of misconduct in public office amid claims he shared confidential government information with Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d235e2538bc53d7290a2f9b9495a41a5</guid></item><item><title>Trump Tower developer David Young ran business that collapsed owing $28 million</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/trump-tower-altus-david-young-business-collapse/106382270</link><description>The businessman behind a proposed Trump Tower on the Gold Coast ran a development business that collapsed owing $28 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20f0579935944319a141698f76e6a03a</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of former prisoners potentially exposed to HIV and hepatitis C after a prisoner shared needles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/hundreds-prisoners-exposed-hiv-hepatitis-needles-prison/106380582</link><description>A Queensland Health communique has revealed hundreds of former prisoners were potentially exposed to HIV and hepatitis C after an inmate shared injecting equipment in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ea1a73def8baa9b4fca1b38e40ca337</guid></item><item><title>Scott Vincent Ward charged with allegedly grooming Philippines mother to sexually abuse her children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/scott-vincent-ward-charged-allegedly-grooming-philippines-mother/106278470</link><description>The man was searched by Australian Border Force officers when he arrived at Brisbane Airport after returning to Australia on a flight from the Philippines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b0e9ca5da89c7b4e3f1b6ac1518eaae</guid></item><item><title>Albanese urges country to 'turn the heat down' after bomb threat — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/albanese-evacuation-labor-taylor-coalition-capital-gains/106382944</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has called for the heat to be taken out of political debate following a bomb threat on The Lodge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77348508578bc054179124f6660dcdaa</guid></item><item><title>Pilot study into early diagnosis of pancreatic cancer by screening diabetes patients to launch in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/pancreatic-cancer-pilot-study-diabetes-qimr-berghofer/106382922</link><description>The study is the first step into investigating whether pancreatic cancer screening — via a non-invasive CT scan — could help save lives by early detection or warning signs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf16cc4fc7e81bd913e1ef2a0c3a94bb</guid></item><item><title>Craig Tiley to leave Tennis Australia for role with United States Tennis Association</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/craig-tiley-leaves-tennis-australia-role/106384386</link><description>Tiley has been tournament director of the Australian Open since 2006 and Tennis Australia CEO since 2013. He'll remain in the role while Tennis Australia appoints his successor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a00aa6f512d90a459a2c2526fc89b3e</guid></item><item><title>Louvre Museum director resigns in wake of brazen October crown jewel heist in Paris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/louvre-museum-director-resigns-after-brazen-jewel-heist-paris/106384280</link><description>Louvre Museum director Laurence des Cars resigns after months of pressure following the brazen theft of crown jewels, water damage, staff strikes, overcrowding complaints and a suspected ticket fraud scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">831bd642e407e80da5f053df10bdaa0a</guid></item><item><title>Thirteen million trees to be replanted after pine plantation wiped out in Walwa-Mt Lawson fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/walwa-mt-lawson-bushfire-homes-destroyed-pine-plantation-burnt/106352790</link><description>The fire threat in Victoria's Upper Murray has eased, but the region's famously green, undulating hills still bear the black scars of a devastating bushfire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97c8fc075c444de8cd7ff73b22cbe99f</guid></item><item><title>Human remains confirmed as abducted Sydney grandfather Chris Baghsarian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/arrests-made-in-relation-to-chris-baghsarian-kidnapping-sydney/106383878</link><description>Two men are arrested less than 24 hours after police discovered human remains near a golf club in Sydney's north-west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef24ed41a5bfff6d07da7264105ce998</guid></item><item><title>ASX 200 hits new high, Australian dollar climbing — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/asx-markets-business-live-news-feb25-2026/106384410</link><description>The local share market is at record levels, while the Australian dollar is climbing after inflation was steady at 3.8 per cent in January. WiseTech and Woolworths shares surge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed97b3919fb81e7d55a53a3b1198c44c</guid></item><item><title>US Winter Olympic ice hockey hero Jack Hughes excited to meet Donald Trump as mum defends Kash Patel video</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/jack-hughes-white-house-winter-olympics-womens-ice-hockey/106384348</link><description>US ice hockey star Jack Hughes defends his team after video of them laughing at Donald Trump's joke about the women's gold medallists sparks backlash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe483c4796cb5a3109bf95b4979dd780</guid></item><item><title>Open letter asks PM to 'urgently rescind' appointment of NT administrator David Connolly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/open-letter-call-for-anthony-albanese-intervene-nt-administrator/106382634</link><description>Politicians, advocates and civil society leaders have made a last-ditch plea for Anthony Albanese to intervene ahead of the swearing-in of controversial incoming NT administrator David Connolly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9f9004a6582dfbcb6d78bad56957c4d</guid></item><item><title>Mount Isa experiences most February rain on record</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/mount-isa-wettest-february-on-record/106376066</link><description>Dry red dirt turns to flowing rivers and lakes as heavy rainfall breaks a century-old record in Mount Isa.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18499cfff20111771fdd53839df128fa</guid></item><item><title>Connor Rogers recovering from 11 surgeries after nearly losing leg in tackle during local footy game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/connor-rogers-brutal-injury-football-local-div-12/106338682</link><description>A catastrophic footy injury during a Melbourne reserves game changed Connor Rogers's life in an instant. In the aftermath, the support of his local footy club helped him recover and showed him the power of community. WARNING: This article contains graphic imagery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">078399ef98a946f6de58bb17d264207d</guid></item><item><title>Iran signs 'secret' $700m deal for Russian air defence systems, reports say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/iran-missile-defence-deal-russia-verba-manpad-weapons/106380088</link><description>Iran has reportedly signed a secret arms deal with Russia to acquire thousands of advanced shoulder-fired missiles to help boost its air defences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b186d6b24a61905798a901db170096dd</guid></item><item><title>Thai officials say 72 tiger deaths at tourist parks not caused by bird flu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/virus-that-killed-72-tigers-at-thai-zoos-not-bird-flu/106384442</link><description>Thai authorities say tigers in confined environments can be particularly vulnerable to the canine distemper viral infection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08d52138f42cb0ba31f2ed52368e5ca8</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous landscape board chair resigns amid investigation into Telstra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/landscape-chair-resigns-amid-investigation-into-telstra/106367584</link><description>The Alinytjara Wiluṟara Landscape Board chair steps down, saying his ability to speak for a region where Telstra is under investigation for alleged environmental breaches was impeded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">211a65bc84f648de9e49ef376f2bcd2b</guid></item><item><title>Perth doctor Rhys Bellinge's 'entitled, callous' behaviour killed Elizabeth Pearce and ruined lives, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/perth-doctor-rhys-bellinge-killed-elizabeth-pearce-ruined-lives/106383318</link><description>Sought-after obstetrician Rhys Bellinge appeared to have it all — but that changed in an instant when his drunken, high-speed driving killed a young university graduate and left a rideshare driver with permanent injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">355a8d87620787b2e6b4622688729230</guid></item><item><title>Wittenoom traditional owners launch $1.5b asbestos contamination claim against WA government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/banjima-traditional-owners-launch-billion-dollar-wittenoom-claim/106358598</link><description>Banjima traditional owners say the thousands of hectares left poisoned by decades of asbestos mining have caused one of the highest death rates of mesothelioma in the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">889e0a097833cbe734c1fccb6cfd8878</guid></item><item><title>Lake Moondarra overspills for the first time since since 2011</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/lake-moondarra-overspills-for-the-first-time-since-since-2011/106384730</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f810b53ba9fc40815b8ed0f71911982</guid></item><item><title>Yuin elder and public educator Aunty Ruth Simms publishes first children's book, Muttonfish Magic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/muttonfish-magic-by-aunty-ruth-simms/106379544</link><description>Aunty Ruth Simms has published her first book, Muttonfish Magic, as she prepares to celebrate five decades in the public education system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">945febdcf237e891b59df5678c5d7173</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy says Ukraine unbroken after four years, but Russia vows to fight on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/zelenskyy-says-ukraine-unbroken-four-years-russia-fight/106384174</link><description>World leaders gather in Kyiv to mark four years since the launch of Moscow's full scale invasion of Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c283fd4e2bff39088bc07c266c819dee</guid></item><item><title>NSW government launches 24/7 rapid response unit in hate-related offences crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/nsw-rapid-response-hate-squad-under-permanent-operation-shelter/106384276</link><description>More than 200 police officers equipped with long-arm rifles will be deployed to places of worship, major events and mass gatherings like protests on a risk basis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">910a37ea3e45b7b5467209fd76933a1d</guid></item><item><title>Esperance farmers grapple with feral pig surge in WA's south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/feral-pig-boom-esperance-western-australia/106380622</link><description>Farmers call for government support to curb the number of feral pigs in WA's south-east after a rapid jump in numbers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87c7973bd881aa0cf85c7291146dcd3a</guid></item><item><title>How Han Xu's arrival at Perth Lynx has taken the WNBL by storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/han-xu-effect-taking-the-wnbl-by-storm/106373806</link><description>The Perth Lynx were a middling side after eight games of the WNBL season, but the arrival of Han Xu sparked an astonishing turnaround in their fortunes — both on and off the court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc0722a4d31c3e0219be13102e2c16d1</guid></item><item><title>Farmer hopes to represent Australia snowboarding at the Paralympics four years after losing leg</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/farmer-hopes-to-represent-australia-snowboarding-at-paralympics/106383430</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ed6a7ba2bca8bbe0c16658e2ed63f8a</guid></item><item><title>Farmer hopes to represent Australia snowboarding at the Paralympics four years after losing leg</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/farmer-hopes-to-represent-australia-snowboarding-at-paralympics/106376588</link><description>Aaron McCarthy stepped onto a snowboard four years ago. This week he hopes to qualify for the Winter Paralympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cf672d8c6b9ff1a15977538b84bbf1e</guid></item><item><title>Born in a Taxi and Osadía to bring roving performance magic to WOMADelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/roving-performances-bringing-the-magic-to-womadelaide/106382822</link><description>Melbourne's Born in a Taxi will join Spain's Osadía in bringing their unique performances to the world music festival next weekend, but they point out street theatre has not always been received well.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa9d78103d2775d112134500ea080471</guid></item><item><title>Lizzie McGuire and Revenge of the Nerds star Robert Carradine dies at 71</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/star-robert-carradine-dies-at-71/106385198</link><description>Robert Carradine — the youngest member of a legendary Hollywood family — dies, with his loved ones revealing his struggle with bipolar disorder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c0c895ad2beca55fdbbb3d90638f163</guid></item><item><title>Trump swipes at Supreme Court in longest State of the Union speech — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/donald-trump-state-of-the-union-2026/106382332</link><description>US President Donald Trump has addressed Congress in the annual State of the Union speech. Take a look back at how events unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce16501a9de1069b6d15a271802fa650</guid></item><item><title>Mexico's president insists 'no risk' as cartel clashes fuel worries in lead-up to FIFA World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/mexican-cartel-clashes-fuel-worries-ahead-of-fifa-world-cup/106384596</link><description>Claudia Sheinbaum says there is "no risk" to fans coming to the country to attend FIFA World Cup games despite the recent capture and death of Mexico's most-wanted cartel leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5089314ba0a8e035ccef21de150e7e3e</guid></item><item><title>Truckie charged over crash which killed two train drivers has died, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/fatal-truck-crash-accused-kevin-pearson-dies/106385454</link><description>A truck driver charged over a fatal crash which killed two freight train drivers at a level crossing on the Barrier Highway has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7e220ba7552d3e17ee0002c465ebbb9</guid></item><item><title>Security threat prompting PM evacuation linked to intimidation of Chinese dancers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/albanese-lodge-bomb-threat-linked-chinese-dance-group/106384392</link><description>The prime minister was forced to evacuate the Lodge last night due to a bomb threat linked to performances in Australia by a classical Chinese dance and music group that is banned in China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c2f24aaf18103c78d63480741dc5a2f</guid></item><item><title>Sydney doctor Jamal Rifi says IS-linked families in Syria should return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/sydney-doctor-helping-australian-isis-families-in-syria/106385212</link><description>Australian doctor Jamal Rifi has been helping to coordinate a potential repatriation effort from Syria, including by obtaining passports for the families.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d9895896c97fafd5b0ddb78fbb0745c</guid></item><item><title>ACCC 'Down Down' arguments questioned by judge in bombshell court case against Coles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/accc-coles-federal-court-closing-statements/106379734</link><description>The judge overseeing a bombshell federal court case has made a stunning intervention as the consumer watchdog makes closing arguments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">934f8ff93d8e9018723b1aa8503be777</guid></item><item><title>Woolworths shares have best day on record as food sales and profit beat expectations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/woolworths-shares-surge-as-food-sales-and-profit-beat/106385714</link><description>Woolworths shares rally 13 per cent on a well-received result. The supermarket's shareholders will receive an interim dividend of 45 cents per share, up from the same time a year ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2758ff2cae852167c9f1fb63ee6bcf0e</guid></item><item><title>Australian man Peter Williams given 7 years' jail for selling US trade secrets to Russian broker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/australian-sentenced-7-years-jail-selling-us-trade-secrets/106385636</link><description>A judge in Washington DC has sentenced Australian man Peter Williams to 87 months in prison for selling sensitive information to a Russian broker.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eb2b43d9f83ddf83d0cd30591a8558a</guid></item><item><title>Cull and swimming ban resume after fatal shark attack in New Caledonia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/cull-and-swimming-ban-resume-fatal-shark-attack-new-caledonia/106382354</link><description>New Caledonian authorities ban beach swimming and resume shark culling despite concern from environmental groups, after a wing foiler is killed in an attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a8bb518e0a3ed323ae5f8dadc1b4f49</guid></item><item><title>Inflation in January slightly hotter than expected, keeping RBA rate hike on table</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/inflation-australia-january-2026-hotter-than-expected/106385296</link><description>Headline inflation was 3.8 per cent in January, which was unchanged from December, but underlying inflation increased slightly. Both numbers were higher than expected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ebd09c60bb56db7ca84f11a3ac3e523</guid></item><item><title>Woman's family sues NT government over Tennant Creek watch house death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/kumanjayi-dempsey-family-negligence-lawsuit-nt-government/106377134</link><description>The family of a woman who died in police custody in Tennant Creek is suing the Northern Territory government for negligence, alleging officers failed in their duty of care after her arrest and that the 44-year-old was held in an "overheated" cell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c13a5a9ed71fa1e03c03fe256cc4765</guid></item><item><title>Teenager denies driving car that crashed on Canberra road killing 15yo passenger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/teen-denies-being-behind-wheel-of-car-in-fatal-canberra-crash/106375130</link><description>A Canberra boy on trial for manslaughter denies being behind the wheel of a stolen car that crashed and killed another teenager outside Parliament House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0a7868fcd9fc33c57e6bdb1160912d6</guid></item><item><title>"Our country is winning again": Trump invites US men's hockey team to Congress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/trump-invites-us-men-s-hockey-team-to-congress/106386806</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">466893d57c6f8dfe468b51c617ab8ef6</guid></item><item><title>Trump takes swipe at US Supreme Court over tariff ruling</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/trump-takes-swipe-at-us-supreme-court-over-tariff-ruling/106386970</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ca5d92daffac10ce6cdcaef74c91b1d</guid></item><item><title>NSW premier flags new laws after IS-inspired attacks on gay and bisexual teens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/hate-laws-nsw-after-isis-inspired-sydney-attacks-on-sexuality/106386596</link><description>The New South Wales premier has flagged harsher punishments and new criminal offences in response to gay and bisexual teens being lured online and bashed on camera.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e338e8b970cd0bf9e75722c8533b5172</guid></item><item><title>City of Adelaide review its camera car operations for issuing parking fines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/adelaide-city-council-reviews-park-safe-camera-vehicle/106384784</link><description>An Adelaide council administration is reviewing its camera-mounted vehicle as a driver says she was mistakenly fined for performing a U-turn in a permit parking zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0641b9569f3a3c27f7b1f38f058b26a6</guid></item><item><title>Police will not charge Canberra bar owner after seizing posters under new Commonwealth hate laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/police-to-return-posters-after-hate-law-seizures/106387066</link><description>A Canberra bar owner will not be charged with breaching Commonwealth hate laws for displaying posters depicting world leaders and a billionaire in Nazi-like uniforms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b3866b044d0e672078ef56422224136</guid></item><item><title>Payne Haas rejects Michael Maguire rumour in NRL move from Broncos to Rabbitohs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/nrl-payne-haas-brisbane-broncos-south-sydney-rabbitohs/106387292</link><description>Payne Haas speaks publicly for the first time about his move to South Sydney in 2027, explaining why he is leaving the Brisbane Broncos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23d7f158569fe37628f68a479c16b32b</guid></item><item><title>Video shows Ian Wally attempting to set police officers on fire in Perth.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/broome-man-tries-set-police-officer-on-fire/106387158</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35d278062e2d2de2aca36e881723d9f7</guid></item><item><title>WA man who tried to set police officer on fire sentenced to four years in prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/wa-man-ian-wally-set-jailed-attempt-set-police-officer-on-fire/106386692</link><description>Ian Wally attempted to use a jerry can full of petrol to set a Perth police officer on fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">429f5e347931de107ddfb2ce6abbb954</guid></item><item><title>Southern Downs Regional Council rejects developer's proposal for water bottling facility on Cherrabah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/council-knocks-back-cherrabah-water-bottling-plan/106386412</link><description>Farmers say their fight continues after the local council knocked back a Chinese company's bid to extract almost 100 million litres of groundwater a year to bottle and sell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00dcddd89aafebd16a661ba8753b1230</guid></item><item><title>What is duty sex and how do you stop having it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/how-duty-sex-differs-from-maintenance-sex/106325270</link><description>Obligatory or duty sex is most common in long-term relationships, but can also happen in casual relationships where sex is the basis of the connection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdd191427baeb061fa035de6a2d105b3</guid></item><item><title>Connor Rogers learning to walk again after terrifying knee injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/connor-rogers-learning-to-walk-again-/106387768</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9867c848077ceb2f5c362549a6816fd1</guid></item><item><title>WA's population on track to reach 4 million by 2043 amid housing shortfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/wa-population-to-hit-4-million-by-2043-/106386874</link><description>Four million people are tipped to live in Western Australia by 2043 according to a new report which warns the boom could be derailed by a housing shortage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1ccc67305176b1cdfcb4d50fb9a01eb</guid></item><item><title>Troy Maskell found guilty of 73-year-old Strathmerton postmaster's manslaughter in retrial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/troy-maskell-trial-john-burke-strathmerton-verdict/106357564</link><description>A jury has found Troy Matthew Maskell guilty of a 73-year-old Strathmerton postmaster's manslaughter during a retrial ordered due to inadmissible evidence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d65488cc4991e44ceb6a584155755bb</guid></item><item><title>Alleged bomb threat against Gold Coast's HOTA theatre over Chinese dance group</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/alleged-bomb-threat-against-hota-hosting-shen-yun/106387762</link><description>Shen Yun has been the subject of several threats, including one against Australia's prime minister on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">801ec2a28bbf45bb3b0b2fae7382a49e</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor says federal Liberals must 'do better' as he joins Ashton Hurn in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/angus-taylor-in-adelaide-ahead-of-state-election/106386578</link><description>Opposition leader Angus Taylor responds to SA Liberal leader Ashton Hurn's criticism of her federal counterparts, as he joins her on the state campaign trail in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f59ec12c36a5f5b1cfe00a530da36eb</guid></item><item><title>High rainfall has been recorded in parts of far west NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/high-rainfall-has-been-recorded-in-parts-of-far-west-nsw/106386108</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e3dd838dd8600a7ce7a6afade6ba9fe</guid></item><item><title>Outback SA and NSW record up to 200mm overnight, with another 100mm of rain forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/far-north-sa-and-nsw-huge-rainfall-floods-after-drought-outback/106385264</link><description>Some pastoralists have already recorded 215mm of rain overnight, with the coming days forecast to bring an additional 100mm in some parts north-east of SA and far west NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">697d94ace7674f109cd2d23debd0c117</guid></item><item><title>AFL says umpires' opinion still matters after announcing Brownlow Medal voting change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/afl-brownlow-medal-umpires-voting-statistics/106388170</link><description>The AFL confirms umpires will be able to access player statistics before casting their votes in a bid to quell any controversy around the Brownlow Medal count.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34b913b9bfef804143a58f698ebb4095</guid></item><item><title>Rhys Bellinge manslaughter sentence supported by Roger Cook, but Basil Zempilas disagrees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/roger-cook-backs-rhys-bellinge-manslaughter-sentence/106387722</link><description>WA's political leaders are at odds over the sentence given to obstetrician Rhys Bellinge for a fatal drunken car accident, with Premier Roger Cook backing it and Opposition Leader Basil Zempilas saying it was "on the light side."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e77f4634f119cc9545ec53464d670ed</guid></item><item><title>Suspects arrested in relation to kidnapping murder of Chris Baghsarian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/kidnapping-murder-of-chris-baghsarian-arrest/106388262</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfb258075adc61818508acad08810fee</guid></item><item><title>Victorian opposition to expand Melbourne's CBD, fast-track growth area homes under housing plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/victorian-opposition-unveils-home-ownership-housing-plan/106387550</link><description>Victorian opposition leader Jess Wilson vows to scrap plans for higher-density residential buildings in Melbourne's middle-ring suburbs — and focus on expanding the CBD instead — if her party is elected later this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5520718b36f866602e7250368dbad06</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man accused of sexually assaulting woman he held captive tells jury he was under attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/canberra-man-accused-holding-woman-captive-says-he-was-attacked/106388054</link><description>A man accused of holding a woman captive and sexually assaulting her until she fled naked into a Canberra street has told a jury he was the one under attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3649ce1ac7ac040e5511bf11176913d6</guid></item><item><title>Australia at risk of 'supercharged' harm from unregulated AI, Toby Walsh warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/ai-regulation-toby-walsh-national-press-club-warning/106384688</link><description>Renowned AI expert Toby Walsh has used a National Press Club address to warn the Australian government about what he argues are inadequate approaches to regulating the technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c231414957b5623b10d1b040e8ca17ff</guid></item><item><title>Police find car of alleged Mullewa shooter Kenneth John Giles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/car-of-alleged-shooter-kenneth-john-giles-found-/106386140</link><description>Police find a white Nissan Patrol belonging to alleged gunman Kenneth John Giles nearly two months after he allegedly shot his partner and sparked a major manhunt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">786c0c415c0a743457b7b99b8f34cb21</guid></item><item><title>Public sector workers 'furious' as Tasmanian government denies reneging on pay deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/tasmania-public-sector-workers-resume-industrial-action/106384712</link><description>The Tasmanian government has labelled claims it reneged on a pay agreement as "incorrect" and says it is disappointed the unions are labelling recent talks in that way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">729da3bb9b34510869ada6721a93a6cf</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says he won't allow Iran to have a nuclear weapon during State of the Union address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/iran-trump-state-of-the-union-nuclear-weapon/106387402</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65fbad8fb738c8525008ee485b08aad0</guid></item><item><title>Standout moments from Donald Trump's State of the Union speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/standout-moments-from-trumps-state-of-the-union-speech/106385846</link><description>The president gives the longest State of the Union speech in US history, delivering a 108-minute address to shatter Bill Clinton's 89-minute record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b85a36c42a5707d96da7621d72c6b26</guid></item><item><title>Teenager first in SA to be prosecuted for allegedly creating deepfake images</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/william-yeates-charged-deepfake-image-creation/106387272</link><description>A suppression order has been lifted on the identity of the first South Australian man to be prosecuted for allegedly creating and sharing sexually explicit deepfake images.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0579c79d828d326b52afce269b7d6298</guid></item><item><title>WiseTech Global to cut 2,000 jobs as AI ends era of 'manually writing code'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/wisetech-job-losses-losing-2000-over-next-two-years-coding-era/106387486</link><description>The company says almost one third of staff across 40 countries would be affected by the redundancies as a move towards AI sees a reshaping of its workforce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de3b1765eea0903418e1e4e0ceea5bca</guid></item><item><title>Matildas goalkeeper Mackenzie Arnold unfazed by minimal preparation ahead of Asian Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-25/asian-cup-australia-matildas-mackenzie-arnold/106388852</link><description>Mackenzie Arnold says she has enough game time and form behind her to perform in Australia's Asian Cup tilt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28ed29e6bbd568d94cc5f8aa03c63e1f</guid></item></channel></rss>