<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 Sep 2025 03:52:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>How youth orchestras foster lifelong friendships and open career pathways for musicians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/youth-orchestra-lifelong-friendships-career-pathways-musicians/105775992</link><description>With youth orchestras set to busk on the streets of Sydney and Melbourne this weekend, Australian musicians share how those orchestras helped shape their careers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39cc489e47ad597a9a2e2610c3bf0e4a</guid></item><item><title>Cairns maternity ward named as exposure site in Far North Queensland measles outbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/four-new-cases-confirmed-in-cairns-measles-outbreak/105786794</link><description>More locally acquired cases have been confirmed with exposure sites now including Cairns Hospital's maternity ward and areas on the Atherton Tablelands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82362ca4ac1144d4e4b78657ca9250d4</guid></item><item><title>Kmart broke privacy laws by using facial recognition technology, commissioner finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/kmart-facial-recognition-technology-privacy-commissioner/105785802</link><description>The privacy commissioner has found Kmart broke the Privacy Act with its use of facial recognition technology, ordering the retail giant not to repeat the practice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">951624fe912cfaedd0c6e7cac0bca47d</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill launches LGBTQIA+ festival Rainbow in the Outback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/broken-hill-lgbtqia-festival-rainbow-in-the-outback/105782774</link><description>The outback city of Broken Hill is no stranger to celebrating the LGBTQIA+ community, with a new festival focusing on diversity and inclusion launching last weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cca328c6d304217ca3ecde48d89cfac4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's royal banquet dinner in pictures during historic state visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/donald-trump-state-banquet-dinner-in-pictures/105786672</link><description>Surrounded by high-level politicians, a media mogul, tech giants and athletes, the grandeur-loving US president was treated to a glowing spectacle at Windsor Castle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bc4938e2b936e932176490989e7d215</guid></item><item><title>Patient 'devastated' as Sydney's dedicated long COVID clinic to close</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nsw-sydney-long-covid-clinic-st-vincents-hospital-closing/105786680</link><description>A patient of NSW's first dedicated long COVID clinic in Sydney says she is "devastated" and "bewildered" that it will close at the end of the month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6eec0e1b65b01a94cbd8f6b1c7dd571</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel Live pulled from air by US broadcaster ABC over 'insensitive' Charlie Kirk comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/jimmy-kimmel-live-cancelled-indefinitely/105787192</link><description>The late-night talk show's host suggested during a monologue earlier this week that Charlie Kirk's alleged killer may have been a pro-Trump Republican.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42b62491994f952ca23ef1806fafc33b</guid></item><item><title>Gardeners share the joys of turning dust to daisies in the Australian outback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/gardeners-share-the-joys-of-growing-flowers-in-the-outback/105761510</link><description>Flower farmer Suzanne Stanton says generations of outback women have taken comfort in their gardens, proof that life can survive in the harshest of climates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">983de27f94440a9ba1f44837800269ac</guid></item><item><title>Palliative Care Australia art prize inspires conversations about death and grieving</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/palliative-care-australia-art-prize-helps-process-grief/105763880</link><description>In its fifth year, Palliative Care Australia's Live Well, Die Well national art prize continues to spark important conversations about dying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11b336b74532eacba654f9700b7c36e0</guid></item><item><title>Man sets out to combat 'isolating experience' of spinal cord injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/spinal-cord-injury-survivor-helps-to-combat-social-isolation/105567754</link><description>David Ham says the reality of his spinal cord injury hit him when he returned home from hospital and had no-one to talk to with a similar experience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">435c8feb69f9cd68efda827b14435fab</guid></item><item><title>How the Collingwood Magpies are righting the ship this AFLW season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/aflw-collingwood-magpies-round-six-hawthorn/105785982</link><description>A year after finishing dead last in the AFLW, the Magpies have started making moves up the ladder thanks to a new approach at both ends of the field.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09dcd2a4338fbef6fc6396c784fa2fe5</guid></item><item><title>Charges against veteran broadcaster Alan Jones 'downgraded', some withdrawn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nsw-sydney-alan-jones-charges-downgraded-dropped/105787356</link><description>Eleven counts of aggravated indecent assault against the veteran broadcaster have been dropped in what the magistrate described as a "reformation" of the case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c138a3782bc62a82275efd716973097</guid></item><item><title>Australian cow market at record high as US demand hits 'scary times'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/us-cattle-prices-soar-increasing-demand-for-aussie-beef/105776020</link><description>Australian cow prices are at record highs, but are still way below the United States where beef demand is going "crazy".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56f2d0555cc98f7f69e717a8162ea988</guid></item><item><title>Three police officers dead and two wounded in rural Pennsylvania shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/three-officers-dead-two-wounded-in-rural-pennsylvania-shooting/105787226</link><description>Pennsylvania police are investigating after three of their own were killed and another two wounded in a shooting near the rural area of North Codorus Township.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0648ea60108147caaccf749902d9bda1</guid></item><item><title>Australia vows to cut emissions 62 to 70 per cent by 2035</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/australia-vows-to-cut-emissions-62-to-70-per-cent-by-2035/105786880</link><description>Australia will vow to cut its emissions by 62 to 70 per cent by 2035, lifting its sights further as the world strives to reach net zero emissions by 2050.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2e21efb7e74be7accc0d01defc0839f</guid></item><item><title>PNG's much-wanted NRL team has had setbacks. Experts say history is on its side</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/png-rugby-league-history-new-nrl-club/105782492</link><description>Observers say Papua New Guinea's decades-long history of rugby league success and passion is on its side as it prepares for the next sporting leap into the NRL.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d3deca6b656ff8bd1468e46bc6f527e</guid></item><item><title>Magpies overlook Bobby Hill for AFL preliminary final against Lions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/afl-collingwood-magpies-brisbane-lions-bobby-hill/105789152</link><description>Coach Craig McRae reveals he has spoken with Bobby Hill about his chances of playing in the AFL finals, as the Magpies ramp up preparations for Saturday's preliminary final against Lions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fd53afc0b532e11cc1c5091bdf7734c</guid></item><item><title>The AFL is in danger of becoming a 'two-tier competition' as multiple club captains search for the exit door</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/afl-player-movement-merrett-curnow-simpkin-paul-roos-analysis/105784732</link><description>Three captains from the AFL's four worst-performing clubs are searching for the exit door. It is the symptom of a player movement era that has left the gap between the AFL's strongest and weakest larger than ever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fe6fc38b706e2d5bb69fdebfcdad181</guid></item><item><title>What are the best ways to clean windows and fly screens?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/what-are-the-best-ways-to-clean-windows-and-fly-screens/105757576</link><description>Windows and fly screens are often the first things we see when we walk into a home, but rarely at the top of the spring-cleaning to-do list. Experts share their tips on the easiest and most effective ways to clean them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7541abd5471ba63f11dace84578558cf</guid></item><item><title>Australia's 2035 climate targets on path to net zero judged by the experts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/climate-targets-australia-2035-on-path-to-net-zero/105719910</link><description>After much anticipation, Australia has its new climate targets. Now that the dice have fallen, we consult experts on their assessment of how these targets stack up with what’s at stake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dabb8156d4044b51ff0dc8bd8feb97a4</guid></item><item><title>Son, 28, charged with murder after allegedly assaulting parents on Father's Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/man-charged-with-murder-after-alleged-coffs-harbour-assault/105788172</link><description>A 28-year-old Coffs Harbour man has been charged with murder and attempted murder after allegedly assaulting his parents and starting a house fire on Father's Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe632a8da922ef75e0d1e5b6cb68d663</guid></item><item><title>Amid Trump's biggest, best state visit ever, the king delivers a pointed message</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/trump-state-visit-king-charles-message/105788584</link><description>Amid the diamonds, whisky sours and flattery of a royal banquet for Donald Trump's state visit, tiara diplomacy was on full display.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55c7f64974504498042a988379cc1542</guid></item><item><title>Authorities urge parents to check Little Ones Nappy Pants for khapra beetle larvae</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nappy-pants-still-unaccounted-for-khapra-beetle-larvae-found/105787812</link><description>Hundreds of cartons of nappy pants remain unaccounted for after one of the biggest threats to Australia's grain industry, khapra beetle larvae, was found in the imported products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45cfd2bf95d89861ab6dc3f7a688868c</guid></item><item><title>Cats coach Chris Scott regrets run-in with AFL staffer after qualifying final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/geelong-cats-chris-scott-afl-staff-qualifying-final/105789664</link><description>Geelong coach Chris Scott says long-held frustration with the AFL was behind his regrettable post-qualifying final win outburst at a junior league employee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64f8afe41599735121373a93d14d1aff</guid></item><item><title>Patrick Kenneth Dolbey questioned about voice message at trial over murder of David Jenkins in 2022</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/george-town-murder-trial-hears-patrick-dolbey-voicemail-day-8/105789526</link><description>A Tasmanian court hears a man left a voice message "minutes" after an alleged murder, saying he had just seen a person stabbed multiple times.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9adad9a7e9db1d1f9d0d84c3b98e20d4</guid></item><item><title>WA government flags tougher fishing rules, with dhufish and snapper at 'severe risk'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/stricter-fishing-rules-flagged-in-wa/105789778</link><description>Prized fish species including dhufish, snapper and red emperor are at severe risk of population collapse along WA's coast, prompting the state government to flag even stricter measures to protect stocks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fa2f37d5f1c4018f011797861e3f28d</guid></item><item><title>Hobart stadium proponent dismisses planning commission key issues as 'matters of opinion'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/tasmania-hobart-macquarie-point-stadium-tpc-report-opinions/105787276</link><description>The agency behind Hobart's Macquarie Point stadium build says it is undeterred by the three key issues raised by the recent planning commission's final report, arguing it comes down to "priorities".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95214532bc602d9fbcd7742ff8b727a4</guid></item><item><title>Chris Rowbottom explains the Tasmanian government's plan to forge ahead with Hobart's proposed stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/stadium-knockback-not-the-end/105789762</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd372ad670f969aa15aa2bf3779b4d01</guid></item><item><title>Disability employment provider Bedford's financial situation concerns SA, federal government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/disability-employment-provider-bedford-financial-concerns/105787712</link><description>The federal disability minister says his concerns about Australia's second-largest disability employment provider, Bedford, have grown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26088ccc4b0d7adc561a4f0cb51bf652</guid></item><item><title>Family of Aboriginal man killed in Darwin hit-and-run speak out over driver's sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/family-of-man-killed-in-darwin-hit-and-run-speak-out/105787700</link><description>The family of an Aboriginal man killed in a hit-and-run in Darwin have spoken out about the sentence handed to the man who killed him, and the "racist, dehumanising" messages he sent afterwards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc87964fabc0227fe5c48880a62ad60b</guid></item><item><title>Domestic violence comments on fishing show breached classification rules: ACMA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/domestic-violence-comments-on-channel-seven-in-breach-says-acma/105789254</link><description>An exchange about domestic violence between 'Bush Cook Ranger Nick' and the host of Step Outside with Paul Burt, broadcast on 7mate, was in breach of classification rules, the watchdog has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0793754492a6a1f2c4bb7b9112a6cb41</guid></item><item><title>Albanese to meet with Trump after returning from Pacific empty-handed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/anthony-albanese-png-coalition-climate/105767026</link><description>This week in politics, the prime minister returned home from the Pacific empty-handed and the climate debate continued to unsettle the Coalition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e48586b5fbd1829a80e680eae1c55719</guid></item><item><title>Jury urged to consider age of Canberra teen accused of assault, harassment of ex</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/act-jury-retires-in-trial-of-teen-accused-of-assault-harrassment/105788950</link><description>A teenage girl is facing five charges, including an allegation she encouraged her ex-partner to take his own life in an angry stream of messages after she ended their relationship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5324430f58f8ff677877862ff8e960b</guid></item><item><title>National Gathering backs plans for new First Nations body, but tensions remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/national-indigenous-gathering-post-voice-referendum/105787906</link><description>First Nations leaders have endorsed plans for a new national representative body to be established. Here’s what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31e9e3c6ecd0c09297f677025d57e6b6</guid></item><item><title>Albury Wodonga Regional Cancer Centre to become public hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/albury-wodonga-cancer-centre-hospital-ramsay-health-public/105786700</link><description>A major cancer centre on the Victorian-New South Wales border will become a fully public hospital in a move that has caught a healthcare provider by surprise and sparked community concern.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6af03fa22837640d34b69f4c529cc60f</guid></item><item><title>WA coal phase-out uncertainty amid Bluewaters power station closure backflip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/wa-coal-phaseout-uncertain-amid-energy-grid-upgrade-plan/105788864</link><description>Efforts by WA's government to force the premature closure of a privately owned coal plant appear to be unravelling after the market operator backed the power station to keep running towards the end of the decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4f55f2cbe6604ced891de18ea6af73a</guid></item><item><title>Henley residents advised to keep windows, doors closed amid algal bloom crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/sa-beach-residents-algal-bloom-advice/105790474</link><description>Authorities have told a group of residents living near a metropolitan Adelaide beach to close their doors and windows to prevent symptoms related to South Australia's ongoing algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">094835ce530689c0fec54c85ace98853</guid></item><item><title>The Albanese government has learned from the last major climate commitment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/2035-target-energy-debate-power-prices/105787072</link><description>The government is keenly aware that the cost of the transition is a sensitive issue, which is why the prime minister was flanked not just by his climate minister but also his treasurer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb04f44e27c2583896465cd35dce2ecb</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel is the latest to be put on pause. How Trump is influencing the world of late-night TV</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/jimmy-kimmel-stephen-colbert-late-night-in-trump-america/105788394</link><description>Emmys watchers could assume there's never been a better time in Hollywood to hold its most powerful to account, but Jimmy Kimmel's axing proves otherwise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aebb28d38d1022146481b424b8a62c82</guid></item><item><title>Roosters hand Victor Radley 10-match ban for bringing NRL club into disrepute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nrl-sydney-roosters-victor-radley-10-match-ban/105790722</link><description>The Sydney Roosters suspend Victor Radley for 10 matches without pay following media revelations he allegedly requested an illegal substance from former teammate Brandon Smith.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0476c9486f857e18734c6e0056795098</guid></item><item><title>Bindi Magic art exhibition opens in Alice Springs as organisation celebrates 25 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/bindi-magic-art-exhibition-opens-in-alice-springs/105789908</link><description>For 25 years Bindi Mwerre Anthurre Artists has been helping people with a disability to communicate through creativity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac6f9add20cd12006d1f874f0c4e4ec</guid></item><item><title>Ry Jacob Nairn charged with murder after body found in Northampton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/man-charged-with-murder-after-body-found-northampton/105790222</link><description>Ry Jacob Nairn has faced Geraldton Magistrates Court over the death of a 69-year-old man in Northampton earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d19fe3c819e5c9d92d18ba663c9e26f8</guid></item><item><title>Former Roebuck Bay Hotel manager found guilty of raping staff member</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/roebuck-bay-hotel-stewart-burchell-guilty-rape/105788218</link><description>A District Court jury has found Stewart Patrick Burchell raped a former staff member and indecently assaulted several others during his time managing the Roebuck Bay Hotel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4bf9d8271f4c0aafb3b2aaefa1e5200</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with threatening to kill pro-Palestinian rally organiser Remah Naji</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/qld-man-charged-threatening-to-kill-pro-palestinian-organiser/105790946</link><description>Queensland counter-terrorism detectives charge a man with making verbal threats via a carriage service to Remah Naji, a spokesperson for a Brisbane-based pro-Palestinian action group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79fb27d7a9037f6916ba69472b653da7</guid></item><item><title>UK police make arrests for spying as Lithuanian prosecutors target Russia-linked arson network</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/uk-and-lithuania-target-alleged-russian-spies/105791030</link><description>British and Lithuanian authorities have detained people on suspicion of carrying out intelligence-related activities on behalf of Russia</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ddf2a16d6410fbb83734a321a8f2918</guid></item><item><title>NT sports star and school staffer committed to stand trial on student sex charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/nt-sports-star-school-staffer-supreme-court-student-sex-charges/105785686</link><description>A Northern Territory sports star and school staffer will face the Supreme Court on charges of having sex with a student at the school where he worked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5f49a3ef6f1d44a25f8a5ff1e12d5ea</guid></item><item><title>Man jailed for punching boy, 8, threatening to use baby as human shield at WA school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/west-australian-man-jailed-for-punching-child-at-school/105790898</link><description>Details of the 49-year-old's violent outburst at a WA school were revealed during his sentencing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0395a22d78d1606ffa08ed488c473629</guid></item><item><title>Police officer found not guilty of assault during shopping centre scuffle at Batemans Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/police-officer-not-guilty-assault-batemans-bay-shopping-centre/105775816</link><description>A New South Wales police officer is found not guilty of using unreasonable force while removing three girls and a woman from a scuffle at a shopping centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c14d987edba1b9dfa103c7bd81c6de2</guid></item><item><title>All the latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/all-the-latest-financial-news/105791258</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01b895719353cf122016325431e84219</guid></item><item><title>Pope Leo talks Trump, sex abuse scandals, welcoming the LGBTQ+ community and China in his first interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-18/pope-leo-first-interview-discusses-trump-and/105791360</link><description>Pope Leo says he recognises the influence of the United States on world affairs but makes clear he is not a supporter of US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23b4b5afac2ea78ffe86d81dd9c478ea</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Jimmy Kimmel off-air for 'bad ratings' as Democrats slam regulator for 'bullying' US ABC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/trump-kimmel-bad-ratings-democrats-fcc-bullying/105791856</link><description>Prominent leaders in the Democratic Party are accusing the US's communications regulator of "bullying" a network to take the long-running late night show off air.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a35d01ad79ff21536357113faa2da610</guid></item><item><title>AI-generated minister addresses Albanian parliament for first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/ai-generated-minister-addresses-albanian-parliament/105791708</link><description>The world's first AI government minister was appointed last week by Albania's prime minister to oversee decisions on public tenders and to ease voter concerns about corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6ebff04dd13bb994197a62feb3160b9</guid></item><item><title>Clashes and disruption in France amid nationwide protests over Emmanuel Macron's austerity policies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/france-protests-austerity-macron/105791966</link><description>The CGT trade union claims more than a million people took part in demonstrations, while police say more than 90 people have been detained.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8e5b19f23415522807b4f1cf83b7b63</guid></item><item><title>What Donald Trump and Keir Starmer had to say after the US president's historic second UK state visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/what-did-donald-trumps-second-uk-state-visit-achieve/105791450</link><description>The US and UK leaders held a wideranging press conference after nearly two days of carefully crafted pomp and ceremony. Here's what they had to say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec99933b10d971a98ad93c4964a4e4dc</guid></item><item><title>UK prime minister urges Trump to pressure Putin amid escalating 'recklessness'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/trump-starmer-russia-ukraine-oil-drone-strikes/105792022</link><description>Sir Keir Starmer says recent incidents, including Russian drones' incursion in Poland, show the Russian president is not "someone who wants peace".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7d6fb04c7bb765a5f84193a917ae9bc</guid></item><item><title>Independent advice spells out mammoth task ahead for government to reach 2035 target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/the-task-ahead-to-reach-2035-emissions-target/105789538</link><description>Getting to even the bottom end of the government's 62 to 70 per cent emissions reduction target by 2035 will require drastic increases to solar and wind power capacity, electric vehicle take-up and an extension of the safeguard mechanism, according to the Climate Change Authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">112c61869ecf0e96b28c94212500d843</guid></item><item><title>After deadly floods in Bali, its people want answers. Many are blaming overtourism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bali-overtourism-blamed-in-wake-of-deadly-floods/105785674</link><description>Unexpected and deadly flooding rocked Bali last week at a scale many had never experienced before. In the wake of this disaster, the search for answers has begun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">744d51865bef7cb34f9b946d580e8498</guid></item><item><title>The climate conversation is stuck in a loop, but out in the world things are changing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/climate-conversation-is-stuck-but-things-are-changing/105787796</link><description>We don't have to wait for moonshot technologies to reach our climate targets. Most of the solutions to the climate crisis are already around us.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36fccec4cd29f75e6be2134b94cacc07</guid></item><item><title>First Guardian, Shield superannuation disasters expose deep flaws in Australia's $4.3 trillion retirement system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/first-guardian-shield-collapse-asic-and-superannuation-flaws/105783328</link><description>The failed First Guardian and Shield schemes have cost about 12,000 Australians more than $1 billion in retirement savings and exposed deep flaws in how Australia's $4.3 trillion superannuation sector is regulated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b80687a0c984dcbca73fbbe0b5a3dbb7</guid></item><item><title>Therapists, patients raise concerns over The Hobart Clinic closure with fears it could be 'dangerous' for some</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/hobart-clinic-therapists-patients-raise-concern-over-closure/105788162</link><description>For more than four decades, The Hobart Clinic has provided private mental health services to clients. Since the announcement of its October closure, clinic staff, therapists and patients have warned of the negative impact on those reliant on the service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fbc511d8b370e60dea926bbab98c0ab</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout's understanding of patience shows World Athletics Championships performance in 200m semifinal won't be one off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gout-gout-patience-and-time-at-world-athletics-championships/105779054</link><description>Gout Gout's promise and progress are on full display at the 2025 World Athletics Championships. But by showing patience, he could get even better.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5091c293c2d85d7e3aebae30a5ecf2b5</guid></item><item><title>New Huon Aquaculture head Charles von der Heyde says salmon review followed spread of 'gossip'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/huon-aquaculture-new-ceo-charles-von-der-heyde/105789320</link><description>Huon Aquaculture's new chief executive officer has described the upcoming review of Tasmania's salmon industry as "unnecessary", saying that a pause on expansion would not stop the company's plans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd9a2d49083a01e8bc6ceb46139fee35</guid></item><item><title>Home owners warned to consider 'liveability' of properties amid climate change impact warning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/climate-change-impact-on-housing-warning-queensland/105786926</link><description>Property experts say a "dizzying" report forecasting the impacts of worsening climate conditions on Australian properties has sounded a clear warning for the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3721e9130b606a97a1dbc326ef394a9</guid></item><item><title>Parents call for football club culture change after death of 21-year-old son</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/football-club-culture-drugs-alcohol-mental-health/105735836</link><description>Steven Callanan had the world at his feet and loved footy like it was a religion. The talented player could bring together communities while he played, but after a night of partying he took his own life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08703380b01374e017480cd3f1b0b710</guid></item><item><title>Drug checking services handed bitter pill as Queensland government rams through law changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/queensland-government-passes-laws-to-ban-drug-testing/105784786</link><description>The Queensland government has been unrepentant in its tough stance on drugs, with Health Minister Tim Nicholls telling state parliament this week it doesn't "support drug dealers", writes Janelle Miles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af4fc7b6109d00503933ebcf46173537</guid></item><item><title>Carnival of Flowers visitors brace for wet weather while smelling the roses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/storms-set-to-dampen-toowoomba-carnival-of-flowers/105790282</link><description>Visitors flocking to Queensland's Darling Downs for the annual Carnival of Flowers in Toowoomba are advised to take an umbrella, with thunderstorms forecast for the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb4dfb7296770565076ab2a1302356b1</guid></item><item><title>Man fined for dumping 'volatile' chemicals into gutter on suburban Adelaide street</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/robert-wakefield-hydrocarbons-drain-fullarton-erd-court-fine/105783228</link><description>An Adelaide man who emptied drums containing hazardous chemicals into a suburban gutter — causing nearby residents to experience headaches and nausea — has been fined thousands of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61d6ba5dcfcc5161d7db85413cfe7261</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says Jimmy Kimmel was fired for 'lack of talent'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/donald-trump-says-jimmy-kimmel-was-fired-for-lack-of-talent-/105792280</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4701611761257c1687df1bb1a9207e05</guid></item><item><title>Surprise La Niña hints at another wet and stormy Australian summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/la-nina-hints-at-wet-stormy-australian-summer/105790134</link><description>Australia's key drivers of weather variability are stacking up to produce another wet, severe-weather season, with an increased risk of flooding, thunderstorms and cyclones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a42ca16638c1124b410a58f0cccc3ecf</guid></item><item><title>Riverina family grapples with daughter's devastating childhood dementia diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/riverina-family-grapples-with-childhood-dementia-diagnosis-/105789234</link><description>Rachel Anderson says she knew something was not right when her daughter Hannah began struggling to remember things she had just done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30cd776df827d075049497355a0ec58f</guid></item><item><title>Fire at the Jam Factory complex in South Yarra damages Melbourne construction site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/fire-at-the-jam-factory-movie-dining-complex-under-construction/105792298</link><description>Callers to triple-0 report thick smoke billowing from the historical complex in Melbourne's inner south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5145bb865b091f0702cf29ca09b9bd26</guid></item><item><title>ASX rises, Aus Post to resume US parcel deliveries sooner, and BoJ leaves rates unchanged — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/asx-markets-business-live-news-september-19/105792346</link><description>The Australian share market gained, after Wall Street's S&amp;P 500 hit a record high, and the Bank of Japan kept its policy rate steady at 0.5 per cent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a824ad58cb292f6dfdd5a044e5b3e806</guid></item><item><title>Actress Joan Marion never returned to Tasmania, but 'her heart was always in Launceston'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/tasmanian-actress-joan-marion-maintained-links-to-launceston/105774964</link><description>Tasmania's Joan Marion became a star of the screen and stage abroad; her granddaughter says she maintained a connection to Launceston for much of her life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e512ba130678906d9cf74447a7e0d32</guid></item><item><title>Mount Isa waits for '11th-hour' decision on financial support for copper smelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/mount-isa-copper-smelter-glencore-negotiations/105787756</link><description>Copper production is on the chopping block in outback Queensland, with mining giant Glencore about to decide on its future. What is the cost of losing a legacy industry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6389a1b1230c562f480fd57d5cbe967b</guid></item><item><title>Kitchen floor at Palmerston Regional Hospital ripped up, replaced following food safety failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/nt-palmerston-hospital-defective-flooring-freedom-of-information/105783016</link><description>Large sections of flooring at the Northern Territory's newest, multi-million-dollar hospital are having to be ripped up and replaced after the facility failed food safety checks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cd028b5f635de4a7585465e210754bf</guid></item><item><title>Miranda Tapsell and Gwilym Lee show it 'takes a village' to raise a child in Top End Bub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/top-end-bub-miranda-tapsell-gwilym-lee/105775286</link><description>Miranda Tapsell and Gwilym Lee return to their characters from the hit movie, Top End Wedding, to take on parenthood in the TV series, Top End Bub.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6b3a94883d6882b00c7e6f5904787b6</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Albanese seizes on Ley's climate slip up — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/federal-politics-live-sept-19/105790890</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has seized on remarks made by Opposition Leader Sussan Ley about Australia's climate targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d8c53f5355ddd10031e0a3f823e1972</guid></item><item><title>AFL finals fever takes hold as fans line up to buy tickets offline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/fans-line-up-for-afl-grand-final-tickets/105783152</link><description>AFL fans fed up with the online ticketing system have opted to line up in person days in advance to secure their finals tickets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae67e6d9e7b54c457bfa6e91a30fd4f7</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout misses out on 200m final at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gout-gout-misses-out-on-200m-final-at-world-athletics-/105792462</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44814bf4d05e24efb9a86e9874126c57</guid></item><item><title>Young members bring new life to the Rural Fire Service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/rural-fire-service-brigades-seek-new-members/105778996</link><description>Nearly a quarter of all western NSW Rural Fire Service volunteers are older than 70, but some younger recruits are urging others to follow in their footsteps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a9645dec99c6b79501e9b7ecffcd0c1</guid></item><item><title>How Hawthorn can upset Geelong as the Hawks meet the Cats in 2025 AFL preliminary final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/afl-preliminary-final-preview-geelong-vs-hawthorn/105792398</link><description>With a plethora of options up forward, there's one issue the Hawks need to pay attention to out of their back half if they want to upset the Cats tonight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">690d853e61b84e53b4907310f22bd294</guid></item><item><title>No live export ships coming for WA sheep amid high prices, looming ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/no-live-sheep-export-ships-wa-ban-looming/105789752</link><description>Market dynamics are stopping live export ships from coming to WA for the rest of the year, raising the prospect of an official end to the trade years before a legislated ban is enforced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24596fcbd14ee045fa2b692080145ca9</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government commits $4.5 million for locust control as swarms intensify</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/outback-locust-control-funding-queensland-graziers/105787162</link><description>As the native pest destroys crops and pasture across outback Queensland, graziers say authorities must move swiftly to tackle them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2e44afff23dbf4b7b4c4a66888af068</guid></item><item><title>Water Corporation says it got advice wrong on Port Hedland water supply</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/port-hedland-water-supply-at-capacity/105789308</link><description>The state-owned utility says advice that Port Hedland does not have enough water available to support major development was given in error.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48f23c509f4c2d1738afdb51e51b8e70</guid></item><item><title>Gippsland farmer blocks AusNet maintenance workers from entering property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gippsland-farmer-ausnet-transmission-line-dispute/105767192</link><description>A Victorian farmer who has hosted transmission lines on his property for decades says he is sick of maintenance workers damaging his property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">567d67427b571a1d541a4aceb24ac48b</guid></item><item><title>Australian Submarine Agency lobbies Fremantle locals amid protest over AUKUS defence hub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/submarine-agency-lobbies-fremantle-locals-amid-aukus-protest/105791174</link><description>A push to earn the public's trust over a defence hub south of Perth by the Australian Submarine Agency draws protesters and sceptical residents in Fremantle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8095393b39a51688425e02f38c8b989</guid></item><item><title>Warm currents bring tens of thousands of giant yellowfin tuna to NSW South Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/unprecedented-yellowfin-tuna-season-south-coast/105784426</link><description>Fishers are reporting an unprecedented number of yellowfin tuna travelling from the tropics to the NSW South Coast, causing "mayhem" and excitement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d71fe5d9066c0d4471f7c22b0f966ba4</guid></item><item><title>NT Director of Public Prosecutions files appeal against Jake Danby fatal hit-and-run sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/nt-dpp-files-appeal-against-fatal-hit-and-run-jake-danby/105793334</link><description>The NT's Director of Public Prosecutions has filed an appeal against the sentence of hit-and-run driver Jake Danby, who killed one Aboriginal man and injured another.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e3838dc5519f987bfb13479b62436c3</guid></item><item><title>Gardens of Stone State Conservation Area walks open path to incredible vistas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gardens-of-stone-state-conservation-area-walks-open/105788604</link><description>New South Wales National Parks and Wildlife staff have spent 18 months transforming eroded vehicle trails into rehabilitated walks, opening previously inaccessible viewpoints.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0da6f8f660e8929fd1ce6563b317648c</guid></item><item><title>QCOAL's Cook Colliery coal mine in central Queensland to close half of operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/cook-colliery-coal-mine-to-close-half-of-operation/105792906</link><description>A third Queensland coal miner has confirmed job cuts as it prepares to close one of its underground mine sites, with the company also putting the blame on rising costs and state government royalties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adae0677efe1894effb74c23021af5ba</guid></item><item><title>Rabbits cause 'devastating' damage to Junee cemetery in southern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/rabbits-cause-devastating-damage-to-junee-cemetery-southern-nsw/105792784</link><description>The Junee Shire Council says it is battling a rabbit problem, which forced a recent closure of the town's main cemetery for a week, including on Father's Day, for a baiting program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6e24632645222977003b4a6af3561fc</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos discovery further delays Willyama High School demolition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/demolition-of-mouldy-willyama-high-school-delayed-by-asbestos/105733678</link><description>Nearly two years after a mould-infested high school was closed indefinitely, high-risk friable asbestos has caused further delays to its demolition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a23e41ae074ff173d5db5c3d17aa081</guid></item><item><title>RONA. weaves together country, colonialism and club music on new EP It's All Here</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/rona-its-all-here-ep-bush-beats-country-colonialism-club-music/105758094</link><description>This Kaytetye producer has a fresh take on the space race that draws from First Nations knowledge and culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f63cbfd798f6826103c82f171f571494</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Melania Trump bonds with royals over scouts, miniature books and bug hotels</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/melania-trump-queen-camilla-princess-kate-royal-engagements/105792736</link><description>As US President Donald Trump left Windsor to meet UK Prime Minister Sir Keir Starmer, first lady Melania Trump spent the day with the Princess of Wales and Queen Camilla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d9de57ca47acbc2799702a7bbebec86</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man jailed for three years after violently assaulting his partner until she was unconscious</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/act-man-jailed-for-attacking-partner-choking-until-unconscious/105794116</link><description>The 43-year-old man was found guilty of attacking his partner, despite her having withdrawn her complaint against him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c96ba96c080cca0bb9360328dd58b82d</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann likely to face four-day hearing in Tasmania over motor vehicle stealing charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bruce-lehrmann-likely-to-face-four-day-hearing/105794304</link><description>Former Liberal staffer Bruce Lehrmann appears in the Hobart Magistrates Court after pleading not guilty to one count of motor vehicle stealing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">680bec6e2ce2b4d53ae9b27667c53e23</guid></item><item><title>Green Gravity secures old coal mine shaft to test gravitational energy storage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/green-gravity-deal-old-mine-shaft-gravitational-energy-storage/105782756</link><description>A disused coal mine in Wollongong will be the first test site for a renewable energy company that lowers weights down old mine shafts to spin turbines and create electricity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">624bc063af2f9be2f1ecc1717cd562e3</guid></item><item><title>Russell Vale Mine Shaft 4 to trial Green Gravity renewable energy technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/russell-vale-mine-shaft-4-to-trial-green-gravity/105780830</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89d1b1e00372ede47986a5b7fb9f02ce</guid></item><item><title>China urges Papua New Guinea not to exclude other countries after it signed 'Pukpuk' communique with Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/china-warns-papua-new-guinea-against-bilateral-deal-australia/105794018</link><description>China has urged Papua New Guinea not to sign any deal that might exclude or restrict third parties from cooperating with the Pacific nation, as Australia scrambles to clinch a landmark defence treaty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad04d0391ea73681a5f0351d55692b32</guid></item><item><title>Matthew Draganoff sentenced for murder of tenant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/matthew-draganoff-sentenced-murder/105792818</link><description>A man who was found guilty of the "execution-style murder" of his "unarmed" tenant on the northern outskirts of Adelaide has been jailed for at least 28 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa3b06fba77a80f9fd7bdb530be66fe4</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A royal visit, a glitzy award show and a new city plays host to Laneway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/september-19-friday-news-quiz/105788054</link><description>A lot happened this week. Have you been paying attention?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62ecd5fbe8b87d12bdb2cd9e003b1e8d</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley returns after press conference to clarify her comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/sussan-ley-returns-after-press-conference-to/105794464</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd5bbd98a0172483c48df6e2c1dfdf74</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins hints at Ashes strategy amid recovery from back injury with 'starting aim' of playing in all five Tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/ashes-pat-cummins-australia-england-back-injury/105794594</link><description>As the men's Ashes approaches, the Australian captain reveals his hopes for taking part in the five-Test series against England as he steps up his injury recovery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cfd72c66626cbf51c7aab8346b10585</guid></item><item><title>Cowboys prepare to make NRLW finals debut against Sharks in Townsville</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/nrlw-north-queensland-cowboys-play-sharks-in-first-finals-match/105790490</link><description>As the Cowboys eye the path to premiership glory ahead of their sudden-death semifinal against the Sharks, they are also creating pathways off field for the next generation of NRLW stars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45bc33d0af030a85b06c99d0ea5dc2f8</guid></item><item><title>Gareth Ward's victim tells sentencing hearing of abuse trauma</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gareth-ward-victim-speaks-sentencing-hearing/105793278</link><description>One of the victims of convicted sex offender Gareth Ward has told the former NSW MP's sentencing hearing the abuse left him traumatised and suicidal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c555dbb452cc7bfbec788ed505ddc1a</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Greens candidate Hannah Thomas injured in pro-Palestinian protest awarded $22k over dropped case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/nsw-hannah-thomas-court-costs-dropped-charges/105794888</link><description>Hannah Thomas, who sustained an eye injury during an arrest at a pro-Palestinian rally, is awarded legal costs to the tune of nearly $22,000 after all of her charges were dropped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac34d8d826da71ac7bf6bc3b8d3c5ac0</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout receives praise from Noah Lyles at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/world-athletics-championships-tokyo-gout-gout-noah-lyles/105794882</link><description>Nothing Noah Lyles has seen in Gout Gout during the past week at the World Athletics Championships in Tokyo has changed the American great's opinion of the Australian teenager.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28b33140a9273c415fa78f470c7af769</guid></item><item><title>Bus driver pleads not guilty to dangerous driving over triple-fatal collision in Gumlu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bus-driver-in-gumlu-fatal-pleads-not-guilty-to-dangerous-driving/105792662</link><description>A Townsville bus driver involved in a crash that killed three women in north Queensland last year pleads not guilty to dangerous driving causing death or grievous bodily harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">970c592c33595cd809efea0f4925bf86</guid></item><item><title>Former police officer sentenced over perjury in NRL star Jack de Belin's rape case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/ex-police-officer-avoids-jail-for-perjury-in-de-belin-rape-case/105789796</link><description>A former police officer received a 12-month intensive community correction order after he lied about accessing privileged text messages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21518a52dfd7cac5d30c94281cb36bdb</guid></item><item><title>Late-night hosts call out 'unitary intimidation' in aftermath of Jimmy Kimmel's axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/stephen-colbert-seth-meyers-jon-stewart-back-jimmy-kimmel/105794466</link><description>Jimmy Kimmel's fellow late-night stars accuse the Trump administration of overriding free speech with the indefinite axing of the ABC America host, as parent company, Walt Disney, faces growing protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2f64fab37da9ee4ace2388f587b1eab</guid></item><item><title>Hakyung Lee, mother accused of killing children, had a 'disease of the mind', defence expert tells court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/hakyung-lee-suitcase-murders-auckland-new-zealand/105781562</link><description>Hakyung Lee has been charged with murdering her children and has pleaded not guilty by reason of insanity after leaving their bodies in an Auckland storage facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">690cb00a0c2ca94e57c34909bfc58001</guid></item><item><title>Driver, bus company added as cross-defendants in wedding bus crash class action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/class-action-seeks-damages-after-fatal-greta-bus-crash/105793458</link><description>Jailed bus driver Brett Button and the bus company that employed him have been added as defendants in a class action stemming from a crash that killed 10 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65dfe5148085e247e6293ae5a2790844</guid></item><item><title>What to know about the Macrons' legal bid to prove the French first lady was not born a man</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/what-to-know-about-macrons-defamation-suit-against-candace-owens/105794900</link><description>Emmanuel Macron and his wife, Brigitte Macron, have said they intend to provide evidence in court to disprove a right-wing influencer's claims the French first lady is transgender.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4503c882debdf66e431a20c149a3de3b</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann applies for Toowoomba rape complainant's phone download as court hears some evidence may be missing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bruce-lehrmann-toowoomba-rape-complainant-mobile-phone/105792890</link><description>Mr Lehrmann is facing two charges of rape, alleged to have occurred in Toowoomba in 2021. He's indicated he intends to plead not guilty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74c1ad5180bcd48cd8a70cf3751c0111</guid></item><item><title>Sharks vow not to taunt Raiders in sudden-death NRL semifinal as minor premiers look to bounce back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/nrl-cronulla-sharks-canberra-raiders-semi-final/105795410</link><description>Cronulla suggests it will not niggle Canberra in Saturday night's semifinal, despite the Brisbane Broncos successfully getting under the Raiders' skin in their thrilling one-point win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de811a022c87a3d1a6baef74c8c54ce6</guid></item><item><title>How to build a flourishing garden in a courtyard or smaller space</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/how-to-create-a-garden-with-not-much-space-or-sun/105763316</link><description>Living in a smaller space doesn't mean you can't have a lush garden. Here's how to rejuvenate your garden with some easy tips.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10fca8a72dcf1eb2dd616158042c2c3b</guid></item><item><title>Varroa mite could still be in SA despite removal of infected hives, PIRSA says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/varroa-mite-threat-south-australia-pirsa/105787606</link><description>PIRSA says there is a chance the deadly parasite remains in the state where it was detected for the first time earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">199d5d292dcbe93495cf2534c11fa8a2</guid></item><item><title>Justin Holbrook arrives at Newcastle Knights after club's wooden spoon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/newcastle-knights-coach-justin-holbrook-arrives-club/105787242</link><description>Justin Holbrook has started his tenure as Newcastle head coach, tasked with turning the struggling NRL side around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da5ef0727b375ae392cde4c88789e5ee</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill man runs 1,100km to Newcastle to raise funds for Angelman syndrome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/broken-hill-man-runs-to-newcastle-fund-angelman-syndrome/105788134</link><description>A Broken Hill man has run to Newcastle to raise funds and awareness for a rare condition called as Angelman syndrome.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b64dbd898ade0be1f04b32775520eb67</guid></item><item><title>AFLW great Daisy Pearce aiming to take down former club Demons with Eagles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/aflw-daisy-pearce-west-coast-eaglers-melbourne-demons/105795842</link><description>With a West Coast Eagles squad intent of reaching the finals, coach Daisy Pearce has the club she captained to a premiership in her sights this weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4489526b70edc342d88d5fdd23730376</guid></item><item><title>NT attorney-general accused of hiding potential conflict of interest in link to hit-and-run driver</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/nt-attorney-general-related-to-hit-run-driver-jake-danby/105793244</link><description>The Northern Territory's attorney-general is facing backlash after failing to publicly declare a potential conflict of interest regarding a fatal hit-and-run driver before court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">595c64791f195e8a4086a0b80f352e3a</guid></item><item><title>Coronial inquiry into death of newborn Thea Flaskett concludes with family impact statement read</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/qld-thea-flaskett-inquest-concludes-final-day/105795202</link><description>The mother of the "miracle baby" who died hours after her birth read out a family impact statement to the court, on the final day of a coronial inquiry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c9dab527e8a094111904e4c9a6774fd</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man charged with murder after assault victim dies of injuries in hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/act-man-charged-with-murder-assault-victim-dies-in-hospital/105795262</link><description>A 49-year-old Canberra man is charged with murder after a man he fought at the caravan park where they both lived died of his injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">833c0e140bea35199fdb507fae544a4b</guid></item><item><title>InterPrac boss says 'maybe we could have done more' to prevent First Guardian and Shield losses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/interprac%E2%80%99s-under-investigation-by-asic-but-its/105796044</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ac6a09728d88f3a8e841310c1dbfa2a</guid></item><item><title>Optus network failure impacted triple-0 calls in several states where patients died after 'totally unacceptable' lapse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/optus-network-failure-three-people-dead-triple-zero/105796226</link><description>Three people have died, including an eight-week-old baby, after a technical failure impacted hundreds of triple-0 calls on the Optus network.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b1c63e34b7af276f5fb1c828c90e230</guid></item><item><title>Patrick Dangerfield stars to send Geelong into the AFL grand final as concussion rules Tom Stewart out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/afl-preliminary-final-geelong-vs-hawthorn-live-blog/105779366</link><description>Geelong utility Tom Stewart will miss the AFL grand final, but coach Chris Scott feels his Cats are in a great position to win the premiership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dd33f956ae78d4a6741605fb30417b7</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull breaks Oceania record to power into 800m final at World Athletics Championships 2025 in Tokyo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-in-tokyo-day-7/105795898</link><description>Jess Hull has broken the Australian record in the semifinals of the women's 800m. Mackenzie Little qualifies for the javelin final with one giant throw.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a436617f26f5157153dcdaa87ab2099</guid></item><item><title>Measles alert issued for Gold Coast as Queensland cases climb</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/measles-alert-issued-for-gold-coast-as-queensland-cases-rises/105795806</link><description>The highly infectious measles virus is detected on the Gold Coast, just a day after new cases in Far North Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e39d40473f02a7a3bd2fc3d6ed314805</guid></item><item><title>Potato mop-top virus impossible to eradicate, Biosecurity Tasmania says as ninth incursion detected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/potato-mop-top-virus-tasmania-eradication-impossible/105794756</link><description>Potato mop-top virus is here to stay and its source is unlikely to ever be discovered, Biosecurity Tasmania has said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c268afe33690f3e84ce03a889a9681b2</guid></item><item><title>Optus CEO says 'completely unacceptable' triple-0 failure resulted in three deaths — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/optus-reveals-three-dead-after-triple-zero-calls-impacted-live/105796298</link><description>Optus CEO Stephen Rue confirmed that a technical failure resulted in the failure of triple-0 emergency calls in South Australia, the Northern Territory and Western Australia, impacting hundreds of customers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac98c3942c4b566d30914b48eb1cf890</guid></item><item><title>All the latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/all-the-latest-financial-news/105796416</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6301e2bdeedf208ea5d5c5a791f35a27</guid></item><item><title>Optus CEO apologises to customers impacted by major network outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/optus-ceo-apologises-to-customers-impacted-by/105796546</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76fd1e56e640c3fcc4ec93132683da1d</guid></item><item><title>Optus CEO confirms three deaths during network outage affecting emergency calls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/optus-ceo-confirms-three-deaths-during-network/105796530</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2616d41c37b08dbe3f6b1464bddea5b</guid></item><item><title>Perth childcare worker Robert David Reti found not guilty of indecently touching two young girls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/perth-childcare-worker-robert-reti-indecent-dealing-verdict-/105796570</link><description>A Perth childcare worker is found not guilty of indecently touching two girls, aged four and six, at two separate centres in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">627fdd70f61b4fc5965665dfc1a9ff66</guid></item><item><title>Optus makes another catastrophic mistake and three people are dead after letting customers down 'when they needed them most'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/optus-mistake-leaves-three-dead-triple-zero-failure/105796400</link><description>Optus made another catastrophic mistake, but this time three people are dead after the telecommunications giant let customers down "when they needed them most".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a4205c3411b4bd0d3b271674a71744e</guid></item><item><title>Top stories from ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/top-stories-from-abc-news/105796654</link><description>Listen to ABC News interviews and commentary and analysis from radio programs like AM, PM and The World Today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1fd0a20d62045d3452704cde83ff85c</guid></item><item><title>Russia appeals International Civil Aviation Organization's decision blaming it for downing MH17 in 2014</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/russia-appeals-icao-decision-on-mh17-downing/105796644</link><description>Moscow's appeal submitted to the International Court of Justice contested ICAO's decision "on all grounds".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">242a8a4e3d85b9178ecf6cb8e522f4ba</guid></item><item><title>US President Donald Trump says TikTok deal approved following call with China President Xi Jinping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/donald-trump-xi-jinping-approve-tiktok-deal/105796662</link><description>The deal would transfer TikTok's US assets to US owners from ByteDance, according to sources familiar with the deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e668326b33f0b005a99e21b7462b2622</guid></item><item><title>Russian warplanes breach NATO airspace over Estonia as tensions rise on alliance's eastern flank</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/estonia-says-russian-jets-violated-its-airspace/105796844</link><description>Three MiG-31 fighter jets entered its airspace without permission and stayed there for a total of 12 minutes, Estonia's foreign minister said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35a8aa2e96b2ce3a88319fbde5a6fa59</guid></item><item><title>A secret lived in plain sight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/a-secret-lived-in-plain-sight/105708692</link><description>Alliyah is reckoning with a decade of grooming and abuse at the hands of a trusted teacher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e77cd7303996f6436a98d30e0bbc14ed</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the Optus outage which disrupted triple-zero calls, linked to three deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/what-we-know-about-optus-network-outage/105796618</link><description>It's been two days since three people died after a devastating Optus outage caused hundreds of emergency calls to fail, but information about the incident remains scarce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81d841cfe097dc82a144e78eb4423953</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley and the Coalition face a ticking time bomb</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/sussan-ley-coalition-climate-donor-laws/105778688</link><description>The opposition leader survived a bruising post-election fight that left conservatives seething and has been left with no natural allies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40ee9b3f20f82e0c58514ac8c3e2b667</guid></item><item><title>Israel faces pressure over Gaza ahead of General Assembly as United Nations confronts its own identity crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/united-nations-general-assembly-israel-trump-climate/105778680</link><description>The UN's role in areas beyond diplomacy, such as in humanitarian aid and refugees, cultural heritage, health, and climate, are all under assault from savage budget cuts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">375fa7d383a147731e52173b0d2956ad</guid></item><item><title>Climate risks report paints grim picture, but expert on societal collapse explains giving up is not the answer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/climate-fatalism-in-wake-of-climate-risk-report/105780598</link><description>Lethal heat, mosquito-borne viruses, mass displacement and conflict — we got a glimpse into a grim climate future. Can imagining the end of the world be good for us, or is it a path to apathy?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8893cee718d8e9b52a9ba6f66c57ef49</guid></item><item><title>The inside story of an ABC report that helped scuttle Australia's biggest foreign takeover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/abc-report-helped-scuttle-abu-dhabi-santos-takeover/105792998</link><description>Secrecy around a major methane leak helped Santos avoid public scrutiny for years. It backfired after a prospective bidder reportedly found out via an ABC News report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1a48ea533343bfad555aa06ec237be7</guid></item><item><title>Afghan refugees in Pakistan facing deportation amid local crackdown and Australian visa delays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/afghan-refugees-forced-back-from-pakistan/105697460</link><description>After fleeing Afghanistan, many refugees in Pakistan are at risk of being deported back amid a crackdown on temporary cardholders as they wait for humanitarian visas from Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18f5de78f692ffa221aeec3ce52a2172</guid></item><item><title>Senator calls for 'heads on spikes' to deter superannuation mismanagement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/heat-on-asic-first-guardian-shield-fallout-superannuation-fails/105790322</link><description>As questions mount about how Australia's retirement funds industry is regulated, a senator says regulator ASIC must more quickly and forcefully enforce the law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1384c0e0503cda0c65ca3e1bb58adaa9</guid></item><item><title>How Jess Hull's 800m 'side quest' could see her stun at the 2025 World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/jess-hull-800m-side-project-world-athletics-championships/105796664</link><description>Jess Hull was concerned that a focus on the 800m was potentially hurting her endurance. Instead, her "side quest" could lead to a second world championship medal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb294ce7c25dd98766d41b31ae040f4f</guid></item><item><title>Investigation of eye-maker's online presence reveals multiple red flags</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/jack-mcdonald-ocularist-website-warning-signs/105788574</link><description>A reverse-image search of ocularist Jack McDonald's website shows that receptionist "Nadia" also appears on a dentistry blog and is known as "Donna" on a self-help guru's site. It's just one of the red flags that ABC NEWS Verify spotted during its investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d081d56d6116ad09be5333b0e23b73bc</guid></item><item><title>Technology is driving a quiet revolution in the way players relate to golf</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/rise-of-virtual-golf/105774244</link><description>Virtual golf venues are popping up en masse, as the sport adapts to suit the players of a new era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3559da2726e2650b689729488aaf246</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's historic second state visit to the UK was filled with risks for Keir Starmer. Did it pay off?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/donald-trump-uk-state-visit-keir-starmer-special-relationship/105796972</link><description>Britain rolled the dice on an historic second state visit for the US president in a year of domestic and international political turmoil. It found out where its relationship with Washington was at.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd5ca36baa0fcc9dba0912b19652f0a9</guid></item><item><title>Monash IVF pauses donor treatments in NSW as it conducts review of patient records</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/monash-ivf-suspend-donor-treatment-nsw-family-limit/105794278</link><description>Patients have been left blindsided by Monash IVF's decision to temporarily halt treatments using donated eggs and sperm in New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd3fe7d207c0aa4729ed1fbb6dd7e3ea</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood and Brisbane meet again, two years on from classic 2023 grand final, for tantalising rematch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/afl-preliminary-final-collingwood-brisbane-preview/105793028</link><description>The 2023 grand final will go down as one of the best deciders in AFL history, and though the stakes are only marginally lower two years on, the numbers suggest Collingwood and Brisbane's 2025 preliminary final could be another classic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ec81c3cb39b858091335eeff1f3c10e</guid></item><item><title>Woman's snake bite death in Katherine sparks warnings against complacency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/katherine-nt-snake-bite-death-warning/105796156</link><description>Experts say snake bite victims may not even be aware their lives are in imminent danger after a woman was killed by a snake in Katherine earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">066248bbb54d3234414fbd1c1bdacc03</guid></item><item><title>Federal government's agriculture emissions reductions 'ambitious' but 'achievable'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/agriculture-industry-responds-toemissions-reduction-expectations/105792968</link><description>A professor of carbon farming says the agriculture industry will "naturally" contribute to a 28 per cent emissions reduction projected by 2050, but is unlikely to hit its own net-zero targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be4c701559d4d36210ea847a9fa9b087</guid></item><item><title>Matt Kean on the govt's 2035 emissions target || Insiders: On Background</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/matt-kean-on-the-govts-2035-emissions-target/105796304</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcd3e2b5831d08304762f405e7ba4864</guid></item><item><title>Pink Floyd's album and ode to Syd Barrett Wish You Were Here turns 50</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/pink-floyd-wish-you-were-here-turns-50/105782374</link><description>Pink Floyd looked to the past to find a way forward after the massive success of Dark Side Of The Moon in 1973. The result was Wish You Were Here, released 50 years ago this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78a552157b44e92ce3d5f5773e471f3d</guid></item><item><title>New seller disclosure laws expected to redefine property deals in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/qld-disclosure-laws-transparency-and-costs/105789466</link><description>Solicitors are charging anywhere from $300 up to $1,000 to help fill out a form required under the state's new laws, according to a Brisbane buyer's agent and law expert.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4716dcf79cf2c7732ae102e8c503499</guid></item><item><title>Labor reshuffles its furniture as the Liberals try to save what’s left</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/sa-labor-cabinet-reshuffle/105796022</link><description>Two resigning ministers, two major broken promises and an unfolding ecological crisis confront SA Labor six months out from a state election. Yet it's the Liberal Party staring down electoral punishment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80db0e8b704c5090677143ef7dd0b1e3</guid></item><item><title>Australian Grand Prix fans feel the pinch with Formula 1 ticket prices on track to eclipse AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/formula-1-melbourne-grand-prix-ticket-price-hike/105762778</link><description>As general admission ticket prices for the Melbourne Grand Prix accelerate past other marquee sport events, fans are questioning whether the growing expense is worth it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f824480e01384ad2215c9f8f7a0e93c6</guid></item><item><title>Judge throws out Donald Trump's multi-billion-dollar New York Times lawsuit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/judge-throws-out-trump-ny-times-lawsuit/105797222</link><description>The US president's $US15 billion defamation lawsuit against The New York Times has been labelled "improper" by a federal judge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ca8cb4b4a1a6f182f11bd67499c7050</guid></item><item><title>NSW RFS provides tips on preparing your home for bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/rfs-tips-on-preparing-your-home-for-bushfires/105787496</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9fb9639adb5adfa4953dfde776d2aeb</guid></item><item><title>What time does the F1 Azerbaijan Grand Prix start? How can I watch it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/f1-azerbaijan-grand-prix-start-time-how-to-watch-oscar-piastri/105775142</link><description>Oscar Piastri returns to the streets of Baku — one year on from a terrific victory — holding a 31-point lead in the Formula 1 drivers' championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0435d8809244272f8bc9895f461e80b6</guid></item><item><title>Freezing rain or 12,000km away, these green Vikings will do anything for their beloved Canberra Raiders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/raiders-nrl-superfans-still-have-a-spring-in-their-step/105790848</link><description>Simon Tayoun's been a devout member of the Green Army since he watched his first-ever game of rugby league in 1987, and now he's become an unofficial mascot by bringing his custom drum to every game he can to lead the Viking Clap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f466609b2333997a9641d35394e062b7</guid></item><item><title>Perth family endure cold, wet winter in bus amid worsening housing crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/perth-man-living-in-bus-as-housing-crisis-worsens/105745228</link><description>A Perth man who has been sleeping rough in a bus with his family for the past three years wonders if he would be better off with a roof over his head and regular meals in jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e0a5450599eb2f6d62faabef19aae84</guid></item><item><title>Storm damage sees shark net installation delay at Sydney's Shark Beach in Nielsen Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/shark-net-installation-delay-at-sydney-shark-beach-neilsen-park/105794772</link><description>Shark Beach in Sydney's east is seasonally netted with an enclosure to protect swimmers from sharks during Sydney's warmer months — but for the upcoming school holidays, it is unlikely the nets will be installed in time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fb506200ed1eacf664848d3c53c5964</guid></item><item><title>Remote NSW council holds election after 12 years in administration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/central-darling-shire-council-election-nsw-votes-after-12-years/105757794</link><description>The 700 voters living in the remote Central Darling Shire Council area of New South Wales will finally head to the polls to vote again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2af8d61243c1a142aa5a6b000bb6dea5</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's tree fern trade accused of 'greenwashing' over native forest logging links, but others say it is sustainable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/tasmanias-tree-ferns-for-sale/105686750</link><description>Thousands of native tree ferns are harvested from Tasmania's forests for export each year. Some say the trade saves ferns from destruction, while others accuse the industry of greenwashing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a230cf7b613ce9f9908a403f525eaa2</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk’s murder sparks calls for revenge | If You're Listening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/charlie-kirk%E2%80%99s-murder-sparks-calls-for-revenge-if/105796612</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e5ca74218a7fb1258d28dbd24b3cf0f</guid></item><item><title>Chelsea FC Women's star Sam Kerr presented with special football to mark 100 goals for club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/like-a-new-person-sam-kerr-all-smiles-after-comeback-goal/105797260</link><description>Sam Kerr is honoured with a special football to mark her 100 goals for Chelsea — and she can't stop smiling since the landmark strike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52628ebbe474caa569cc4274ed7dde0b</guid></item><item><title>Victor Caulfield moved to Florence in his 70s and became an artists' model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/victor-caulfield-moved-to-florence-and-became-an-artists-model/105762988</link><description>Victor Caulfield packed up his Australian home and moved to Italy, where he fell into the art scene as an accidental model.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf11c6e1cc2bef7d1c59c017a7b1915d</guid></item><item><title>British couple freed from Afghanistan's Taliban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/uk-couple-released-by-taliban/105797262</link><description>The couple, who ran a charity in Afghanistan where they had lived for 18 years, were freed after months of negotiations with the Taliban by Qatar in coordination with Britain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c3a221396bea8b5f6b5593e7f36bf7b</guid></item><item><title>British couple embrace family after Taliban release</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/british-couple-embrace-family-after-taliban-release/105797320</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd2bb119d8a7aa3913b7c1fcb94d7394</guid></item><item><title>South Australians reflect on life, 50 years after homosexuality was decriminalised</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/sa-50-year-anniversary-decriminalisation/105749058</link><description>Since homosexuality was decriminalised in South Australia half a century ago, LGBTIQA+ people say the state has made strides, but there is still some way to go towards equality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7eaea53257eef0f6a9ab9627e79de7ac</guid></item><item><title>One-tray honey chicken wings are an easy family dinner - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/one-tray-sticky-chicken-wings/105658174</link><description>It’s easy to make these irresistibly sticky wings that will have you licking your fingers and reaching for more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b49e38fcb0cc57c3220c789ba5301301</guid></item><item><title>Eucalypt trail named after botanist Dean Nicolle opens in SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/rail-trail-forest-blyth-dean-nicolle-eucalypt-walk-sa/105779316</link><description>A unique partnership between an artist and a botanist has resulted in an old rail corridor in South Australia becoming an eucalypt forest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a634367098f7c56af4d4f383b07c47fd</guid></item><item><title>More than 800 Indonesian students get food poisoning from free school meals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/mass-food-poisoning-indonesian-students-government-free-meals/105797326</link><description>Over 800 students fall sick in two cases of mass food poisoning in one week after consuming free school meals sponsored by the Indonesian government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfb25b0f8356cd7bf1bbc285b8ae6a80</guid></item><item><title>Kianga coal mine tragedy 50 years later and the reforms that followed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/kianga-mine-disaster-moura-reforms-50-years-on/105790100</link><description>Half a century after the Kianga mine explosion killed 13 workers in central Queensland, a community gathers to remember the tragedy as survivors and experts raise fresh concerns about ongoing safety risks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1421c884189e1563dea4eee7ea99764</guid></item><item><title>Why was CommBank down? Customers impacted by planned outage for maintenance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/commonwealth-bank-commbank-app-outage-maintenance-/105797316</link><description>The Commonwealth Bank originally estimated the planned maintenance would mean some features would be unavailable until about 9am AEST — but it took longer than expected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b38e422c5f4dd731cfb79e521009be26</guid></item><item><title>'America is not happy': ABC under fire for pulling Jimmy Kimmel Live!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/complaints-about-kimmel-axing-meant-for-us-abc-sent-to-australia/105793428</link><description>The ABC has received hundreds of complaints about US talk show Jimmy Kimmel Live! being pulled off air and threats to boycott sponsors ... but that's the problem when two broadcasters from different countries share a name!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">058463060dc5663ada42854e5496b80c</guid></item><item><title>Wide Bay affordable housing estate scrapped due to 'unfeasible' costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/green-space-saved-as-bundaberg-housing-estate-scrapped/105792456</link><description>A controversial housing estate that would have been built on 26 hectares of Bundaberg's green space has been scrapped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">265b915b78077a19eec8da45dffd2c79</guid></item><item><title>Female jockeys on the rise after a dominant season across northern WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/female-jockeys-dominate-northern-wa-racing/105793598</link><description>The number of female apprentice jockeys skyrockets across Australia, as women take out seven of 10 cup races across northern WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec1f4d0151714a973e804ebb2f541313</guid></item><item><title>Richmond fire spreads through three shops, causing significant damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/richmond-three-shops-damaged-by-fire-burnley-street/105797290</link><description>The early morning blaze has caused significant damage to the Burnley Street businesses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">651ac94ae4556838da777e82d397d051</guid></item><item><title>Canada beats New Zealand 34-19 to reach Women's Rugby World Cup final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/canada-dazzles-to-end-new-zealand-women-rugby-world-cup/105797400</link><description>A changing of the guard in women's rugby union as two-time defending world champions New Zealand is beaten for the first time at the tournament since 2014 by a brilliant Canadian side.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db955f9919a07cd55204d1ec6a7e244c</guid></item><item><title>Victorian apiarists finding it harder to access public land 'vital' for bees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/victorian-beekeeper-concerns-about-reduced-access-to-public-land/105788666</link><description>Apiarists are concerned they are losing access to public land in Victoria that provides a critical food source for their hives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc97f3abc783cc7a3d5c36c88876bac1</guid></item><item><title>Near-blinded police officer reunites with those who saved him after rural motorcycle crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/police-officer-john-kenworthy-returns-to-thank-those-at-crash/105724428</link><description>Police officer John Kenworthy returns to thank the first responders in Mackay, and others who were with him in his darkest moments, after a rural motorcycle crash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af7195369dfa834fd85a7caed2683441</guid></item><item><title>Trump says the US has fatally struck another alleged drug-smuggling boat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/trump-says-the-us-has-fatally-struck-another/105797516</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e4cbf81ef58b8503289114b9de47803</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says three 'narcoterrorists' killed in US strike on alleged drug boat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/us-military-carries-out-another-strike-on-alleged-drug-boat/105797450</link><description>This is the third fatal strike the US military has carried out this month on a vessel allegedly carrying drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf472bdd8248b7f4868d93c2f0b2c4f1</guid></item><item><title>Turtling tracking in Broome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/turtling-tracking-in-broome/105794988</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10cb5e530edb2253e9361a5ada40925c</guid></item><item><title>World-first turtle tracking reveals secrets of flatback turtles in WA's Roebuck Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/world-first-tracking-of-flatback-turtles-in-roebuck-bay-broome/105794534</link><description>GPS tracking, motion sensors and video cameras reveal where flatback turtles in Broome's Roebuck Bay feed and travel, contributing to a richer understanding of the vulnerable species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6abd49307f41fd71e6160fa5f1479b4d</guid></item><item><title>Optus failure to pass on details about deaths 'beggars belief', premier says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/premier-slams-optus-over-triple-0-outage-linked-to-deaths/105797404</link><description>Optus has come under fire from South Australia's premier who accused the telco of not disclosing to police the addresses, phone numbers or the names of the people affected by an outage that sparked triple-0 call failures linked to three deaths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eabee930f01140e7cb723cca048d206</guid></item><item><title>Freezing rain or 12,000km away, these green Vikings will do anything for their beloved Canberra Raiders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/freezing-rain-or-12,000km-away,-these-green/105797680</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff39865f3b0a61caa40366eb6bb508cd</guid></item><item><title>Canberra Raiders receive NRL semifinal blow, losing five-eighth Ethan Strange to illness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/raiders-star-ethan-strange-ruled-out-of-nrl-semifinal/105797628</link><description>Canberra Raiders are forced to reshuffle their team on the morning of the semifinal against Cronulla after illness struck wunderkind Ethan Strange.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f5873d0c087b62f90bf15bc27f5fcab</guid></item><item><title>Teenager pleads guilty to manslaughter over Hobart waterfront drowning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/youth-pleads-guilty-to-drowning-death-man-hobart-waterfront/105794682</link><description>Deepinderjeet Singh was sitting with a woman near Franklin Wharf in Hobart in late January 2024 when a 17-year-old boy pushed the pair into the water and stole the woman's handbag.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80c316b498383625f4162e7c1e66ea7c</guid></item><item><title>Critical incident declared after man dies during alleged DV arrest in Sydney's south west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/nsw-sydney-critical-incident-declared-in-sadleir/105797330</link><description>Police were called to two separate domestic-related incidents in New South Wales overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bea73896721ecf6c280747e26d7597d</guid></item><item><title>UN says there's evidence organised crime scam centres are moving from South-East Asia into new frontier of the Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/organised-crime-scam-centres-move-into-pacific-united-nations/105775972</link><description>As scam centres run by organised crime find it harder to operate in South-East Asia, evidence emerges of them moving into the Pacific and setting up lucrative operations estimated to net billions each year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb89464594316563fc34dc56a716880e</guid></item><item><title>Kamala Harris's frustration with Joe Biden, and other takeaways from her election trail memoir</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/kamala-harris-election-campaign-memoir-key-takeaways/105797598</link><description>Kamala Harris has kept a low profile since losing the US election, but she has plenty to say in her upcoming book — a diary from her doomed campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">889a1be8632644b869e3a832fcf2a96a</guid></item><item><title>Transition from sheep to cropping in WA's Avon Valley leaving limited balloon landing sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/crops-to-sheep-hot-air-balloon-landing-sites/105794124</link><description>The move out of sheep by an increasing number of WA farmers is having an unexpected impact on the state's hot air balloon pilots.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c79d7f50ce8880f2a74edb7c05cab83</guid></item><item><title>Yolŋu people celebrate 50 years of the homelands movement in East Arnhem Land</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/nt-laynhapuy-homelands-movement-anniversary-indigenous-yolngu/105796404</link><description>Yolŋu children from nine Laynhapuy communities are screaming the Yothu Yindi anthem, Homeland Movement, in a ceremony celebrating the Indigenous elders who claimed back life on their country 50 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3184235034372056a06780912d5fe26e</guid></item><item><title>Hunter Correctional Centre prisoners refurbish rescue truck for VRA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/hunter-correctional-centre-inmates-refurbish-rescue-truck/105792352</link><description>The prisoners relished the chance to give back to the community and learn skills that could help to prevent them reoffending.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">898acebb0f44f37668b5fe49797d3188</guid></item></channel></rss>