<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 15:59:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>After 40 years of plot twists and drama, Neighbours wraps up for the last time — again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/neighbours-finale-recap/106133684</link><description>Relive the highlights, such as they were, in the final episode of Neighbours, which went to air last night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66d77596370f9dcb56e3473c4c20e070</guid></item><item><title>Demersal fishing ban leaves industry 'drowning' as mental health concerns rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/fishing-industry-drowning-in-emotional-toll-of-dermersal-ban/106109302</link><description>WA fishers are raising concerns about a lack of mental health support as the commercial industry comes to terms with a ban on demersal fishing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">780356866a5457fda1599f1fb8e408ed</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says land strikes on Venezuela drug shipments coming soon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/us-ready-to-seize-ships-venezuelan-oil-tankers/106134498</link><description>Donald Trump says the US will soon strike drug shipments making their way from Venezuela on land, amid a large-scale military build-up in the southern Caribbean to increase pressure on Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3988de499dfa17007965f95e974b24e4</guid></item><item><title>Record-breaking crocodile Cassius taxidermied for Green Island exhibit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/world-record-crocodile-cassius-taxidermied-new-exhibit/106131178</link><description>The world's largest crocodile in captivity until its death last year is going on display in Far North Queensland, as more findings are revealed about its cause of death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">733169fd9a429b9ff1e0b26e8fc099d4</guid></item><item><title>Matilda Bay and Applecross ferry terminals approved in Swan River Metronet plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/swan-river-matilda-bay-applecross-ferry-terminals-approved/106130810</link><description>WA's planning authorities approve the construction of two new ferry terminals at Applecross and Matilda Bay as part of the state government's expansion of Swan River ferry services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">263609e9363897531936e450b7d42c1d</guid></item><item><title>Eurovision winner Nemo returns trophy in protest over Israel's participation in competition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/nemo-returns-eurovision-trophy-over-israels-participation/106134594</link><description>Swiss singer Nemo says they will return the trophy they won in 2024 over the EBU's decision to let Israel participate in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cb716762728053bb6ac34183a1719bf</guid></item><item><title>Career counselling lacking as students try to predict AI impact on jobs of the future</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/ai-jobs-student-anxiety-vce-university-atar-employment/106123826</link><description>A Victorian Parliamentary Inquiry report finds youth career support is "severely lacking" as students fear AI is threatening white-collar industries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5781af3b1fbb37853c9b606b2ddad516</guid></item><item><title>Treasurer Jim Chalmers gives green light to Hanwha's double stake in shipbuilder Austal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/hanwha-austal-bid-approve-jim-chalmers/106134860</link><description>Jim Chalmers said there will be "strict conditions" on the South Korean defence conglomerate's stake in the strategic shipbuilder, in a nod to the diplomatic and security sensitivities surrounding the bid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">110810108c4d6e185f96e797e7f4a857</guid></item><item><title>French game Clair Obscur breaks records with Game of the Year 2025 win — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/game-awards-2025-live-coverage/106102718</link><description>The biggest night in gaming is getting underway in the heart of downtown Los Angeles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8d73ac44f3cef79d117d2e04e651b49</guid></item><item><title>Hollywood director Carl Rinsch convicted of scamming Netflix out of $16.5m</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/hollywood-director-convicted-of-scamming-16-million-aud-netflix/106135428</link><description>Carl Erik Rinsch is convicted on charges that he scammed Netflix out of $US11 million for a show that never materialised, instead using the cash for purchases including luxury cars and homewares.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e8489bf4a398903633591b2660742f</guid></item><item><title>Perth fires prompt warning of extreme conditions as Kenwick, Bullsbrook blazes downgraded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/extreme-fire-danger-forecast-for-southwest-western-australia/106134884</link><description>A Kenwick resident who lost a shed and thousands of dollars worth of machinery in a bushfire in Perth's south-east says the blaze came within metres of her house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">870a179de0c5ec4dc83ae20ac37cc618</guid></item><item><title>New SA Liberal leader Ashton Hurn unveils 'streamlined' shadow cabinet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/new-sa-liberal-leader-unveils-shadow-cabinet/106135116</link><description>South Australia's new Liberal leader Ashton Hurn unveils a "streamlined" shadow cabinet, just 99 days out from the next state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1951d24f5aa21dc00e9d0d2831cd4cb9</guid></item><item><title>How long does it take to fix an underperforming school?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/boonah-high-agriculture-education-turnaround/105983794</link><description>A Queensland high school has re-engaged students by embedding agriculture into the curriculum and building strong local industry ties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b4dcb5993bb0060e638f96fbbe9c04</guid></item><item><title>PM says he has asked independent watchdog for advice on politician entitlement rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/parliamentary-expenses-rules-review/106135370</link><description>Sports and Communications Minister Anika Wells referred her claims to the Independent Parliamentary Expenses Authority for review after a stream of questions over her spending earlier this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bef836fe52d78ae8131a7227fe19a13</guid></item><item><title>Surfers find 'earthquake wave' off Western Australia's remote south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/decade-long-search-for-unique-wa-big-wave/106133082</link><description>A natural phenomenon leaves surfers in awe of the "earthquake" wave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04596bfe87994ec9243bbca950c9b61b</guid></item><item><title>Surfers capture weird wave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/surfers-film-wild-wave/106133580</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a965f9627b6775da38a95dd70e718e7c</guid></item><item><title>Dicky Bill salad farm's $10m debt shock as creditors try to claw back millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/dicky-bill-salad-farm-10m-debt-blow/105904126</link><description>Administrators for failed Australian salad farm company Dicky Bill reveal its business debts to hundreds of staff and suppliers could exceed $10 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8e5be403ca29b045c30bc879c4ed016</guid></item><item><title>Port Fairy residents demand answers after council abruptly closes only all-abilities pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/belfast-aquatics-community-pool-abruptly-closes/106135078</link><description>The south-west Victorian community of Port Fairy is demanding answers after an abrupt announcement from its council that it has closed the town's only pool.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2475053435283faa9f963d9cc4a5eb3d</guid></item><item><title>National Portrait Gallery unveils video portrait of Matildas honouring their contribution to sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/new-video-portrait-of-matildas-pays-tribute-to-their-legacy/106136190</link><description>The 23-minute video portrait of the Matildas 2023 World Cup squad cost $400,000, in what the National Portrait Gallery describes as its most ambitious commission ever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b67ac0ff5d6ccb3e375135e07013ed8</guid></item><item><title>Former ANZ chief executive Shayne Elliott sues banking giant after losing $13.5m in bonuses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/former-anz-ceo-shayne-elliott-sues-bank/106136712</link><description>Shayne Elliott says he has been left with "no alternative" but to launch legal action against the bank over its decision to slash $13.5 million from his bonus payments after he retired.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7d863795f4422aa214a07f5703eaf25</guid></item><item><title>New concessional loans for drought-affected farmers and algae-impacted fishers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/government-ric-review-new-loan-program-farmers-fishers-drought/106134810</link><description>The federal government is introducing new low-interest loans for drought-affected farmers and algae-impacted fishers, but some are worried it doesn't go far enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">637d56e286835d468cfe8a39ac049e83</guid></item><item><title>Our 10 best Christmas recipes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/easy-christmas-recipes-mains-desserts/105721782</link><description>Christmas is around the corner and we have plenty of delicious ideas whether you're hosting or bringing dessert.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4744c3fde22d977ef3646b0be11dd87a</guid></item><item><title>Thailand's bombing of Cambodian casinos could be putting trafficking victims at risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/thailand-bombs-cambodian-casinos-and-scam-centres/106125824</link><description>An expert says the Thai military's strikes on Cambodian casinos and suspected scam centres could be putting the lives of civilians and human trafficking victims at risk and may be considered war crimes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c044830d17205d2026f93fd522896c7a</guid></item><item><title>Court hears Dreaming story not 'trump card' to halt Regis Resources' McPhillamys Gold Project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/court-told-dreaming-story-not-trump-card-to-stop-gold-mine/106135486</link><description>An elders' group has told a Federal Court in Sydney that the Blue Banded Bee Dreaming story was not being kept "up its sleeve" three years after a protection bid was first made to the Commonwealth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a40abe62a175d5b6f25efd398ee39997</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106137824</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ec17792ba04e87136ec7434373520ed</guid></item><item><title>Man jailed for not stopping to help 3yo hit by car in Geraldton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/geraldton-man-sentenced-hit-and-run-young-child/106135848</link><description>The boy was dragged under a car for more than 100 metres, with the judge saying she does not know how he survived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bd7f61e8707e8c652c007a46ad18dfd</guid></item><item><title>Adult content creator 'Bonnie Blue' leaving a Bali court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/adult-content-creator-bonnie-blue-leaving-a-bali-court-/106137870</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366cc6f24c711d807db94a02fc595df2</guid></item><item><title>British porn star Bonnie Blue deported from Bali after 'Bang Bus' case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/bonnie-blue-faces-bali-court-after-studio-raid/106137670</link><description>The controversial adult content creator has faced court for flouting the resort island's road rules.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8222c1e101256089be61bc436435f9d8</guid></item><item><title>Bunbury masseur Anthony Brain guilty of sexually assaulting clients</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/anthony-brain-guilty-sexually-assaulting-massage-clients/105877236</link><description>A WA masseur who described himself as a nudist and provided "internal" massages without consent is found guilty of multiple sex charges after a trial that ran for more than two months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e565f667d28927f6c1fddffcd4f3027</guid></item><item><title>Horse owners urged to vaccinate animals after bat tests positive to Hendra virus in the NT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/hendra-virus-found-in-the-northern-territory-darwin-bat/106135238</link><description>Horse owners in the Northern Territory are being encouraged to vaccinate their animals after a bat tested positive for Hendra virus, in the territory's first confirmed case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47cf55f810d41349e77a2a2323137bb2</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's historic treaty formally commences with cultural celebration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/victorias-historic-treaty-formally-begins/106137848</link><description>Victoria's statewide treaty has officially launched with a day of cultural celebrations in Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9af5d95067bab0db07b1bdad72cf6ac</guid></item><item><title>Americans sceptical of Trump on Epstein, as poll finds just 23pc approve of how he's handled crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/brk-polling-on-trump-handling-epstein-files/106138506</link><description>Most Americans believe Trump's administration is covering up Epstein information, with 62 per cent believing the government is hiding information about Epstein's death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18cc07d2d9e4c3f207ce4eb84ac7f679</guid></item><item><title>Trump's quietly released national security document didn't escape Europe's attention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/donald-trump-foreign-policy-national-security-strategy-europe/106136354</link><description>When the White House quietly released its national security strategy late one night last week, it instead seemed to get lost in other news. Except, perhaps, in Europe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a638ba1f7a2b1556fc4a3782ee5651f1</guid></item><item><title>Aged care reforms leave elderly Australians and their loved ones in the lurch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/aged-care-package-reform-worse-off-confusion-despair-waitlist/106136364</link><description>The reforms have unleashed a wave of confusion and despair amongst hundreds of thousands of elderly Australians, from those wanting care to those who already have it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bccf44fd0309fdda714dc96ed3d5cde5</guid></item><item><title>How a grieving mother's letter helped Australia's world-first social media ban come into being</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/how-australia-developed-social-media-ban-under-16s/106137700</link><description>Key players including Anthony Albanese, Peter Dutton, Peter Malinauskas and Julie Inman-Grant tell the inside story of how an unprecedented ban came to be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a518d11646c795b19b3f686350ae927</guid></item><item><title>Warner Bros Discovery battle draws in billionaires, celebrities and Trump's son-in-law</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/warner-bros-discovery-paramount-skydance-netflix-battle/106126968</link><description>The dramatic escalation in the fight for Warner Bros is one of the biggest in recent corporate memory, drawing an unlikely cast of celebrities and business figures including Jared Kushner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1412d0a2b8f61f8e6f279b4a1e8d252c</guid></item><item><title>When can politicians put sport or family trips on the 'company card'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/when-can-sport-be-charged-to-taxpayers/106128390</link><description>A spotlight on sports minister Anika Wells prompts fresh scrutiny of the rules about the expenses politicians can claim, including to attend big-ticket sporting events and concerts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fe77984fac9fd83754193d222751701</guid></item><item><title>Partygoers using walking sticks after ketamine, drug use at music festivals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/partygoers-using-walking-sticks-after-drug-use/106125022</link><description>Australian partygoers are using walking aids to support their ketamine habit at music festivals across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">261b99de3f1a68de6536bd5e8840d45b</guid></item><item><title>Best books of 2025, by Hannah Kent, Arundhati Roy, Charlotte McConaghy and more</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/best-books-2025-hannah-kent-arundhati-roy-charlotte-mcconaghy/106131106</link><description>An exciting Australian debut, a bevvy of award-winning literary fiction and more than one heart-wrenching memoir are among our critics' favourite reads of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a47e37b2c20cf9e65c12b0b5f5610b</guid></item><item><title>Matildas midfielder Tameka Yallop requires surgery, all but ruling her out of home AFC Asian Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/matildas-midfielder-tameka-yallop-out-of-asian-cup/106138960</link><description>Matildas veteran Tameka Yallop will require surgery on a serious hamstring injury, all but ending her hopes of playing at the Women's Asian Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9891e03aaac924ec2a7ebb8aedf1419e</guid></item><item><title>50 years ago, Patti Smith’s Horses fused poetry and punk, rewriting rock's rule book</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/patti-smith-horses-50-years-anniversary-punk-poetry-rock-classic/106125110</link><description>The power and importance of Horses, the seminal debut of punk-poet Patti Smith, still lingers five decades after its release.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb54679b32daf54876ce47e32191e9fa</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 13: Box-office hit Sense and Sensibility hits US cinemas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/sense-and-sensibility-released-in-us-cinemas-30-years-ago-today/106127910</link><description>Sense and Sensibility was marketed "chick flick". But this 90s re-imagining of Sense and Sensibility starring British powerhouse Emma Thompson was more than just a bubbly romance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d6d813b6850c55992c00eb46f6b7b0c</guid></item><item><title>From devastation to wonder as Kangaroo Island bushfires lead to cave discoveries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/more-than-150-caves-discovered-in-ki-after-devastating-bushfires/106095942</link><description>It was an adventure into the unknown. From the surface all that could be seen was a small opening. The ABC has been given exclusive access to newly-discovered caves on South Australia's Kangaroo Island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc388cc62031e7ced86dc36fdeb23d3e</guid></item><item><title>Meet the fleet: The helicopters and planes protecting you this bushfire season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/victoria-firefighting-air-fleet-helicopters-aircraft-planes-fire/106130296</link><description>They are an eclectic mix but this diverse fleet of helicopters, water bombers and planes is ready to protect south-eastern Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd08d6e255b4c21288305aa9323d9bbc</guid></item><item><title>West Gate Tunnel project is set to open after delays and cost blow outs pushed onto road users</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/west-gate-tunnel-set-to-open-after-delays-and-cost-blowouts/106137268</link><description>The long-awaited West Gate Tunnel project will open on Sunday, with Labor hoping it's enough to win voters back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf91745cc022d88d7e89031bbf02b1bc</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous community feels 'forgotten' in nation's capital after two decades of Labor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/aboriginal-canberrans-feel-forgotten-failure-close-the-gap/106112204</link><description>After 24 years of Labor government, First Nations people in Australia's capital are frustrated and exhausted by a lack of meaningful progress to close the gap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4500ab690127d5eece816a53bb22af25</guid></item><item><title>Illicit vaping, cigarette raids create game of 'whack-a-mole' but health campaign urges patience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/illicit-vaping-cigarette-raids-create-game-of-whack-a-mole/106120236</link><description>Despite a record $15.7 million nicotine seizure, experts say Australia's multi-billion-dollar illicit tobacco and vape market continues to thrive, exposing the limits of raids and crackdowns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26c5c6e9b33a21cf459c67553f43b018</guid></item><item><title>Changes to Queensland's political donation laws could increase corruption risks, experts say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/queensland-political-donations-property-developers/106135566</link><description>A ban on political donations by developers, introduced by the former Qld Labor Government, will be lifted by the LNP.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d622effc6640efe205ef4fafbe6ecae8</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill community fundraises for mental health in wake of tragic loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/mental-health-fundraiser-in-memory-of-alice-wilkinson/106032394</link><description>Alice Wilkinson loved music and was the life of the party. Her death has prompted her family to help others who might be struggling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9948ad96b75034e1c1748aa31157b822</guid></item><item><title>Australia's social media ban reminds us of the power of a loving boundary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/social-media-ban-teens-roblox-son-boundary-safety/106131786</link><description>This is where we parents should remind ourselves of the power of the loving boundary: not to bind and constrain, but to properly demonstrate that we hold our kids and their safety in our mind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b63e161e0d7b0716938ae584d3056917</guid></item><item><title>Gen Z drawn to bird watching after growing up on Pokemon GO</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/gen-z-drawn-to-bird-watching-after-growing-up-on-pokemon-go/106136816</link><description>Raised on Pokemon GO, generation Z is finding the hobby of birding just the ticket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57a5e8f5b4102873e2ea387eb135bd1c</guid></item><item><title>New generations take to bird watching</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/bird-watching-for-everyone/106138172</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be3cd15eb3f374029864ad60e0572480</guid></item><item><title>Matcha's popularity a boon for Japanese farmers but counterfeits a problem</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/counterfeit-matcha-is-flooding-the-market-to-meet-demand/106115334</link><description>As Japanese matcha producers struggle with the surge in demand, the industry is facing another problem — counterfeit matcha.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b338d270f01bd62218b06c26a1978a6</guid></item><item><title>Grassroots First Nations organisation flags concern for at-risk youth under social media ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/nt-social-media-ban-indigenous-teens-darwin-aunties-place/106133746</link><description>Social media can help at-risk youth connect with support services, so what impact will the federal government's under-16s ban have on those community hubs?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">090b6a9b3a1c75a2d5531cc8512af193</guid></item><item><title>Record gold prices drive investment in exploration across Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/record-gold-prices-drive-investment-in-exploration-australia/106121424</link><description>The money being spent on drilling for gold has increased 45 per cent in the past 12 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d69ff758de9fcfef8c74baabbe66e46</guid></item><item><title>Migrant workers raise concerns at modern slavery inquiry in Coffs Harbour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/modern-slavery-migrant-hearings-in-nsw/106130342</link><description>Witnesses have told an inquiry into modern slavery that migrant workers are being exploited in the nation's blueberry capital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad5a183a10a9cc947ab7eba5cea3574c</guid></item><item><title>Public housing residents in Roebourne swelter through heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/public-housing-residents-in-roebourne-swelter-through-heatwave/106129428</link><description>WA's Pilbara has already endured a seven-day heatwave this month, but many in the town of Roebourne have little more than a hose and wet sheets to keep them cool as temperatures top 45 degrees Celsius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd37452858bfa7de9710ef2891b41309</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire survivor calls for better emergency planning in the suburbs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/how-to-prepare-for-summer-bushfire-season-perth-wa/106120466</link><description>After a fast-moving bushfire reached the front door of her home in 2023, Kay Douglas is now better prepared in case it happens again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81bd001f98f7b1e53f812e5c94b138b1</guid></item><item><title>Underwater microphone records humpback whale sounds off NSW south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/underwater-microphone-records-humpback-whale-sounds/106129670</link><description>Underwater microphones off the NSW south coast capture consistent humpback whale sounds throughout the 2024 migration season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cc82218726405dc2f124c6cb8f59615</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne lawyer Dean Hadjina sentenced to prison for stealing from grieving widow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/melbourne-lawyer-dean-hadjina-prison-sentence-stealing-widow/106139262</link><description>Dean Hadjina is sentenced to prison for stealing $482,154 from a vulnerable widow who spoke little English as she sought compensation payouts after her husband's workplace death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b4d1bb774295f2d85cb6eceb1c2956</guid></item><item><title>18-year-old man in critical condition after Gold Coast assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/qld-serious-assault-gold-coast/106139282</link><description>An 18-year-old man is in hospital in a critical condition after being assaulted on the Gold Coast on Friday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c56049f475d1eb150165a6fdc757cdfa</guid></item><item><title>Croc wrangler Matt Wright's prison sentence a stark warning after years-long court saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/matt-wright-sentencing-fallout-for-helicopter-industry/106136470</link><description>Crocodile wrangler Matt Wright built a television and tourism empire in the Northern Territory, but that's all come crashing down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68ab8e1dd2c64631e9d79719aeb78b86</guid></item><item><title>Perth's queer nightclub, Connections, celebrates 50 years of dancing and difference</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/perth-queer-nightclub-connections-celebrates-50-years/106137800</link><description>Founded in 1975, when homosexuality was still illegal in Western Australia, Connections nightclub has seen waves of social change and kept the party going.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbfccd7dc10d5ba74db21e7a1c43fba5</guid></item><item><title>Google to build undersea cables in Papua New Guinea under Australia defence treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/google-building-undersea-cables-in-png/106139500</link><description>PNG says the measure will provide a key upgrade to its digital backbone and link the north and south of the nation with high-capacity cables.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bdcdd335abbb5327aeebb352b5456bf</guid></item><item><title>Government-formed agency recommends against NSW coal industry expansion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/independent-agency-recommends-against-nsw-coal-expansion/106139270</link><description>Coal mining extensions and expansions will continue, the New South Wales premier says, despite a government-appointed agency finding further approvals were not consistent with emissions targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9daf0baa045cb5bb4ef13da04acdb8b6</guid></item><item><title>Australian fans among most active in searching for FIFA World Cup tickets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/australian-fans-search-for-fifa-world-cup-tickets/106139824</link><description>Australia are among the countries with the most ticket requests for next year's World Cup, which is bound to please Socceroos coach Tony Popovic and his team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">316d9995db7dddc4dbd80b9b4e357dbc</guid></item><item><title>What you should know about 'Bali belly' and how to avoid it before it ruins your holiday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/what-do-you-need-to-know-about-bali-belly-and-how-to-avoid-it/106133990</link><description>Every year about 1.5 million Australians travel to Bali. Chances are either you or someone you know has caught a stomach bug after travelling to the popular Indonesian destination. So what can you do to avoid it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e5d649d03f0cad3ea98b4b637b0d8ae</guid></item><item><title>Desert Fireball Network students find fist-sized meteorite in outback WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/desert-fireball-network-students-find-meteorite-outback-wa/106139512</link><description>PhD students from Curtin University have found a 300-gram meteorite after a five-day search in remote bushland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a00682db69e225e1eeff0b8b54a44fd</guid></item><item><title>United Nations delegation warns of Australia's treatment of prisoners, detainees and breach in human rights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/united-nations-warn-australia-prison-detention-human-rights/106136950</link><description>A delegation of United Nations inspectors have raised the alarm about Australia's detention facilities and a breach of human rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">075a06b44f92126c2bd0015a8827c776</guid></item><item><title>Severe heatwave cancels event, closes popular abalone fishing spot as season begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/severe-heatwave-as-wa-abalone-season-begins/106139888</link><description>Perth is in the grip of its hottest spell so far this summer, forcing the closure of a popular tourist attraction as abalone fishing season got underway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e379757217715ba153713c1409b032d</guid></item><item><title>Jailed Myanmar leader Aung San Suu Kyi's supporters rally in Sydney to protest junta elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/aung-san-suu-kyi-supporters-rally-sydney-myanmar-junta-election/106139074</link><description>Aung San Suu Kyi's son leads a rally of supporters in Sydney as part of global demonstrations trying to increase international pressure on Myanmar's ruling military junta.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7882d7a6e0844c1867f57f204dfb409d</guid></item><item><title>Roger Rasheed slams 'battle of the sexes' tennis clash between Nick Kyrgios and Aryna Sabalenka</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/roger-rasheed-nick-kyrgios-aryna-sabalenk-battle-of-the-sexes/106140068</link><description>High-profile Australian tennis coach Roger Rasheed has questioned the value of the upcoming "battle of the sexes"-style exhibition match between Nick Kyrgios and Aryna Sabalenka.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44c26b0beab1855f4660c042d1252f87</guid></item><item><title>China Coast Guard fires water cannon at Philippine fishing vessels in South China Sea, Manila says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/south-china-sea-chinese-water-cannon-philippine-coast-guard/106140098</link><description>Manila's coastguard says nearly two dozen Philippine fishing boats near Sabina Shoal were targeted with water cannon and blocking manoeuvres on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bb328352925a9ae0fcc01bbc0e0e037</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja open to middle order role for third Ashes Test in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/khawaja-open-to-middle-order-ashes-2025/106140150</link><description>Australia batter Usman Khawaja is feeling 100 per cent fit and is open to a return to the middle order for the third Ashes Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de5665c9e9bc10d34d2ac7d2c9d8c0c7</guid></item><item><title>Lizelle Lee stars as Hobart Hurricanes claim maiden WBBL title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-13/hurricanes-claim-maiden-wbbl-title/106140180</link><description>Hurricanes opener Lizelle Lee hits an unbeaten 77 as her side claims its first WBBL title with a dominant eight-wicket win over the Scorchers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdfc4baf4edce297b59ca622e0b895a6</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: It's the season of giving so I'm gifting you a chance at redemption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106130212</link><description>Your track record doesn't leave me hopeful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">693aef896cb1373b315facefcd53f061</guid></item><item><title>'I was tricked': African athlete lured to Russia for work, ends up on front lines of Ukraine war</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/athlete-says-russia-lured-him-for-work-then-sent-him-to-war/106122770</link><description>Vladimir Putin says Russia has "no need" to recruit foreign fighters to bolster its invasion of Ukraine, but inside this prisoner of war camp, people have a very different story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0f54e990b1e6ae1e6cd660235034b18</guid></item><item><title>Sanction-skirting 'shadow fleets' in Trump's sights. Here's how they work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/what-are-shadow-fleets/106137346</link><description>Tensions between the US and Venezuela are soaring after American forces seized an oil tanker in the Caribbean Sea. So why is US President Donald Trump targeting so-called "shadow fleets"?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28967e6fabbd1b6edbe8e8daa824b124</guid></item><item><title>How Benjamin Netanyahu's corruption trial became a struggle for Israel itself</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/israel-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-corruption-trial-and-deep-state/106124242</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's backers view his corruption trial as a witch hunt — but his detractors argue it is the system finally catching up to a ruthless political operative who is prepared to do anything to hold on to power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">868ab4d48d09c7dddeca77bf4f254be5</guid></item><item><title>Two US troops killed in Syria ambush along with one American civilian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/us-service-members-killed-in-syria/106140654</link><description>Two US service members and one American civilian are killed in an ambush in central Syria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63bd2995922c21f9ffbaed628e6b75e2</guid></item><item><title>After tragedies and rescues, Tasmanian bushwalkers urged to 'be prepared' for all conditions this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/tasmania-cradle-mountain-rescues-hiking-prep-for-summer/106028884</link><description>It has been a busy year for search and rescue operations in the Tasmanian high country. Authorities say a concerning number of visitors to the state's famous national parks are ill-prepared for the fickle weather — even during summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">366e2bd207b3ac5db65be6ca27b9bd08</guid></item><item><title>Iron deficiency is a challenge for many female athletes, like Super Netball's Zara Walters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/zara-walters-victorian-institute-of-sport-iron-deficiency/106108280</link><description>Zara Walters felt tired, dizzy and unable to recover from training sessions — then she found out she was low in iron. It's a condition that often goes undiagnosed, especially in female athletes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ee03bad452a9f38b43e0a5a4d93185d</guid></item><item><title>Gippsland teenager Ethan Monck celebrates first job after a lifetime battling cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/ethan-monck-gets-his-first-job-fast-food-chain-mcdonalds/106001356</link><description>Ethan Monck's health problems began the day he was born. Now aged 17, he's celebrating after starting his first job and the freedom it gives him to pursue his hobbies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d8cd975bcb08a3e9ad54c598b450043</guid></item><item><title>Bree Walker seals IBSF World Cup monobob gold in Lillehammer, Josie Baff, Adam Lambert and 16yo Ally Hickman claim snowboard bronzes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/bree-walker-wins-monobob-gold-in-lillehammer/106140660</link><description>Bree Walker's superb sliding season continues with a third World Cup victory in a row on the Lillehammer sliding track in Norway, putting her into second place in the overall IBSF standings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81178ae79fe9afbcdb4132b5077f5a4c</guid></item><item><title>Is Sydney's high-rise future equipped to withstand a Hong Kong-like fire?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/lessons-for-sydney-high-rises-after-hong-kong-building-fire/106108100</link><description>Warnings have been raised for NSW not to be "complacent" about the state's ability to fight high-rise apartment fires, following last month's blaze in the Wang Fuk Court estate complex in Hong Kong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2388c0c3b0004b7b7416631a1228bf0</guid></item><item><title>Earthquake due 'in foreseeable future' after 70 years of Adelaide tremors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/is-adelaide-due-for-another-big-earthquake/106126974</link><description>Adelaide sits on the most active seismic zone in Australia and has more than its fair share of tremors below magnitude-4, but it's been 71 years since it was rocked by a serious earthquake. Now, it's a matter of when, not if, it gets another one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">547eb51b5fce33d426720340f3261fa1</guid></item><item><title>The Kaurna cultural program inspiring students in Adelaide's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/sa-students-find-connection-through-kaurna-program/106136626</link><description>Kanyanyapilla means "place of many eagles", and it's where Indigenous students in Adelaide are coming to connect with Kaurna culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2cc1db9b6981d4c5f9aed4bf8c5c018</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Sweeney transformed herself to play Christy Martin in a biopic as Hollywood struggles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/how-sydney-sweeney-transformed-herself-to-play-a-boxer/106132482</link><description>Sydney Sweeney changed a lot about herself to play Christy Martin in a biopic about the boxer. She says it was a role she had to take.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51771885fbf1fdd5558fa08cca2331b1</guid></item><item><title>Lionel Messi's India tour begins in chaos, seats ripped out in Kolkata</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/lionel-messi-india-tour-chaos-seats-ripped-out/106140692</link><description>Indian football fans ripped up seats and invaded the pitch in Kolkata as Lionel Messi's first appearance in India took a chaotic and dangerous turn.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6942144dbdac54fd6b55f6ac85693f8</guid></item><item><title>Medical groups push for consequences for freebirth 'birthkeepers' posing as medical professionals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/inside-the-freebirth-birthkeeper-movement/106137044</link><description>A number of recent deaths linked to freebirths — where a pregnant woman chooses to give birth with no registered medical professional present — is prompting health groups to speak out about rising levels of misinformation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16095bdb783bfd370331e86386a64607</guid></item><item><title>Israel says Hamas commander Raed Saed was among five killed in Gaza City attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/israel-kills-senior-hamas-commander/106140722</link><description>It was the highest-profile assassination of a senior Hamas figure since a Gaza ceasefire deal came into effect in October.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9511c3513952beac1daba85cc2926e6</guid></item><item><title>Alpha Bakery making famous pies again with family support after dementia diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/alpha-bakery-making-pies-again-family-supports-brother-dementia/106050182</link><description>Christopher Tilse has worked from dawn to dusk in a bakery most of his life. Dementia made that a challenge, but thanks to family support, he is still baking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef9efe3534ff9ae6f4fdc06349c272fd</guid></item><item><title>Three quarters of Canberra's suburbs see reduction in tree canopy despite government's 2045 goal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/decline-tree-coverage-bush-capital-canberra/106139714</link><description>It's called the 'bush capital', but three quarters of Canberra's suburbs have recorded a decline in tree coverage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a1e07b3043c41eef341fae603953e04</guid></item><item><title>UK police won't probe claim former prince Andrew asked bodyguard to investigate Virginia Roberts Giuffre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/uk-police-wont-probe-andrew-claim/106140752</link><description>London's police force says it will not take further action over claims that former prince Andrew asked his protection officer to carry out checks on Virginia Roberts Giuffre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">804859bb33197ef5054bd889c0dbd03a</guid></item><item><title>Two-thirds of women escaping violence in Broome cannot access help</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/hundreds-turned-away-from-broome-domestic-violence-refuge/106057354</link><description>In a region with Western Australia's highest rates of family and domestic violence, a Kimberley service provider says it can only help one-third of women who need it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">337b73f0f8756ae11e894af3cf8dbae2</guid></item><item><title>Pulp Fiction, The Mask actor Peter Greene dies aged 60</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/pulp-fiction-the-mask-actor-peter-greene-dies-aged-60/106140816</link><description>Peter Greene, a character actor best known for his role as the iconic villain, Zed in Pulp Fiction, has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36ad8509e456fcf6d30148f22f003c23</guid></item><item><title>Brown University shooting in US leaves two students dead and nine injured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/active-shooter-brown-university/106140822</link><description>Police detain a "person of interest" in connection with the Brown University shooting that left two students dead and another nine people wounded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2eefee872256923a130ecd2adf6c1ab</guid></item><item><title>Conservationist uses invasive fox fur to make ethical clothing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/conservationist-clothing-maker-turns-fox-pelts-to-coats/106049382</link><description>In six months, Emma Sinclair went from not knowing how to sew to launching her own fashion label based around fox fur.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be15a03e36974b98c27cb9abdac073ef</guid></item><item><title>Two students killed, nine injured in shooting at Brown University — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/brown-university-active-shooting-live-blog/106140862</link><description>Two students have been killed and nine other people have been injured after a gunman entered an engineering building during final exams at Brown University in the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a993b5dc81abdc518e58657733134887</guid></item><item><title>Attorney-General Michelle Rowland to repay family travel expenses after independent review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/michelle-rowland-to-repay-expenses-claim/106140868</link><description>Attorney-General Michelle Rowland is told to repay a portion of travel expenses she claimed for a 2023 family trip to Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f97d3490b9622ca1c57d638e075a94ba</guid></item><item><title>Budding musicians on NSW far south coast create songs about First Nations culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/first-nations-musicians-mentored-by-band-to-create-songs/106113948</link><description>With sounds recorded in a makeshift studio, this group of high school students produced music about First Nations culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d20d7fec8bae421ad705bc5fc8033d39</guid></item><item><title>Searching for treasure in the Aussie bush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/searching-for-treasure-in-the-aussie-bush/106109214</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca8167284f0f87b8b3d3de1ba0cc8a2b</guid></item><item><title>Orchid enthusiasts call for greater protection for native species facing habitat threats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/new-orchids-discovered-habitat-threat-mount-wedge/106072786</link><description>Two centuries after orchids were first documented in South Australia, photographers are still discovering new plants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d238655dc5d75962a61dc09df9c50031</guid></item><item><title>Ashleigh Gentle shares 'incredibly isolating' miscarriage news before competing in T100 Qatar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/ashleigh-gentle-t100-qatar-miscarriage/106140914</link><description>Australian triathlete Ashleigh Gentle reveals she suffered a miscarriage just days before competing in the season-ending T100 event in Qatar, earning significant praise for her bravery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f78297feb0f2276cd51a9cfa1f4a5b3c</guid></item><item><title>Households without power after Russian attack on Ukraine's power grid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/russian-attack-ukraine-power-grid/106141006</link><description>Five people were left wounded from the attack that Volodymyr Zelenskyy said consisted of more than 450 drones and 30 missiles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afcae4c642b6e6aeab8e1c46ac60f297</guid></item><item><title>Brett Lee backs current Australian bowling attack as greatest ever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/brett-lee-backs-current-australian-bowling-attack-as-greatest/106141014</link><description>Brett Lee ranks Australia's bowling attack as better than the one he was part of, which featured the likes of Glenn McGrath and Shane Warne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6e1aa66b31fbbd1ea5a920c9345b872</guid></item><item><title>Books reflecting remote Indigenous lifestyles and culture 'key' to students' reading success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/improving-indigenous-students-reading-skills-with-relevant-books/106056534</link><description>An educator says books that reflect remote Indigenous cultures and lifestyles are "the key to success" in improving reading outcomes for First Nations students.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7add03b17810e2b90d8dc3cd234850c0</guid></item><item><title>Virtual fencing is now legal in NSW. This is what you need to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/virtual-fencing-legalised-nsw/106128536</link><description>NSW farmers have been given the green light to use virtual fencing, providing an option over traditional posts and wires. Here is how it works.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e9f8e8bdd44e4f16106cd6fd01eb862</guid></item><item><title>Coles and Woolworths hit back at government's price gouging ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/coles-woolworths-hit-back-at-price-gouging-ban/106141094</link><description>Lower grocery bills are being promised within this new ban on price gouging, but giant retailers say they are the ones feeling the pinch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b22d07967f57eba637ea6d9f424f96a9</guid></item><item><title>I’m heading overseas. Do I really need travel vaccines?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/i-m-heading-overseas-do-i-really-need-travel-vaccines-/106139094</link><description>Australia is in its busiest month for short-term overseas travel. And there are so many things to consider when planning your trip. Unfortunately, it's easy to overlook the importance of pre-travel vaccinations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3487138a302c170a64988aa991484502</guid></item><item><title>'It's cooked': Big Brother contestant quit so she could afford the dentist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/abiola-big-brother-prize-money-dentist/106135150</link><description>Data obtained by the ABC shows people are waiting months, if not years, for dental care in every Australian state and territory due to the cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">062c6c7e609df623f810eb7822b805f4</guid></item><item><title>Australians open to dealing with AI on a Triple Zero emergency call, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/triple-zero-000-call-service-needs-ai-tech-upgrade-survey-finds/106120258</link><description>Could artificial intelligence speed up emergency responses by receiving a caller's video or smartwatch data and capturing words like "knife" and "collision"? Most people think so and welcome the technology's potential, a survey finds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9bee4df8d38455408afb5df240c0fcf</guid></item><item><title>Researchers call for water safety to be part of English education for migrants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/call-for-water-safety-to-be-incorporated-into-english-learning/106119112</link><description>As the country heads into the summer holidays, experts are again warning Australians to be aware of swim safety at beaches, pools and other waterways.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4390c5ccee6eff142d214ab84533e218</guid></item><item><title>Brendon McCullum vows against 'knee-jerk reactions' for third Ashes Test in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/mccullum-kneejerk-reactions-ashes-test-adelaide/106141442</link><description>England coach Brendon McCullum confirms his side's batting line-up will be unchanged for its must-win third Ashes Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6b4eae7c4f8a17c2ac9e7248c34c94d</guid></item><item><title>Short-form videos could be harming young minds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/how-short-form-videos-could-be-harming-young-minds/106139042</link><description>Online short-form video has shifted from a light distraction to a constant backdrop in many children's lives. But they were never built with children in mind, although many children use them daily.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0673a03803caca19c88a5d008e4686de</guid></item><item><title>Matt Wright's character references from famous singer, high-powered business person, media heavyweight released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/matt-wright-character-references-lee-kernaghan-mick-burns-/106141232</link><description>Country music star Lee Kernaghan, powerful business person Mick Burns, traditional owner Brian Tipungwuti and media heavyweight Nick Fordham all provided character references for celebrity crocodile wrangler Matt Wright ahead of his sentencing, court documents show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">278dc76daef3e70967b88f3de9193549</guid></item><item><title>Law enforcement source identifies Bondi gunman as Sydney man Naveed Akram</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/law-enforcement-source-identifies-bondi-gunman-as-naveed-akram/106141750</link><description>A law enforcement official has told the ABC that police have raided one of the alleged gunman's house in Sydney's south-west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c27975b9fb669ae4eaf99f4ad3e6223</guid></item><item><title>How the gunmen positioned themselves above Bondi Beach and opened fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/bondi-mass-shooting-/106141652</link><description>Videos and witness accounts from Bondi Beach have been shared widely. This is what they tell us about how the shooting unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95cdd8e99ecd7d8dbc0e73142876c667</guid></item><item><title>Moment Ahmed Al Ahmed disarms gunman Sajid Akram captured on film</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-14/bondi-shooter-tackled-and-disarmed-by-possible-civilian/106141690</link><description>Dramatic video shows 43-year-old Ahmed Al Ahmed crouching behind a parked vehicle near one of the Bondi Beach gunmen before disarming him during the terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab2602ba86af28c27b8e903ac7a50125</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine drops ambition to join NATO ahead of peace talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/ukraine-drops-nato-ambitions-ahead-of-peace-talks/106141924</link><description>Ukraine relinquishes its plan to join the NATO military alliance in exchange for Western security guarantees as it seeks an end to the war with Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24e2902f4acc583e3cebf3bfa496308b</guid></item><item><title>More Bondi Beach shooting victims named, including 10yo girl and rabbis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-attack-victims-named-including-10yo-matilda-and-rabbis/106142362</link><description>A 10-year-old girl named Matilda has been identified as one of the victims of Sunday's terror attack at Sydney's Bondi Beach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53a394237dc8574b1a190bf35db22cd6</guid></item><item><title>More Bondi Beach shooting victims named, including 10yo girl and rabbis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-beach-shooting-victims-named-as-10yo-matilda-and-rabbis/106142362</link><description>A 10-year-old girl named Matilda has been identified as one of the victims of Sunday's terror attack at Sydney's Bondi Beach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e03ef2b7174c78ebdf7e7b8679f5bb8a</guid></item><item><title>Australia's medicinal cannabis situation leaves government in a bind</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/australia-s-medicinal-cannabis-bind-is-a-political-hot-potato/106140878</link><description>There doesn't seem to be much political mileage for the government to do anything at all — whether that is cracking down and forcing cannabis users back onto the black market or fully legalising the substance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">351d59353e06489323dfd13cb834bafa</guid></item><item><title>Brain research centre The Florey sues executive, alleging he stole and erased files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/the-florey-brain-research-centre-files-claims-against-executive/106135388</link><description>Australia's biggest brain research centre is suing one of its executives, alleging he deleted troves of commercially sensitive information during a midnight incursion at its Melbourne laboratory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8345d1270fa7ecf8c2167fcfa10b7f08</guid></item><item><title>Photographing penguins in Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/leila-jeffreys-photographing-penguins-antarctica/106136800</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f292e504bf8faabeea539a3c5e5b979c</guid></item><item><title>Antarctic Arts Fellowship allows artists to develop works on the ice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/australian-antarctic-arts-fellowship/106139246</link><description>Over the past four decades, the Australian Antarctic Arts Fellowship has given creatives the opportunity to travel south and develop works on the icy continent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">574f0d2516ef3270e6679d6ed8e90ea9</guid></item><item><title>Retiring captain Elyse Villani says Hurricanes' WBBL win shows team's potential</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/hurricanes-captain-elyse-villani-retires-after-wbbl-win/106141334</link><description>Elyse Villani has described the Hurricanes' win as a "fairy tale" ending to her WBBL career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">111f91f49499824a5d1f69e7c6e6f83c</guid></item><item><title>This week in history quiz, December 15: Do you remember the first Simpsons episode?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/this-week-in-history-quiz-december-15/105877268</link><description>Do you have the answers for our This Week in History quiz?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2da6e529ed31b18eee47527e77124283</guid></item><item><title>Superannuation funds accused of delaying disability insurance claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/super-funds-accused-of-poor-handling-of-tpd-insurance-claims/106050046</link><description>The regulator has found that while some superannuation funds have improved insurance claims response times, others are still falling short, with long delays in relation to mental health claims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aed72917ef5a3d4a0f3e4254687d92da</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting death toll rises as police scour crime scene after terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/nsw-sydney-bondi-beach-shooting-hanukkah-jewish-community/106141648</link><description>Fifteen people and one of two gunmen are confirmed to have died after the attack on Sunday evening as members of the Jewish community attended a Hanukkah event in the city's eastern suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f396411115ff090ddac9ce77ff86537f</guid></item><item><title>Arrest warrant issued for alleged scammer claiming to be Gold Coast builder's nephew</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/alleged-builder-fraud-gold-coast-police-investigation/106120404</link><description>Police have issued a warrant for the man, who has allegedly scammed unsuspecting clients out of tens of thousands of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcce6941fe9987e6bc44777b95241b9e</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting live updates: PM to strengthen gun laws across Australia following Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-beach-shooting-terrorist-attack/106142446</link><description>Fifteen people were killed, including a 10-year-old girl. One of the two gunmen has also died, while a further 42 people were taken to hospital. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53ed92f5b0514ac2d2ce9a3d9c4074e1</guid></item><item><title>It's hard to imagine Bondi attack won't change Australia like Port Arthur did</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-attack-could-change-australia-like-port-arthur-massacre/106142102</link><description>For a while, it was like so many other summer Sundays in Bondi, but Australia's most deadly mass shooting in almost three decades could change the country forever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">002e5bc350add14a22451807be66fa87</guid></item><item><title>Heat to give way to more rain and storms in the south-east as school holidays kick off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/southeast-qld-weather-wrap-rain-heat-bom-storms-forecast/106137146</link><description>Parts of south-east Queensland can expect a slight easing of summer heat early this week, with the Bureau of Meteorology forecasting a 6C drop in some areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4603cfa94b2cb04a4119a9de594b8f66</guid></item><item><title>Australian share market falls, ASX Limited shares tumble on ASIC hit — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/106141546</link><description>Shares in stock exchange operator ASX fell as the regulator increases its capital requirements after damning inquiry findings. The local share market started the week in the red, weighed down by heavy selling in the miners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db7d6217383059e0fe312947317bdea9</guid></item><item><title>Cooper Connolly stars as Perth Scorchers down Sydney Sixers in BBL opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/scorchers-down-sixers-bbl-opener/106142124</link><description>Cooper Connolly leads the Scorchers to victory as star Sixers recruit Babar Azam struggles in the BBL curtain raiser at Perth Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50698296472667855f8c9cd66d6cabac</guid></item><item><title>ASIO examined Bondi Beach gunman Naveed Akram in 2019 for close ties to Islamic State cell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-beach-attack-gunmen-father-and-son/106142630</link><description>Australia's domestic intelligence agency, ASIO, examined one of the Bondi Beach gunmen six years ago for his close ties to a Sydney-based Islamic State terrorism cell, the ABC understands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61d8702038585ef6be9d3817b6662640</guid></item><item><title>City of Karratha applies for international airport status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/karratha-applies-for-international-airport-status/106055700</link><description>The City of Karratha has applied to the federal government for international airport status in a move that has been welcomed by residents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20f676ae0e352997f26bf0cfca24e1db</guid></item><item><title>Kendrick Lamar delights young fan with birthday song at Canberra Spilt Milk festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/kendrick-lamar-serenades-young-fan-at-canberra-spilt-milk/106142574</link><description>American rap superstar Kendrick Lamar brought the house down at Spilt Milk in Canberra, but it was his interaction with a nine-year-old superfan that stole the show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16ca55a20161d6ca4cbf526e3b6f236a</guid></item><item><title>England warned Adelaide pitch is not as friendly as it looks ahead of third Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/ashes-adelaide-test-england-warned-pitch-not-friendly/106142732</link><description>With England pinning its hopes on victory in the third Test, the tourists have been warned that the Adelaide pitch is not as friendly as it looks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aec1d41e99ee9fd7c4c64bcffb15282b</guid></item><item><title>Hollow Knight: Silksong, Death Stranding 2 and Donkey Kong Bananza among our best games of 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/video-games-end-of-year-wrap-2025/106038598</link><description>There are games to suit everyone, and overwhelmingly Australians are a game-playing nation. Here are some of the most important titles released this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">213c78332ceb94cd8515daaa19a2dc06</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu lashes out at Anthony Albanese over Bondi Beach shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/israels-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-lashes-out-over-bondi-shooting/106142722</link><description>In a fiery address overnight, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said "antisemitism is a cancer" and that it "spreads when leaders stay silent".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05b77a04119cf49f9a9dacbb6e0c0843</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley accuses Albanese of failing to keep Jewish Australians safe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/albanese-told-to-endorse-antisemitism-plan-after-bondi-shooting/106142578</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley says Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has allowed antisemitism to "fester" and failed to keep Jewish Australians safe in the wake of yesterday's "evil" terror attack on the shores of Bondi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b45fc7ff1574ff3e49240c068f74667d</guid></item><item><title>WA's wettest towns have had no local drinking water for 15 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/wa-wettest-towns-drinking-water-carting/106120700</link><description>Quinninup and Northcliffe in Western Australia's south-west receive an average of 1 metre of rain every year, so why has the state government spent millions of dollars trucking in drinking water?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b73df9467313d7d89bd980191d5e1a4</guid></item><item><title>Matildas star Sam Kerr impresses again for Chelsea in WSL after starting as sub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/matildas-star-sam-kerr-impresses-again-for-chelsea-in-wsl/106143024</link><description>Matildas gun Sam Kerr starts on the bench again, but makes an immediate impact for Chelsea in a 3-0 WSL victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e34c904b76ecd95d28f27217323aecd</guid></item><item><title>Jewish community leaders say 'things can't go back to normal' after deadly Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-shootings-jewish-community-response/106142772</link><description>The Australian Jewish community is in a state of shock following the Bondi shootings, with leaders calling for more to be done to combat anti-Semitism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ad2b17010a2d178bc4822ae0b4fc9af</guid></item><item><title>Kahu's been woodchopping his whole life, but a heart attack mid-competition almost killed him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/axeman-brought-back-to-life-after-heart-attack/106113688</link><description>Kahu Woolley was clinically dead multiple times, but quick actions by his friends brought him back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cf809b3bb5a37d997237793fca40e31</guid></item><item><title>Soren Copley in court over Philippines child sex abuse allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/soren-copley-philippines-sex-abuse-allegations/106143004</link><description>The Australian Federal Police says it launched an investigation into North Queensland man Soren Copley in September after a tip-off from US Homeland Security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bd26689ae3d937711a3d87272f6fabd</guid></item><item><title>Dolphin Sands bushfire sparked by improperly extinguished burn off, Tasmanian authorities confirm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/dolphin-sands-fire-caused-by-a-landowner-burning-off/106143708</link><description>A bushfire in Tasmania that destroyed 19 homes was caused by a registered burn conducted about a week earlier, which was not extinguished by a landowner, authorities have confirmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b23d3e099993b34951f2b4167aa81e0b</guid></item><item><title>Australians urged to give blood in wake of Bondi Beach mass shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-shooting-how-to-help-call-for-blood-donations/106142864</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns urges community members wanting to help the Jewish community following the Bondi terror attack to donate blood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63d91f901c3614f575701fabeb7f39f0</guid></item><item><title>Premier says Operation Shelter will be ‘inconvenient’ but necessary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/premier-says-operation-shelter-will-be-inconvenient-/106144190</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75e37e30fce5d51941239075cba2a66a</guid></item><item><title>Parole release of Snowtown murderer James Vlassakis overturned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/sa-snowtown-murderer-james-vlassakis-parole-overturned/106143062</link><description>Snowtown serial killer James Vlassakis will remain behind bars, after the South Australian Parole Board's decision to release him was overturned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54e1e8b751e40e2d894b77e66170274a</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese will face questions over Bondi Beach shooting as Australia mourns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/anthony-albanese-bondi-terror-attack-sussan-ley-mike-burgess/106143400</link><description>Anthony Albanese's first responsibility after the horrific Bondi terror attack is to lead a grieving nation. His next will be to explain how this happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6338d979d5dcf6d65657f254be1bde4f</guid></item><item><title>NFL quick hits: Patrick Mahomes tears his ACL, Micah Parsons suffers knee injury, Philip Rivers scores a touchdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/nfl-quick-hits-patrick-mahomes-tears-his-acl/106143906</link><description>Patrick Mahomes tears his ACL, the Packers suffer a major blow, Donald Trump's coin toss goes viral and Old Man Rivers scores a touchdown. Here's the five quick hits from the NFL action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">917e095a65744a38572239a34aadbcce</guid></item><item><title>Cameron Pearson admits murdering Perth lawyer Alice McShera at Crown Towers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/cameron-pearson-admits-murder-lawyer-alice-mcshera-crown-towers/106144072</link><description>A 44-year-old man admits killing Perth lawyer Alice McShera, whose body was found in a hotel room in the upmarket Crown Towers complex in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef9f1ecaf2e9fe522b333dec140916b4</guid></item><item><title>What videos tell us about the final moments of the Bondi Beach terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/abc-news-verify-bondi-beach-terrorist-last-six-minutes/106143126</link><description>In the final horrific minutes of the Bondi Beach terror attack, more than 100 shots were fired. ABC NEWS Verify has analysed footage showing how the last six minutes unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a855c002e49658b5a61e812833f1e71</guid></item><item><title>Australian luger Alex Ferlazzo makes stunning recovery during run after falling off his sled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/australian-luger-alex-ferlazzo-recovers-fter-falling-off/106144550</link><description>Australian luger Alex Ferlazzo pulls off a miracle recovery after falling off his sled halfway through a run.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da90e58ae3290114d4c144cf32e28ab1</guid></item><item><title>Inquest to probe death of Allan John Houston at Saraji mine in 2018</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/inquest-for-death-of-allan-john-houston-at-saraji-mine-in-2018/106143884</link><description>The veteran miner died when the bulldozer he was operating rolled off an embankment into a pool of mud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55c0604be4bff0f1b094511f5bc1eaa7</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong media mogul Jimmy Lai found guilty of sedition and collusion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/hong-kong-media-mogul-jimmy-lai-guilty-sedition-collusion/106143206</link><description>Jimmy Lai, a former Hong Kong media mogul and one of the city's most outspoken critics of China, has been found guilty of sedition and collusion in a landmark national security case that has drawn international scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b999a3880da2cb74b288fabc6b5fd306</guid></item><item><title>Deaths of Rob Reiner and wife investigated as apparent homicide, LAPD says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/two-found-dead-at-rob-reiners-home-brentwood/106145062</link><description>Rob Reiner, known for directing When Harry Met Sally... and A Few Good Men, was found dead alongside his wife inside their Los Angeles home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d04a94b290cb0635eec136bb99bef983</guid></item><item><title>Man convicted of kidnapping 19yo Charlie Gander now eligible for parole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/danny-clarke-convicted-of-kidnapping-eligible-for-parole/106137450</link><description>A judge says the offending of a man found guilty of kidnapping a Victorian 19-year-old, who was later murdered, was "spontaneous" and "born of panic".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ead77bc71a42109697426dd3359607aa</guid></item><item><title>'We are born into that fear': Canberra's failure to fix systemic racism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/canberra-failure-to-fix-systemic-racism-closing-the-gap/106145214</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a82ceccfbdc1215df5b9decf9c2dd47b</guid></item><item><title>National cabinet agrees unanimously to strengthen Australia's strict gun laws in wake of Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/albanese-proposes-tougher-gun-laws-after-bondi-attack/106143310</link><description>An urgent meeting of national cabinet agrees to strengthen Australia's gun laws in the wake of the Bondi Beach shooting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e758b09f0c99d1348b909c0f9e2e87a</guid></item><item><title>Man charged over newborn's death in Gold Coast M1 crash granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/man-charged-over-m1-death-granted-bail/106134844</link><description>A man charged over a crash that killed a one-month-old baby on the Gold Coast has been granted bail following an 11-week police investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">390bad92c54818ff286ba65c3086d062</guid></item><item><title>Man who killed two people in Bowen Bridge crash sentenced to home detention and community service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/death-by-negligent-driving-bowen-bridge-sentence/106143712</link><description>A man who caused the death of an elderly couple while driving with methamphetamine in his blood is ordered to complete 100 hours of community service and four months of home detention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb2e47144ce2e8a2f0896e8526ff92b3</guid></item><item><title>Parents of man who wrestled gun from Bondi Beach shooter call son a 'hero'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-beach-shooting-fruit-shop-gunman-hero-parents-speak/106143864</link><description>The ABC has spoken to the parents of Ahmed Al Ahmed who was shot after he heroically wrestled and disarmed one of the Bondi Beach attackers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6a595472638fcebca399c76d7ebf9fa</guid></item><item><title>WA government meets with Jewish leaders after Bondi beach terror attack, increased police patrols</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/wa-government-meets-with-jewish-leaders-after-bondi-attack/106143968</link><description>WA Premier Roger Cook condemns the "cowardly and heinous" attack in Bondi, after meeting with Jewish leaders in Perth as police increase patrols.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aebd956f068195b9dae5bb04c75acfc7</guid></item><item><title>NSW inquest told how exploding lithium-ion batteries caused volatile fires killing three</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/lithium-battery-fire-inquest/106143100</link><description>A NSW inquest has been told exploding lithium-ion batteries caused volatile fires killing three people in separate blazes within minutes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45b2521beb7a85c63b52380d119cbe74</guid></item><item><title>Adele Ferguson among three board directors resigning from Walkley Foundation over reform stoush</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/adele-ferguson-board-directors-resign-from-walkley-foundation/106143900</link><description>ABC journalist Adele Ferguson is among three directors who have resigned from the board of Australia's most prestigious journalism awards over governance issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9aee12f96e5d2c18349f9914cd58fe97</guid></item><item><title>John Howard speaks to a pro-gun rally after the Port Arthur massacre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/john-howard-speaks-to-a-pro-gun-rally-1996/106143920</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb0c11f113fbc89c7f7bb6b7ef18a7a1</guid></item><item><title>Bondi shootings show Australia's gun laws slipping since Port Arthur reforms, advocate says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-shooting-proof-port-arthur-guns-laws-failing-advocate-says/106142756</link><description>Gun control advocates say the terrifying mass shooting in Bondi on Sunday shows Australia's firearms laws, reformed after the Port Arthur tragedy, have been weakened in the years since.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">661087b209c6fe9d5ab3e6f97e76a808</guid></item><item><title>Consolidated Pastoral Company buys Beetaloo aggregation in historic deal worth more than $300m</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/cpc-buys-beetaloo-station-aggregation-for-300-million-plus/106143408</link><description>Consolidated Pastoral Company spends more than $300 million to buy the Beetaloo aggregation of stations in the NT.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49aa2ab64911fd8e49ebe2728109def3</guid></item><item><title>Australian National University stabbing victim tells court she's 'riddled with flashbacks'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/act-alex-ophel-attempted-murder-two-women-anu-trial-begins/106144496</link><description>One of two women stabbed in an attack at the Australian National University two years ago tells the ACT Supreme Court she will never feel safe again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff88c54644a3807d9bb7a84803ec5b16</guid></item><item><title>Harry Brook will rein in batting technique as England confirm team change for Adelaide Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/harry-brook-adelaide-test-cricket-bazball/106145512</link><description>As England reveal their changes for the Adelaide Test, Harry Brook has conceded he will rein in his batting technique in an effort to save the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08d7ea0d4a671a1c52d26ce33f1bcc66</guid></item><item><title>From barbecues to busy weeknights, here are seven salads to prepare this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/best-easy-summer-salads/106090760</link><description>Summer is the season for salad, and in that spirit, we've gathered seven of our finest together for you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a893c2c3c550d95330f8fcc101b821c</guid></item><item><title>Bondi's antisemitic attack is the Jewish diaspora's worst nightmare come true</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/benjamin-netanyahu-anthony-albanese-bondi-massacre/106144038</link><description>Israeli politicians have blamed Anthony Albanese for the devastating massacre in Bondi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93258c51718a7305f368056d7988e502</guid></item><item><title>What is Hanukkah, the Jewish festival being celebrated before the Bondi Beach terrorist attack?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/hanukkah-chanukah-jewish-holiday-candles-menorah/106143052</link><description>Also spelt Chanukah, the eight-day celebration observed by Jewish people around the world carries a message of resilience and positivity — one that a Melbourne rabbi said would endure despite the Bondi Beach terrorist attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89cf5b5fb3f6fd35ca69ac32e730ca4a</guid></item><item><title>New Queensland hospital bed timeline reveals some pushed back to 2032</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/queensland-hospital-beds-expansion-plan-pushed-back/106142866</link><description>The Queensland LNP government says it aims to roll out 2,600 new hospital beds across the state by 2032 at a cost of about $18.5 billion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0f70e307f0a646af575be863068b029</guid></item><item><title>As medicinal cannabis approvals surge, regulation sits on the fence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/medicinal-cannabis-approvals-alan-kohler/106146088</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f52809e4d9aa8ad5a5d7986ce32b28ff</guid></item><item><title>CAR T-cell cancer therapy to be available in SA from mid-2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/cart-t-cell-cancer-therapy-sa-royal-adelaide-hospital-mid-2026/106145758</link><description>The number of critical patients having to travel interstate to receive CAR T-cell therapy will be reduced from mid-next year, with SA to launch a service at the Royal Adelaide Hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ae439e4e2397dd9c07932e389d511f8</guid></item><item><title>ASX bosses committed to reform after damning inquiry into stock exchange operator sees shares fall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/asx-limited-shares-fall-stock-exchange-operator-inquiry/106145156</link><description>ASX bosses say they are committed to reform after the corporate regulator lashes the operator's failings in a report, saying it underestimates long-term problems, is insular and defensive with deficiencies in culture and leadership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">539b7179d78b2fd2bc2e222f96aca241</guid></item><item><title>Nathan Lyon insists he has nothing to prove in Adelaide ahead of Test return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/nathan-lyon-adelaide-ashes-england/106146112</link><description>For the first time in an age Nathan Lyon is not an automatic selection in the Test side but the returning off spinner insists he has nothing to prove ahead of the upcoming clash with England in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97c540c4314a16e1aaf6f5acb8364799</guid></item><item><title>Largest Western Power outage in 15 years cuts essential mobile phone services in firegrounds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/western-power-outage-firefighters-mobile/106144026</link><description>Firefighters are left without communications while battling emergency-level bushfires as an extended power outage sees mobile phone towers fail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c3c9a457b6b4b4e000fe93d9490541c</guid></item><item><title>Jewish community mourn terror attack victims at Bondi Pavilion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/jewish-community-mourn-terror-attack-victims-at-bondi-pavilion/106146334</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de03e93fe4908934e36c7a318e2ad2cb</guid></item><item><title>How to talk to your kids about the Bondi Beach shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/talking-to-kids-about-bondi-shooting-terror-attack/106143526</link><description>This is what psychologists have to say about approaching the subject with children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9576f64cd4cb9ccb08452a02745df59</guid></item><item><title>Aerial vision of vigil for Bondi Beach attack victims at Bondi Pavilion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/aerials-bondi-vigil-beach/106146454</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f0986ba3db8be08578dcec7479742e</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106146368</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94742278037ce655405db43417aa2f4a</guid></item><item><title>Australians urged to give blood following mass shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/australians-urged-to-give-blood-following-mass-shooting/106146572</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd7043a9f592c59253e00470ecdb8d9b</guid></item><item><title>Multiple emergency bushfires blazing across WA as communication system fails</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/wa-regs-emergency-bushfire/106146320</link><description>Western Australia's emergency warning system fails as multiple bushfires threaten lives and homes in the state's south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20826f3c75922354cd4fabe552181140</guid></item><item><title>Four dead, five hospitalised after minivan crashes near Victoria–New South Wales border</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/victoria-four-dead-in-car-crash/106146620</link><description>Police say they are responding to a crash that has claimed the lives of four people near Cobram in Victoria's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac7ff04f0322194ccb615a188f90cfbe</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with alleged murder of woman in Adelaide's parklands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/man-charged-with-murdering-woman-in-adelaide-parklands/106146510</link><description>Police have arrested a 37-year-old man for the alleged murder of a woman who was found unresponsive in Adelaide's parklands in January.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b9fdeadd6941ea76da4164d30f3f01f</guid></item><item><title>‘So many pairs of shoes’: Bondi deserted after shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/-so-many-pairs-of-shoes-bondi-deserted-after-shooting-/106146988</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89b39bea411e3896d6f0817f24e646af</guid></item><item><title>Woman recounts watching gunman fire first shots</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/woman-recounts-watching-gunman-fire-first-shots-/106146992</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eb020ff497a7997118e3296ab0ed0d3</guid></item><item><title>Suzi Milgate defends crepe attack on former NT chief minister Natasha Fyles as 'protest', during assault trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/suzi-milgate-nt-chief-minister-crepe-assault-trial-evidence/106144734</link><description>A former Darwin real estate agent charged with assaulting the Northern Territory's then-chief minister with a plate of crepes has tried to justify her actions as a "protest" against COVID-19 rules.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2ae2ac70dd50b27bd25b8dc92a5b1aa</guid></item><item><title>NSW Premier Chris Minns on the lessons that must be learned from Bondi terror attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/nsw-premier-chris-minns-interview-bondi-attacks-730/106147040</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d309729a4047a877ce3254f4f07910e1</guid></item><item><title>This fire destroyed a tractor east of Eneabba on Sunday.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/this-fire-destroyed-a-tractor-east-of-eneabba-on-sunday-/106146894</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2587a6f3abac72702bce7793d9b771c8</guid></item><item><title>Australia is in shock after a terror attack at Bondi Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/australia-is-in-shock-after-a-terror-attack-at-bondi-beach/106146612</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8024e5e3e4cc1905a3e4c79dd414c426</guid></item><item><title>Communities pay tribute to Bondi shooting victims in Sydney and Melbourne vigils</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/bondi-shooting-vigil-jewish-community/106145098</link><description>Crowds gather at Bondi to lay floral tributes and mourn, just 24 hours removed from a mass shooting that left 15 people dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45313a13879a0109b10eb980263e24e5</guid></item><item><title>10-year-old girl, Holocaust survivor and local rabbi among Bondi terror attack victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-15/10-year-old-girl-holocaust-survivor-rabbi-among-bondi-victims-/106147252</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64d662304500f506f5b4a37421542dd1</guid></item><item><title>McLeod's Daughters star Rachael Carpani dies aged 45</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/mcleod-s-daughters-star-rachael-carpani-dies/106147286</link><description>The actress had recently appeared on long-running Australian soap Home and Away and frequently spoke out on a range of issues, including on the need to address domestic violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b8b6b2d5bba69f83523097d1fe5e862</guid></item></channel></rss>