<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 19:05:17 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Benin President Patrice Talon says coup attempt thwarted with help from Nigerian military</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/benin-coup-attempt-thwarted/106114130</link><description>Patrice Talon says the West African nation's government will punish those responsible for a coup attempt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ea8421ac418ad9f8ca71e83b162b1df</guid></item><item><title>Cleveland Dodd's care in Unit 18 'inhumane', coroner examining youth detention death finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/cleveland-dodds-care-in-youth-detention-inhumane-coroner-finds/106112004</link><description>Western Australia's first recorded death in youth detention was predictable, a coroner finds, declaring the care of 16-year-old Cleveland Dodd was "inhumane" and "reminiscent of 19th century jails". WARNING: This story contains the name and image of an Indigenous person who has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6ae9813e2e602a349029e2320971ce1</guid></item><item><title>Water leak at the Louvre museum damages hundreds of works</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/hunderds-of-works-damaged-in-water-leak-at-louvre-museum/106114116</link><description>The leak occurred after a valve was accidentally opened in a heating and ventilation system, allowing water to seep through the ceiling of the Mollien wing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcd11071a8244d998a994b13c1876405</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce joins One Nation, concluding defection from Nationals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/barnaby-joyce-joins-one-nation/106114758</link><description>Barnaby Joyce's defection gives One Nation its first lower house seat since 1998.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">278b33937863e280a5410062430ada30</guid></item><item><title>England's lack of Ashes depth highlighted as Australia A thumps Lions at Allan Border Field</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/australia-a-thumps-england-lions-to-highlight-ashes-problem/106114756</link><description>England's lack of Test depth is highlighted as Australia A beats the Lions by an innings and 127 runs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cb0896b3276dafa3d9d5ad9a03b7b6e</guid></item><item><title>Government will not extend energy bill relief</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/government-will-not-extend-energy-bill-relief/106114842</link><description>Jim Chalmers says the end to the "temporary" subsidy was a "hard" decision but recognises pressures on the budget.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55398d2d5d6a262e7d4a8cd38ce0ebd8</guid></item><item><title>Thailand launches air strikes amid new border clashes with Cambodia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/thailand-launches-air-strikes-on-cambodia-border-clashes/106114878</link><description>Thailand launches air strikes along its disputed border with Cambodia, after both countries accuse one another of breaching a ceasefire agreement brokered by US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fff6be86fabeb871f89a1632dbbb598f</guid></item><item><title>One of PNG's rare conjoined twins dies after urgent surgery in Sydney, brother survives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/png-conjoined-twins-tom-sawong-surgery-sydney/106113822</link><description>Surgeons have separated a rare set of conjoined twins after they were urgently flown from Papua New Guinea to Australia, but only one of the boys has survived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a079440a2938e807240cbf33338baccc</guid></item><item><title>Coalition puts heat on Wells over trips to cricket and AFL with family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/coalition-anika-wells-cricket-expenses-travel/106113546</link><description>The Coalition is applying more heat to Sport Minister Anika Wells over flights she claimed for herself and her husband to attend two Boxing Day cricket test matches in recent years, and several AFL Grand Final events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4275bb62ee4e0bc79aac67e67b200901</guid></item><item><title>Toddler's septic tank death 'likely would have been prevented' with sufficient NT government maintenance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/nt-septic-tank-death-toddler-remote-community-coroners-report/106114688</link><description>A coroner's report has found there were multiple missed opportunities to improve or replace the public housing septic system, which the NT government had responsibility for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98d947177f624dd68d704b5339256202</guid></item><item><title>Australian Ashes openers Travis Head and Jake Weatherald praised as Usman Khawaja call looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/ashes-test-series-travis-head-jake-weatherald-usman-khawaja/106116580</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne says Australia's opening partnership is making the rest of the batting order improve, as selectors deliberate over Usman Khawaja's Test future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd19c84e600636615e42a245d0785fe1</guid></item><item><title>Should you go screen-free after giving birth? These mums share their stories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/mums-mental-health-online-postpartum/106086872</link><description>Readers share how they approached their online and social media use in the weeks immediately after giving birth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42d427354161a31e013bc51ecf3cbd12</guid></item><item><title>Trump hosts Kennedy Center Honors in historic first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/trump-makes-history-hosting-the-kennedy-center-honors/106115478</link><description>Donald Trump has made the Kennedy Center a touchstone in a broader attack against what he claims is "woke", anti-American culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1c346ecf0726a7d78fd03b0d4f5725b</guid></item><item><title>More than 30 zinc sunscreen brands using formula that failed preliminary SPF testing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/zinc-sunscreen-brands-spf-testing-lower-than-advertising/106050396</link><description>It's been almost two years since Craig Jones first ran preliminary tests on his zinc sunscreen. When he discovered it wasn't providing the SPF it was supposed to he threw it out and set out on a quest to find out why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4753ebb9b4860304072af5ef3e08466</guid></item><item><title>NRL proposes lengthy bans for Tonga officials following Eli Katoa head knocks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/nrl-tonga-officials-face-bans-over-eli-katoa-incident/106116872</link><description>Three Tonga team officials are facing two-year suspensions following the NRL's investigation into the incident that forced Eli Katoa out of the 2026 season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27f95fe22540f5745ec85088c7fcfb22</guid></item><item><title>Nant whisky founder Keith Batt pleads not guilty over alleged fraud</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/nant-whisky-founder-not-guilty-plea-over-alleged-fraud/106117058</link><description>The founder of a Tasmanian distillery behind an alleged investor fraud scheme has pleaded not guilty to 736 criminal offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c10c33c233b525683804fc6dc5a17a1e</guid></item><item><title>Perth boy's death in Department of Communities care may have been accidental, inquest told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/inquest-examines-death-of-10-year-old-boy-in-state-care/106112324</link><description>An inquest hears the 2024 death of a 10-year-old Indigenous boy while he was under the care of the Department of Communities may have been an accident, not suicide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83ca7dea763d310cb801eb99d903a67c</guid></item><item><title>Clermont's only GP clinic closes after hospital doctor suspended</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/clermont-hospital-doctor-tim-lane-suspended-after-dispute/106113774</link><description>The suspension of Tim Lane leaves a Central Queensland town of 3,000 people with no permanent hospital doctor or GP.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d72146816b82719750eec96cfb2ce126</guid></item><item><title>Thailand-Cambodia border conflict reignites.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-08/thailand-cambodia-border-conflict-reignites/106117524</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71ed64bea61eb140d343da497cb72d80</guid></item><item><title>Renters need $300,000 more superannuation in retirement than home owners, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/renters-need-twice-more-super-than-home-owners-in-retirement/106104784</link><description>Rising rents mean older Australians who are not home owners will need twice as much superannuation to enjoy the same retirement lifestyle as those who are mortgage-free, according to a study by a leading advocacy group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f0e8be479137557c82638664cac88ce</guid></item><item><title>Magnitude-7.6 earthquake in Japan prompts tsunami warning and evacuation order for 90,000 people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/japan-earthquake-prompts-tsunami-warning/106117964</link><description>The quake has seen a tsunami warning issued for large parts of Japan's northern coastline and about 90,000 people ordered to evacuate to higher ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bb4b46720be5433eaa15872180e00ad</guid></item><item><title>Jacob Elordi, Rose Byrne and Joel Edgerton score Golden Globes nominations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/golden-globe-nominations-2025/106117782</link><description>Jacob Elordi is Australia's big hope at the Golden Globes after scoring two nominations overnight for the 83rd iteration of the film and television awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aebf576e95042edfa57508a1e792b2c0</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 9: How smallpox was eradicated after killing 300 million people in the 20th century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/smallpox-eradication-infectious-disease-ring-vaccination/105999388</link><description>The eradication of smallpox 46 years ago has been hailed as the greatest triumph of global public health. It has also been held up as a model for global cooperation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd95131d8068f6201274ad73e3783a82</guid></item><item><title>Australia's favourite political test depends on who is at the pub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/barnaby-joyce-annabel-crabb-expenses-one-nation-defection/106114804</link><description>The "pub test" tends to be applied when we've run out of avenues to pursue a public figure, but are still super annoyed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bb613641045e771ebed97e24f6e6ad9</guid></item><item><title>For some teenagers, 'life is better' without social media and they support the ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/teenagers-who-support-social-media-ban/106095948</link><description>Patrick, 15, does not use social media and hopes he never does. Nick, 15, had a flip phone for the first few years of high school. Here is why they support the social media ban.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11cd0cfc0070dd985225db4602176ddc</guid></item><item><title>Fluke discoveries of asbestos in children's sand strike twice decades apart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/fluke-discoveries-asbestos-children-play-sand-decades-apart/106056760</link><description>A doctor in the US who found asbestos in his son's sandpit tried in vain to get stronger regulations. Almost 40 years later he says he's "not surprised" the problem re-emerged in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">073011ed164029fa273c9d40b51498b2</guid></item><item><title>A logical gas exports policy could put the economy back on an even keel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/time-to-fix-gas-policy-to-ease-inflation-cost-of-living-pressure/106116030</link><description>For a decade, a disaster has unfolded. We've run short of gas through indecision and incompetence, and that's driving energy costs and inflation. We need a solution and an unlikely source may have one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">474f58cf1e220611fdd153145a49d0a9</guid></item><item><title>Wells spends thousands on Comcars to attend grand finals, but has plenty of company</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/wells-spends-thousands-on-comcars-for-grand-finals/106117742</link><description>The sports minister has endured scrutiny over her use of parliamentary expenses, but is one of dozens of MPs to have accumulated large Comcar bills.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">539e905664a43e0090610d9a8afe2e80</guid></item><item><title>Halfbrick Studios CEO Shainiel Deo on creating the first Bluey video game made in Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/bluey-video-game-halfbrick-studios-brisbane/106113906</link><description>Halfbrick Studios, the company behind Fruit Ninja, has created the first ever Bluey video game made in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1957f4f6e0250e77e45f7285388a026</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy meets with European allies as Donald Trump accuses him of not reading US-led peace plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/zelenskyy-european-allies-downing-street-trump/106117756</link><description>European leaders express scepticism about US-led plans to end Russia's invasion, following peace talks between US and Ukrainian officials end without a breakthrough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a788d9da4a6464c4aa1a3f92e35c20a</guid></item><item><title>Moment magnitude-7.6 earthquake strikes near Japan’s coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/moment-magnitude-7-6-earthquake-strikes-near-japan-s-coast/106118186</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6c3f48e38de8a8b929215f4f8541fbf</guid></item><item><title>Penny Wong and Richard Marles meet US counterparts in Washington after AUKUS review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/marles-wong-hegseth-rubio-hold-ausmin-talks-aukus-defence/106118088</link><description>The recommendations made by the US's recent review of the AUKUS pact remain confidential after the talks in Washington, where the two nations have committed to the continued growth of the American military presence in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2ad9c9f6e38d4d71c90442aa95f7e80</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government makes historic apology to Aboriginal people following signing of treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/government-apology-to-aboriginal-victorians-after-treaty/106116798</link><description>The Victorian government makes a historic apology to Aboriginal Victorians, in one of the first public acts to follow the signing of the state's treaty agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c287b141c7986bd0cde18ca5ae9b903f</guid></item><item><title>Paramount counters Netflix with hostile bid for Warner Bros Discovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/paramount-hostile-bid-warner-bros-netflix/106118082</link><description>The offer paves the way for a battle between Paramount — whose owner, Larry Ellison, is an ally of Donald Trump — and streaming behemoth Netflix to buy one of Hollywood's most storied studios.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25d82dd9ad8a74c2e91677b8cbc0028d</guid></item><item><title>Bulahdelah farmers count the cost after devastating bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/bulahdelah-farmers-count-the-cost-after-devastating-bushfire/106114632</link><description>Farmers and businesses on the Mid North Coast are reeling after a fire tore through the region, destroying homes and forcing families to evacuate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">468939875f6419fddbed642b64f925c5</guid></item><item><title>Some Israeli-backed anti-Hamas gang members surrender to group</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/some-israeli-backed-anti-hamas-gang-members-surrender-to-group/106117908</link><description>A handful of members of an Israeli-backed anti-Hamas gang in Gaza have surrendered to the militant group, days after their leader was killed in the strip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edbd622b9355b843303b4233556f08a7</guid></item><item><title>AUKUS project ‘full steam ahead’, US top diplomat says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/aukus-project-full-steam-ahead-us-top-diplomat-says/106118264</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0155a4f0bdc8724995086a7da122b98b</guid></item><item><title>Mitch Marsh to retire from Sheffield Shield but leaves door open for Test recall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/mitch-marsh-announces-retirement-from-sheffield-shield-cricket/106118274</link><description>Mitch Marsh tells his Western Australia teammates he is retiring, but keeps the door ajar for a Test recall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7aeffa9d95cb18c8b91fc44297d744e8</guid></item><item><title>Families left in the lurch after Zone RV caravan manufacturer collapse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/zone-rv-customers-in-limbo-after-collapse/106098684</link><description>The sensational shutdown of the luxury caravan manufacturer has had a gut-wrenching impact on families from Australia and abroad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f30fe67994eba4db444803d85e6c20e</guid></item><item><title>Telcos call for national register of mobile phones after Triple Zero outages — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/federal-poltics-live-blog-dec-9/106115678</link><description>Telcos and government staffers have been questioned about who knew what and when, after a second Triple Zero failure was linked to a possible death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d4831f888454f5f69cc1a8e0c33484e</guid></item><item><title>Farmers and innovators say there is potential in Australia's untapped biofuel sector</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/australia-biofuel-sector-has-untapped-potential-say-farmers/105802948</link><description>Fuels produced from waste and agricultural feedstock are tipped to play a role in cutting emissions, but a leading Victorian farmer says political will is required to seize the opportunity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3de76cd91935af910eb720c85fa0a201</guid></item><item><title>Farmsafe Australia issues warning after two serious hay bale incidents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/farmsafe-australia-warning-after-hay-bale-incidents/106115168</link><description>A woman has died and a man has been hospitalised in two separate incidents involving falling hay bales in southern Queensland. Farm safety advocates are calling for increased caution while manoeuvring hay bales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f235659ff20a96eb4a19df846d06f8d6</guid></item><item><title>NT police restart investigation into mysterious disappearance of Yolŋu clan leader Dhakiyarr Wirrpanda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/nt-police-restarts-investigation-into-yolngu-leader/106116104</link><description>The announcement from NT police follows a months-long ABC investigation into the disappearance of a Yolŋu clan leader who vanished without a trace after being acquitted of murdering a police officer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df20398d6d11c7e4b745c78042fa3f2d</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur wins fourth Newcombe Medal as Maya Joint finishes runner-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/newcombe-medal-alex-de-minaur-wins-fourth-trophy/106118368</link><description>Alex de Minaur wins the Newcombe Medal for a fourth time, as Cruz Hewitt claims a junior award at Australian tennis's night of nights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b238379fbc44b34014ba11a6eeff9b7</guid></item><item><title>The Australian Christmas carols that should be on your playlist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/the-australian-christmas-carols-that-should-be-on-your-playlist/106105838</link><description>We've rounded up some Australian Christmas carols to enhance your festive mood, from W.G. James to Christine Anu.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87b21b60041e0e154a9475ba1ba8208c</guid></item><item><title>Alter Boy's NRG nominated for WA Music Award for Auslan performances</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/alter-boy-nrg-luke-eastman-auslan-wa-music-awards/106083818</link><description>Luke Eastman's interpretation work using Auslan in the band Alter Boy is recognised in this year's WA Music Awards, with a nomination for vocalist of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f40c0220a5ab8b708a0cacac4ee90e1</guid></item><item><title>Search underway at Coffin Bay on SA Eyre Peninsula for man who reportedly fell off jetty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/coffin-bay-water-search-jetty/106118414</link><description>Emergency services are searching for a man in Coffin Bay on the state's Eyre Peninsula after the alarm was raised about 1am on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fcd30bb2a0ac47e47a84a1c4eca51a6</guid></item><item><title>As the Cleveland Dodd inquest calls for a 'complete reset' in WA youth detention, what are the next steps?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/cleveland-dodd-inquest-analysis-next-steps-for-wa-youth-justice/106117732</link><description>The WA government has been sent yet another warning over the death of 16-year-old Cleveland Dodd, who was held in conditions a coroner has compared to "19th century jails". History will show if lessons have been learnt. WARNING: This story contains the name and image of an Indigenous person who has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">841065e8f15b724ea8b1c4ba434c0369</guid></item><item><title>Jake Weatherald and Ben Stokes caught up in Ashes sledging after Jofra Archer and Steve Smith clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/ashes-2025-jake-weatherald-and-ben-stokes-caught-up-in-sledging/106118556</link><description>Sledging between Jake Weatherald and Ben Stokes emerges after Jofra Archer and Steve Smith's fiery clash at the Gabba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e00b33bef30b94b8d30a2fe9a69f9944</guid></item><item><title>WA regional air travel fare cap changes anger residents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/wa-regional-air-travel-fare-cap-changes-anger-residents/106081870</link><description>The WA government says it will continue to cap airfares for regional residents but from July next year they will be more expensive during peak holiday periods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dac5f0e779750c284965330b5dabb7de</guid></item><item><title>FIFA announces scheduled water breaks during all games at the 2026 World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/fifa-2026-world-cup-water-breaks-to-be-scheduled-for-all-games/106118696</link><description>FIFA announces three-minute water breaks in both halves of all games will be included in the 2026 World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0585b3d784e1cc9bbe779d339890911</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce's defection to One Nation — the view from his electorate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/barnaby-joyce-voters-nationals-reaction/106115442</link><description>Voters in the New England electorate share their feelings as they digest the news that local MP Barnaby Joyce has defected from the Nationals to One Nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">202e2b3d7841f8522ad173d1b8b99a8b</guid></item><item><title>Mackay riverfront under the microscope as community grapples with addiction and homelessness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/mackay-riverfront-grapples-with-addiction-and-homeless/106117362</link><description>The banks of the Pioneer River near Mackay's CBD are home to makeshift camps nestled among the trees, while others reside in picnic shelters by the wharves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07e12624fb72728b2861297dd7541855</guid></item><item><title>Why Kate chose to 'stay flat' after breast cancer surgery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/why-kate-chose-to-stay-flat-after-breast-cancer-surgery/106087348</link><description>After a cancer diagnosis, Kate Miller's doctor recommended a mastectomy on one side only. But Kate wanted both breasts gone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee9c5fda1e5f653e7df6819b46e1e433</guid></item><item><title>TPG Telecom boss says second person may have died due to Triple Zero failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/triple-zero-outage-senate-hearing-tpg-telecom-second-death-link/106118690</link><description>TPG Telecom chief executive Iñaki Berroeta flags another death possibly linked to a customer's inability to call Triple Zero (000) on their Samsung mobile phone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ca9a724d429ca8f7534afb45866024b</guid></item><item><title>Canadian traditional owners fear Australian-style LNG development</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/canada-traditional-owners-in-australia-to-protest-against-gas/106111960</link><description>Canadian hereditary chief Na'Moks wanted to find out what a gas pipeline on his land would look like, so he flew to northern Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fec3762dac068c1104d6fbd8727431f5</guid></item><item><title>Josh Hazlewood ruled out of remainder of the Ashes in injury blow to Australian attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/ashes-2025-josh-hazelwood-ruled-out-of-series-with-injury/106119372</link><description>Coach Andrew McDonald confirms Josh Hazlewood will not play in the Ashes due to ongoing injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">097860d022b48b46eb529bbc4ab183dc</guid></item><item><title>Travelling teacher Tina Greenfield brings instrumental music to regional schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/travelling-instrumental-music-teacher-tina-greenfield/106107440</link><description>Tina Greenfield drives 350 kilometres each week to teach music to students at five schools in regional Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af0e9509f44753cea55e61d61c0fef55</guid></item><item><title>Four dead, one missing after powerful wave drags swimmers out to sea in Tenerife</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/powerful-wave-in-spanish-island-of-tenerife-kills-four/106118978</link><description>Local media reported that a weather advisory for rough seas was in effect when the swimmers were swept out to sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79e49197f544ed3aaafe83edbdd961e4</guid></item><item><title>University of Technology Sydney facing crisis amid union-led no-confidence vote in vice-chancellor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/university-of-technology-vote-of-no-confidence-vice-chancellor/106114890</link><description>The union-run vote comes as controversial, consultant-designed redundancies continue and politicians call for resignations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d99a7a07c10de436af442171b41740ba</guid></item><item><title>Wellington North solar farm grass fire burns almost 100ha</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/wellington-solar-farm-fire/106113846</link><description>The cause of a grass fire that started on one of Australia's largest solar farms remains a mystery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c01c7027c20f76ec5ab2adb267a0fd3</guid></item><item><title>China's trade surplus tops $US1 trillion as exports to Europe, Australia, South-East Asia surge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/china-trade-surplus-tops-one-trillion/106118828</link><description>China's record trade surplus comes as manufacturers seeking to avoid US President Donald Trump's tariffs ship more to Europe, Australia and South-East Asia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">164aff05a83bc6bd8df4845a3ab58e4f</guid></item><item><title>Beetaloo Basin gas piped north to 'keep the lights on' in NT from 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/nt-beetaloo-basin-agreement-fracked-gas/106119676</link><description>The gas-rich Beetaloo Basin in the Northern Territory has been in development for years — now, the NT government says the gas will finally flow from 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d74885298a0685ba44389d466256d0a</guid></item><item><title>Tameka Yallop waits on scan results that could put Asian Cup campaign in jeopardy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/tameka-yallop-hamstring-injury-ahead-of-matildas-asian-cup/106119984</link><description>Matildas stalwart Tameka Yallop's Asian Cup campaign hangs the balance as she awaits news on the hamstring she suffered over the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f0d00cd65166b56f01ab3005823edd6</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese delivers eulogy at Graham 'Richo' Richardson's state funeral</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/nsw-graham-richardson-state-funeral/106116350</link><description>Hundreds of former and current politicians from all sides of the spectrum gathered to remember powerbroker and kingmaker Graham 'Richo' Richardson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bba30371e6067e2b9a76aa0391892a10</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested following 'direct and significant' threats to Crows player Izak Rankine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/arrest-after-crows-player-allegedly-threatened-on-social-media/106120732</link><description>SA Police have arrested a 31-year-old man after he allegedly sent five threatening messages on social media to a Crows player, who the ABC understands is Izak Rankine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a57f2db2aecb089b0107bec1776ef6b</guid></item><item><title>Popular Bluey, Paw Patrol toy sets recalled over asbestos fears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/popular-bluey-paw-patrol-toy-sets-recalled-over-asbestos-fears/106120502</link><description>The three "sensory activity sets" from HL Toys International include sealed tubs of coloured sand which Kmart said may contain the toxic mineral.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c543ab4844a699d3b7981e15b1e19f1d</guid></item><item><title>Mackay set to host first Test cricket match when Australian men face Bangladesh in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/mackay-first-test-cricket-match-bangladesh/106120442</link><description>The Australian men will play a two-match series against Bangladesh in 2026, with the second venue yet to be decided.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">350f478bd03b64460b75dbf6cbde5bbf</guid></item><item><title>Life-saving blood platelets found to be effective when frozen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/blood-platelets-found-to-be-effective-when-frozen/106110512</link><description>Research proves that frozen blood platelets are safe and effective to use on critically injured patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aba1abdc29be0f93c88d1fc82ca21b4a</guid></item><item><title>Body of Western Australian man found after he reportedly fell off jetty at Coffin Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/body-of-wa-man-found-near-coffin-bay/106121134</link><description>The body of a Western Australian man missing in waters off Coffin Bay on South Australia's Eyre Peninsula has been found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ab8a31f2fad958c3c4a0ab7faceea06</guid></item><item><title>Patients say pelvic botox injections ease endometriosis pain, but access has been pulled from the ACT public system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/act-doctor-ordered-to-stop-botox-injections-for-endometriosis/106119880</link><description>Patients have described the procedure as "life changing" but pelvic botox injections are no longer available publicly in the ACT, with Canberra Health Services ceasing the procedure "as a precaution due to unknown risks".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">776d2c5deeb527199442777fa4cbbb92</guid></item><item><title>Small ways to teach babies and toddlers body safety and consent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/teaching-babies-and-toddlers-about-consent-and-body-safety/106026064</link><description>Narrating nappy changes is one way parents and caregivers can strengthen bonds and start lessons around body safety early.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a833a4932bef9d8cd9d0fc724760c23d</guid></item><item><title>Wells initiates audit of expenses as Shorten defends her against 'pile-on'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/wells-initiates-audit-of-expenses-as-shorten-defends-her/106121558</link><description>The sports minister maintains all her taxpayer-funded expenses have been within the guidelines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcc6d6fc2462e8a41d1a3538f647f210</guid></item><item><title>Mount Gambier woman accused of placing googly eyes on sculpture to begin negotiating with prosecution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/mount-gambier-cast-in-blue-googly-eyes-court/106114750</link><description>A 20-year-old Mount Gambier woman appears in court in person for the first time, accused of damaging a controversial sculpture, following a campaign to raise money online for her defence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c79fc42a45c2d01dc33843a0dcf6086a</guid></item><item><title>Canberra doctor ordered to stop botox injections for endometriosis pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/act-doctor-ordered-stop-botox-injections-for-endometriosis-pain/106121916</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78776bc7f795577774761fe5d1d5dc63</guid></item><item><title>People have been filmed swimming with sharks at Byron Bay.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/swimming-with-sharks-at-byron-bay/106121628</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b58fde1c722be35fe4840e91f135e73</guid></item><item><title>Byron Bay shark frenzy attracts onlookers and a warning to steer clear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/byron-bay-shark-frenzy-bait-fish-marine/106120054</link><description>A marine scientist warns against getting in the ocean with sharks after footage emerges of swimmers at Byron Bay next to a huge school of bait fish and hundreds of the predators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b506d6361289ffe47d63439b3fbe309c</guid></item><item><title>Trump laments he 'can't appoint anybody' as handpicked prosecutor Alina Habba quits unlawful tenure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/alina-habba-resigns-new-jersey-federal-prosecutor/106120108</link><description>US President Donald Trump has expressed frustration over his judicial nominations getting blocked as the lawyer he hand-picked as New Jersey's top federal prosecutor, Alina Habba, quits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27c842b3f7abec43b230a46a0ef8459a</guid></item><item><title>Woodford Folk Festival founder Bill Hauritz dies at 73</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/woodford-folk-festival-founder-bill-hauritz-dies-at-73/106119912</link><description>Woodford Folk Festival founder Bill Hauritz has died after a lengthy illness, but his grieving loved ones say his legacy will live on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6f371b4e87d96d72b2afcc929d5b404</guid></item><item><title>England quick Mark Wood to fly home after being ruled out of final Ashes Tests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/mark-wood-injury-ashes-ruled-out-knee/106122064</link><description>England's Ashes woes have continue with spearhead quick Mark Wood ruled out of the rest of the tour with a knee injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f63ca2ef36edd3b563f640b67c3c8dc7</guid></item><item><title>Canberra doctor ordered to stop botox injections for endometriosis pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/doctor-ordered-stop-botox-injections-endometriosis/106122142</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6996c6af1f8d722d8483289513235541</guid></item><item><title>Prosecution tells jury a jailhouse confession proves Jodie Hill was involved in alleged murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/jodie-hill-dimboola-alleged-murder-of-john-hunter/106121116</link><description>The prosecution has begun its closing arguments in the final stages of Jodie Hill's three week murder trial following the brutal killing of an elderly man in his Dimboola home almost three years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24924d56bd3a654f74a8daaf6759fade</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106122084</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c21b8d7898702e4a9a0aa8d34e792f65</guid></item><item><title>More crocodiles to be targeted for removal under expansion of Queensland management plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/expansion-of-queensland-crocodile-management-plan/106122482</link><description>The government says the plan will help improve public safety and make it easier to remove crocodiles in hotspots along the coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7643c257a92de6d8610cfc839d0b4457</guid></item><item><title>Honduras seeks international arrest of ex-president Hernández after Donald Trump pardon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/honduras-seeks-arrest-of-ex-president-hernandez/106122456</link><description>Juan Orlando Hernández had been sentenced in US federal court last year to 45 years in prison for helping move tons of cocaine to the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">191667dbb88d743f39f0a0f1b080a28b</guid></item><item><title>Inquest wraps up into death of Perth 10yo boy in Department of Communities care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/coronial-inquest-boys-death-state-care/106119640</link><description>The inquest into the boy's death in state care hears he was a bright and mischievous boy who was proud of his heritage. WARNING: This story contains distressing content.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c8aee7e439269d996632f3e856c75ef</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine to send US revised peace plan as Volodymyr Zelenskyy rules out ceding territory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/ukraine-revised-peace-deal-russia/106122932</link><description>Donald Trump's initial proposal to end the war was judged by Ukraine's allies to be overly favourable to Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7859a572783d96750d89e7629d931fb9</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump criticises 'weak' leaders of 'decaying' Europe and hints he could stop backing Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/trump-criticises-european-leaders-as-weak/106122876</link><description>The US president hints he could walk away from supporting Ukraine and suggests the nation could cede territory to Moscow because "Russia has the upper hand".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1375a929313f6d603f0d6f9a4dfd9737</guid></item><item><title>Spreading Thailand–Cambodia border clashes force tens of thousands of civilians to flee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/thailand-cambodia-conflict-spreads-as-civilians-flee/106117760</link><description>More than 140,000 civilians have been evacuated from border regions since fresh fighting between Thailand and Cambodia began on Sunday, officials said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3316e33dd369b44c28d7097f7680bc13</guid></item><item><title>Borders quiz: How well do you know Australian geography?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/geography-quiz-australian-borders/106117786</link><description>Which state has the longest land border? Test your knowledge in today's quiz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8418d66f47f32f5513dfacbd0f7e2b9f</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 10: How Lord of the Rings changed cinema — and New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/today-in-history-december-10-lord-of-the-rings/106088682</link><description>Peter Jackson's life wouldn't be the same after that red carpet event on December 10, 2001, but it's fair to say cinema, and New Zealand, wouldn't be the same either.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c66528cfccf90a3b11cde05e03e5ad0a</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate rises replace cuts on Michele Bullock's RBA agenda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/no-interest-rate-cuts-on-horizon-rba-december-decision/106120192</link><description>The Reserve Bank governor has opened the door to interest rate hikes in 2026, but how soon will she walk through it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53e6bff8894500c822d365e08bcbc61b</guid></item><item><title>Australia's social media ban for under-16s starts today. Here is what you should know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/australias-social-media-ban-for-under-16s-starts-today/106119800</link><description>After months of build-up, the time has finally come. From today, Australians under the age of 16 are banned from having a social media account.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a4c2f9c3bb4a52b674bb0cb3610c885</guid></item><item><title>Australian man Lamar Ahchee accused of smuggling cocaine in Bali tells court he was 'coerced'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/lamar-ahchee-trial/106122748</link><description>Lamar Ahchee was arrested in Bali in May after Indonesian police tracked the delivery of two packages containing cocaine to his apartment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02501394495649542a4da17150b1e071</guid></item><item><title>Penalties push for financial abusers who draw partners into tax and company fraud</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/penalties-call-for-perpetrators-coercive-financial-abuse-fraud/106093388</link><description>Perpetrators of financial abuse commit fraud by impersonating their partners, making them company directors in secret and putting business and tax debts in their names. The government wants to fix the problem, but will its proposed reforms go far enough?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c0103b20da54e62ba192f00031481d1</guid></item><item><title>Demand for water cannot be an 'afterthought' in AI push</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/demand-for-data-centre-water-in-ai-push/106102208</link><description>Australia has more than 250 data centres and more in the pipeline, prompting experts to warn against using drinking water to cool servers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a5bd0c991902768cecab60b229aa0cb</guid></item><item><title>AEMO slashes forecasts for wind farms as falling costs fuel solar and batteries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/aemo-isp-slashes-wind-forecasts-as-solar-batteries-rise/106120076</link><description>Soaring costs and trenchant criticism from some put the brakes on wind and transmission as the sun shines on big solar and batteries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90d859eebe5329bffe3e92e1956af9a9</guid></item><item><title>Federal politicians charge taxpayers $1.1 million for family travel in 12 months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/pollies-charge-taxpayers-for-family-travel/106122328</link><description>Family reunion travel is under scrutiny as new analysis shows federal MPs and senators spent $1.1 million on flying and driving their loved ones to Canberra and around Australia in 12 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c99d94530ebf0f953b42ed026043308</guid></item><item><title>The best albums of 2025 from Lorde, Tame Impala, FKA twigs and more</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/double-j-50-best-albums-of-2025/106096938</link><description>It's been an incredible year of music. Did your favourite album of 2025 make our list?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e420c61da6e6b1442e1abcf07c9f9154</guid></item><item><title>ABC 2026 Heywire winners bring 'raw, honest storytelling' of life in regional Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/abc-2026-heywire-winners-tell-of-life-in-regional-australia/106021792</link><description>Thirty-five young people have been named 2026 ABC Heywire winners for the bravery and authenticity of their life stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c61b48b006d0310fe5b555ccd5171a3</guid></item><item><title>Gaza named deadliest place for journalists in 2025 RSF report on dangers facing media globally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/gaza-named-deadliest-place-for-journalists-in-2025/106123004</link><description>Gaza has been named the deadliest place in the world to work as a journalist by French-based press freedom advocates Reporters Without Borders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5f9ba03199b188b75b459b67a38bd69</guid></item><item><title>Widespread rain across NSW to reduce threat of bushfires leading up to Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/widespread-rain-forecast-for-nsw-a-relief-for-bushfire-threats/106121526</link><description>The most widespread rain in three months will develop across New South Wales during the coming days, reducing the threat of bushfires in the lead-up to Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49da9ef067c2ff0b09f499e9525d7e9f</guid></item><item><title>Abuse survivors say Centrelink's 'couple rule' puts women in danger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/couple-rule-centrelink-income-test-concerns/106100196</link><description>Financial and domestic abuse survivors say the way Centrelink assesses benefit payments for people in a relationship makes it harder for women to leave dangerous relationships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df9ee2f41264eeace457f874b59e068c</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police charge 19yo over alleged grenade, gunfire attack at Tallawong home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/man-charged-over-grenade-gunfire-attack-tallawong-home/106123066</link><description>A 19-year-old is expected to front court on Wednesday after been charged over the alleged shooting at a Tallawong home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f35db945aa17061eea479523aebef76</guid></item><item><title>Scorchers take aim at Sixers ahead of WBBL semifinal after eliminating Stars in knockout final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/cricket-wbbl-scorchers-aim-at-sixers-after-beating-stars-final/106123136</link><description>The Perth Scorchers keep their WBBL title hopes alive with a win over the Stars in a knockout final, as youngster Chloe Ainsworth shows her credentials on the big stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68ef51afed024ed6a33a6d8c3ab91f31</guid></item><item><title>Taronga Zoo to 'rewild' cleared farmland in northern NSW with native Australian animals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/taronga-zoo-to-rewild-cleared-farmland-with-native-animals/106121552</link><description>Taronga Zoo has successfully bred native Australian animals for years — but it now has a vision on how to re-establish their populations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6c2a1e5a637e00e6fe97b1cdfef3359</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal group left without legal recourse without federal human rights act</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wunna-nyiyaparli-title-fight-human-rights-act/106036872</link><description>Legal experts say Australia is lagging in its human rights approach and should adopt a federal human rights act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd168af02397f759e879efd42ef0044c</guid></item><item><title>Max Verstappen pays tribute as influential Red Bull adviser Helmut Marko retires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/formula-1-red-bull-adviser-helmut-marko-retires-verstappen/106123162</link><description>Max Verstappen reacts as Helmut Marko's retirement leaves Red Bull without its two main guiding personalities since its entry into F1.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf49a6414f0bbf1052aea6ed876d72ad</guid></item><item><title>Ten-year-old snake bite survivor gives back to community through cow sale</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/10-year-old-snake-bite-survivor-giving-back-to-community/106114456</link><description>This 10-year-old is selling her family's cows to help raise funds for those who rescued her when she suffered a potentially deadly snake bite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c8898cb976b32ba6705953d32764ac0</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Albanese says social media ban biggest 'cultural change' Australia has faced — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/federal-politics-live-blog-december-10/106120662</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese says Australia's social media ban will change lives as Australia takes "back control" from social media companies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1ff720287ed0c2f11b929cfb5ed3724</guid></item><item><title>Markets live: ASX falls and Wall Street cautious ahead of likely US rate cut decision — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/asx-markets-business-live-news/106123228</link><description>The Australian share market has fallen slightly on a mostly flat day, following a cautious performance on Wall Street as the US Federal Reserve decides whether to cut interest rates. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">549bc1efccb37c60046b791c696abee0</guid></item><item><title>US judge approves release of grand jury documents against Ghislaine Maxwell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/us-judge-approves-release-of-documents-against-ghislaine-maxwell/106123122</link><description>The judge grants the Justice Department's request under a new law requiring the release of files related to Jeffrey Epstein and Ghislaine Maxwell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">debcadced8c2241d8734bcafbc24d8e9</guid></item><item><title>Why is Elon Musk fighting with the European Union over social media platform X?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/elon-musk-fighting-with-european-union-over-x/106117886</link><description>The latest target of Elon Musk's ire is the European Union, which he has called a "bureaucratic monster" that "should be abolished". So, what's going on?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ead87207d43858d0d334a7337c9b1679</guid></item><item><title>Mayhem at Brisbane Lady Gaga concert as long queues blamed on 'technical issues'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/fans-report-waiting-hours-to-get-into-brisbane-lady-gaga-concert/106122524</link><description>The stadium says "technical issues" identified during a sound check meant the gates did not open until 50 minutes later than scheduled, which caused long queues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b49b600c553349c4191db9c0fcf5ad5f</guid></item><item><title>South Africa dismissed for its lowest ever T20 score as India sends ominous message to rivals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/cricket-south-africa-lowest-t20-score-india-world-cup-rematch/106123238</link><description>The rematch of last year's T20 World Cup final is dominated by India as South Africa is dismissed for just 74 runs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e17db46b43fe455f0053c869e6f32bb</guid></item><item><title>Report finds 'shockingly low' government spend on preventing child removals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/snaicc-family-matters-report-calls-for-investment-in-prevention/106114764</link><description>Only 15.6 per cent of national child protection funding goes towards family support services aimed at keeping families intact, a report has found. Advocates are urging the government to "invest in families, not crisis".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1544693c4556d3b47c92547a3625a01</guid></item><item><title>'Integrity' of environmental approvals questioned in WA government's attempt to balance nature and industry in new laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/state-development-laws-wa-analysis/106119780</link><description>As WA's state development laws make their way through parliament, critics are worried about environmental approvals and concentration of power, but the government insists the changes mean more transparency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a2c6a5a4c2925cd9dd74ff67db7c18e</guid></item><item><title>Pet cam captures bull and horse sneaking into home of NT politician Andrew Mackay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/dogs-let-bull-and-horse-to-enter-nt-politicians-home/106118568</link><description>An NT resident tells of discovering he had unexpected guests in his home, after his dogs were filmed nudging open a door and letting inside a pet bull and horse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9537621f3ff0b957105d2fb27fec790d</guid></item><item><title>Volunteer WA firefighter with rare and aggressive cancer calls for compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/volunteer-firefighter-fighting-cancer-calls-for-compensation/106054572</link><description>Matthew Petch says firefighters like him are being left behind by an outdated compensation scheme and a lack of health screening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cdcb02a9468eb0fac75e6784d411e21</guid></item><item><title>Hannah Wilson has quit medicinal cannabis but has been relentlessly targeted by advertisements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/how-cannabis-companies-exploit-australias-legal-loopholes/106074556</link><description>Hannah Wilson says she found it shockingly easy to obtain a medicinal cannabis prescription, despite her history of schizophrenic psychosis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed85e20d31c6a635d841a3adababa780</guid></item><item><title>Formal complaint filed to FIFA over Gianni Infantino's peace prize awarded to US president Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/complaint-filed-to-fifa-over-peace-prize-awarded-to-donald-trump/106123358</link><description>A human rights organisation files an official complaint to FIFA over its peace prize awarded to US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e14bd5d331879d3b0f8004d5d410ade9</guid></item><item><title>Domestic violence offenders sentenced for calling victim-survivors from WA prisons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/broome-regional-prison-phone-calls-fdv-casuarina-victims/106086374</link><description>A WA District Court judge questions how family and domestic violence perpetrators were able to "persistently" contact their victims using a regional prison's phones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11d5f8df23afc93335ca7d0198f0d4bf</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian ministers access $45,000 in free NBL and AFL tickets in a year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/tas-gift-registry-for-politicians-published/106119614</link><description>Tasmanian government ministers have accessed more than $21,000 of free tickets to Tasmania JackJumpers games in the past 12 months, available as part of an agreement with the basketball club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ea0ae056c66fbc39dd6bff1d95c87c2</guid></item><item><title>Social media ban: Families, teens question new access and verification rules — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/social-ban-experts-blog-media-under-16/106118846</link><description>Ten major platforms are now expected to check the ages of all their Australian users and prevent anyone found to be under 16 from holding an account. Our experts have been answering your questions to help clear up confusion around the new access and verification rules. Look back on our live coverage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fda3457cf8713a8cb496b9c238627241</guid></item><item><title>NFL's Indianapolis Colts turn to 44yo grandfather Philip Rivers to play as quarterback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/nfl-indianapolis-colts-set-to-sign-philip-rivers-as-quarterback/106123424</link><description>The Indianapolis Colts reportedly sign Philip Rivers to play at quarterback, four years after his retirement from the NFL.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0118a8196d44cd691bacb17eda8d20ed</guid></item><item><title>Tottenham under fire after relocation of rainbow flag for Champions League clash with Slavia Prague</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/tottenham-moves-rainbow-flag-for-sparta-prague-football-game/106123418</link><description>Tottenham moves a rainbow flag inside its stadium following a request from Czech side Slavia Prague ahead of the two teams' Champions League meeting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9486528382366dc9ec2d80e7c1825f35</guid></item><item><title>Rare brain illness could not stop Milly from making country netball history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/milly-brock-tongala-netball-encephalitis/106098456</link><description>A rare brain illness left Milly Brock unable to walk or speak, but eight months later, she was back leading her regional netball club on grand final day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">821bba383f0020f9d6f99b0b9a15f322</guid></item><item><title>Houses destroyed in bushfire near St Helens as 'hundreds' flee to evacuation centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/tasmania-st-helens-stieglitz-bushfire-houses-destroyed/106123090</link><description>At least two properties have been destroyed in a bushfire burning near St Helens, on Tasmania's upper east coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13ff35bca8f1bf640e6b0f90c5a6c228</guid></item><item><title>Sydney lawyer Sylvan Singh charged with alleged attempts to import drugs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/sydney-lawyer-sylvan-singh-charged-shooting-drug-importation/106123490</link><description>Solicitor Sylvan Singh, 26, is granted bail after being charged with four counts of attempting to import a commercial quantity of drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4d90537381dcbf1049bd12e1e2ea7b7</guid></item><item><title>In Data Dreams: Art and AI at the MCA, 10 artists explore the impact of AI on contemporary life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/data-dreams-art-and-ai-mca-sydney-christopher-kulendran-thomas/106115358</link><description>Can you tell what's real and what's fake online? Data Dreams: Art and AI at the MCA, featuring a Kim Kardashian deepfake, looks at the impact of AI on everyday life</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6da8bd58bdbf5d37f5aac827b55e6a1</guid></item><item><title>Union votes for correctional officers to continue strike, leaving prisoners in SA locked down indefinitely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/sa-prisons-remain-locked-down-indefinitely/106123454</link><description>The union representing correctional officers has voted to strike indefinitely, while officers who monitor 1,500 people on home detention will stop work for 24 hours</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de83151db4cfaac739301d3b4df83317</guid></item><item><title>Karen community keeps traditional sport of sepak takraw alive and kicking in Bendigo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/sepak-takraw-sport-connects-karen-refugees-bendigo/106114240</link><description>Karen and Karenni refugees in central Victoria are taking a traditional sport to the world championships and staying connected in the process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a02849ca09108d493102694c09cd4b0d</guid></item><item><title>Dancing gorilla wins Comedy Wildlife Photo Awards 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wildlife-comedy-photo-awards-winners-2025/106123480</link><description>The winning images pair talented nature photography with humour that often relies on capturing a moment at just the right time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50aafd52b8ccb489374be2add3c97440</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins returns as Australia names squad for third Ashes Test in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/cricket-pat-cummins-returns-australia-3rd-ashes-test-squad/106124238</link><description>Australia's captain is poised to make his return to the Ashes as Australia names its squad ahead of the third Test at the Adelaide Oval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c153466865a6d565b0c36df8cd289167</guid></item><item><title>Wells says 'gut reaction' to travel claims fair but she has 'upheld' rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/anika-wells-gut-reaction-travel-expense-rules/106118512</link><description>Communications and Sports Minister Anika Wells accepts her taxpayer-funded travel claims have prompted a "gut reaction" in people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b44d2a73090ecce02214e2201b1dfe7e</guid></item><item><title>Liverpool records Champions League win without Mohamed Salah amid public fallout with coach Arne Slot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/football-champions-league-wrap-salah-slot-liverpool-win/106123934</link><description>Liverpool coach Arne Slot picks up a crucial win against Inter Milan with his tenure on shaky ground amid a public fallout with his star winger Mohamed Salah.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c89422b7d8d41e1ddf25b4ebf161c809</guid></item><item><title>Anika Wells answers questions over entitlements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/anika-wells-answers-questions-over-entitlements/106124188</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8dc8ceaa41b627cc9842c3349865ab</guid></item><item><title>Testing on supermarket imported honey finds some is not all honey</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/testing-finds-some-imported-honey-not-honey/106119344</link><description>Australian beekeepers are funding their own investigation into the authenticity of imported honey, with tests showing other products are being added.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a452fb7b1b2545a83a7b102f3a342b2</guid></item><item><title>Daniel Craig and director Rian Johnson on how they assemble the remarkable Knives Out cast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/daniel-craig-and-director-rian-johnson-on-how-they-assemb/106124508</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db427001260fdb1d9835b8beb97c8ede</guid></item><item><title>Crucial koala corridors are dwindling in Sydney's south-west, conservationists warn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/koala-corridors-under-threat-in-sydney-conservationists-warn/106099774</link><description>Key wildlife links between two of Sydney's major rivers are under threat from land clearing for housing, according to a koala conservation group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f91af6ff105daa364b7ab66152f69f9a</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the balloons disrupting air traffic in Lithuania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/smuggling-balloons-disrupting-air-traffic-in-lithuania/106123572</link><description>The balloons have been causing disruptions with air traffic since October. Here's what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f6343042bae9c9669c92481fb87f65b</guid></item><item><title>Mother whose son died after deliberately-lit house fire in Sydney says 'life is precious'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/arthur-haines-house-fire-manslaughter-mother-victim-impact/106124786</link><description>The mother of a teenager who was killed in a deliberately-lit house fire has told a Sydney court her son taught her "life is so precious" and she longed to be with him again for the rest of her days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db28f1e4f8b6f53849fe0a5cbf6f9a1c</guid></item><item><title>AI to be trialled at Royal Perth Hospital in bid to reduce pressure on WA health system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wa-health-system-turns-to-ai-in-bid-to-free-up-doctors-nurses/106124964</link><description>A trial of artificial intelligence at Royal Perth Hospital is announced in an attempt to help health workers focus on patient care, as new data reveals WA's emergency departments are among the most stretched in the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">916420c5a5be3e9614bebad33b7e6ec3</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste remembers Indonesian invasion 50 years after military assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/timor-leste-invasion-indonesia-anniversary/106118850</link><description>Survivors still have clear memories of the invasion by Indonesia, as Timor-Leste this week commemorates the beginning of a brutal 24-year occupation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb2d22cb023e1625be40a01636cd7005</guid></item><item><title>Star-studded cast of James Cameron's third Avatar film on what makes the movie series so special</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/star-studded-cast-of-james-cameron-s-third-avatar-film/106124758</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cbc9edb17d13ab3422fa7c0bc3c7c9f</guid></item><item><title>Taliban arrests young men in Afghanistan for Peaky Blinders dress-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/taliban-arrests-afghan-men-for-peaky-blinders-dress-up/106119104</link><description>Morality police in Afghanistan detain several influencers who have gone viral for dressing up as 1920s gangsters in the style of BBC series Peaky Blinders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b60e2a3095ffcf14564a6d30d3f6b72f</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne nutrition influencer died from postpartum haemorrhage after freebirth, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/stacey-warnecke-free-birth-death-coroner-investigates/106124514</link><description>A coroner's court has heard Melbourne nutrition influencer Stacey Warnecke died from a postpartum haemorrhage following a freebirth in September.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5cfcb104032fdb91e4e566b5242f6c8</guid></item><item><title>CFS firefighter Peter Curtis's 'great courage' remembered at funeral service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/cfs-firefighter-peter-curtis-remembered-at-funeral-service/106123650</link><description>Peter Curtis, who died at a bushfire ground on SA's Eyre Peninsula last month, has been remembered as a loving husband, father and grandfather, and a firefighter who "led from the front" and was a "bloody good bloke to have around".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4caa694bc7bc38cedf0419b7e3011d0</guid></item><item><title>Four more teenagers charged over stabbing at Ellenbrook Secondary College</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/ellenbrook-school-stabbing-three-more-teenagers-charged/106125770</link><description>A 10th teenager is charged over an alleged premeditated gang attack at Ellenbrook Secondary College on Monday that left a student with stab wounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3bdb120f5abcc8527b2d16b44b6ac22</guid></item><item><title>Bathurst childcare worker sentenced after dragging and throwing child</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/bathurst-childcare-sentencing/106118862</link><description>A woman has been sentenced after pleading guilty to assaulting a three-year-old at a childcare centre in the NSW central west. The worker pleaded guilty to dragging and then throwing a child onto a mattress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e12f968a01583772671872ed68cd28a</guid></item><item><title>Stieglitz residents stay to defend homes amid bushfire near St Helens on Tasmania's east coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/st-helens-stieglitz-locals-praise-community-spirit-bushfires/106124180</link><description>As a bushfire rages on Tasmania's east coast, bayside resident Paul Worsteling shelters in his car, charging his phone while saltwater rains down on the roof.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">becb31f702320a39f9b429aefcc7cad1</guid></item><item><title>From peacekeeping in Timor-Leste to PTSD in Afghanistan: The beauty and terror of being an official war artist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/being-an-official-war-artist/106074572</link><description>Australia has been sending artists to the frontline since World War I, with more than 50 local artists taking part since then. But what's it actually like to head into war armed with a paintbrush?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0869c324d87322e512f070bec50429fd</guid></item><item><title>Bodycam vision shows initial police encounter with Luigi Mangione.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/bodycam-vision-shows-initial-police-encounter/106125496</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a27646895597dc3baa6ec0b2c9b7d9b6</guid></item><item><title>To-do list, travel plans found during Luigi Mangione arrest revealed in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/to-do-list-travel-plans-luigi-mangione-arrest-court/106125418</link><description>A to-do list and travel plans shed light on the steps the 27-year-old may have taken — or planned to take — to avoid capture after UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson's killing last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc92e74ed867d6535763e8a1031721ea</guid></item><item><title>Alex Volkanovski hoses down retirement rumours ahead of first UFC title defence on Australian soil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/alex-volkanovski-ufc-325-diego-lopes-fight/106125956</link><description>Alex Volkanovski hoses down retirement rumours ahead of his first hometown fight in almost a decade with Australia's greatest ever UFC fighter aiming for another lengthy run defending the featherweight title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75fbbb1fadea9b7e6985f043af6c40aa</guid></item><item><title>WA opposition blames police staffing levels for slow response to Boulder ambulance emergency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wa-opposition-blames-police-numbers-for-slow-ambulance-response/106119620</link><description>The WA Liberals say a slow police response to a violent incident involving St John Ambulance officers in the Goldfields is due to understaffing but the claim has been rejected by the police minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89a501a2552c0abb67b6dad738e4d227</guid></item><item><title>Alexandar Rasic jailed for nine years over one-punch attack that killed Michael Hayes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/alexandar-rasic-michael-hayes-one-punch-sentence/106125964</link><description>Alexandar Rasic pleaded guilty to unlawful striking causing the death of Michael Hayes on the Gold Coast in June, 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5829d1a0d06f28b511963013e55a019</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's bushfire danger arrived suddenly. Here's how to prepare</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/tasmania-bushfire-preparation-explainer-what-to-do/106125742</link><description>Tasmania's bushfire season has suddenly arrived, with two catastrophes within days of each other. Here is how to prepare if one comes your way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b16253a54f55c77704f587d31bb4f7d</guid></item><item><title>Children as young as 10 could be fitted with ankle monitors under proposed Queensland laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/queensland-proposed-laws-crime-children-ankle-monitors/106126136</link><description>The legislation removes the requirement for either the child, or their parent or guardian, to consent to wearing the device.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5f1ff9a7a6110c8e573a7b919ca2410</guid></item><item><title>Defence briefs Pacific nations on China's naval flotilla but 'final destination' unknown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/australia-briefs-pacific-nations-chinese-navy-flotilla/106125002</link><description>Australian Defence officials have been briefing Pacific nations about the formidable capabilities and weaponry of a Chinese naval flotilla in the region, which the ADF is continuing to monitor closely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db439db52988340f905c0e260d1bb3ff</guid></item><item><title>Man sentenced to six years' jail for series of high-speed chases in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/thor-kristiansen-sentenced-jail-speeding-act-supreme-court/106125708</link><description>A Canberra man has been sentenced to six years in jail after a string of high-speed police chases, including at extreme speeds on the wrong side of the road.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31bcfe0520deb57d6e0eff99473e7279</guid></item><item><title>Caravan manufacturer Zone RV's $40 million creditor debt revealed after collapse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/zone-rv-owes-40-million-collapse-creditors-meeting/106121536</link><description>Zone RV plunged into administration last week, leaving customers, suppliers, employees and taxpayers in a $40 million hole.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">663ec97de5ee1c8e769840eab1a49814</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle musician Taison Brockbank talks of flashbacks and pain after being set on fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/rap-musician-fight-back-tears-when-describing-being-set-on-fire/106125498</link><description>Newcastle rapper Taison Brockbank tells the court he nearly died after being set on fire during an attack in inner-city Newcastle in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b82af3830d8926fc3b46bb742adabf13</guid></item><item><title>Coroner finds police action 'inadequate' in lead-up to murder-suicide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/lynette-thompson-inquest-domestic-violence-murder-suicide/106119798</link><description>Lynette Thompson was set on fire by her partner who later committed suicide. A coroner wants NSW police to change their procedures in dealing with domestic violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ecc6cb1a56d684447a509949476c7c2</guid></item><item><title>Woman found dead in NSW police station car park feared she was being stalked, father says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/woman-found-dead-at-nsw-police-station-had-stalker-fear/106124756</link><description>According to her father, Kirsten Moriarty had lodged a stalking report prior to her body being found in a car outside a NSW police station.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24a959929e4d55bed5d0e15eb7e47eca</guid></item><item><title>Retailer Bed Bath N' Table wins High Court case against competitor House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/bed-bath-n-table-high-court-win-house-similar-name/106125788</link><description>The stoush began in 2021 when the company House began opening new stores selling soft furnishings under the name House, Bed &amp; Bath.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e42f94bf6a8533b4e92049feb814fce</guid></item><item><title>Halls Creek man arrested after allegedly selling $45k worth of alcohol in dry WA communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/halls-creek-alcohol-sly-grogging-money-laundering-charge/106126488</link><description>The man allegedly bought large quantities of beer, champagne and rum in Darwin before selling it in WA's Kimberley region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2051a7f7ce917ea09a9f94d88ea4d89</guid></item><item><title>Teen's video diary on social media ban morning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/teens-video-diary-on-social-media-ban-morning/106126866</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d10543e40a5204d040f0e428b810b8eb</guid></item><item><title>Bail denied for 16-year-old accused of murdering Melbourne teenager Dau Akueng</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/cobblebank-stabbing-death-dau-akueng-chol-achiek-bail/106125272</link><description>A teen charged with the stabbing murder of a 15-year-old boy in Melbourne's west will remain in youth custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5bd34b36ffd93a333f427c3bac8eab6</guid></item><item><title>Victim statements redacted in 2014 fatal SA freeway crash court hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/south-eastern-freeway-fatal-crash-victim-impact-statements/106126356</link><description>The daughters of a man who died in a truck crash at the bottom of the South-Eastern Freeway in 2014 have their heavily redacted victim impact statements read aloud in court, more than 11 years after their father died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1dc19e37a9e8742d452e5c79fcaebad</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of men march against domestic violence in Alice Springs on Human Rights Day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/hundreds-of-men-march-against-domestic-violence-alice-springs-/106126534</link><description>Up to 300 men — and a similar number of women — have taken part in the annual Ingkintja Men's March Against Domestic Violence under the slogan End the silence! Stop the violence! in Alice Springs, coinciding with the International Human Rights Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afb9de3eaad61b077c62d7b9feab54d1</guid></item><item><title>Age verification errors see some under-16s retain access to banned social media platforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/social-media-ban-day-one-teen-access/106126706</link><description>It's day one of the social media ban, but dozens of parents have told the ABC their children have already been able to get around the restrictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24031d86565b1c6820fd19fd4b8bb05b</guid></item><item><title>New order banning supply of NSW North Coast green prawns a 'death knell' for industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/five-year-ban-on-nsw-raw-prawn-supply-due-to-white-spot-disease/106123412</link><description>White spot disease in prawns has led the NSW government to issue a new, five-year control order which will ban the sale of green prawns caught in affected waters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49297718e7446a4d6c754181c2e15c1d</guid></item><item><title>New crocodile management plan draws mixed response in north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/north-queenslanders-split-over-new-crocodile-management-plan/106125448</link><description>The new management plan sees the expansion of crocodile removal zones across north and far north Queensland. Some say it will not increase safety without better community education.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d527c03e914a223eb5eb665d7dd0aa2</guid></item><item><title>Man found guilty of raping 76yo woman at Coffs Harbour aged care facility</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/hayden-carl-skinner-guilty-of-raping-woman-at-aged-care-facility/106118594</link><description>Judge Michael McHugh finds Hayden Carl Skinner guilty of sexually assaulting a woman after breaking into a Coffs Harbour aged care facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9c3dfe96fd72e4892d8d2041a0f7c21</guid></item><item><title>Police discover remains while investigating 2014 disappearance of Melbourne toddler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/missing-toddler-remains-brookfield-victoria-police/106127540</link><description>Detectives have discovered what appear to be human remains while investigating the disappearance of a Melbourne toddler 11 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f766faaa59cca7afdffa0e118733055</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Supreme Court judge says burning Charlie Gander's body was a 'horrible thing to do'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/charlie-gander-murder-sentence-hearing/106123548</link><description>A Victorian Supreme Court judge says the destruction of 19-year-old Charlie Gander's body after his murder has added to the impact on his family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39907e0f8f2a2907cccd9b9d67e27913</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106127258</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e85aeff20efe1d71f9c55706e4551a44</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne expect to land former number one AFLW draft pick Kristie-Lee Weston-Turner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/north-melbourne-aflw-former-number-one-pick/106127740</link><description>North Melbourne have been unable to trade for Kristie-Lee Weston-Turner but the two-time defending AFLW premiers are still confident they'll secure the former number one draft pick.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ea6b8b1cac99bb7b87d916611cd573f</guid></item><item><title>Former specialist school worker strongly denies child sex abuse charges, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/endeavour-hills-sexual-assault-court/106125344</link><description>The former staffer of a school for children with disabilities vigorously denies child sex abuse allegations, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a7ef6bcac422f27cd3baeee08496d4a</guid></item><item><title>Cambodia pulls team out of Thailand's Southeast Asian Games over border conflict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/cambodia-withdraws-atheletes-southeast-asian-games-thailand/106127382</link><description>Cambodia withdraws its team from the Southeast Asian Games in Thailand for safety reasons, as a border conflict between the two neighbours rages for a third day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7945fa312f967c8741bb7b2e62a2856f</guid></item><item><title>Climate crisis is threatening disabled Australians' access to nature</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/climate-crisis-access-to-nature-disability/106116294</link><description>From bushfires and decreasing air quality to flooding and erosion, climate change is threatening our relationship with nature, and people with disability are being disproportionately impacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e6030aecdfc7bd4bfb090bffc4c8061</guid></item><item><title>At least 22 killed in collapse of two buildings in Morocco, state news agency says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/people-killed-in-collapse-of-two-buildings-in-morocco/106127820</link><description>The two adjacent four-storey buildings that collapsed overnight were home to eight families, the country's state news agency says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92bd56a8fa8414d90108a0b6e7481e91</guid></item><item><title>Inquest into toddler's septic tank death sparks calls for improved maintenance in remote NT public housing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/septic-tank-death-kumanjayi-fly-public-housing-coronial-inquest/106118886</link><description>Aboriginal housing advocates are calling for urgent improvements to the way remote public housing is maintained in the Northern Territory, after the coroner found the death of a toddler who fell into a backyard septic tank could have been prevented.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">caec77585ea2e595da2a95f4e9e2f192</guid></item><item><title>Kane Scott Dallow pleads guilty to forgery, fraud charges in Launceston Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/kane-scott-dallow-pleads-guilty-to-forgery-fraud-charges/106126948</link><description>A convicted conman tells a court he was trying "to keep up an appearance" as he pleads guilty to forgery and fraud charges in a Tasmanian court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d73dd250a186b6f5c0f3eaa533a64f1</guid></item><item><title>Australia has recorded the highest number of Indigenous deaths in custody since 1979</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/largest-number-of-indigenous-deaths-in-custody-since-1979/106121828</link><description>Australia recorded the largest number of Indigenous deaths in custody in the last financial year since 1979. Experts say over-incarceration remains a national crisis and prisons are neglecting the physical and mental health of vulnerable people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beaf475b8b27faa178ef96c69cf1409b</guid></item><item><title>Marco Rubio orders US State Department to revert to Times New Roman font, calling Calibri adoption 'wasteful'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-10/us-state-department-reverts-times-new-roman-font/106127732</link><description>In a leaked internal cable, Secretary of State Marco Rubio calls the department's decision to adopt Calibri in 2023 a "wasteful" diversity move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f98705a0075c776b00b9cb6290441f9</guid></item><item><title>US backs Japan in dispute with China over radar incident as tensions escalate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/us-backs-japan-in-dispute-with-china-over-radar-incident/106128020</link><description>China and Japan have given differing accounts of the incident, which was a major escalation in tensions between the two nations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f7c862084fd730289846293bc733530</guid></item><item><title>Nearly 200 children conceived from sperm donor with increased cancer risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/children-conceived-from-sperm-with-cancer-risk/106128026</link><description>Between 2006 and 2022, the man's sperm was sold to 67 clinics in 14 countries, whereas 99 children were fathered by the donor in Denmark alone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cd952c66ea268a278bb59c7d05297ca</guid></item><item><title>US plans to order foreign tourists, including Australians, to disclose social media histories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/white-house-plans-social-media-requirement-visa-exempt-countries/106128022</link><description>Applicants would also have to submit phone numbers, email addresses, personal details of family members and biometric information under the plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91b5c6ed58ba5307414ebb7f60b53bb4</guid></item><item><title>Half a million people flee Thailand-Cambodia border conflict as Trump moves to intervene again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/half-a-million-people-flee-thailand-cambodia-border-conflict/106128158</link><description>Thailand has rejected Donald Trump's plan to call both sides to achieve peace, with half a million people forced to flee the fighting along the border.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2187d0404028679ddc4bb7ef75216c4e</guid></item><item><title>Sophie Kinsella, author of the best-selling Shopaholic novels, dies at 55</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/sophie-kinsella-author-of-shopaholic-book-series-dies-aged-55/106128174</link><description>Kinsella, who also published under her real name, Madeleine Wickham, announced in April 2024 that she had been diagnosed in late 2022 with glioblastoma, an aggressive form of brain cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5df3ad8902d66540f2d3c6b1a47afb4</guid></item><item><title>Democracies must fight for freedom, Nobel Peace Prize laureate Machado says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/democracies-must-fight-for-freedom-nobel-peace-prize-machado/106128196</link><description>Democracies must be prepared to fight for freedom in order to survive, Nobel Peace Prize laureate and Venezuelan opposition leader Maria Corina Machado says in a speech delivered by her daughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a802fb115dd97304b5ad35f3a4d04cf9</guid></item><item><title>Two-way tolls with $60 permanent cap confirmed for Sydney's harbour bridge and tunnel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/two-way-tolls-60-dollar-cap-sydney-harbour-bridge-and-tunnel/106127264</link><description>Drivers are set to be tolled on all three Sydney Harbour crossings in 2028, but a weekly toll cap will be made permanent, the NSW government confirms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b883ae01cc030e0748bd7cdc0c48bd0a</guid></item><item><title>Tens of thousands of VCE students to receive ATAR as results released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/vce-school-results-year-12-025-/106125626</link><description>The nail-biting wait is over for tens of thousands of Victorian year 12 students, who will begin receiving their much-anticipated VCE results online from 7am today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7688aac51c3046dea9872d2303ec06fc</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 11: How a van full of armed men and millions of dollars inspired Goodfellas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/today-in-history-december-11-lufthansa-heist/106116722</link><description>It has been almost 50 years since armed men burst into the Lufthansa cargo terminal at New York's John F Kennedy International Airport and got away with stealing millions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa60e0fd4333897c002bc02951aff74a</guid></item><item><title>Formula 1 quiz: How much do you remember from the 2025 season?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/formula-1-quiz-test-your-2025-season-knowledge-oscar-piastri/106124134</link><description>After 24 grand prix and plenty of champagne, the Formula 1 2025 World Championship is over. But between all the races and rivalries, points and penalties — how much do you remember?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81eb62d04ff26dd2500736d5c77b76fc</guid></item><item><title>Landmark case aims to force betting agencies to return gambled stolen millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/case-seeks-to-recover-gambled-stolen-millions-from-bookmakers/106127214</link><description>A landmark legal case against three of Australia's biggest online betting agencies has been filed in the Federal Court, aimed at recovering millions of dollars' worth of stolen money that was gambled away and kept by corporate bookmakers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdbffe5eb41d9639002ebac899132190</guid></item><item><title>Meta ran ads for bond scheme run by GIM Trading that allegedly defrauded millions from investors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/meta-ads-gim-trading-alleged-bond-scam/106077848</link><description>Tech giant Meta ran advertisements used to lure Australian investors into a fraudulent bond scheme that allegedly defrauded tens of millions of dollars from them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bae24be29737c8b1263ca154a35d4a2</guid></item><item><title>Nationals MP's high family travel bill highlights generous rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-11/nationals-mps-high-family-travel-bill-highlights-generous-rules/106126842</link><description>Calls for politicians' family travel entitlements to be tightened are growing, as analysis shows one Nationals MP was allowed to charge taxpayers more than $80,000 flying his spouse to and from Canberra 27 times in two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7e02c292ccefc5d6bca00c1bf777cbb</guid></item></channel></rss>