<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 17:00:49 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>RBA forecasts suggest more cost-of-living pain and risk of no more interest rate cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/rba-interest-rates-statement-on-monetary-policy-analysis/105969494</link><description>Will 3.6 per cent be as low as the Reserve Bank's cash rate gets? A majority of economists now believe so.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a49ecbfed42d168ca6196d7a4b67cac</guid></item><item><title>Some Australian states are set to get a free electricity period every day</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/solar-sharer-free-energy-three-hours-outlier-states/105968998</link><description>The federal government says its new Solar Sharer scheme will also benefit Australians who aren't able to access it, but some experts are hesitant to agree.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ed74aea8c7ca1a5ed89fd3d67d343fa</guid></item><item><title>Half Yours wins $10 million Melbourne Cup at Flemington, beating Goodie Two Shoes and Middle Earth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/melbourne-cup-wrap-half-yours-wins-at-flemington/105969044</link><description>Half Yours wins the 165th edition of the Melbourne Cup at Flemington, with jockey Jamie Melham making history as the first female jockey to win both the Melbourne and Caulfield Cups.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4146c0a445122ebed8d609b3f62efabd</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley almost certain to face challenge next year, detractors say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/sussan-ley-almost-certain-to-be-challenged/105970786</link><description>While conservatives are waiting for the net zero issue to be resolved, those who support Andrew Hastie or Angus Taylor for the leadership say her leadership will likely be threatened after the summer break.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f28a7dd365e917dcf51154d1b2cbdd1d</guid></item><item><title>Sorry seems to be the hardest word for ACT Transport Minister Chris Steel after bungled MyWay+ rollout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/sorry-the-hardest-word-for-act-transport-minister-chris-steel/105969026</link><description>Five days after being censured in the ACT's Legislative Assembly for the bungled rollout of the territory's MyWay+ network, Transport Minister Chris Steel has issued a statement to "apologise to anyone impacted by the transition to the new service".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e37c545d0d688068102d25ea466764bd</guid></item><item><title>Hektoria Glacier in Antarctica shrinks at fastest rate recorded in modern history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/hektoria-glacier-antarctica-retreats-fastest-pace-recorded/105968782</link><description>Antarctic scientists have documented the fastest retreat of a glacier in modern history, after it lost eight kilometres of ice in just two months, according to a new report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d7a7558133afee244b380a294b75313</guid></item><item><title>Streaming services to be made to produce Australian content</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/streaming-services-to-be-made-to-produce-australian-content/105970910</link><description>The federal government puts laws requiring streaming services to produce Australian content back on the table after a hiatus following the US election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcc02221f7eedf3c50ecac05c253f945</guid></item><item><title>Multi-generational housing could be a solution to housing shortage, NSW inquiry hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/nsw-housing-crisis-rural-land-zoning-secondary-dwelling-reforms/105970220</link><description>Communal living was once common in regional Australia. Now an investigation is underway into whether it could help ease the housing crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bb1fb4a807d14b85440e9bfac0f885c</guid></item><item><title>Woman convicted of starving ballerina daughter denied bail ahead of appeal hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/ballerina-starvation-trial-mother-denied-bail-appeal/105971136</link><description>A Perth mother jailed for starving her only child to the point of severe malnutrition is denied bail after arguing she should be released because she had not been given a fair trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ade1bcda1fbf909d0978e59c72c5258</guid></item><item><title>Mother had 'callous disregard' for deteriorating health of dying six-year-old daughter, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/crystal-hanley-criminal-neglect-daugther-charlie-death/105968420</link><description>A court has heard harrowing accounts from emergency services and the siblings of a young girl who died after her mother criminally neglected her. Warning: Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander readers are advised this article contains the first name and image of a person who has died. Readers are also advised this story contains content which may be distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62bd92f2d569de80172b7c7dcef2adb5</guid></item><item><title>Fugitives could be stripped of welfare payments, but critics say it denies 'natural justice'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/fears-fugitive-welfare-cut-off-will-capture-innocent-people/105971100</link><description>Fugitives wanted for some of the most serious crimes and sexual offences could soon be stripped of their welfare payments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad32719dd40599eb4ea863faadf6c79a</guid></item><item><title>Jillaroos boosted by return of Tamika Upton for Pacific Championships final against New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/rugby-league-jillaroos-tamika-upton-return-pacific-champs-final/105971642</link><description>Australia's hopes of claiming the Pacific Championships are handed a major boost with star fullback Tamika Upton ruled fit to play after recovering from a calf injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ce3694d85d94b2ec998942b37dc9e9a</guid></item><item><title>Jamie Melham joins Michelle Payne in rare club after overcoming challenges to reach pinnacle of career</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/horse-racing-jamie-melham-melbourne-cup-journey-analysis/105971088</link><description>Jamie Melham overcomes numerous challenges to reach the pinnacle of her racing career, joining Michelle Payne in the rarest of rare clubs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e2f5f6d120790aecd81a0f86f7cfd7f</guid></item><item><title>Osborne Park Football Club suspended for two years after Stephen Hawking costume controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/osborne-park-football-club-suspended-two-years-perth-league/105971762</link><description>A suburban Perth football club is suspended from its league for two years after a "severe breach" of integrity standards, following an end-of-season costume stunt that left City of Stirling workers distressed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fd1c7d382d9d859b21e11ff03d7cc49</guid></item><item><title>PNG hospital says anyone prepared to take on conjoined twins 'must be willing to take on' the risks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/png-conjoined-twin-boys-parents-ask-doctors-to-explore-options/105969288</link><description>The mother of a rare set of conjoined twins is begging doctors to explore other options after a Papua New Guinea hospital recommended against sending the infants overseas for surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d657803cebee8550f4a21eafec07ffad</guid></item><item><title>New vaccine gives fresh hope to save the koalas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/new-vaccine-gives-fresh-hope-to-save-the-koalas/105971598</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9142881ef1d5d357ab9ce70d1cb69a72</guid></item><item><title>At least three nations 'willing to kill' on Australian soil, spy chief says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/asio-chief-warns-three-nations-willing-to-kill-in-australia/105971692</link><description>The nation's top spy uses a major speech to warn there is a "realistic possibility" a foreign government will try to assassinate a dissident on Australian soil, saying ASIO believes "at least three" nations are willing and capable of carrying out such a plot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">640b6baaec87f19cdca711e0f84ab10e</guid></item><item><title>Queensland medical professionals to take industrial action as negotiations with state government stall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/qld-united-workers-union-health-workers-industrial-action/105972044</link><description>About 2,000 radiographers, pharmacists and radiation therapists will take industrial action from Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b402c0ecef21867ce09397bed50a27aa</guid></item><item><title>Reddit and Kick added to child social media ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-04/reddit-and-kick-added-to-child-social-media-ban/105971750</link><description>Reddit and Kick will be included in the world-first social media ban for children under 16, which begins next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1d270418671127d74fc448c316aa89b</guid></item><item><title>ASIC shone a light on private lending and did not like what it saw</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/asic-deep-dive-into-the-hazy-world-of-private-lending/105965776</link><description>The corporate regulator is threatening Australia's nascent private lending industry with tighter regulation if it does not see a significant lift in standards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1c877b2ee59f887d73b8608bf4dbc63</guid></item><item><title>David Beckham receives knighthood from King Charles at Windsor, with wife to be known as Lady Beckham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/david-beckham-receives-knighthood/105972298</link><description>World-famous footballer David Beckham is handed the honour, for services to sport and charity, at a ceremony at Windsor Castle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74efafab9422e6724ca17f6569405651</guid></item><item><title>Five people sentenced to death in China for their role in Myanmar scam centres</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/myanmar-scam-factory-death-penalty-in-china/105972292</link><description>A Shenzhen court has sentenced five people to death for their involvement in a violent criminal gang with fraud operations in Myanmar, Chinese state media says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe3501bf310ef97982468b513af36bca</guid></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani favourite to become New York mayor as polls close in US elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/new-yorkers-head-to-the-polls-mamdani/105972344</link><description>Zohran Mamdani, who looks set to become the Big Apple's first Muslim mayor, has declared that it is "time for a new day in our politics" as voters headed to the polls in America's largest city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">888fcf543615e64b28ecf28585e00c6c</guid></item><item><title>Marinus Link project payouts cheered by some Tasmanian farmers, but others refuse to budge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/landowners-compensation-to-host-marinus-transmission-lines/105969056</link><description>The fate of the contentious Marinus Link project lies in the hands of hundreds of Tasmanian landowners, some of whom are welcoming the financial compensation. For others, it's a different story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0375c1b94325d40ff0cbe22e3132d300</guid></item><item><title>US Federal Reserve pumps cash into Wall Street as banking system shows signs of stress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/us-fed-pumps-billions-into-economy-to-avert-credit-crunch/105970180</link><description>Analysts say recent Wall Street activity shows pockets of global money markets are coming under strain. It has got some people worried the world could be heading towards another global credit crunch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c41e7ad4a49feaf61dda8a2c61d228b</guid></item><item><title>Does intermittent fasting dull your mental edge? We crunched the data for the best advice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/intermittent-fasting-mental-performance-research/105970476</link><description>Intermittent fasting can have health benefits, but does being hungry affect our cognitive abilities? Here's what all the evidence tells us.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b79d77e8e5083c608a92039765518c74</guid></item><item><title>November's 'beaver' full moon will be the closest supermoon of the year. Here's how to see it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/november-supermoon-beaver-full-moon/105969072</link><description>The difference from other full moons won't be all that noticeable to the naked eye, but you can enhance the viewing experience if you pick the right time and vantage point.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bab3dc4ef250ead0cd4756b6ec191cd</guid></item><item><title>Workplace culture reviewed at Toowoomba Hospital amid maternity leadership turnover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/toowoomba-hospital-workplace-culture-review-maternity-concerns/105965506</link><description>Thousands of babies are born at the Toowoomba Base Hospital each year, but some women say they are scared to give birth there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b2e79adfa9003ccfd3e3a85b025d55</guid></item><item><title>Judge awards $500,000 to Joanna Scott in Ben Aulich-founded companies share dispute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/federal-court-joanna-scott-compensation-share-dispute/105971892</link><description>The Federal Court has found a Canberra woman was unfairly stripped of the value of her shares in two companies founded by former lawyer Ben Aulich, awarding her $500,000 in compensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c5bde13edb3b0ea97324eaf9647dc96</guid></item><item><title>Residents warned to be aware of 'disaster chasers' after severe storms. Here's what to look out for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/qld-warning-for-people-impacted-by-storms-disaster-chasers/105970790</link><description>After being smashed by giant hail, south-east Queensland residents are being warned to be aware.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a52108c0a415a64a3024d5dfba1cffb</guid></item><item><title>Documents reveal Bureau of Meteorology's new website could cost $78m — or as much as $150m</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/true-cost-of-bureau-of-meteorology-new-website/105948508</link><description>Tender documents and sources show the Bureau of Meteorology's new website may have cost between $78m and $150m — much higher than initially reported.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7041e67cdf3a5add3f12bb1f0d49a9cc</guid></item><item><title>Western Sydney hospital report finds 'avoidable' errors in lead up to Deaf man's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/western-sydney-hospital-admits-errors-deaf-man-death/105969074</link><description>Bruce Drabsch's daughter Melinda Dagger, who was travelling to hospital to be with her ailing father, was phoned by a doctor and asked to inform her mother her husband of more than six decades had died, because no Auslan interpreter was provided.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b21237108b80b0debc2a50538b2cb874</guid></item><item><title>NRL to crack down on poaching contracted stars in wake of Lachlan Galvin saga</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/nrl-launches-new-anti-tampering-rules-in-wake-of-galvin-saga/105972520</link><description>NRL clubs are set to be put on notice and told they can no longer publicly declare interest in a player at a rival team unless the target is off contract.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1f8ce2e6e4238a45e37ee2da215f34a</guid></item><item><title>Typhoon Kalmaegi leaves dozens dead in flooding rains and intense winds in Philippines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/typhoon-kalamaegi-leaves-dozens-dead-in-floods-and-winds/105972498</link><description>More than 50 people are dead and hundreds of thousands displaced after rains from Typhoon Kalmaegi flooded the central Philippines, sweeping away trucks and shipping containers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ec4eb2ce5ff5a78e63e738a3ca8aaa0</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Question Time erupts as treasurer accuses Ted O'Brien of 'egregious lies' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/federal-politics-live-blog-nov-5/105971464</link><description>Jim Chalmers accuses Ted O'Brien of spreading "egregious lies" about government spending, leading to protests from the opposition. Take a look back at the day's coverage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78157b6e3b56ff4b146a0f2531b2d83b</guid></item><item><title>CSIRO koala population estimates triple, but conservationists cast doubt on figures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/csiro-koala-monitoring-population-estimate-triples/105958844</link><description>Koala advocates and logging supporters have seized on the release of data showing koala population estimates tripled in the past three years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c2275f4a2bbf56302eb72d9521503cb</guid></item><item><title>Key Queensland inland highways left without EV chargers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/inland-highways-left-without-ev-chargers/105950356</link><description>The Queensland government says schemes to help grow its electric charger network have been "fully contracted" with "no additional funding committed", leaving it to towns, roadhouses and accommodation providers to fill the gap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b56f386070c9f02dad04599f79cd50ab</guid></item><item><title>Karenia cristata species source of toxins in SA's algal bloom, scientists believe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/south-australian-algal-bloom-source-identification/105968904</link><description>Scientists believe they have identified the species responsible for the toxins in South Australia's marine algal bloom that has killed millions of aquatic animals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">290c55cec4033bb9e0d95d0dd09f8377</guid></item><item><title>Liz Heggaton lobbies federal parliament for better prostate treatment after husband's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/widow-takes-fight-for-awareness-of-prostate-cancer-to-canberra/105947410</link><description>Liz Heggaton has become an "accidental advocate" for prostate cancer after her husband Craig took his own life while receiving treatment for the disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f87ad562de25f3e888ead140d6427e7</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios to face Aryna Sabalenka in Battle of the Sexes exhibition in Dubai</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/kyrgios-to-face-sabalenka-in-dubai-exhibition/105972676</link><description>Nick Kyrgios and Aryna Sabalenka are to star in the latest man-vs-woman tennis match, with Kyrgios following several notable Australians in doing so.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1599946063764dd30e9cd2dee209bbb4</guid></item><item><title>Thunderstorms, hail, damaging winds mark WA weather forecast for much of the week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/severe-weather-warning-for-wa-with-thunderstorms-damaging-winds/105971670</link><description>A severe weather system is expected to bring thunderstorms, damaging winds and hail to much of Western Australia this week — with 50mm of rain or more possible for some areas through Thursday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a86567a88b312d0246b0f30c41788cb</guid></item><item><title>GrainCorp class action settlement fails with dispute set to head back to court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/graincorp-numurkah-class-action-pollution-settlement-fails/105969088</link><description>A class action stemming from a long-standing dispute over alleged noise and odour pollution from a GrainCorp factory in Victoria will head back to court after the parties failed to agree on a settlement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89032351edc8881f6a530948097f5f55</guid></item><item><title>‘Deeply scar and hurt people’: Women and girls turning away from community sport due to racism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/racism-turning-women-and-girls-away-from-community-sport/105966058</link><description>A new study reveals women and girls are being turned away from community sport by racist behaviours including appearance-based name-calling and a lack of understanding of diverse cultures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fa7a391bfb82a77139c75cb2e824ce3</guid></item><item><title>Police charge husband with murder over the 1991 death of Whittlesea woman Melinda Freeman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/vic-man-charged-over-melinda-freeman-death/105972814</link><description>Police say 63-year-old Craig Freeman has been charged with murder over the death of Whittlesea woman Melinda Freeman in 1991.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">218ad57b382f24fbf0960c21713ebbdd</guid></item><item><title>Robert Taylor, ex-lead guitarist of NZ rock band Dragon, dies aged 74</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/robert-taylor-lead-guitarist-of-dragon-dies/105972792</link><description>Robert Taylor, the former lead guitarist of the New Zealand band behind hits like April Sun in Cuba and Are you old Enough?, has died aged 74.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55396787ee92895e52a061349eadc616</guid></item><item><title>Synergy lodges applications for 'divisive' wind farm on WA's south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/scott-river-wind-farm-divides-community/105967602</link><description>A proposed 20-turbine wind farm at Scott River in WA's South West reaches a development milestone with developers and power provider Synergy lodging formal applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5751ae247bc4d76af5cb9707f8a08d13</guid></item><item><title>Helen Garner wins Baillie Gifford Prize for collected diaries, How to End a Story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/helen-garner-diaries-baillie-gifford-prize-how-to-end-a-story/105942040</link><description>After being featured in Dua Lipa's book club and the SATC spin-off, Helen Garner has won the Baillie Gifford Prize for non-fiction for her collected diaries, How to End a Story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc9ca65daad3bb3dd0b24fafb4b31c93</guid></item><item><title>Bell Bay Aluminium and Hydro Tasmania 'buy time' with short-term power deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/bell-bay-aluminium-one-year-in-principle-power-agreement/105972712</link><description>Bell Bay Aluminium and Hydro Tasmania reach an in-principle power agreement, after the smelter last month told staff the company's future in northern Tasmania was at "significant risk".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4298c97de9ac427f425a17e120620b39</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley confronts leadership coup speculation head-on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/ley-confronts-leadership-coup-speculation-head-on/105972636</link><description>The opposition leader has sought to hose down speculation she will soon be toppled, saying she is "completely confident" she will still be in the job at the end of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27dd7b404e344f1c584ef230d5c292ca</guid></item><item><title>Dawesville man accused of grooming, sexually assaulting girls faces 59 charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/dawesville-man-accused-of-grooming-sexually-assaulting-girls/105973002</link><description>WA Police charge a 34-year-old man with dozens more child sex abuse charges, including sexually assaulting girls he groomed online, after an initial investigation earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9307ff31ea9c97b85fa9a2c44b67661f</guid></item><item><title>Older Australians face long wait to be assessed for aged care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/older-australians-face-long-wait-for-aged-care-assessments/105971968</link><description>Families and insiders say the system to assess people for aged care is in crisis, with 116,000 people on the waiting list. Once approved, they join the queue to get a home care package, which stands at more than 120,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0de5763dd459968f4d5932df674f951f</guid></item><item><title>Little penguins re-establish breeding grounds on NSW far south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/little-penguins-eden-breeding-twofold-bay/105963874</link><description>A re-establishing little penguin colony, once locally extinct, is finding its feet on the NSW far south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e10f957ed611f695bf39b4cf259a0a5a</guid></item><item><title>Max Dowman, 15-year-old Arsenal winger, becomes Champions League's youngest player</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/max-dowman-arsenal-champions-league-youngest-player/105973312</link><description>At 15 years and 308 days old, Arsenal winger Max Dowman comes on as a sub against Slavia Prague to become the youngest player in Champions League history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d4ce5fd11cc2e2739eb8714e11ffba4</guid></item><item><title>Australia names its squad for the first Ashes Test in Perth, Jake Weatherald potential opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/live-ashes-first-test-squad-announcement/105973038</link><description>Australia has named its squad for the first Ashes Test, but is no closer to knowing who will open the batting in Perth on November 21.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0d0c619f43c5212413b9ae025f1ea53</guid></item><item><title>Murchison shires, residents complain about water quality despite significant upgrades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/murchison-shires-residents-call-for-water-infrastructure-upgrade/105966434</link><description>Stinging eyes, dead plants and a "white" film over appliances are among water complaints in Western Australia's Murchison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">016fd112348bb6fa7d37a1ebf49e6143</guid></item><item><title>Ballina shipwreck mystery close to being solved by analysis of single piece of wood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/shipwreck-mystery-close-to-being-solved-maritime-history/105969238</link><description>The identity of a shipwreck that was exposed in northern New South Wales by Cyclone Alfred has been narrowed down to just 13 vessels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6775e15d7d59b516970a94ace342837</guid></item><item><title>Man rescued near Mount Buller after being caught in unexpected November snow dump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/mt-buller-rescue-snow-dump-hikers/105972882</link><description>Police say that a 20-year-old man who was caught in a blizzard near Mount Buller overnight has been safely rescued.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cefd2142c50ec9161672bd272387b36b</guid></item><item><title>Behind the News presenter Jack Evans designs T-shirts to share Indigenous language on screen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/behind-the-news-indigenous-language-t-shirts/105953066</link><description>Every week ABC Behind the News presenter Jack Evans designs a T-shirt featuring a word from his mob's language and shares it with the show's audience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7ab1434c160dd6d0b882200d6674082</guid></item><item><title>Race discrimination commissioner questions AFL's commitment to fighting racism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/race-discrimination-commissioner-questions-afls-commitment/105956870</link><description>Australia's race discrimination commissioner says the AFL is falling far short of its responsibility to combat "horrific racism" aimed at its players.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cbaad57fc32fce7ce02fb245ee9f682</guid></item><item><title>Father and son die after being stung by swarm of 'murder hornets' during Laos holiday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/father-and-son-killed-by-murder-hornets-during-holiday-laos/105973530</link><description>An American teacher and his teenage son die after being stung more than 100 times by a swarm of hornets while climbing down a tree after zip-lining at a resort in Laos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f91785963588c4bc0b4b9dc7a491425</guid></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology wave buoy in SA offline again despite nine-month repair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/bureau-of-meteorology-wave-buoy-in-sa-offline-again/105971410</link><description>Despite a new "specialist mooring" part that took nearly a year to import and install, the Cape du Couedic wave buoy is offline again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea42eb950667781326303b07e17db109</guid></item><item><title>NYC election result delivers democratic socialist candidate Zohran Mamdani stunning win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/nyc-election-results-set-to-deliver-win-for-zohran-mamdani/105968288</link><description>New Yorkers shake the United States's political establishment and deliver 34-year-old democratic socialist Zohran Mamdani a stunning victory in the city's contentious mayoral election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffed6d1ff9cd680875f37d08206f16a6</guid></item><item><title>Pedestrian dies after car ploughs into Launceston CBD food court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/mortys-launceston-food-court-car-crash/105974210</link><description>Tasmania Police says a woman has died after a car crashed into a food court in Launceston's CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2c0da38e17576740aa0249b2f1af54b</guid></item><item><title>Two men charged with murder over gangland assassination of John Versace in Condell Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/john-versace-two-men-charged-with-murder/105974366</link><description>The pair have been charged after the cleanskin tradie was killed outside his family home in May.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78c1f52631bfbfbe386183900863725a</guid></item><item><title>Man's misdiagnosis with cancer after pathology error 'linked with his death', coroner finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/sa-pathology-error-leads-to-cancer-misdiagnosis-coroner-finds/105974340</link><description>The consequences of a contaminated biopsy sample, which led to a man being wrongly diagnosed with lung cancer and having part of his lung unnecessarily removed, were "profound", a coroner has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9661527d7a456e3279840a2fcf36925</guid></item><item><title>Experts share tiny home warning as interest from young people soars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/are-tiny-homes-the-solution-to-the-housing-crisis/105971646</link><description>Public interest in tiny homes has skyrocketed in recent years, but experts warn they come with their own problems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a6a8b535f9eee8a3528beda0ca121e3</guid></item><item><title>Former NRL star Trent Merrin charged with $140,000 crypto theft</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/trent-merrin-arrested-over-crypto-theft/105973884</link><description>Former NRL star Trent Merrin is arrested in the Illawarra, accused of stealing $140,000 in cryptocurrency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f39c5f0d9ca5b3479b340b2cd87dea8</guid></item><item><title>AFLW rising talent Sophie McKay comes from a famous football family. Yet she almost didn't play</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/sophie-mckay-carlton-blues-aflw-eve-of-finals/105969480</link><description>Despite coming from a family with a strong pedigree for football, one of the AFLW's best new talents almost gave it up. Now, she is enjoying putting on a show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">927031e16b31748a06901aafcabd936e</guid></item><item><title>Former Zimbabwe cricket captain Sean Williams reveals 'drug addiction' during probe over mystery withdrawal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/cricket-sean-williams-drug-addiction-zimbabwe-career-over/105974698</link><description>Sean Williams's cricket career with Zimbabwe comes to an end as a probe into his withdrawal from a T20 World Cup qualification tournament reveals his battle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f80e3000838b09f8e430be4cd2d897aa</guid></item><item><title>Local screen industry welcomes proposed Australian content obligation for streaming services</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/local-content-quotas-streaming-services-industry-response/105974654</link><description>On Tuesday, Arts Minister Tony Burke proposed a requirement for 10 per cent of streaming services' local expenditure to be spent on Australian film and TV. Here's what the industry thinks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2774843308e682b9de6dc892da81a1e</guid></item><item><title>Coalition housing spokesman says first home buyer house prices should fall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/bragg-housing-prices-first-home-buyers-fall/105974600</link><description>Taking a position he acknowledges his colleagues may not always want to admit, the Coalition's housing spokesman says prices for "entry-level" properties need to come down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de130e155bef690054826aef5fed6239</guid></item><item><title>Workers at Sydney's Concord Hospital critically injured when hit by car during coffee break</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/concord-hospital-crash-two-seriously-injured-sydney/105974296</link><description>NSW Ambulance paramedics treated a 47-year-old man and a 24-year-old woman, who are Concord Hospital employees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">859a9f71992e8204ded6a84d48854a6f</guid></item><item><title>Moving to the outback gave me courage to do things I never dreamed of</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/moving-to-the-outback-gave-me-courage/105952130</link><description>Being in the middle of nowhere, you learn what really matters. You find yourself experiencing things with unbridled passion, without shame or second-guessing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bcd8762ccdfc9d3d756e2c0f2ff17cd</guid></item><item><title>Seven people arrested in counter-terrorism sting in regional Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/police-arrest-seven-people-in-qld-counter-terrorism-operation/105974254</link><description>Seven people have been arrested in a months-long counter-terrorism sting in regional Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd2105f0e1587785961253281032fb8f</guid></item><item><title>National Gallery of Australia anticipates rolling closures for repairs as it flags funding gaps</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/david-pocock-concerned-national-gallery-nga-leaking/105973662</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese's 2023 promise to fix a "building with buckets to collect leaks" remains unfulfilled, according to the National Gallery of Australia's annual report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eefeed72542fa85bceba3bf142639057</guid></item><item><title>Bundaberg council takes roadside produce seller to court twice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/bundaberg-council-takes-roadside-produce-seller-to-court-twice/105974120</link><description>Raymond Aitkin has been selling seasonal fruit by the side of the road for more than 20 years, but he has found himself before the court twice this year and claims the council is singling him out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">561144eac511440df4e875071ed0c951</guid></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani's win in New York City will send a message to Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/new-york-mayor-zohran-mamdani-donald-trump-and-democrats/105973460</link><description>After using a Trump-style tactic in his campaign, Zohran Mamdani probably now has the US president's begrudging respect — as well as his attention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f47c35effdd3a7250244702bc28abfd8</guid></item><item><title>US 2025 election winners: Virginia and New Jersey get new governors, Proposition 50 passes in California</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/us-2025-election-winners-governors-mayors-ballot-measures/105975214</link><description>Millions of Americans have flocked to polling booths around the US, casting their votes for governors, mayors and ballot measures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">689d23ed2a36fc25c1198318e2cda549</guid></item><item><title>Nearly 8 million hectares burnt during Northern Territory's hottest October on record</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/eight-million-hectares-burnt-during-record-hot-october-nt/105975262</link><description>Last month nearly 8 million hectares were burnt in the Northern Territory, an area bigger than the entire state of Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab9112ca30b6ed547b7c19fc1f795222</guid></item><item><title>Twice proves there is an audience thirsty for K-pop in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/twice-sydney-k-pop-concert-attracts-excited-fans/105975422</link><description>Next stop Melbourne for multinational K-pop group Twice after Sydney concerts are lapped up by excited fans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">719039fdc9dbad1f64054f2ced27b6c3</guid></item><item><title>Parents call for action after Islah Metcalfe's death outside Rouse Hill Public School</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/rouse-hill-school-parents-call-for-action-girls-death/105975566</link><description>Parents of students at a Sydney school where a five-year-old girl was hit by a car and killed last week have demanded action to prevent another tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4965a2929369af52c1bdfe1018f59a8</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand coach Stacey Jones calls for greater scrutiny of warm-ups as NRL continues probe into Eliesa Katoa incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/rugby-league-stacey-jones-eliesa-katoa-warm-ups-scrutiny/105976068</link><description>New Zealand coach Stacey Jones says his thoughts are with Eliesa Katoa as he prepares his side to take on Samoa in the final of the Pacific Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1c60b917a6b66b573f077d0cf70324c</guid></item><item><title>Logan City Council commissions independent review into flood map modelling after receiving thousands of complaints</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/qld-logan-city-council-flood-modelling-independent-review/105974734</link><description>A south-east Queensland council has commissioned an independent review of its flood zone mapping modelling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6af7b2511dd5d2498d6e6027b7afb5d</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate vandalism of telecommunications tower as Optus outage hits NSW Hunter region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/vandalism-causes-optus-outage-in-hunter/105975986</link><description>Police are investigating damage to a communications tower in the NSW Hunter region after calls to triple-0 were impacted by an Optus outage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad2a04b7f77f8fcf827e850da44b4c99</guid></item><item><title>Convicted mushroom murderer Erin Patterson outlines her reasons to appeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/erin-patterson-mushroom-murderer-appeals-conviction/105975896</link><description>Triple-murderer Erin Patterson is fighting to have her conviction quashed, claiming there was a "substantial miscarriage of justice" during her trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e76f0eb39a86c9cfe816e7b6d2a57764</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105975122</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e91d0465be4ab338c89eeb1fe81826c2</guid></item><item><title>Perth Football League's suspension of Osborne Park FC a 'line in the sand' moment, says league boss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/perth-football-league-osborne-park-ban-line-in-sand/105975548</link><description>The boss of the Perth Football League urges clubs to treat the suspension of Osborne Park FC over an end-of-season costume stunt as a "line in the sand moment" for their culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d14c5720caea0299a7ea4e19c1fa4a2c</guid></item><item><title>One in 10 homes bought using first home buyers guarantee in October</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/one-in-10-homes-bought-using-government-incentive-in-october/105976010</link><description>About one in 10 homes sold last month were bought by Australians using Labor's expanded 5 per cent deposit scheme to enter the market for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">105390b5913544e9cb6aac68340591e5</guid></item><item><title>Danielle North leaves Ambulance Victoria executive role after parliamentary inquiry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/victoria-ambulance-danielle-north-covid-funerals/105974020</link><description>Executive director Danielle North has departed Ambulance Victoria, after the service said she may have misled a parliamentary committee about her knowledge of gatherings during COVID lockdowns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85051c441df0330f241c97cf81bf1f76</guid></item><item><title>China lifts some tariffs on US farm goods but soybeans remain costly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/china-suspends-us-tariffs/105976254</link><description>China has ended retaliatory tariffs on a range of US agricultural products but will maintain 10 per cent tariffs on all US goods in response to President Donald Trump's "Liberation Day" duties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d957204129d4de0b35cb10e301561d2</guid></item><item><title>Evidence concludes in murder trial of man who fatally stabbed his wife in NT remote community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/steven-john-murder-trial-nt-supreme-court-evidence-concludes/105974990</link><description>Evidence has concluded in the three-day murder trial of a man who fatally stabbed his wife following an argument in a Northern Territory remote community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4023f63c6519c03625e8ce595d7fb081</guid></item><item><title>Japan deploys troops to the northern town of Kazuno to trap bears after record wave of attacks and deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-05/japan-bears/105976502</link><description>In September, the government relaxed gun rules to make it easier for hunters to shoot bears in urban areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea9232eba3986ac940dcc01dca20642f</guid></item><item><title>Five injured after driver rams car into pedestrians and cyclists in France</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/10-injured-driver-rams-car-into-pedestrians-cyclists-oleron/105976562</link><description>A prosecutor has said a 35-year-old man deliberately rammed his car into pedestrians and cyclists on the French island of Oleron.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f953057e54ca923052b741438026e383</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine and Russia locked in intense clash over key strategic city of Pokrovsk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/ukraine-and-russia-clash-in-pokrovsk-strategic-city/105976672</link><description>Moscow says it is making advances in the key city, which it says would allow Russian forces to claim more territory in Ukraine's eastern Donbas region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff832ca5fdcd517e53e31fb69fab57bb</guid></item><item><title>France suspends Shein over sex doll sales hours after first Paris store opens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/shein-suspended-in-france/105976702</link><description>The Chinese fast-fashion retailer opened its first ever physical store worldwide in Paris, only to be told the French government would be suspending access to its online platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">059a31397ca3ec770970152cc8d5461d</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested after groping Mexican president Claudia Sheinbaum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/man-arrested-after-groping-mexican-president/105976744</link><description>Claudia Sheinbaum says her government will review the country's laws on sexual harassment, saying she has filed a complaint to stand up for other Mexican women who are not in positions of power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0da601ce6cf0adff9eb7fe78165663de</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley's net zero problem won't only impact the Coalition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/coalition-net-zero-energy-labor-sussan-ley-thin-ice/105965502</link><description>If, as expected, the net zero target is abandoned, the long delay in reaching this point will leave the Liberals looking like they've capitulated once again to the Nationals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2e607eecea9396eefa4c5ba767b7bd9</guid></item><item><title>Launceston General Hospital air-conditioning upgrades won't be complete for summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/air-conditioning-delayed-results-in-hot-temps-for-patients/105964806</link><description>Exhaust fans from patient bathrooms at Launceston General Hospital are being used to instead suck in cold air from the air-conditioned corridors, documents obtained under Right to Information laws show, as summer approaches again without crucial cooling upgrades being complete.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3420cd17a73b5ff187adf9dd6c8a3afa</guid></item><item><title>AI is changing jobs fast — and Australians are beginning to wonder how they’ll stay relevant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/workers-face-career-change-ai-technology/105926750</link><description>AI's rapid uptake in Australian workplaces has many workers asking how they can stay relevant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7beaa4878a0d8fa04e57c73fcfcf8632</guid></item><item><title>Artificial intelligence, therapy and education: How AI is reshaping our lives whether we like it or not</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/artificial-intelligence-rise-australia-readers-concerns/105861182</link><description>We asked readers if they had thoughts or concerns about the rise of AI. This is what they told us.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5990ae1c1c1cb564c80d90272b32ae0</guid></item><item><title>Secret WA government report casts doubt on claims domestic gas will help other countries in energy transition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/wa-government-gas-industry-energy-transition-deloitte-report/105970038</link><description>A secret report undermines the WA government's claim that domestic gas production is helping the rest of the world decarbonise, while the state's own greenhouse gas emissions rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98e0108e91777c9ddfa5b797bb1c12bc</guid></item><item><title>Builders face daunting mission to boost housing supply despite 'green shoots'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/builders-how-to-solve-housing-crisis-construction-industry/105950578</link><description>The building industry is reporting a lift in approvals and new home sales, but says planning delays and skilled labour shortages are holding back construction, amid calls to unlock higher density development.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abde6ce9d71b731de8c6f3148a2538ab</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Festival 2026 line-up includes Hot Chip, The Crown star Khalid Abdalla and a The Smiths cabaret</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/sydney-festival-2026-kris-nelson-hot-chip-khalid-abdalla/105922318</link><description>The 50th anniversary of Sydney Festival — and the first from new artistic director Kris Nelson — features a mix of Australian and international artists taking over spaces across the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee019987000001eeb35bcdab0ce7aa24</guid></item><item><title>Nearly 10,000 SA childcare incidents reported resulted in 'no action', FOI documents show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/thousands-sa-childcare-incidents-reported-resulted-in-no-action/105973134</link><description>South Australia's childcare regulator has cancelled the registration of just one provider in recent years, while nearly 10,000 reported incidents have resulted in no further action, FOI documents obtained by the ABC have revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54527f1d8ad8df1c9a79a9b8029b8267</guid></item><item><title>Free buses and child care part of Zohran Mamdani's planned socialist overhaul of New York City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/zohran-mamdani-new-york-city-mayor-policies-explainer/105970926</link><description>New York City's newly elected mayor Zohran Mamdani is promising to make people's lives cheaper, but even some of his supporters are sceptical about whether he can deliver.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">460d32093b8f9be4c0b1616b93774b91</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian town of Longford urges authorities to find source of mystery stink</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/longford-smell-odour-pongford-tasmania-epa-sewage-abattoir/105966730</link><description>Authorities say $38 million has been spent trying to stop this town from stinking, but residents say they are still being forced indoors, put off meals and subjected to humiliating jokes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8254afb59669ac96315bf2e8f6be1bb5</guid></item><item><title>Latrobe Valley manufacturer pivots from coal to wind as region braces for energy shift</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/gippsland-renewable-energy-local-jobs-offshore-wind/105919426</link><description>As major offshore wind developers wait for an auction process in Victoria to begin, work is already underway to ensure Gippsland's long energy legacy translates into new opportunities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12ec0e78eb55090de5a3e912718897fc</guid></item><item><title>What is the new species detected in SA's algal bloom?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/new-species-detected-in-algal-bloom-explained/105973280</link><description>New research awaiting peer review has provided a few revelations about the make-up of South Australia's algal bloom, with a new predominant species — Karenia cristata — identified by scientists. Here's what we know so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d242cb8692a6a254497f3c200df8db9</guid></item><item><title>Doctors at Northern Beaches Hospital issue warning over loss of private beds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/northern-beaches-hospital-doctors-warning-private-beds/105975904</link><description>Medical staff at Northern Beaches Hospital say a potential loss of private beds could mean less expertise, fewer services and more travel for patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0cdced0c93d7626ad29045e776969cc</guid></item><item><title>Queensland breeder says she 'would have apologised' if buyers told her of dogs' health issues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/qld-puppy-buyers-allege-breeder-sold-dogs-with-health-issues/105974618</link><description>A Queensland dog breeder has been accused of selling puppies with broken teeth, gunky eyes, lice and hookworms, years after being fined for failing to care for animals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26875446a4005e5a2be5a9582b8fa99c</guid></item><item><title>Young men rejecting 'cookie-cutter' masculinity but many still feel pressure to act tough, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/young-men-masculinity-adolescent-man-box-study/105970962</link><description>Many young men are rejecting the "Herculean cookie-cutter mould" of masculinity, but a new report warns boys who hold rigid views are suffering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af12d37436d70df244dcae3497a09f50</guid></item><item><title>Are you navigating modern masculinity? We want to hear from you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/share-your-experience-navigating-modern-masculinity/105974406</link><description>Are you wrestling with what it means to be a young man in a rapidly changing world? Or do you have teenage boys in your life navigating modern masculinity?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81f377249594f915ecfbd1717e34494f</guid></item><item><title>Victorian police chief faces more questions over use of force's helicopter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/victorian-police-commissioner-questioned-over-helicopter-travel/105976776</link><description>Victorian Police Chief Commissioner Mike Bush, having already apologised for flying in the service's helicopter to Hobart, confirms he has travelled in the police helicopter on a previous occasion, as it is revealed his wife has separately flown in the helicopter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a261c271f8e18fafa5bff12bb5035c43</guid></item><item><title>Eddie Obeid, Ian Macdonald and Moses Obeid appeal convictions over corrupt coal licence deal in High Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/eddie-obeid-ian-macdonald-appeal-corruption-convictions/105969834</link><description>Three men at the centre of one of NSW's biggest corruption cases are fighting to overturn their jail terms over a $30 million coal deal tied to a family property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc9adcf75e7161b1c2b06ae19eff1ea9</guid></item><item><title>Venus Williams's Auckland Classic entry sparks hope of Australian Open appearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/venus-williams-aims-for-another-australian-open-appearance/105976852</link><description>Venus Williams is to start her 33rd straight season in women's tennis at the Auckland Classic, with another Australian Open appearance for the 45-year-old now a possibility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a84d0232bb6179da5afcd97218afbc87</guid></item><item><title>Owner of seven cats modifies home to keep them away from wildlife</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/cat-owner-creates-enclosure-to-keep-animals-safe/105951784</link><description>Tim Bestwick has modified his northern NSW so his beloved seven cats do not spoil his other passion, bird watching.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84b2ee3ea37cf9411b656b80cd8da07e</guid></item><item><title>Jess Jonassen keen for Australia recall as Brisbane Heat skipper nears WBBL milestone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/jess-jonassen-keen-for-australia-recall-wbbl/105976812</link><description>Jess Jonassen is not holding her breath for an Australian recall, but the Brisbane Heat captain believes she can still contribute at the international level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfcaafd6aaa5457a1a4f7a4d542a9795</guid></item><item><title>Build townhouses to lower rents and house prices, Grattan Institute report says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/three-storey-city-zoning-property-rental-price-grattan-report/105975946</link><description>Rents and house prices would be 12 per cent lower than otherwise within a decade if all capital cities are rezoned to allow three-storey buildings, a report finds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db4a0066fbb266cd8c8a5b5f6c1089f9</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: PM unveils official portrait of Bob Katter — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/federal-politics-live-blog-nov-6/105975894</link><description>Anthony Albanese unveils an official portrait of Bob Katter to commemorate his more than 50 years of service to Queensland and federal parliaments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a0f63cbc42b241e78d52d88dc0b2f19</guid></item><item><title>Image of stranded humpback whale wins Ocean Photographer of the Year award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/ocean-photographer-of-the-year-winners-2025-craig-parry/105976036</link><description>Craig Parry is used to capturing beautiful photographs of the ocean at its best, but this heartbreaking image won him a prestigious Ocean Photographer of the Year award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b0bd7575bed965871c1434042cd9617</guid></item><item><title>Doctor heard about $600k Julia Creek job from truck-driving brother, not from viral campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/julia-creek-outback-doctor-gp-job-600k-hired/105501740</link><description>Julia Creek welcomes a rural Australian GP after running a viral job campaign and receiving 95 applications from across the globe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c72a7d69f8579d8f7ae23a24e43639d</guid></item><item><title>Family of Australian man accused of cocaine smuggling speak ahead of possible Bali death sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/australian-man-lamar-ahchee-family-speaks-to-abc-news-in-bali/105974682</link><description>The sister of Australian man Lamar Ahchee, who has been on trial on drug charges in Bali, describes the moment she heard the news of his arrest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">271d268e1f515e85a72bb2001ee899e1</guid></item><item><title>NAB shares down as bank's profit comes in below expectations, James Hardie shares plunge -- as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/asx-markets-business-live-news-november-6/105973420</link><description>NAB shares have dropped after reporting a dip in net profit, as the bank's boss flags housing as Australia's biggest challenge. But the big move of the day came from James Hardie, with its stock plunging 13%.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df3384558918eea6cf62f989a802a4ae</guid></item><item><title>Millions are going unpaid and hungry as the US federal government shutdown breaks records</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/us-federal-government-shutdown-data/105965562</link><description>The ongoing federal government shutdown has surpassed the record for the longest in US history, leaving thousands of workers without pay. Here are some of the key numbers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9046281db4ecb4a0fbeb7b27f517f64b</guid></item><item><title>Isaah Yeo returns as Kangaroos look for Rugby League Ashes clean sweep in Leeds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/isaah-yeo-returns-as-kangaroos-rugby-league-ashes-third-test/105976876</link><description>Isaah Yeo is back after concussion but, with the Ashes series already won, Kangaroos coach Kevin Walters has still opted against changes for the last Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdbf04925f197ceefad46a311336ea0f</guid></item><item><title>When is the Brazilian F1 grand prix Australian time and how to watch Oscar Piastri in action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/f1-brazil-sao-paulo-grand-prix-start-time-how-to-watch-piastri/105973476</link><description>Oscar Piastri enters this weekend's Formula 1 racing, trailing his teammate by one point in the drivers' championship. Here is how to follow the Formula 1 São Paulo Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">461e6382f23e6e381ff01c2f303e4b0e</guid></item><item><title>UPS plane death toll rises, authorities say engine fell off before crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/ups-cargo-plane-crash-investigations-data-recorders-recovered/105976950</link><description>Louisville Mayor Craig Greenberg has confirmed the death toll has risen to at least 12, with several people still missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5e1b0377c01a52fb6a96296fd1298cc</guid></item><item><title>Who could benefit most from free power hours under Labor's proposed Solar Sharer scheme?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/solar-sharer-scheme-free-power-electricity-who-benefits/105973232</link><description>The federal government wants to introduce a retail offering that gives people in certain states free electricity in the middle of the day, but one expert fears there could be hidden costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">662ff5de9afe452fcc3bedbff6492d87</guid></item><item><title>Spud King expands business with $14 million South West orchard investment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/tony-galati-group-buys-apple-avacado-orchards/105973692</link><description>WA's "Spud King" Tony Galati has expanded his empire with a $14 million bid to purchase two South West orchards which will see his business move into apples and avocados.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1472c01a66d95d1cba6cf7782ecf5855</guid></item><item><title>A huge fireball moments after the crash in Kentucky</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/ups-plane-crashes-near-the-louisville-airport/105973472</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">980dd2114e8d7ad39c21668e40ce2034</guid></item><item><title>Microsoft to refund customers for 365 subscription price hike after ACCC action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/microsoft-to-refund-customers-for-365-subscription-price-hike/105977094</link><description>Microsoft apologises to customers and says it will refund them, after the consumer watchdog alleged the tech giant misled about 2.7 million Australians over subscription costs so they would remain on more expensive plans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ff6ead53e7a3a71017bdb325ebc306b</guid></item><item><title>Man suffers stab wounds during citizens' arrest of knife-wielding man in Melbourne's CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/melbourne-cbd-stabbing-arrest/105977238</link><description>Two bystanders have helped detain a man who was allegedly seen wielding a knife and behaving erratically in Melbourne's CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">813a6c0176c91ed26d1057e086f95e2d</guid></item><item><title>Four bodies found after central Queensland house fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/four-dead-in-emerald-house-fire-queensland/105977172</link><description>Queensland's Premier David Crisafulli says the community of Emerald will be in shock after this morning's fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fff0b340610d80fdbfa1a1780bc1143c</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios aims to play Australian Open after 'miracle' knee recovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/nick-kyrgios-aims-to-play-australian-open-after-knee-recovery/105977346</link><description>A revitalised Nick Kyrgios has revealed his shock plans to make a summer comeback and hopefully play the Australian Open in January.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d505be6541d69a67266950d3c53aff3</guid></item><item><title>Australia captain Pat Cummins says he is still trying to keep the second Ashes Test as a 'live option'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/pat-cummins-feeling-good-for-gabba-test-but-rest-may-be-needed/105977454</link><description>Pat Cummins says his return to bowling has gone better than expected, with Australia's captain still eyeing off a return for the second Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebd5056092829c69de1c407ff84d2579</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested after allegedly crashing vehicle into Bolton Rural Fire Service building and stealing fire truck</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/man-arrested-for-stealing-fire-truck/105977008</link><description>Police say the man stole the fire truck from a Rural Fire Service garage in southern NSW and allegedly drove it with the lights and sirens on before he was stopped in Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4effcb16630bebc5bedb1336f8b5b9f9</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Swans AFLW part ways with inaugural coach Scott Gowans after missing finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/sydney-swans-inaugural-aflw-coach-scott-gowans-leaves-club/105977414</link><description>The Sydney Swans are in need of a new AFLW head coach after parting ways with Scott Gowans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09be5dd3ce2b26ec53cf598df352c9da</guid></item><item><title>'Conscious consumers' embrace of Australian goat meat presents a quality challenge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/conscious-consumers-drive-goat-meat-demand/105969236</link><description>Producers will have to balance consistent supply with the ethical expectations of America's "conscious consumers" as international demand for wild-caught rangeland goat meat surges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4086676422a603f55e0be2136fc9ae25</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Trains worker dead after cherry picker crashes into rail overpass in Lithgow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/bridge-collapses-after-truck-crash-lithgow-nsw/105977736</link><description>A cherry picker passenger has died after the vehicle crashed into a bridge in the NSW Central West, causing it to collapse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe165e38e127746941c198dd6d7e2a51</guid></item><item><title>WA government to buy St John of God Mount Lawley Hospital, fund major hospital upgrades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/wa-government-scrap-convention-centre-plan-buys-private-hospital/105977696</link><description>A major upgrade of the Perth Convention and Exhibition Centre is axed to help pay for three major Perth and Mandurah hospital projects under a $1.5 billion health infrastructure fund.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">109f63b6228a7145f27996cdfcd34aec</guid></item><item><title>Theatre-maker Lamine Sonko explores Senegalese cosmology in his latest show, Guewel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/guewel-lamine-sonko-theatre-senegal-cosmology/105923684</link><description>When Lamine Sonko arrived in Australia 20 years ago, audiences didn't understand his work. Now he is sharing the rituals and rhythms of Senegal with a willing crowd.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">109a463fcc2f00961a462d5bcab6f478</guid></item><item><title>NSW Health to review regional hospital security after Tamworth guard bitten</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/nsw-hospital-security-review-after-tamworth-assault/105956344</link><description>The New South Wales health minister says he intends to review security powers at regional hospitals after four guards were injured at Tamworth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72eafd83a5e64fdd97500fc9e1a5dc21</guid></item><item><title>Court of Appeal spares underworld figure Tony Mokbel extra jail time over drug scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/court-of-appeal-spares-tony-mokbel-additional-prison-time/105978172</link><description>Victoria's highest court rules that Mokbel is no longer "a serious drug offender" and won't be sent back to prison over a methamphetamine trafficking racket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4eca194f722eaa8640b98cdc0df42cbc</guid></item><item><title>Man suffers stab wounds during citizen's arrest in Melbourne's CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/man-suffers-stab-wounds-during-citizen-s-arrest-/105978436</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4160f4c1fb503a54eeeafd89a7c6c1ac</guid></item><item><title>Sydney man Danny Zayat found guilty of murdering Tatiana Dokhotaru in Liverpool apartment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/danny-zayat-guilty-of-murder-tatiana-dokhotaru-in-liverpool/105965814</link><description>Danny Zayat has been found guilty of murdering his ex-partner Tatiana Dokhotaru after a heated argument inside her Liverpool apartment two years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09f5949febd81264e188f48229493f95</guid></item><item><title>Greg Lynn's lawyers challenge 32-year sentence on day two of High Country killer's appeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/greg-lynn-appeal-challenges-high-country-murder-sentence/105978070</link><description>The High Country killer's legal team says the 32-year prison sentence Lynn was handed for the murder of Carol Clay was "manifestly excessive".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd03180957456445582ed5b2470ee703</guid></item><item><title>Healthcare professionals accused of negligence in Diego Maradona's death to face fresh trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/football-maradona-healthcare-professionals-facing-new-trial/105978626</link><description>The seven healthcare professionals accused of negligence in the death of Argentine soccer great Diego Maradona are facing a new trial after a mistrial last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94c62df8eb238d1ee58ac593db8bef3b</guid></item><item><title>Typhoon Kalmaegi leaves 114 dead and 127 missing in Philippines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/typhoon-kalmaegi-leaves-114-dead-and-127-missing-in-philippines/105977676</link><description>The death toll from Typhoon Kalmaegi in the Philippines has risen as the storm gathers strength and heads towards Vietnam.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af7e9d8421a4b759a0b301c9c3c28502</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister confident social media ban will work and will empower parents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/prime-minister-says-social-media-ban-will-work/105978424</link><description>Anthony Albanese says he is confident Australia's social media age limit will be a success when it begins next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f87884cab9104c1c546e2a65f9c0105</guid></item><item><title>The potential use of fracking continues to divide West Australians, particularly in the Kimberley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/kimberley-fracking-controversy-explained/105968978</link><description>As WA's EPA assesses a proposal to drill and frack in the Kimberley's Canning Basin, groups call for WA Labor to enforce a ban across the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99d38dec5b4682adca06a646a3d9d8f2</guid></item><item><title>Jake Weatherald's route to the Australian Ashes Test squad a path less trodden</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/who-is-jake-weatherald-ashes-opening-option/105950984</link><description>Jake Weatherald could become the latest player to represent Australia in the Ashes following a superb 18 months in the Sheffield Shield. But his path to the Test squad has not been conventional.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36ec25a04bbf49543a5055b9bda18682</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder and coercive control after Claire Austin's death in Randwick unit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/claire-austin-man-randwick-death-man-arrested/105979148</link><description>The 44-year-old is charged almost seven months after Claire Austin's death in Randwick.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e2c3bde3dace9797f5e143ee9e3e735</guid></item><item><title>High-speed rail business case linking Sydney and Newcastle supported by government assessment body</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/high-speed-rail-sydney-and-newcastle-another-step-closer/105978262</link><description>The business case for high-speed rail between Sydney and Newcastle identifies four initial station locations for a one-hour journey.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c13c1f5942eb64b891c8be688b0154e6</guid></item><item><title>SA Police begin search at property 37 years after disappearance of Mount Gambier woman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/sa-cold-case-search-margaret-burnie/105978990</link><description>Major Crime Detectives have started searching a property for the remains of Mount Gambier woman Margaret Bernie, who SA Police believe was murdered almost 40 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9925d8ab85801048c467c143580df081</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese confident under-16 social media ban will succeed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/anthony-albanese-confident-under-16-social-media-ban/105979154</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3788aa420c18e76ea851bcb3a68513d2</guid></item><item><title>Prince William joins Kylie Minogue, Shawn Mendes for green-carpeted Earthshot Prize awards in Rio de Janeiro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/prince-william-joins-kylie-minogue-at-earthshot-prize-awards/105978164</link><description>Prince William has joined Kylie Minogue and Shawn Mendes, along with a swag of world leaders and celebrities, for the annual Earthshot Prize awards in Rio de Janeiro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">725a1fa02588aa2e7a906c46476e4cff</guid></item><item><title>Zak Brown says McLaren will not prioritise Oscar Piastri or Lando Norris for F1 title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/mclaren-f1-drivers-championship-piastri-norris-verstappen/105979212</link><description>McLaren's boss says he would rather Red Bull's Max Verstappen win the Formula 1 drivers' championship than prefer one of his racers over the other.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d835a9e72bf00781417b00876ca66683</guid></item><item><title>RePoly defends Moss Vale plastic recycling project amid court appeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/repoly-land-environment-court-plastics-recycling-plant-appeal/105977786</link><description>RePoly accuses a Southern Highlands community group of spreading misinformation about its proposed plastic recycling plant as a campaign against the project is launched.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">233af0398f4a433f286cc8194978fd5e</guid></item><item><title>Taylor Swift sings about 'eldest daughter syndrome', but is it real?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/eldest-daughter-syndrome-explained-in-taylor-swift-song/105957100</link><description>Jess King says being the firstborn child in her family brought a weight of responsibility and she still struggles with feelings that she's "not doing enough".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">378530744ac6d8d9be2979a264c7f163</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian budget 2025 shows lower forecast state debt, few new savings measures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/tasmania-state-budget-2025-eric-abetz/105975908</link><description>Tasmanian Treasurer Eric Abetz has vowed to take "decisive action" to rein in the ballooning debt, but the "interim" state budget contains few major initiatives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d9e0dfb5a646e46ad7f1f5ff0ec2a1f</guid></item><item><title>Cassowary wandering 150km from home in Queensland's Gulf Savannah baffles residents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/mount-surprise-cassowary-sighting-baffles-outback-residents/105976574</link><description>Queensland's department of environment says it has no plans to relocate a cassowary spotted roaming the dry Gulf Savannah.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b6411ff810166264a14b873951ce30e</guid></item><item><title>Hail and heavy rain batter West Australia's Great Southern and Wheatbelt region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/wild-weather-wreaks-havoc-for-west-australian-farmers/105978410</link><description>Severe weather has swept through large parts of the Great Southern and Wheatbelt, causing significant damage to crops during the critical harvest period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab1243c2637f701d0a104525f22b5197</guid></item><item><title>World Club Challenge returns as NRL premiers Brisbane Broncos schedule clash with Super League champions Hull KR</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/world-club-challenge-brisbane-broncos-hull-kr-2026/105979980</link><description>Brisbane will take on Hull Kingston Rovers in the World Club Challenge in late February with the NRL premiers confirming the return of the showpiece event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c115a6445c0023654348a8c78dc24615</guid></item><item><title>Port Adelaide coach Josh Carr denies Warren Tredrea has been kicked out of club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/afl-port-hasnt-kicked-out-tredrea-despite-board-sacking-carr/105979702</link><description>Warren Tredrea's premiership teammate Josh Carr says he will always remain a Port Adelaide legend despite being sacked from the club's board last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecb351caf43a6cbe86052df252e47321</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide artist Peter 'Jungle' Phillips dies aged 69 in his gallery home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/adelaide-artist-jungle-phillips-dies-in-his-gallery-home/105978944</link><description>Known for his generosity and a spectacular art gallery home filled with colourful works, Peter "Jungle" Phillips is remembered by those who loved him dearly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74cd35336a1a33fe6f9e4085f9876c8e</guid></item><item><title>David Wayne Jenkins's family describe heartbreak during sentencing submissions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/george-town-murder-david-wayne-jenkins-sentencing-submissions/105978592</link><description>Family members of murder victim David Wayne Jenkins describe the anguish they felt when hearing about his death during sentencing submissions at Launceston's Supreme Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83e1e8832f6903532f03c7cc64350b91</guid></item><item><title>Katter's present comes early, Coalition stalls on net zero New Year's resolution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/bob-katter-portrait-albanese-net-zero-coalition/105965242</link><description>"There will be a corner of this Parliament House that is forever Bob Katter," the prime minister said this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c305281e43e73daab6bb1a7f19966fb</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder over fatal vehicle strike during Timber Creek brawl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/nt-timber-creek-fatal-pedestrian-strike-murder-charge/105979596</link><description>Police have charged a 21-year-old man with murder for allegedly killing another man by driving a car into him during a brawl in a remote Northern Territory town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25e6733836e322baa4dbbd073e69ae40</guid></item><item><title>Walgett councillor charged over alleged assault of female bowling club worker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/walgett-shire-councillor-alf-seaton-charged-with-assault/105979450</link><description>A Walgett Shire councillor stands down while investigations continue into an alleged assault at a bowling club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02fabb09bc528759b2c954cf09122eea</guid></item><item><title>The art of price baiting — how real estate agents lure buyers to auction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/real-estate-agents-bait-buyers-to-auction-by-underquoting-prices/105973828</link><description>To advertise a property for $1 million, knowing it must sell above $1.3 million, is illegal. It is called underquoting, and in NSW it is rife, according to data analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad152ea0bc248bbeb98993ec6a464f97</guid></item><item><title>Boyfriend welcomes coronial findings about Simone Strobel's murder 20 years ago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/simone-strobel-inquest-findings-into-lismore-murder/105950872</link><description>The findings of a coronial inquest into the death of German backpacker Simone Strobel in Lismore in 2005 have been delivered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42466c411b08a01b8d9575837309708b</guid></item><item><title>Parliamentary inquiry probes experiences of children in high-control religious groups</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/former-scientologist-fronts-cult-fringe-group-inquiry/105979444</link><description>A Victorian parliament probe into the impacts of cults and organised fringe groups hears lived experience testimony from two women who grew up in high-control religious groups.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa768d9a5ef3f66ef5b494d49c93fd7b</guid></item><item><title>Serial rapist Graham Kay pleads guilty to sexually touching Sydney schoolgirl without consent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/graham-kay-pleads-guilty-to-sexual-touching-young-girl/105980416</link><description>Convicted rapist Graham Kay will remain in custody after sexually touching a 16-year-old girl in the Sydney CBD while on a strict supervision order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">064862d4079098783e59817c5fa86f68</guid></item><item><title>Murdered doctor's family confronts killer during plea hearings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/ashley-gordon-murder-stabbing-plea-hearing-supreme-court/105440348</link><description>The convicted killer, who cannot be named, showed no emotion as Ashley Gordon's family members confronted him one by one during a plea hearing at court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2b7886121652da0f4332118d1dd698a</guid></item><item><title>NT man Steven John found guilty of wife's murder in unanimous jury verdict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/steven-john-found-guilty-of-dv-murder-wife-nt-supreme-court/105980258</link><description>A jury has unanimously found Steven John guilty of murdering his wife when he stabbed her in the back following a drunken argument in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19d257e41d895872f782bd3cd13479e1</guid></item><item><title>Federal government approves expansion of Victoria's largest gold mine near Bendigo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/expansion-of-victorias-biggest-gold-mine-fosterville-approved/105820838</link><description>Fosterville Gold Mine in central Victoria is approved to continue running until 2045 despite concerns from neighbours and environmental advocates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82d57c3f7c894ffb523c7212f98b01f5</guid></item><item><title>Toddler dies after vehicle accident on rural property in Abergowrie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/toddler-dies-vehicle-accident-rural-property-north-queensland/105980178</link><description>A two-year-old boy has died in an accident involving a vehicle on a rural property in north Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37ebc0f513ba883de49eddc7a90c3b90</guid></item><item><title>Australia's de facto online gambling regulator stops accepting gifts from betting companies, for now</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/nt-gambling-regulator-stops-accepting-hospitality-gifts/105977024</link><description>The announcement comes six months after the ABC first reported the Northern Territory Racing and Wagering Commission chair had accepted corporate hospitality from bookmakers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">054df1c3df66a24b168bb79d5d973453</guid></item><item><title>Liberals recalled to parliament to thrash out net zero problem</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/liberals-recalled-to-parliament-to-thrash-out-net-zero-problem/105980878</link><description>Liberal MPs will return to parliament on Wednesday to thrash out a position on the party's net zero commitment ahead of a joint party room meeting with the Nationals next Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc6311e8941c1307e54a41f449b07dc4</guid></item><item><title>Five feared trapped after structure collapse at power plant in South Korea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/five-trapped-at-south-korean-power-station/105980796</link><description>The rescue operation is ongoing, with four people pulled from the rubble so far, a fire official says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa59bebf8d39db727539d27ad52ac215</guid></item><item><title>Opposition parties respond to State budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/labor-greens-interim-budget-tasmania/105980702</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba0c3a760bfb926afab67c2e6f6a479b</guid></item><item><title>Canberra teenager behind bars over detailed plans for public attacks, possessing violent extremist material</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/act-teen-behind-bars-over-detailed-plans-for-public-attacks/105980252</link><description>A 17-year-old Canberra boy is behind bars after shocking allegations he developed detailed plans for public attacks and had equipment to create a bomb in his bedroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fe64fc6696ae57e2474bf3323c24da8</guid></item><item><title>Male nurse charged with raping two elderly women at Greenslopes hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/male-nurse-charged-rape-elderly-women-greenslopes-queensland/105980938</link><description>Police allege the 41-year-old committed the offences against two women in their 80s in 2020 and 2024 at a hospital in Brisbane's south.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">629a56f60615894c48c61a067fd0fd71</guid></item><item><title>Anti-corruption commission watchdog inquiring into NACC chief Paul Brereton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/nacc-inspector-inquiring-brereton-complaints/105980792</link><description>The inspector of the National Anti-Corruption Commission is inquiring into the agency's head, Paul Brereton, in relation to several complaints including from a former employee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cc388dddda1b38961125058526d275c</guid></item><item><title>How Zohran Mamdani's triumph in New York is making waves around the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/zohran-mamdani-political-landscape/105980512</link><description>The blistering rise of New York City's new mayor, Zohran Mamdani, has captured global attention. So what's going on and what does his win say about the American political climate?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fc1ddae3c5072f9c5b018033e43f0ca</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos not offended Hawthorn players missed Jasmine Garner's guard of honour after 100th AFLW game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/aflw-kangaroos-respond-hawthorn-garner-100th-game-snub/105981256</link><description>Hawthorn players were noticeably absent from the guard of honour for North star Jasmine Garner after her 100th AFLW game, but the reigning champs are not too fussed about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">947b1b6e8038390076adca24bebe6512</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/105980726</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce1026aaae1d4162b44c6311a14f390b</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian unions and community organisations respond to Tasmanian state budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/tasmanian-unions-and-community/105980794</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">857e60897d387a151b569d455ca811c6</guid></item><item><title>Economist Saul Eslake on Eric Abetz's first State Budget</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/economist-saul-eslake-on-eric-abetz-s-first-state-budget-/105980590</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1551c8f2c647e8edb76457e6fd842d90</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's state budget 'less worse' than feared but still 'dire' with enormous budget repair ahead, economists say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/economists-react-to-tasmanias-interim-budget/105977690</link><description>Independent economist Saul Eslake and Deloitte's Cedric Hodges warn there is no easy way out of Tasmania's dire budget situation, after the treasurer delivered an "interim" budget with little in the way of concrete solutions for fixing the state's debt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aff5af94eff9d323d8c92a2e95a45a57</guid></item><item><title>Australia vs India fourth T20 live updates: Scores, stats and commentary from Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/cricket-australia-india-fourth-t20i-gold-coast-live-score-centre/105981170</link><description>Australia is looking to nudge ahead of India as the five-match T20 series shifts to Gold Coast's Carrara Stadium for the penultimate match. Follow here for live text updates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">722f6d4d71e8d60751df3f2d947e6fe9</guid></item><item><title>Sena needed surgery, but she couldn't understand her doctors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/calls-for-more-translators-australian-medical-industry/105981340</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41daf6331b86a7c662ce645ab1e5cbb7</guid></item><item><title>Martin Dole and Leanne Liddle unveil anti-racism plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/martin-dole-and-leanne-liddle-unveil-anti-racism-plan/105981258</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e048e32a4ebecf2c1c5a77dbe1489a52</guid></item><item><title>NT Police Force announces anti-racism action plan in bid to drive cultural change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/nt-police-announces-anti-racism-strategy-for-cultural-change/105974362</link><description>The Northern Territory Police Force has released its first anti-racism strategy for staff, following years of headlines about racist attitudes that have dogged the organisation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5834a33da566676ec93669ddd492b69</guid></item><item><title>Carrie Bickmore named Victorian Australian of the Year for work to progress brain cancer research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/carrie-bickmore-victorian-australian-of-the-year-awards/105981282</link><description>The radio host and former TV presenter has been recognised for her fundraising work to progress brain cancer research.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a64e4d0265ecb546047d43e0cd22cab</guid></item><item><title>As Russian drone incursions rattle Europe, Poland and Romania deploy a new defensive system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/drone-defence-system-poland-and-romania/105981642</link><description>The United States-built Merops system can identify drones and close in on them, using artificial intelligence to navigate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff1bfb390d76d1e1f7b5f26eef6187db</guid></item><item><title>Australia's $4 billion illicit tobacco trade has become one of the nation's most violent criminal markets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-06/black-market-cigarettes-cost-australia-4bn-in-one-year/105981786</link><description>Authorities stress the $4 billion figure is conservative, as it does not include illegal vapes and e-cigarettes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">358fd392575026d8d0bfb9140f325913</guid></item><item><title>German police investigate swastikas drawn in human blood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/german-police-investigate-swastikas-drawn-in-human-blood/105981882</link><description>The Nazi symbol was smeared dozens of times on cars, letter boxes and building facades, with tests confirming they were daubed in human blood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41adc70d01452049c09c2ce3b49ad188</guid></item><item><title>Typhoon Kalmaegi makes landfall in central Vietnam, bringing destructive winds and heavy rains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/typhoon-makes-landfall-in-vietnam/105981940</link><description>Forecasters warn that Kalmaegi could dump more than 600 millimetres of rain in Vietnam.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">969151d8c2fd5d6cd66a0a856d0a86a8</guid></item><item><title>Louvre managers prioritised art over upgrading security in years before heist, report says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-07/louvre-security-flaws-years-report-finds/105982046</link><description>France's highest auditor says the theft of $157 million worth of jewels was a "deafening alarm bell" for the world-renowned Parisian museum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b9b0a8a2d754a58367472453e9a8c75</guid></item></channel></rss>