<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Sep 2025 03:26:12 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Australian-born singer drops out of Russian-hosted Intervision song contest after 'political pressure'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australian-born-singer-drops-out-of-russian-hosted-song-contest/105799020</link><description>Vassy dropped out of the contest at the last minute after coming under what Russian organisers said was "unprecedented political pressure from the government of Australia".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6f53824a2ed40b9ae66bd7ebdb25e1a</guid></item><item><title>How Brisbane, Hawthorn, Geelong and Collingwood stay on top of the AFL world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/afl-analysis-geelong-brisbane-collingwood-hawthorn/105797710</link><description>The 21st century has been dominated by four AFL clubs — Geelong, Hawthorn, Collingwood and Brisbane — but there's no single secret to their success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0de8258f95182f2d73692053694b3fa</guid></item><item><title>Penola High School's agriculture program revives community and enrolments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/penola-high-school-ag-program-revives-falling-enrolments/105787042</link><description>Cory O'Connor's three-week teaching placement turned around his hometown high school. Now he's receiving an award for the agriculture program he started there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">800678cadea15a18ec482186c893d046</guid></item><item><title>Pistachios are the latest food trend and a lot of work goes into predicting what's next</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/pistachios-are-everywhere-but-how-was-that-decided/105680106</link><description>Pistachios have become the food flavour of the season, and a lot of work goes into predicting what the next big thing will be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5eba132db24b42ad0a82c8f2ec02621</guid></item><item><title>Cats star Tyson Stengle desperate to win second AFL premiership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/afl-grand-final-geelong-cats-brisbane-lions-tyson-stengle/105799288</link><description>Three years after Tyson Stengle capped off his remarkable AFL career resurrection with a premiership, the Geelong forward believes a second premiership would hold greater significance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4c3712d165c2a42a93ac12de61b5a9d</guid></item><item><title>WA police investigate after man found with critical injuries dies on Kalgoorlie street</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/detectives-from-major-crime-investigating-man-death-kalgoorlie/105799278</link><description>Detectives from the Major Crime Division are investigating the death near a popular park in the Goldfields city early on Sunday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa4bf44f1133d9f74f858639d1791a0c</guid></item><item><title>Penrith Panthers hammer Canterbury-Bankstown Bulldogs to keep NRL premiership five-peat hopes alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/nrl-semifinal-live-updates-bulldogs-vs-panthers/105799314</link><description>Penrith has crushed Canterbury-Bankstown after a phenomenal first half to claim a 46-26 victory, keeping their hopes of a fifth-consecutive NRL premiership alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73ad6ec14b559cb36a842edc842a9431</guid></item><item><title>Optus CEO confirms further customer report calls, service outage at NSW-SA border.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/optus-ceo-confirms-further-customer-report-calls,/105799496</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99f2ad74ac543864780c38476c5a3384</guid></item><item><title>Dayne Zorko fined by AFL for targeting Mason Cox's glasses in Lions' win over Magpies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/afl-brisbane-lions-collingwood-magpies-dayne-zorko-mason-cox/105799528</link><description>Brisbane Lions stalwart Dayne Zorko is punished by the AFL after he ripped off Mason Cox's glasses during their fiery preliminary final clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34b6f6c464fdb14a9fdb5f312f87feab</guid></item><item><title>Australia formally recognises state of Palestine as Anthony Albanese arrives in US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australia-formally-recognises-state-of-palestine/105799238</link><description>The historic decision foreshadowed last month has now become a reality, as Australia moves with Canada and the United Kingdom to join the growing list of countries to recognise Palestinian sovereignty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f7f36cbe6b5b1fbaaf3e78efd2951a2</guid></item><item><title>Can recognising the state of Palestine achieve a two-state solution as Israel continues bombing Gaza?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australia-recognises-state-of-palestine-two-state-solution/105799276</link><description>While the Israel Defense Forces bomb Gaza and bulldoze the West Bank for settlements, moves to recognise Palestine in pursuit of a two-state solution may appear like something of a sick joke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfa3467335da07f9ce07cf8e87421ac9</guid></item><item><title>Is artificial intelligence overhyped or is AI the 'fourth industrial revolution'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/is-ai-the-fourth-industrial-revolution/105790912</link><description>It's estimated 30,000 people are working in the AI industry in Australia, and fanfare is growing with start-ups tapping into billions of dollars of venture capital. Yet there are concerns about hype and a lack of regulation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26daac2bce5f986abcbf545a3ec82df2</guid></item><item><title>Older Australians to pay up to $50/hour for basic care at home under aged care changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/older-australians-to-pay-for-showers-under-home-care-changes/105796118</link><description>Older Australians entering the aged care system will have to pay for "non-clinical" services such as showers and help with medication under wide-ranging changes taking effect in November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fad2ebda86259a9a52aff0b346c39071</guid></item><item><title>Brownlow Medal 2025 — when is it, how to watch and who are the favourites for AFL's best-and-fairest award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-medal-2025-explainer-how-to-watch-who-might-win/105799236</link><description>The AFL's big night is here, as the league's best and fairest player is honoured with the Brownlow Medal. Here is everything you need to know about the big event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a533b478e86cba0a5d23c3da7fd118e4</guid></item><item><title>The government says its 2035 climate targets are achievable but mathematics suggests a different story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/climate-target-2035-2050-carbon-emissions-global-warming/105799080</link><description>The problem with an emissions reduction target is that its mere existence implies it is achievable and that if we do achieve it, we will be fine. The truth is more complex.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55dd3a3450e5da05cd2e7e786ef836f8</guid></item><item><title>Lachlan Murdoch involved in possible TikTok deal, Donald Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/tiktok-deal-involves-murdoch-trump-says/105800256</link><description>The deal would see TikTok's American assets transferred from China's ByteDance to American owners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da7908cffd99b9ae76881cabbe2df158</guid></item><item><title>Dementia-linked protein lower in people reporting vigorous exercise, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/how-exercise-can-reduce-risk-of-developing-dementia/105783238</link><description>Scientists have, for the first time, linked exercise with a particular protein in the blood that is associated with brain health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1927e46b141094965051ff5e6c95b5c2</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump calls Charlie Kirk a 'martyr' at memorial service, widow Erika Kirk forgives alleged assassin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/thousand-gather-charlie-kirk-memorial-service-donald-trump/105800038</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Charlie Kirk was a "martyr to American freedom", while his widow says she forgives his alleged assassin during a memorial to the right-wing activist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a195c5eaab3b46f9f8c92705e3433bbb</guid></item><item><title>Storm-damaged turbine at NSW Central West wind farm raises safety concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/storm-damaged-turbine-at-nsw-central-west-wind-farm-concerns/105782400</link><description>After a wind turbine blade snapped in half during a storm, the NSW National Party has called for a safety audit into the renewable technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">020cbe7c7b785e21c8f3c2fd850c4be9</guid></item><item><title>This program could be the blueprint for helping kids fleeing domestic violence stay off the streets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/homeless-kids-domestic-violence-solution-politics/105793902</link><description>Every night, thousands of Australian kids are homeless without an adult to look after them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e17c22bd4e0bdb7ea0d6cd380a87fbf</guid></item><item><title>NT police data shows violent crime increasing, property crime decreasing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/is-nt-crime-decreasing-since-clp-government-elected-police-data/105797920</link><description>NT police data show crime rates in the NT are moving in two directions, with violent crime increasing and property crime decreasing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdbfb4dc342090b5ac73b9b9188a7325</guid></item><item><title>Explaining the NT's crime data</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/explaining-the-nt-s-crime-data/105799232</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">007afa55f8cb659a4ac03254c3d6d0c4</guid></item><item><title>Protesters in Philippines clash with police in rallies against corruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/protesters-in-philippines-rally-against-corruption/105800512</link><description>Thousands of Filipinos marched in the capital to vent their anger over a ballooning scandal involving bogus flood-control projects believed to have cost taxpayers billions of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffa83e3c2e5be80abb8e2dcb772951a9</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage investigation underway as minister warns of 'consequences'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/optus-investigation-triple-0-outage/105800556</link><description>The Australian Media and Communications Authority begins its investigation into the Optus triple-0 outage that has been linked to multiple deaths in South Australia and Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64e8d943c326b70c38e9b095d514da19</guid></item><item><title>Jacqui Lambie calls on independent MLCs to 'block' the proposed Macquarie Point stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/jacqui-lambie-calls-on-independent-mlcs-to-block-hobart-stadium/105797716</link><description>Senator Jacqui Lambie tells the independents in Tasmania's upper house — who hold the fate of the Macquarie Point stadium in their hands — to "find the courage the premier can't" and stop the project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b78160dbac88202c3169fcc945ea29c</guid></item><item><title>'Turning it up to eleven': Spinal Tap returns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/turning-it-up-to-eleven-spinal-tap-returns/105792970</link><description>The new film follows the fictional heavy metal band reuniting for one final gig with cameos from Elton John and Paul McCartney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4608648fffc66e4e36ba98d635f1990</guid></item><item><title>Easy and healthy dinner recipes for spring</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/easy-healthy-recipes-for-spring-dinners/105660408</link><description>If you're looking for light dinner ideas as the weather warms up, we have plenty of easy options. Think veggie-filled frittatas and beef taco bowls with a few healthy swaps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c28e2a7be5345c5402fc685acca89162</guid></item><item><title>NT Police complete Kumanjayi White death in custody autopsy, with brief of evidence handed to prosecutors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/kumanjayi-white-death-in-custody-alice-springs-autopsy-completed/105801756</link><description>The autopsy into the Aboriginal man's death in custody in Alice Springs has been completed, with the police brief of evidence handed to prosecutors to determine whether any charges should be laid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b34f78ebd2e7994895d35c509e3ce63</guid></item><item><title>Australian pair Holly Harris and Jason Chan qualify for ice dance at 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/ice-dance-at-2026-winter-olympics-australia-qualifies-in-beijing/105802160</link><description>Australian pair Holly Harris and Jason Chan finish second at the Skate to Milano event in Beijing to book their spot at the Milan-Cortina Olympic Games in February next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbfee981ea89ca45bca4d6f89ad7983b</guid></item><item><title>Is AI impacting your career or life plans? Has its rapid rise got you rethinking your future? The ABC wants to hear from you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/ai-artificial-intelligence-future-job-career-impact/105762606</link><description>Whether you’re a student halfway through a degree or a mid-career manager planning the next five years, artificial intelligence (AI) is reshaping lives across the country. If you've been feeling its effects, the ABC wants to hear from you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc9fb0b057b73e053ee1ce795957b20a</guid></item><item><title>Masood Zakaria asks court to permanently stay his murder trial over 'unlawful' deportation from Türkiye</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/masood-zakaria-trial-vacated-re-alleged-illegal-deportation/105802494</link><description>A major Sydney murder trial is at risk of falling over as a Supreme Court judge ruled there was evidence the man charged was deported back to Australia unlawfully.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50b9900e4915898991b85033dca86795</guid></item><item><title>Geelong star Max Holmes admits missing 2022 grand final hurt relationship with coach Chris Scott</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/i-was-pissed-with-scotty-cats-star-holmes-eyes-afl-flag/105802834</link><description>Geelong speedster Max Holmes is desperate to put his previous grand-final week anger and heartbreak behind him as the Cats eye AFL premiership glory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd1f4bd169de77ac34368207d9141381</guid></item><item><title>Super Netball's Sunshine Coast Lightning enters new Global Sports Fund Management Group ownership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/super-netball-sunshine-coast-lightning-new-ownership/105801344</link><description>Almost a decade after being co-founded by the Melbourne Storm and University of the Sunshine Coast, Super Netball's Lightning is entering a new era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">725e5769d7aa41a90979ec4d3e47f5bd</guid></item><item><title>Endangered Littlejohn's tree frog finally bred in captivity amid habitat threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/endangered-littlejohns-tree-frog-finally-bred-in-captivity/105799502</link><description>Scientists have achieved a breakthrough in their work to save the Littlejohn's tree frog species which only exists in three isolated regions in New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">242f7f349ef09c427b4a7b8724bf30e1</guid></item><item><title>Brownlow Medal 2025: All the best fashion looks from AFL's night of nights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-red-carpet-wrap/105802436</link><description>Just after the fashion from this evening's Brownlow Medal? We've got you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8922390581e8430e878c1aa384dd8e2d</guid></item><item><title>Matt Rowell wins 2025 Brownlow Medal as Gold Coast star beats out Nick Daicos and Bailey Smith</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-medal-2025-live-blog-daicos-smith-dawson-rowell/105798968</link><description>Matt Rowell becomes the second Gold Coast player to win the prestigious AFL award, as a questionable voting call regarding Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera leaves the room stunned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08247d0fedaa413c59c8aea7818c6570</guid></item><item><title>Bathurst childcare worker charged over alleged common assault of 4yo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/bathurst-childcare-worker-allegedly-assaults-4-year-old/105802944</link><description>Police allege the 18-year-old educator dragged a four-year-old boy by the arm and threw him on a mattress at a childcare centre in Bathurst earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">042ef8f6e996c2b1dc656c9cd9fb6114</guid></item><item><title>Latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/latest-financial-news/105804002</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a2a0a2b0118f619ddf3cb8e2061e8e4</guid></item><item><title>More than $4 million in drugs seized across WA's far north in ongoing operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/kimberley-police-seize-meth-ammunition-and-other-drugs/105804038</link><description>Police in the Kimberley say an ongoing investigation has seized millions of dollars' worth of ammunition, methylamphetamine and other drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29a62dd5dae99250a80b3b8152cf6465</guid></item><item><title>Ley writes to Republicans vowing to revoke Palestine recognition ahead of Albanese's UN address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/albanese-un-palestine-address-ley-republican-letter/105803078</link><description>In an unorthodox move, Opposition Leader Sussan Ley writes to a group of Republicans reassuring the Coalition would withdraw recognition of Palestine, ahead of a major United Nations address to be delivered by the prime minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98f3481476a06e3c9782e1032f1893d8</guid></item><item><title>Moldovan authorities arrest 74 people over alleged Russia-backed election plot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moldova-election-arrests-russia-backed-plot/105804776</link><description>The widespread raids came ahead of the country's parliamentary elections on Sunday, expected to determine whether the country will pursue closer ties with the European Union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a647be00ecfc0d387fa0b9a153bf4406</guid></item><item><title>Artificial intelligence to dominate Australia's future economy, but who will reap the benefits?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/australias-future-economy-will-be-dominated-by-ai/105802364</link><description>From robots to supercomputers, artificial intelligence is set to become an integral part of the Australian economy, with tens of billions in benefits to be gained … but for whom?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12e16358f1d06001f22c8315b12c996c</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar junta revoking citizenship of actors, singers and other celebrities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/myanmar-celebrities-left-stateless-after-criticising-junta/105787574</link><description>Myanmar's military junta is using citizenship as a weapon, targeting political opponents, activists and even celebrities who speak out against the regime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df5568a6e89118d9a0c2db08ec61854c</guid></item><item><title>Three Australians lay dead as investors of Optus's parent company Singtel were buying up its shares</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/three-australians-lay-dead-investors-buy-up-shares/105803922</link><description>The actions by Optus management in the hours following a series of failed attempts by its customers to call triple-0 raises questions about the telco's fitness to operate in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24e9f1bc9c2b8e3b2e1bdab5ae2ccb23</guid></item><item><title>Moment Matt Rowell announced as 2025 Brownlow medallist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moment-matt-rowell-announced-as-2025-brownlow-medallist/105805032</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4336530cc59f3c10ad2c74d7b058cebe</guid></item><item><title>Doctors concerned easily accessible illegal cigarettes are causing smoking rates to increase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/act-easy-access-to-illegal-cigarettes-seeing-high-smoking-rates/105803450</link><description>Doctors say smoking rates are at levels they haven't seen in a decade due to easy access to illegal cigarettes that are a "quarter of the price" of legal cigarettes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">150ad4af75b20ef2e67ba79a215e5c20</guid></item><item><title>Dash camera mandate for WA driving instructors considered as part of regulation review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/wa-government-consider-driving-instructor-camera-mandate/105790618</link><description>The WA government is considering mandating the use of dash cameras for driving instructors, in a bid to better protect vulnerable student drivers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a8f037624e70614c35efe8b66ab697d</guid></item><item><title>Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera being robbed overshadowed Matt Rowell's Brownlow Medal win, and could change the voting process forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/afl-matt-rowell-nasiah-moment-brownlow-medal-voting-analysis/105804320</link><description>It is not often that the AFL's night of nights gets hijacked by a moment not involving the winner of the Brownlow Medal. This is exactly what took place when Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera was seemingly robbed in broad daylight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dfdde5b406fc68132f52c264d89b4c9</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire survivors still camping years later amid construction backlog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/mallacoota-builders-struggle-five-years-after-black-summer-fires/105562838</link><description>Five years after devastating bushfires swept through Mallacoota, some survivors are still making do with tents and camp kitchens amid a backlog of construction jobs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1121db6b9066459f003795b1fb706907</guid></item><item><title>Paddleboarder gets too close to whales to film them, gets nudged away</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/paddleboarder-gets-too-close-to-whales-to-film-them/105801626</link><description>Drone footage shows a paddleboarder getting too close to film a southern right whale mother and calf, and being nudged away by the whale, off Point Ann.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccd42678f7b40484099efe1f5126dddd</guid></item><item><title>Women band together to create community for rural mums feeling lonely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/women-create-community-for-rural-mums-suffering-from-loneliness/105803024</link><description>After raising biological and foster children on a farm 60 kilometres from the nearest major town, Tracey Angwin says being part of a community is essential for rural mums.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da92ce9d728ad981483651f9d4c38527</guid></item><item><title>NSW police suspend investigation into murder of homeless man Reginald Mullaly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/police-suspend-investigation-into-reginald-mullaly-murder/105800932</link><description>Police have suspended an investigation of a homeless man's brutal murder in Bathurst a decade ago, prompting a fresh plea from his family for information.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b768354a6a3c6bade70c04eb09c0541d</guid></item><item><title>Deeming rates have increased after a five-year freeze. Here's how that could impact pension payments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/deeming-rate-freeze-ends-impact-on-pension-payments/105798966</link><description>The changes impact people on Centrelink payments who earn an income from financial assets, but pensioners are the biggest group to be affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2a6081a58d1e888118022ad40f5fcfd</guid></item><item><title>Childcare boss unsure if bonuses were docked over rise in safety breaches, inquiry told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nsw-childcare-inquiry-ceo-questioned-over-bonuses/105805562</link><description>The CEO of Affinity Education Group appears at a state parliamentary inquiry into the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3ece1d8ebaeed33106cbc2f0f9066d1</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police officer charged with assault over protest arrest of former Greens candidate Hannah Thomas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nsw-officer-charged-assault-hannah-thomas-greens-arrest/105805966</link><description>Hannah Thomas was among a group of pro-Palestinian protesters who demonstrated outside a manufacturing facility in June when she sustained a serious eye injury during her arrest for failing to comply with a move on direction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ffd2b5888a415cc414e269d4943cf29</guid></item><item><title>EPA investigates disturbing hum sound keeping north-west Sydney residents up at night</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/epa-investigates-disturbing-hum-sound-parramatta/105805278</link><description>One sleepless resident said he drove around his local area to find the source of the disturbance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b07ecb0776d08afdd32e2f257e0a26f</guid></item><item><title>Historic war ledger stolen from Toowoomba church before Carnival of Flowers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/historic-war-ledger-stolen-from-toowoomba-anglican-church/105786718</link><description>After being on display for more than a century, a handwritten ledger of local soldiers who gave their lives during World War I and World War II has been stolen from a Toowoomba church.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bd6ba2d8d5fad85b653cf165472bf3d</guid></item><item><title>Experts say it is safe to use paracetamol during pregnancy and Trump's autism declaration is 'baseless'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/taking-paracetamol-during-pregnancy-does-not-cause-autism/105806092</link><description>Donald Trump's advice that pregnant women should limit the use of paracetamol in pregnancy has been criticised as "baseless". So what does it mean for you?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81c81571674ce6c676915af2ca81de9b</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of hitting 42yo with vehicle in Kalgoorlie appears in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/detectives-from-major-crime-investigate-kalgoorlie-mans-death/105801802</link><description>A 29-year-old man has faced court today after detectives from WA Police's Homicide Squad charged him with murder, two days after the death of a man in the state's Goldfields.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46cd053682653a831ef9b4ab4db28ca6</guid></item><item><title>Hakyung Lee found guilty over deaths of children found in Auckland storage unit suitcases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nz-suitcase-verdict-hakyung-lee-trial/105658224</link><description>Hakyung Lee admitted to giving her two children an overdose of prescription medicine before changing her name and leaving New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76f153f712f5238ae870dbe2b49d9150</guid></item><item><title>Siosifa Talakai says Cronulla Sharks players 'at each other's throats' before revival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nrl-siosifa-talakai-cronulla-sharks-season-revival/105806244</link><description>Sharks star Siosifa Talakai gives an insight into the heated player meetings that came during Cronulla's mid-season slump before the team's spectacular charge to an NRL preliminary final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5df9ad45da27441d21ee6e4e6523186c</guid></item><item><title>Eighth person charged with murder following stabbing deaths of Chol Achiek and Dau Akueng</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/eighth-person-charged-cobblebank-murder-dau-akueng/105806430</link><description>Police charge a 15-year-old boy with the murder of Dau Akueng, also 15, who was found with fatal injuries alongside his 12-year-old friend Chol Achiek in Melbourne's outer west earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8265c1db246493e4501d2856c4a45b73</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane bus driver charged over fatal CBD crash thought he was pressing brakes before he mounted footpath, trial hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/bus-driver-charged-death-brisbane-teen-tia-cameron-cbd/105806472</link><description>A Brisbane bus driver charged over a fatal crash in the CBD last year thought he was pressing the brakes before he mounted a footpath and killed a pedestrian, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b04c56f204a9178efca4f6b96879527</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions star Lachie Neale trains strongly and looks on track for a grand final spot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/neale-trains-as-lion-s-grand-final-return-hopes-gather-pace/105806698</link><description>The 31-year-old dual Brownlow medallist, who has been battling a calf injury, took part in training drills in front of 2,000 Brisbane fans at the team's Springfield home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c61b547c00f1a6df00fecccb68dde8b8</guid></item><item><title>Man known as 'Moore Park Rapist' pleads guilty to series of sexual assaults in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moore-park-rapist-glenn-cameron-pleads-guilty-sexual-assaults/105806986</link><description>Glenn Cameron has remained in custody since he was arrested in February last year and charged with more than 30 offences in relation to eight victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c631b0b48e05bf34d6cd7b4127803d77</guid></item><item><title>Egyptian activist Alaa Abd el-Fattah released from prison after nearly 12 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/egyptian-activist-alaa-abd-el-fattah-released-from-prison/105805902</link><description>Pro-democracy activist Alaa Abd el-Fattah has been released from prison, following a pardon from the Egyptian president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d429202c47e43999510999e5ea936c5c</guid></item><item><title>Father charged with manslaughter of seven-month-old son during camping trip in Queensland granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/qld-jaye-lee-walton-granted-bail-manslaughter-baby-son/105806058</link><description>Jaye Lee Walton, 42, has been charged with the manslaughter of his seven-month-old son Reef Hunter Walton in July.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1c7d659fa35821d1c36f548378d9a1f</guid></item><item><title>Northern Territory CLP government is reviewing sentencing laws. But will it change anything?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/jake-danby-hit-and-run-nt-sentencing-act-changing-clp-government/105801232</link><description>The case of hit-and-run driver Jake Danby has brought renewed focus to the NT's legal system and the problems it faces. But will changing sentencing laws help?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">181ee879b9bbed91231a5952dddf97e9</guid></item><item><title>Kevin Bacon on the importance of music, philanthropy and acting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/kevin-bacon-take-5-actor-music-philanthropy-interview/105793360</link><description>He's a prolific fixture on our screens who's famously six degrees from almost anyone. But Kevin Bacon is also a passionate musician and philanthropist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45104e05b24001759cca6f2985a81b97</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu plans to sign police deal with China while Nakamal pact with Australia is left hanging</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/china-vanuatu-police-agreement-equipment-training/105806934</link><description>Vanuatu declares it will sign a new policing agreement with China as the landmark Nakamal pact between Australia and the Pacific Island nation hangs in the balance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e015a5946bffafc3e5c33cd1d8fa895e</guid></item><item><title>Sean 'Diddy' Combs's lawyers pitch shorter prison term, therapy ahead of sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sean-diddy-combs-lawyers-try-to-impose-14-month-sentence/105807480</link><description>The disgraced hip-hop mogul is expected to be sentenced on October 3.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a3eba260c2608ab5712fd146ba5a4b4</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage tragedy: What we know and how events unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/timeline-on-optus-triple-0-outage-what-we-know/105805890</link><description>The first sign something was wrong came late on Friday afternoon. Now we have a clearer picture of how the triple-0 outage unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c548c42002e87e4dd015358e8d8279e9</guid></item><item><title>Unproven autism claims like Donald Trump's risk undoing decades of progress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/trump-unproven-autism-claims-risk-undoing-decades-of-progress/105807344</link><description>The Trump administration's rhetoric only adds to the noise around autism and will make it harder for the community to feel understood and accepted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00fa47bf5ec49c44ed4dd1852e1689f4</guid></item><item><title>Debate over Macquarie Point stadium rages in Tasmanian parliament following release of damning report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/macquarie-stadium-debate-tasmanian-parliament/105806814</link><description>In the first Question Time since the release of the Tasmanian Planning Commission's damning report on the Hobart AFL stadium, the Labor Party questioned the government's ability to deliver the stadium, while an independent labelled it a "dud deal".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">accf0e157a3f7bdf9cc737117f4b639c</guid></item><item><title>How Sydney Trains's lacking communication issue can be overcome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nsw-sydney-trains-communication-issues-new-report/105806734</link><description>A scathing report into Sydney Trains has put a "disturbing" spotlight on the "absence of effective communications" and "information voids" on the network, but one transport expert says this was not always the case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b7a173dc56a72adad406543107b5381</guid></item><item><title>Sale of Australia's biggest sheep station at Rawlinna finally gets WA government approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sale-of-australias-largest-sheep-station-at-rawlinna-station/105807106</link><description>The WA government has finally signed off on the sale of Australia's largest sheep station almost seven months after UK-based Consolidated Pastoral Company announced plans to buy Rawlinna Station.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">453798f3baadfee94d513f7ea0e7efc3</guid></item><item><title>Cedric and Noelene Jordan lose appeal over conviction for murder of former son-in-law Shane Barker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/cedric-noelene-jordan-lose-appeal-over-murder-sentence/105807794</link><description>Cedric and Noelene Jordan's attempt to overturn their conviction for the murder of their former son-in-law in 2009 has failed, with the Court of Criminal Appeal rejecting it on all grounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d80214da46831af19f2e7cd071adf8a4</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of bees swarm Wagga Wagga CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/thousands-of-bees-swarm-wagga-wagga-cbd/105808258</link><description>Thousands of bees appear without warning in the regional city, alarming locals and causing a commotion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27722e02bcf2c9eb1efacb7eed1b7299</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie's spray at 'muppet', 'coward' Liberal colleagues after post bemoaning loss of Aussie car making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/andrew-hastie-car-making-coward-muppet-liberals/105808280</link><description>Senior Liberal Andrew Hastie has taken aim at colleagues who questioned a social media post where he bemoaned the loss of Australian car making, calling them "nameless cowards" and "muppets".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa8f233e21c3cb087597a2e4648810dd</guid></item><item><title>Khapra beetle found in Woolworths nappy pants poses $15b threat to grains industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/khapra-beetle-15b-dollar-threat-to-grains-industry/105807350</link><description>The estimated cost of the invasive khapra beetle to Australia's grains industry could be more than $15 billion if it became endemic across the country after being discovered in imported nappy pants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">028e1416aef9b2bb3928cd6f4f4fd1fb</guid></item><item><title>Teenage girl to stand trial for alleged Hervey Bay caravan park murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/girl-to-stand-trial-for-alleged-hervey-bay-caravan-park-murder/105805474</link><description>One of the youngest Australians ever to be charged with murder will face a jury trial over the stabbing death in a Hervey Bay caravan park of a 24-year-old man in August 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ee4913dd0bfa32590ddaa5163670af</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm's Jahrome Hughes and Ryan Papenhuyzen return for NRL preliminary final against Cronulla</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/storm-jahrome-hughes-against-cronulla-broncos-panthers/105808480</link><description>Melbourne recall three big guns, led by star half Jahrome Hughes, as their NRL title hopes go on the line in Friday night's preliminary final against Cronulla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1926a9906773436f42474dc790c296f5</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105809052</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2291dde89e5f6f2e800c553bd2118818</guid></item><item><title>Two teenagers sentenced to detention over attacks on Perth men lured via Grindr app</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/teenagers-detention-grindr-attacks-men-perth/105807670</link><description>Two "lawless" and "cruel" teenage boys who used social media to lure gay men to isolated locations in Perth before attacking them will remain in detention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04ac3ca89cb5b2ff893be3071e8400f4</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn's Mabior Chol has three-match ban overturned at AFL tribunal as rough conduct charge dismissed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/hawthorn-mabior-chol-afl-tribunal-hearing/105808298</link><description>The AFL tribunal quashes Mabior Chol's three-match ban for rough conduct, finding he did not act unreasonably in his tackle which left Geelong's Tom Stewart concussed and out of this weekend's grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a927a04bec9e6ad920a7713d7f32bccf</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Ragasa lashes Taiwan, with at least 15 dead and 152 missing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/super-typhoon-ragasa-taiwan-dead-missing/105809264</link><description>The most powerful storm so far in 2025 is now heading towards the Chinese mainland, prompting widespread disruption and warnings of sea surges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e86c797982ae3107e7d7d8203132df06</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump uses United Nations speech to lay out the US's complaints with the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/united-nations-general-assembly-donald-trump-speech/105809190</link><description>Donald Trump uses a speech at the UN to criticise US allies' moves to recognise Palestine and chastise the international community over a range of other American grievances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">251d1ac533cc88fd01a9540772aff365</guid></item><item><title>Russia systematically torturing Ukrainian civilians, UN says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/russia-systematically-torturing-ukrainian-civilians-un-says/105809316</link><description>The report is based on detailed interviews with 215 former detainees captured since Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b3ec3854b230344943aa0ea9a1c50f</guid></item><item><title>Incoming triple-0 reforms may not have helped prevent Optus failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/triple-0-reforms-may-not-have-helped-optus-failure/105807524</link><description>The federal government has yet to pass legislation to empower a new coordinator for the emergency services line, but experts say tougher conditions are needed on the telco itself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">196d665b157a51d6ce3440ca5be81bfc</guid></item><item><title>Could artificial intelligence and a universal basic income eliminate 'meaningless jobs'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/will-we-need-a-universal-basic-income-to-deal-with-ai-job-losses/105747954</link><description>COVID showed just how "fragile" our economic security is. As artificial intelligence potentially takes jobs from humans, a universal basic income might be a solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5953e2ae7f84df41d0ff5021a284652b</guid></item><item><title>Ryan Routh faces life in prison after guilty verdict in Donald Trump assassination attempt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ryan-routh-guilty-of-donald-trump-assassination-attempt/105809490</link><description>A man accused of trying to assassinate Donald Trump at his Florida golf course last year has been found guilty on all charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0214a8b817cf4108f24678a4dba1f80a</guid></item><item><title>Australians are moving to Tasmania to escape climate change, but the island state is not immune</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/australians-moving-to-tasmania-to-escape-climate-change/105785996</link><description>Jack and Anna swapped the humidity of Queensland for chilly days in Tasmania, but is Tasmania really the climate refuge many think it is?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0ff7fbad477aed99626b4746b82c14c</guid></item><item><title>Holbrook Landcare wins Bob Hawke award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/holbrook-landcare-wins-bob-hawke-award/105806834</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebdc5b27d20f0774f792387b024bec7b</guid></item><item><title>Holbrook Landcare Network wins 2025 Bob Hawke Award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/holbrook-landcare-network-wins-2025-bob-hawke-award/105803040</link><description>A landcare network at "the forefront of technology" has won the 2025 Bob Hawke Award for its innovative approach to sustainable farming practices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">704bd35d01dd4bdc8154c105eb49b76a</guid></item><item><title>Canola crop invaders seeking social media selfies told to stay off farms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/canola-crop-invaders-told-to-stop-trespassing-for-selfies/105802230</link><description>Selfie hunters seeking the perfect social media photo among flowering canola are putting their safety and growers' livelihoods at risk, farmers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c76b7d5ced248e1d7be9cfa5c171c969</guid></item><item><title>Key moments from Trump's speech to UN General Assembly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/highlights-of-trumps-speech-to-un-general-assembly/105809546</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">625a3f17cbf39ff5d80c0a1dc0ce0116</guid></item><item><title>How climate change impacted the 2025 snow season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/climate-change-impacted-2025-snow-season/105808698</link><description>The general sentiment is Australia's ski resorts are coming to the end of a bumper snow season — but is this evaluation accurate, or just positive spin after the dismal 2023 and 2024 seasons?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d83586cda83a6d18a50afafa5ab2f844</guid></item><item><title>NT government open to subdividing purpose-built State Square Art Gallery in Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nt-government-open-to-state-square-art-gallery-subdivide-darwin/105807672</link><description>A leading figure in Australia's art world has criticised the Northern Territory government for considering splitting up the lease for a building designed as a major new art gallery, describing the plan as "pure madness".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cea270549341f3bb40e1fafe548161cf</guid></item><item><title>Video record of violence and racism at Purnim Bears, Noorat country football grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/violence-racism-of-80s-country-victoria-football-grand-final/105741080</link><description>The Purnim Bears were supposed to be the feel-good story of country football — a team uniting black and white communities. But their 1987 grand final was so violent it ended with their expulsion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">231bb9fc7a4848fb3114f306c75ce3e0</guid></item><item><title>England names squad to face Australia in men's Ashes series 2025/26</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/england-name-squad-to-face-australia-in-men-s-ashes-series/105809606</link><description>England will bring a strong pace bowling attack, but several members of the squad, including captain Ben Stokes, are under injury clouds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d0a0a9cfab837e21e9251c67e841c3</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine can win back all territory lost to Russia, Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ukraine-can-win-back-all-territory-lost-to-russia-trump-says/105809578</link><description>The US president criticised Russia on the sidelines of the UN General Assembly, saying it had been fighting "aimlessly" in a war that a "real military power" would have won in less than a week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51fff57c3ffcb071ce802513857b4a30</guid></item><item><title>Mal Lanyon chosen as next NSW Police Force commissioner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/mal-lanyon-new-commissioner-of-nsw-police-force/105701914</link><description>Deputy Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon has been chosen to head up the NSW Police Force, replacing commissioner Karen Webb.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cd3192bee4641f04f5b65931d5fe5d6</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou 'excited' to defend his Europa League trophy with Nottingham Forest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ange-postecoglou-nottingham-forest-europa-league/105809674</link><description>Four months after leading Tottenham Hotspur to Europa League triumph in Bilbao, Ange Postecoglou has returned to Spain and UEFA's second-tier club competition with a new challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d7d5db2308c2c5b39a10ccc3cdf7870</guid></item><item><title>Australian speed skydiver hangs on to title of fastest woman in the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/natisha-dingle-wins-fai-world-cup-speed-skydiving-title/105805486</link><description>Jumping out of planes and freefalling at nearly 500 kilometres per hour is "addictive" for Queensland woman Natisha Dingle, who has just set a new Oceania speed record in the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6dae41d360c4eeda58220eedaf6442a</guid></item><item><title>Queensland speed skydiver Natisha Dingle shows off her impressive skills.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/speed-skydiver-natisha-dingle-shows-off-her-impressive-skills/105807064</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c809122700c1bf91a2b261a16e110608</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's meeting with Trump matters for AUKUS and the role of the US in the Asia-Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/anthony-albanese-donald-trump-meeting/105801298</link><description>Trump clearly disagrees with Albanese on Palestine and the reality of climate change, but it's not on the scale of the beef he has with other countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1daf71c6599467c19439c0e23875de0e</guid></item><item><title>Warragul man knocks back dream job after NDIS funding for van rejected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/ndis-rejects-van-man-needs-to-drive-to-dream-job/105762830</link><description>Josh Evans, who uses a wheelchair, had to turn down a job with the Bureau of Meteorology because he was unable to get NDIS funding for a vehicle to drive himself to work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21c25c4b57843d7697e914107db94243</guid></item><item><title>Trump claims paracetamol link to autism. Five experts explain what's wrong with that statement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/what-the-experts-are-saying-about-paracetamol-use-lead-to-autism/105806230</link><description>Some leading Australian experts in medicine, autism research and obstetrics say the US president's claims are "a misreading of science," or at worst, "a misuse". Here's why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bffee58bd319bdb466db1eb8559f629b</guid></item><item><title>Why the legacy of the 2023 NRL grand final hangs over the Broncos and Panthers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/panthers-broncos-nrl-preliminary-final-grand-final-cleary/105809026</link><description>On Sunday, the Broncos and Panthers will face off in the finals for the first time since the 2023 grand final, but the memory of that night still hangs over both sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad8624f8c74a64751af52bbcd1e11c56</guid></item><item><title>ABC ordered to pay $150,000 fine for unlawfully sacking journalist and presenter Antoinette Lattouf</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/antoinette-lattouf-costs-decision-in-abc-unlawful-termination/105810052</link><description>The judge ordered ABC to pay a fine of $150,000 for unlawfully sacking journalist and presenter Antoinette Lattouf for reasons including her political opinions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dad4cb7dec36a5f662b73fe15e33939</guid></item><item><title>Sandy Brondello axed by WNBA side New York Liberty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/sandy-brondello-axed-by-wnba-side-new-york-liberty/105810534</link><description>Australian basketball coach Sandy Brondello is let go by the New York Liberty after a disappointing first-round exit from the WNBA play-offs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a4504d3bbba4c100278133bdd4d6055</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann seeks funding to pay for legal representation over raids at his home in 2024</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/bruce-lehrmann-seeks-funds-for-legal-representation-over-raids/105809920</link><description>Former Liberal staffer Bruce Lehrmann launches Federal Court action seeking funding for legal representation at a National Anti-Corruption Commission hearing after raids on his home in June last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">749a230c4ad7fe395ea22940c47b8259</guid></item><item><title>Canberra golf course redevelopments providing both much-needed housing and financial lifelines for struggling clubs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/golf-course-redevelopments-providing-housing-financial-lifelines/105799100</link><description>With the ACT government pushing for greater urban density, golf courses in inner Canberra suburbs are becoming attractive sites for redevelopment to provide much-needed housing and a way for struggling clubs to bolster their budgets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b488a99ab4311911d8fa6f87e596dc4c</guid></item><item><title>Gender-based violence services prepare for increased calls on AFL grand final weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/increased-rates-of-gender-based-violence-during-football-finals/105809996</link><description>Ahead of the AFL grand final, national violence prevention organisation Our Watch is calling for the sporting community to address the increased risk of violence facing women during football finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4d5c539ddee700b75c82661684fb340</guid></item><item><title>Camp Mystic plans to reopen next summer, a year after floods killed 27</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/camp-mystic-plans-to-reopen-a-year-after-flood-deaths/105810114</link><description>Camp Mystic also announces plans for a memorial dedicated to "the lives of the campers and counsellors lost on July 4th".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">496ec39f957a1a61a68f959f6319b508</guid></item><item><title>Kalgoorlie-Boulder hit by massive power blackout again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/kalgoorlie-boulder-loses-power-again/105811398</link><description>More than 15,000 homes and businesses were without electricity after the entire town of Kalgoorlie-Boulder lost power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccbb9d5abaa29e6ec88dabc0c8930e7a</guid></item><item><title>Sculpture by the Sea could be cancelled due to $200,000 shortfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/sculptures-by-the-sea-facing-cancellation-funding-shortfall/105810510</link><description>Australia's famed sculpture walk is facing cancellation after failing to secure funding less than a month out from this year's event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ca69999aba4ff9483322749a16b717e</guid></item><item><title>When is the 2025 AFL grand final? Here's what time it starts and where to watch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/when-is-the-afl-grand-final-time-where-to-watch-explained/105809976</link><description>Wondering what time the AFL grand final starts and how you can watch it live? We've got you covered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b35be59cc10e4e0032348864c66bd1c7</guid></item><item><title>Despite past controversy, NSW Police commissioner Mal Lanyon has a strong backing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nsw-police-commissioner-mal-lanyon-premier-chris-minns-analysis/105810774</link><description>For newly-announced Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon, Wednesday morning would have been both one of his proudest moments, and his most uncomfortable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed72f9bcc7ce20d2d722b8b43d539719</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel returns, addressing Charlie Kirk and 'un-American' axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/jimmy-kimmel-returns-thanking-supporters-speaks-to-free-speech/105808410</link><description>Despite the late-night host's return, several US ABC affiliates did not air the episode, excluding an estimated one-quarter of American households.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac8b78a8e557c0d2a91d42ed04e2eed</guid></item><item><title>Family suspects foul play in Noosa man Byron Dumschat's death in a Bali villa pool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/family-suspects-foul-play-in-bali-death-noosa-man-byron-dumschat/105809846</link><description>An Australian family is asking why Indonesian police allowed three Australian witnesses to return home without being interviewed after their 23-year-old son died on the Indonesian holiday resort island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4e8e32abe23c1a44f62c5e3f023e2a2</guid></item><item><title>Rape case against Bruce Lehrmann delayed after lawyer misses deadline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/bruce-lehrmann-rape-case-faces-more-delays-in-toowoomba/105811608</link><description>A judge says the process of a bid to stop a criminal rape case against former Liberal Party staffer Bruce Lehrmann proceeding has been "problematic" after his lawyer missed a key deadline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20b38956daedd1cd16f45a4769958aa6</guid></item><item><title>How #RedundancyDiaries are busting the stigma of being let go</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/busting-the-stigma-on-redundancy-by-sharing-online/105751880</link><description>Camille says being made redundant was hard, so she began sharing her experiences on TikTok hoping to help others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69e9a0930ebbcb9805519c817968e9ee</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's changed stance on Ukraine could be a challenge for Vladimir Putin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/donald-trump-ukraine-nato-comments-a-challenge-to-vladimir-putin/105810170</link><description>If Donald Trump actually means what he has just said — that NATO countries have a right to shoot down any Russian jets in their airspace — the US president may be contracting out a serious counteroffensive against Russian aggression to NATO countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c624737442bcb04137b18db123e6997</guid></item><item><title>Report recommends gondola access to Jenolan Caves near the Blue Mountains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/report-recommends-gondola-access-to-jenolan-caves/105809918</link><description>A report recommends building a gondola to the tune of $44 million to bypass catastrophic road failures that have long plagued the Jenolan Caves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27aa154744525803a917b0b5069cde36</guid></item><item><title>Why did the UN escalator stop after Donald and Melania Trump stepped on it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/donald-melania-trump-escalator-teleprompter-un-marcon-call/105810256</link><description>Footage of the US president and his wife's reactions to the mishap was shared widely on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87fdb12fe7af401b7964018acf19bc5f</guid></item><item><title>Optus admits procedural failure before outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/optus-admits-procedural%C2%A0failure-before-outage%C2%A0/105811978</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b84c417046bbfc3acea16532e90a47cf</guid></item><item><title>AFL boss hints at Brownlow voting shake-up after Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/afl-boss-hits-at-brownlow-voting-shake-up-after-controversy/105812086</link><description>Voting for the Brownlow Medal has been a hot topic again in the wake of Monday night's count, with the AFL open to letting umpires have access to statistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5d9c582b445942c6c11e6f1591db872</guid></item><item><title>Kindergarten cleaner who allegedly filmed children in bathroom faces more charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/kindergarten-cleaner-who-secretly-filmed-children-in-toilet/105811222</link><description>Prosecutors have flagged more potential charges for the Victorian kindergarten cleaner accused of secretly filming children in a bathroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a0e03375009bb4e55aea4b0a8b01d7e</guid></item><item><title>Missouri woman gets more than four years jail for trying to sell off Elvis' Graceland property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/missouri-woman-jailed-for-elvis-graceland-property-scam/105810930</link><description>A woman's attempt to sell off one of the most storied pieces of real estate in the US has come to naught. Here's how it happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87c9bf726b751fc3728cdd75266b9d0d</guid></item><item><title>Hockeyroos legend Katrina Powell quits as coach after two Olympic campaigns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/hockeyroos-legend-katrina-powell-quits-as-coach/105812958</link><description>Hockeyroos great Katrina Powell has quit as coach of Australia's women's team after rebuilding a criticised culture in the elite program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3362fa20010b71b5d18e66dc93b4c83</guid></item><item><title>Christopher John Sullivan sentenced for stabbing partner Pauline Mountford in Gooseberry Hill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/christopher-john-sullivan-domestic-violence-sentencing/105812460</link><description>A 74-year-old man who slashed his partner's throat in their Perth Hills home is sentenced to 10 years in jail over the near-fatal attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b34ba7512fda4d4c878ff84234b915f6</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's gripe-filled United Nations speech unsurprising, Foreign Minister Penny Wong says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/penny-wong-responds-to-donald-trump-un-speech-albanese-meeting/105809070</link><description>Foreign Minister Penny Wong says the speech US President Donald Trump delivered at the UN is simply more of the same from him and "consistent" with his views and actions since being elected for a second term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d44f8f03841ac14753961232f5608cf4</guid></item><item><title>Former A-League footballers Clayton Lewis and Kearyn Baccus sentenced over betting scam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/a-league-betting-clayton-lewis-kearyn-baccus-sentencing/105811400</link><description>Both players were paid $10,000 each to intentionally get themselves yellow cards while playing for Macarthur FC against Sydney FC to influence overseas bets on the game.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4d047a9369284c7941aaf5cccc0a654</guid></item><item><title>Farmer Sam Bailey, who worked to be the world's first quadriplegic helicopter pilot, dies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/quadriplegic-helicopter-pilot-sam-bailey-dies/105811530</link><description>A "true blue" farmer, pilot, and pioneer for accessibility in agriculture has been honoured after his sudden death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1022bcfec676038f6c3bd27cde15e24c</guid></item><item><title>Former police officer Stephen Michael Calcutt pleads guilty to filming teenagers in shower and up skirt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/former-police-officer-pleads-guilty-filming-teenager/105812714</link><description>The former sergeant also filmed up another teenager's skirt and had a number of cartoons depicting children in sexual situations on a hard drive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d016f9d7ccabbb8651e7cb9fc607919e</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions trust Lachie Neale to make right call ahead of AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/brisbane-lions-lachie-neale-right-afl-grand-final-call/105813604</link><description>All eyes are on Lachie Neale's bid to make a remarkable grand final return from injury, and his teammates will back him to make the right call.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b33183c69e679601c3ad83c2c662b7b</guid></item><item><title>Murder trial hears final arguments from trio accused of 2022 stabbing death of David Jenkins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/trial-of-men-accused-of-david-jenkins-murder-final-arguments/105805736</link><description>The trial of two brothers and another man accused of the stabbing murder of a man in Tasmania's north in 2022 hears there is "no serious dispute" that Luke Shaw "was the person who killed" David Jenkins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">621a1d67e3bb519003eb4e577b718a6e</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105813848</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbeee129e3122b06287a24ba6aa752ed</guid></item><item><title>Men sentenced for riot amid 'pressure cooker' conditions in Alice Springs prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nt-nine-alice-springs-prisoners-sentenced-in-court-over-riot/105810344</link><description>Lawyers for nine Alice Springs prisoners who rioted at the facility last year say the unrest was akin to a "pressure cooker release valve" amid "feelings of degradation and neglect".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f4122da2e195a834f3006510b2c73ce</guid></item><item><title>South Bunbury Football Club apologises for president's Charlie Kirk party costume</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/south-bunbury-football-club-apologise-over-charlie-kirk-costume/105813358</link><description>A West Australian football club issues a public apology after photos emerge of its president in a Charlie Kirk costume, featuring a gunshot wound to the neck.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ef0f41127e48d1b3de0be09e1592a79</guid></item><item><title>Top stories from ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/top-stories-from-abc-news/105814116</link><description>Listen to ABC News interviews and commentary and analysis from radio programs like AM, PM and The World Today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a14c87bdf4cdf55e4c6350e762ba357f</guid></item><item><title>Gaza aid flotilla targeted by drone explosion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/gaza-aid-flotilla-targeted-by-drone-explosion%C2%A0/105813242</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0a5e80c988063752bd5ac9a46ef8695</guid></item><item><title>Italy sends navy frigate to assist Global Sumud Flotilla after vessels targeted by drones off Greece</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/global-sumud-flotilla-says-vessels-targeted-by-drones/105812860</link><description>The flotilla carrying aid and pro-Palestinian activists said they heard explosions and saw multiple drones that targeted some of their boats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b77e1392b4829d64f6d75add8a54c81</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Ragasa hits south China as death toll rises to 14</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/super-typhoon-ragasa-kills-several-people-many-others-missing/105813684</link><description>Super Typhoon Ragasa has killed at least 14 people in Taiwan as it struck the southern Chinese coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3debe7584f1c0715ebb83364e81b822c</guid></item><item><title>One dead in 'targeted' shooting at Dallas immigration centre, DHS says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/multiple-dead-at-dallas-ice-shooting/105814138</link><description>Police were first alerted to the incident at 6:40am on Wednesday, local time, and later found the shooter on a nearby roof dead from an apparent self-inflicted gunshot wound.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41372aed6a1e8513347f563b066ef004</guid></item><item><title>London mayor calls Trump racist, sexist and Islamophobic, hitting back at US president's 'sharia law' comments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sadiq-khan-hits-back-at-trump-over-islamophobic-comments/105814108</link><description>The US president described Sadiq Khan as "terrible" and warned the British capital was heading towards "sharia law".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">422ae10fb37033a360fbadff60ea4a35</guid></item><item><title>Kimmel monologue racks up millions of views on social media as Joe Rogan slams government 'dictating'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/kimmel-video-and-rogan-lashing-viral/105814274</link><description>Kimmel's program was indefinitely suspended last week after he made comments about the late conservative commentator Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">125445d0de8a02f7060a350896e799ff</guid></item><item><title>Australia's social media ban wins praise from Europe at UN event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/united-nations-general-assembly-social-media-ban/105814246</link><description>Australia's willingness to take on the social media giants is drawing significant international interest, winning the support of the European Commission president at a forum in New York.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13cbd1fcaa9fc632384fa2b086577151</guid></item><item><title>Who is really pulling the strings at Optus and what does that mean for you?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/who-really-controls-optus/105813620</link><description>The Singapore government's sovereign wealth investment vehicle is majority-owned by Singtel, which owns Australia's second-largest telco provider.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6aded4f6f61a6898c3ed39fc7af059c2</guid></item><item><title>University of Technology Sydney under investigation by National Student Ombudsman over gender-based and sexual violence policies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/uts-investigation-into-sexual-harassment-gender-policies/105811036</link><description>The National Student Ombudsman is investigating allegations UTS failed to improve its response to sexual harm and gender-based violence despite four reviews since 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c08cc57e36783d5633eaf660ecf3bf6</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie taunted over claim that high immigration is making Australians 'strangers in our own home'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/hastie-migration-strangers-liberal-policy/105813654</link><description>The home affairs minister says Andrew Hastie should name which visa classes he would cut after the shadow home affairs minister suggested "unsustainable" immigration was making Australians "feel like strangers in our own home".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13e71a456d250f5a995b477b981c4622</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: PM bids for UN Security Council seat in major address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/federal-politics-live-sept-25/105812720</link><description>Australia will make a bid for a seat on the UN Security Council, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has told a meeting of the UN General Assembly. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a1855533ef7e4ee2263abc39c01aed0</guid></item><item><title>AFL super fans prepare for the grand final clash between Geelong and Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-football-fans-brisbane-lions-geelong-cats-2025-premiership/105812254</link><description>From a unique tattoo to a personalised burger, the AFL grand final is more than just a game for these super fans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85ea949cc04c0beee30263008e182e01</guid></item><item><title>Will food prices ever come down? Don't bet on it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/will-food-grocery-prices-ever-come-down/105811296</link><description>While recent cuts to interest rates may have given mortgage holders a bit of a financial breathing space, the cost of food continues to creep upwards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fce87e998f0daf4d07d83c36c6038f70</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy blames Putin for 'most destructive arms race in human history'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/zelenskyy-blames-putin-for-most-destructive-arms-race/105814378</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7700655ee2a3abe520a419b677e6593f</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian horse breeder says she will rehome more than 100 animals after social media outcry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/concerns-for-horse-welfare-at-weona-park-stud-tasmania/105801614</link><description>A Tasmanian horse breeder has been told to reduce the number of horses on her property and rehome them, after concerns were raised by members of the racing community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a597ef583c4431b5038d56d38a58a6e</guid></item><item><title>Independent review launched into Australia's fire ant eradication program amid warnings of a 'closing window of opportunity'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/fire-ant-eradication-program-review-launched/105811790</link><description>Authorities launch an independent review of Australia's national fire ant eradication program to evaluate the country's fight against one of the world’s most destructive pests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c444298e462f9192611f3572f0c28de3</guid></item><item><title>Families demand inquiry into NSW Police handling of missing persons cases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/families-of-missing-persons-call-for-probe-into-police/105693338</link><description>Nikii Smith is one of 10,000 people who signed a petition calling for a NSW inquiry into the handling of missing persons cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86bd1e4db1094cebb0f4277ff0ad4c3b</guid></item><item><title>China retains narrow edge over US as South-East Asia's most influential partner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/china-us-influence-south-east-asia/105812866</link><description>New research shows that China retains a very narrow edge over the United States as South-East Asia's most influential partner, with experts predicting it will soon pull further ahead as the Trump administration's policies begin to bite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7b10409c8753c731ed70c5ed5ed7bea</guid></item><item><title>Solar, batteries and the 'phone charger dilemma': How a standards gap threatens clean tech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/smart-tech-benefits-at-risk-over-lack-of-common-standard/105808798</link><description>In the same way Apple and Samsung used different phone chargers, many clean tech products are not compatible with others. Experts say it is a big problem for the energy transition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84ec00dd3b63db045677af76a0c64880</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Ragasa leaves trail of destruction in Hong Kong, mainland China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/super-typhoon-ragasa-leaves-trail-of-destruction/105814414</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea6a7a5ee520e38455556c3ef9f800c2</guid></item><item><title>Family calls for change amid frustration at seven-year coronial inquest wait</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/anger-at-seven-year-coronial-inquest-wait/105805234</link><description>Robert Hall was killed when he was struck by partially blind driver John Charles Robertson on the Horrocks Highway in 2018. It has been a long wait for the family ahead of the release of coronial findings into his death next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dedbef63ba8aa61b8045e0d358939858</guid></item><item><title>Victim-survivors left to self-represent in Family Court of Australia proceedings due to legal fees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/parents-self-representing-in-family-court-due-to-high-legal-fees/105767468</link><description>Jacinta says she is part of a "big wave" of litigants self-representing in Family Court of Australia proceedings after facing extraordinary fees from family law firms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5a4fec0b01dc945b1744b6c215769aa</guid></item><item><title>Australia wins mixed relay gold medal at UCI Road World Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/australia-wins-mixed-relay-gold-uci-road-world-championships/105814410</link><description>Australia has retained its title in the mixed team relay at the UCI Road World Championships as it stormed to victory over two circuits of a hilly 20.9-kilometre course in Kigali on Wednesday, local time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bb1b152e105b4009b0d3e97b9a547aa</guid></item><item><title>Elevated E. coli levels recorded at major NT crocodile farm owned by luxury label Hermès</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/lambells-lagoon-crocodile-farm-nt-high-e-coli-levels-in-water/105806340</link><description>One of Australia's largest crocodile farms, owned by a subsidiary of luxury label Hermès, is consistently irrigating with water containing E. coli concentrations almost 500 times the national guidelines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcebaaf92f52cb686dddde475db8c67b</guid></item><item><title>Police launch fresh search of WA outback over Ray and Jennie Kehlet cold case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/wa-police-search-sandstone-kehlet-cold-case/105813086</link><description>Detectives are this week revisiting the site in WA's outback where the body of prospector Ray Kehlet was found. His wife Jennie is still missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eda36c180ee83ef793f5a6e386ed8ef6</guid></item><item><title>Former AFL boss Andrew Demetriou insists league would embrace a gay men's player</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/andrew-demetriou-says-afl-a-safe-space-for-gay-players/105813820</link><description>Former AFL boss Andrew Demetriou says the public would embrace a gay men's player and rejects that the AFL is an unsafe environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d77a4e9f1c05a3808354f694994d6ee</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous teen speaks out against heckling of Welcome to Country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/indigenous-writes-essay-against-heckling-welcome-to-country/105808140</link><description>An Indigenous high school student's essay on the Anzac Day heckling of an Indigenous elder by far-right supremacists has earned her a nationally recognised award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d0978c16ddeb79e39b966dd2e565459</guid></item><item><title>New gene therapy for Huntington's 'changes everything', say researchers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/huntingtons-disease-gene-therapy-slows-progression/105814436</link><description>Clinical trials of a groundbreaking new gene therapy for Huntington's disease have shown that it slows progression of the condition by 75 per cent after three years, researchers say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38bce5a01d090886db2ddeef7689a3bb</guid></item><item><title>Alexa Leary and Callum Simpson win gold medals for Australia at World Para Swimming Championships in Singapore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/alexa-leary-callum-simpson-gold-world-para-swimming/105814486</link><description>Alexa Leary's win in the final individual event of Wednesday night's action in Singapore bookended a golden night for Australia after Callum Simpson won gold in the first event of the evening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24509973b18c1db25ad97fe2c3eae8f7</guid></item><item><title>Magnitude-4.1 earthquake rattles Tasmania from Maydena to Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/tasmania-rattled-with-magnitude-4-1-earthquake/105814558</link><description>Tasmania records a magnitude-4.1 earthquake in the state's south-west that was felt from Maydena to Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84775edf57cd76c9bc0ca385f3b919d5</guid></item><item><title>Live market updates: Macquarie to compensate Shield investors, share markets fall as traders dial back rate cut bets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/105814572</link><description>Corporate regulator ASIC reaches a deal with Macquarie to fully compensate investors in the collapsed super fund Shield. Meanwhile, major share indices are easing on worries that interest rates will not fall much further. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d14279b842237d15d950214fbd7b970</guid></item><item><title>Wells meets with Singaporean officials but fails to mention Optus triple-0 outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/wells-meets-with-singaporean-officials-but-fails/105814624</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23e9cc5645aa51f35556ac9f983ffc9e</guid></item><item><title>Who is Samoa's new prime minister, Laaulialemalietoa Polataivao Fosi Schmidt?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/new-samoa-prime-minister-election/105789496</link><description>Supporters are fervent in their enthusiasm for Samoa's new prime minister, but voters who are more sceptical of Laaulialemalietoa Polataivao Fosi Schmidt, question his motives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">625c6497fc8280a6929fa5f29c6e97f3</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy warns UN of 'the most destructive arms race in human history'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/united-nations-general-assembly-volodymyr-zelenskyy-speech/105814462</link><description>Ukraine's president calls for global action to regulate the twin threats posed by drone technology and artificial intelligence, warning "no-one can feel safe" from Russia's expansionist goals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5f96320cb70d90485b91a1058586e74</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final sprint won't feature all teams, as Gout Gout and Harry Garside to feature at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-grand-final-sprint-gout-gout-and-harry-garside/105814536</link><description>The AFL announces that only seven AFL players will run in the traditional grand final sprint, with Olympic boxer Harry Garside also joining in.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90c0207e2a6dabd51c17d24fbfdde78c</guid></item><item><title>China's President Xi Jinping announces new climate goal to cut emissions by 2035</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/china-plans-carbon-emissions-cut-by-2035/105814492</link><description>Outlining China's new carbon targets in a video link to the UN climate conference in New York, President Xi Jinping says "green and low carbon transition is the trend of our time".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f28b3d1c00395f4695e9369d6c444f2</guid></item><item><title>Nottingham Forest draws 2-2 with Real Betis in opening UEFA Europa League match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nottingham-forest-draws-with-real-betis-europa-league/105814730</link><description>Nottingham Forest's long-awaited return to European competition ends 2-2 at Real Betis, with Igor Jesus's first-half double cancelling out by a late Antony strike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7da92da66bbef30024c541232032313</guid></item><item><title>Lawn bowls championship puts small border town of Barham on the sporting map</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/2025-world-bowls-champion-of-champions-barham-murray-river/105805760</link><description>It may not seem like the place to host a prestigious World Bowls competition, but a small Murray River town is doing just that.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b17779031706e3877e6c0532de5cc11</guid></item><item><title>ARIA Award nominations 2025: Ninajirachi, Dom Dolla, Amyl &amp; The Sniffers lead the pack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/aria-award-nominations-2025-aria-nominees-full-list/105815074</link><description>All the contenders are hopefuls vying for ARIA Awards glory at the music industry's glitzy ceremony, taking place next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">959594b1e7f091dd3de19e45dc3888ab</guid></item><item><title>Peter Tonagh to replace Catherine West as Nine's chair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/peter-tonagh-to-become-chair-of-nine/105814974</link><description>He replaces Catherine West, who spent 18 months in the position.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2a5f2c444b61e900f222e4b49c5f0b5</guid></item><item><title>New stats reveal highest number of criminal incidents in Victoria since records began</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/victoria-crime-statistics-agency-new-stats-highest-number/105814382</link><description>The latest figures from Victoria's Crime Statistics Agency show the highest number of criminal incidents in at least two decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">500fef92cd2f6d069d1fe5f61f29fcd2</guid></item><item><title>Massive sinkhole disrupts traffic and power supply in central Bangkok</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/massive-sinkhole-disrupts-traffic-and-power-supply/105815094</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cce7d7b5d0f17665bf2d2fc459ec5537</guid></item><item><title>Bathurst mother speaks of hardships of losing daughter to cyber bullying</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/bathurst-mother-speaks-of-hardships-/105814658</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9b973393377919a40baffbc21da8385</guid></item><item><title>Dramatic footage shows sinkhole swallowing up road in central Bangkok</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sinkhole-swallows-road-in-central-bangkok/105814850</link><description>Social media footage shows powerlines being pulled down into the 50-metre deep hole and vehicles teetering on the edge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">341b949dae61cd2058ac47c271016c61</guid></item><item><title>Andrea James to lead Ilbijerri Theatre Company as artistic director Rachael Maza steps back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/ilbijerri-theatre-company-artistic-director-andrea-james/105806022</link><description>Andrea James will take the helm of Australia's oldest Indigenous theatre company Ilbijerri, as outgoing artistic director Rachael Maza steps back after almost 18 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4a3dbe4751b97f43dde74a8c6965376</guid></item><item><title>Man to be charged with 'serious offences' over domestic violence incident and pursuit, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/vale-park-man-arrested-over-alleged-dv-incident/105815044</link><description>South Australia Police says a Vale Park man has been arrested following a pursuit that led STAR group officers and police negotiators to a unit in Adelaide's western suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d31264009557887152139ca68f0250</guid></item><item><title>NT para athlete Briseis Brittain wasn't born when Cathy Freeman won Olympic gold, but the moment fired a dream</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nt-para-athlete-briseis-brittain-new-delhi-world-championship/105810758</link><description>Arnhem Land teenager Briseis Brittain is set to represent Australia at the World Para Athletics Championships in New Delhi this month, competing in the 200m and 400m races.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc07264a34fb78aeac4e200e6ca98512</guid></item><item><title>Liberal candidate Gisele Kapterian abandons court challenge for Sydney seat of Bradfield</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/liberal-gisele-kapterian-abandons-bradfield-court-challenge/105815662</link><description>Gisele Kapterian abandons her court action challenging the election result in the federal Sydney seat of Bradfield.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72e919021e6b203c2c61364023ef65cb</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese addresses UN on climate goals, Gaza and Australia's security council bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/albanese-united-nations-general-assembly-speech/105815200</link><description>The prime minister uses his UN speech to talk up Australia's emissions plan after Donald Trump called climate change a "con job", and confirms Australia is still seeking a temporary seat on the body's security council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a232f435066d64bce12998bbb55c68d5</guid></item><item><title>Nicho Hynes shrugs off personal barbs ahead of NRL preliminary final between Melbourne and Cronulla</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nicho-hynes-cronulla-sharks-nrl-preliminary-final/105815774</link><description>Accused by some of being too nice and not nice enough by others, polarising Cronulla star Nicho Hynes "doesn't give a rats" about criticism that comes his way anymore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab3262fd8438997bf3566bc3f3afd340</guid></item><item><title>Figure skating star scraps program amid probe involving artist who co-wrote music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/figure-skating-star-scraps-program-amid-investigation-of-artist/105815302</link><description>Figure skaters spend months perfecting their programs ahead of big competitions, but now world champion Alysa Liu has to come up with a new short program months out from the Winter Olympics as her existing music involves an American artist under investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdb57cf2473b758d2fe046f294292f23</guid></item><item><title>Postal voting issues identified ahead of 2025 WA local government elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/postal-voting-problems-for-2025-local-government-election/105815250</link><description>Incorrect ballot papers are among several problems identified with postal voting packages sent out ahead next month's local government elections in WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4995a33060a008be1386f30e6e5a7afe</guid></item><item><title>Goldfields residents brace for future blackouts as long-term solution still years away</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/kalgoorlie-power-outage-frustrates-residents/105813042</link><description>Business owners and locals in Western Australia's Goldfields have dealt with the first power blackout of the season while waiting for a long-term energy solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb7f4c0c25a06be356d0545b6a5c38a7</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian MPs to receive $30,000 pay rise against government's wishes after upper house tussle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/tasmanian-politicians-pay-to-rise-despite-gov-wishes/105816164</link><description>Tasmanian politicians will receive a 22 per cent pay rise despite the government's attempts to block it, after upper house MPs voted to accept a determination by Tasmania's Industrial Commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">760f80a393afa047ecf95a03ee9dfac5</guid></item><item><title>Scott Selwood takes break from AFL after 'personally challenging year'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/scott-selwood-steps-away-afl-collingwood/105815996</link><description>Scott Selwood will take time away from football, stepping down as an assistant coach with Collingwood, following a year marked by personal tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41d251b3ccf71ca56edd70b60deeeab9</guid></item><item><title>AI image recognition technology used to detect traffic offences raises privacy concerns, Queensland audit finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/ai-image-technology-phone-speeding-offences-privacy-audit-qld/105815134</link><description>Queensland's transport department uses AI in its cameras to detect mobile and seatbelt offences, but a new audit has ordered called for a review into how that's done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11d46c909160642ceb7265e8809e201c</guid></item><item><title>ABC News - Trusted Source of Latest News &amp; Headlines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2022-12-13/harley-and-katya-the-price-of-an-olympic-dream/101557348</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee96c51cbc5b98d83ab9002535dfc647</guid></item><item><title>Breastfeeding in public is protected in Australia. So why are mothers still facing discrimination?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/why-are-we-still-asking-mothers-to-hide-breastfeeding/105789046</link><description>Last week a breastfeeding mother was asked to leave a Virgin Australia lounge for pumping. Experts says while there is a level of awareness that breastfeeding in public is protected, some people in the community still view it as "inappropriate".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5341713f4b5168cc3ed1630a81ef91c6</guid></item></channel></rss>