<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Jan 2026 07:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Actor Awards nominations 2026: Australian stars Jacob Elordi, Sarah Snook and Rose Byrne among nominees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/sag-actor-award-nominations/106208668</link><description>Australian names are among the mix of nominees unveiled for Hollywood's Actor Awards, formerly known as the Screen Actors Guild Awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2da960f27bdebc5e7ba4cd8afcc9844</guid></item><item><title>Marble Bar residents share their tips for keeping cool in nationwide heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/beating-the-heat-in-marble-bar-australias-hottest-town/106204346</link><description>From 30 bags of ice in a blow-up pool to misted toilets and getting plenty of sleep, residents in Marble Bar share their top tips to weather a heatwave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09532239a65ed148c6c952b574dd0e7c</guid></item><item><title>ICE agent fatally shoots woman in Minneapolis.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/protests-erupt-after-ice-agent-fatally-shoots-woman/106208574</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99716935e082906aa4b7bf6ce1ed4743</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2026: Australia claims 4-1 series win after surviving nervy run chase to win Sydney Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/ashes-live-blog-day-five-scg/106208540</link><description>Australia chases down 160 with five wickets remaining in Sydney to round out the Ashes in style as Usman Khawaja bids farewell to Test cricket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">561f6e0d36232b22c3058b783d0b4529</guid></item><item><title>Gunshots heard as woman shot dead by ICE officer in Minneapolis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/gunshots-heard-as-woman-shot-dead-by-ice-officer-in-minneapolis-/106208960</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c25ec786dde086a9d79fedbf2e800254</guid></item><item><title>Algal bloom researcher 'deeply disturbed' by political interference claims, committee told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/claims-algal-bloom-cause-probe-delayed-until-after-sa-election/106208450</link><description>An inquiry into South Australia's harmful algal bloom has been rocked by claims from a prominent ecologist, who has raised allegations of government interference in scientific research into the bloom's causes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddbdc6a9b523b6c81afed0925ddeaa47</guid></item><item><title>Commercial fishers hit by Kimberley Marine Park left waiting five years for compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/commercial-fishers-still-waiting-compensation-kimberley-wa/106206918</link><description>Kimberley fishers impacted by the establishment of a marine park say the government has failed to deliver promised compensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6002d73bf44564f51ba3d2a7fc29d97d</guid></item><item><title>What the seizure of Maduro means for China, Venezuela's biggest oil buyer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/china-close-ties-with-venezuela-inaction-since-maduro-capture/106205836</link><description>Despite being one of the strongest critics of Donald Trump's move to capture Nicolás Maduro, Beijing has not moved beyond condemnation of Washington.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f783c8e2d27f1fa5e3da5837c0681ffa</guid></item><item><title>Veteran Stan Wawrinka says Nick Kyrgios is an 'amazing player' amid wildcard debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/wawrinka-on-kyrgios-australian-open-wildcard/106209186</link><description>Retiring veteran Stan Wawrinka was all class discussing the AO wildcard debate surrounding Nick Kyrgios, putting aside the pair's troubled history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32410a257a44771fc70bd7f1a788ca37</guid></item><item><title>Independent film collective Movie Juice launches inaugural summer film fest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/independent-film-collective-movie-juice-summer-film-festival/106207546</link><description>Summer has hit its stride with a heatwave across the country this week, providing the perfect backdrop to a new film festival that features beaches, surfing, young love, and that horrible feeling of holidays ebbing by.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c4265944145f44c4bd0a1e77ac10d99</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Test cricketer Damien Martyn returns home after waking from induced coma</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/cricket-damien-martyn-returns-home-after-induced-coma/106209598</link><description>Adam Gilchrist says his former Australia teammate Damien Martyn has been released from a Gold Coast hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49020d9667afff535b334516291f1145</guid></item><item><title>Kentbruck Green Energy Hub passes planning hurdle but report highlights environmental concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/kentbruck-wind-project-environmental-effects-approval/106206224</link><description>The Kentbruck Green Energy Hub would include wind turbines up to 270m tall, and be built inside active pine plantations, but its location has worried conservationists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3fb1208cb6857282d20eabaa766c4bf</guid></item><item><title>Reserve Bank deputy governor Andrew Hauser downplays easing inflation ahead of February meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/rba-deputy-andrew-hauser-inflation-interest-rates/106208716</link><description>The deputy governor of the Reserve Bank Andrew Hauser confirms the news mortgage borrowers would not have wanted to hear — interest rates are highly unlikely to head lower anytime soon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe254d1365e7c4696f8ec418bfb00e24</guid></item><item><title>No subscriptions? No problems. Here are the best movies and TV series you can watch for free</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/free-movies-free-tv-watch-online/106207308</link><description>From Academy Award-winning performances to classic Australian comedy, fill the last moments of your holidays with these free movies and TV series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ce170a90764ebd85c804dafd5fbfac9</guid></item><item><title>Boom time for active holiday tours attracting travellers with 'young energy'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/active-holidays-ocean-swimming-popular-on-turkish-lycian-coast/106173770</link><description>There is no lounging by the pool for these travellers, who are spending a week swimming the remote waters of the Turkish Lycian coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f50bd5e400dc329dbb870202b6788d7b</guid></item><item><title>PM's possible pick to lead Bondi royal commission sparks pushback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/bondi-attack-royal-commission-albanese-pick-pushback/106209204</link><description>Anthony Albanese has been in talks about calling a Commonwealth royal commission into last month's attack, signalling to colleagues he is preparing to renege on his opposition to the idea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42ef15f840ee4889890b49e87d097982</guid></item><item><title>Wild mountain gorilla gives birth to twins in Virunga National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/gorilla-twins-born-virunga-national-park-drc-congo/106209406</link><description>A mountain gorilla named Mafuko gives birth to twins, a "rare and remarkable event", in Virunga National Park in the Democratic Republic of Congo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">998b170e96d5631d89a0dcba5830c535</guid></item><item><title>Lachie Neale given Lions' 'blessing' if he wants to return to Perth at end of 2026 AFL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/brisbane-lions-lachie-neale-chris-fagan/106210014</link><description>The Brisbane Lions will not stand in the way of Lachie Neale if the club's former co-captain chooses to return to Perth at the end of the season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">265443ee944d4f0969e173229e5bcc74</guid></item><item><title>Minnesota ICE shooting takes life of a legal observer, according to local representatives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/minneapolis-ice-shooting-inside-the-legal-observer-networks/106209032</link><description>As Donald Trump's immigration crackdown escalates in Minneapolis, networks of local residents patrol the streets too, warning of incoming ICE raids, documenting what happens and offering legal advice to those targeted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cf336bfbdefd534a2fa8318e8d340b4</guid></item><item><title>What led to an ICE agent fatally shooting a public observer in Minneapolis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/ice-shooting-minneapolis-minnesota-immigration-crackdown/106209128</link><description>The fatal shooting of a legal observer by an ICE agent in Minneapolis is the latest flashpoint in Donald Trump's crackdown on immigration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11849a2196d3508fa03e7f8c93c295ee</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja's fitting farewell, DRS drama and Marnus Labuschagne keeps things interesting — quick hits from day five of the SCG Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/quick-hits-scg-day-five-ashes-khawaja-marnus-labuschagne-run-out/106208590</link><description>The SCG celebrates a retiring hero and a rising star, tempers flair after another DRS debacle and Marnus mourns a horror run-out. Here are the quick hits from the final day of the 2025-26 Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77ca3d9cc1cfdef04cb23ba77b921608</guid></item><item><title>Summernats begins in Canberra as organisers brace for large crowds and heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/summernats-2026-begins-city-cruise-canberra/106209124</link><description>Australia’s biggest car festival roars to life amid a scorching heatwave, thrill-seeking crowds and strict policing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d109c5ccd9d8e4556b5f60b426db9d3</guid></item><item><title>Australia underlines its Ashes dominance of England to write its own story at the SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/australia-underlines-ashes-dominance-to-write-its-own-story/106209390</link><description>A 4-1 scoreline can leave no doubt, this has been an Ashes summer of dominance for a resilient Australian side and a tour of errors and mismanagement for England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">606001ce9ef51ebfbcdb879075270f38</guid></item><item><title>Lifting ban on developer donations could increase corruption risk, Queensland watchdog says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/qld-political-donation-ban-property-developers/106210392</link><description>Queensland's corruption watchdog has warned lifting a ban on political donations from developers could increase the risk of "actual or perceived" corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec8a36f9dc9f5bef9f5c83b607d43f0e</guid></item><item><title>Authors withdraw from Adelaide Writers' Week after Randa Abdel-Fattah axed for 'cultural sensitivity'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/randa-abdel-fattah-adelaide-writers-week-axed-authors-withdraw/106210464</link><description>After Randa Abdel-Fattah was dropped from Adelaide Writers' Week by the Adelaide Festival Board, a slew of authors, including Michelle de Kretser, have withdrawn from the event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbd24da619c619fbb5f6c152023696dd</guid></item><item><title>Former High Court justice Virginia Bell to lead Bondi royal commission</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/albanese-bell-royal-commission-antisemitism-bondi/106210052</link><description>A national royal commission into antisemitism and social cohesion has been called by Anthony Albanese after weeks of pressure to establish an inquiry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bafdd0d809232c7d5e25a141799792e</guid></item><item><title>Comiskey Group's 'eco-tourism' park approved for Coochin Creek</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/coochin-creek-tourist-park-approved/106209514</link><description>The state government approves a 150-site tourist park with 95 conditions despite ongoing environmental concerns from authorities and community groups.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5154da108b6229fb799dd8e46b791ef7</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka and Elena Rybakina march on to Brisbane International quarter-finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/sabalenka-rybakina-brisbane-international-third-round-pegula/106210594</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka and Elena Rybakina continue their 2026 campaigns in emphatic fashion with victories at the Brisbane International.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92ccba7ac40057a455324a9c01d15e3e</guid></item><item><title>Two-week chase ends in dramatic seizure of Russian-flagged oil tanker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/how-the-russia-flagged-marinera-oil-tanker-seizure-unfolded/106208808</link><description>When a US-sanctioned oil tanker originally bound for Venezuela abruptly changed course, it set off a dramatic chase at sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f9641191277ec55bb68a88279d678a9</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: PM announces antisemitism royal commission after Bondi terror attack — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/live-blog-albanese-antisemitism-royal-commission/106205802</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has announced a royal commission into antisemitism after the Bondi Beach terrorist attack</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94310421a68e882725eeea301656e2d8</guid></item><item><title>Three options the US is considering to take Greenland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/three-options-us-considering-to-take-greenland/106207610</link><description>At least three options have been floated for Donald Trump to achieve his goal of taking Greenland for the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3601b8c080e0918077e50115bc01c245</guid></item><item><title>Self defence or murder? What the videos of the Minnesota ICE shooting show us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/what-happened-in-minnesota-ice-shooting-abc-verify/106209188</link><description>ICE agents shot a woman in Minnesota. The president says it was self-defence while protesters claim it was murder. Here's what the vision shows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9039ec1dfeba5997c2b389a07fab6acf</guid></item><item><title>Loraine Braham, trailblazing Northern Territory politician dies, aged 87</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/loraine-braham-northern-territory-politician-dies-aged-87/106211014</link><description>Loraine Braham, a pioneering figure in Northern Territory politics and the first woman to serve as Speaker of the Legislative Assembly, has passed away aged 87 in Alice Springs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">624d4af3ac5b20e25157e59b8ee75467</guid></item><item><title>Ashes player ratings: England and Australia report card from 2025-26 Test series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/ashes-england-and-australia-player-report-card-grades-ratings/106208798</link><description>Here are the player ratings from a one-sided Ashes series with a few stand-outs and perhaps more flame-outs across the five Tests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">939d1f0d022317cea88e5225e6a8ace9</guid></item><item><title>New research finds keeping room temperature at 24 degrees or below could reduce sleep stress for older Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/study-room-temperature-24-degrees-reduces-sleep-stress-elderly/106210362</link><description>The study by Griffith University in Brisbane finds that a room temperature while sleeping of more than 24 degrees Celsius increases heart rate variability and physiological stress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b774992e996255b6e0f55a92360ad037</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106210068</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69e249fc81f420bec1c7f1dbb652f773</guid></item><item><title>No sightings of Kenneth John Giles 24 hours after shooting near Mullewa in WA's Midwest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/mullewa-shooting-manhunt-continues-kenneth-giles/106209978</link><description>Police have issued a "personal plea" for Kenneth John Giles to turn himself in, almost 24 hours after a shooting in Mullewa.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a30c947e66a941861dbed6d92e1c0c20</guid></item><item><title>What is a pyroCB, a fire-generated thunderstorm?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/what-is-a-pyrocb-a-fire-generated-thunderstorm/106210552</link><description>The fire burning in north-east Victoria near Walwa was so fierce it generated its own weather this afternoon, including a substantial pyrocumulonimbus cloud with lightning and thunder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5efce84e61a4f0c416252768757be9b7</guid></item><item><title>Tensions rise in Colombia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/tension-rises-in-colombia/106211572</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dfa6765f3cf91cb16400ecb7601c41b</guid></item><item><title>Police arrest suspects after armed heist at airport believed to be Vanuatu's first organised robbery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/vanuatu-robbery-port-vila-airport/106206412</link><description>A brazen heist at Port Vila International Airport has stunned Vanuatu and become the talk of a nation unused to such overtly public acts of crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c81aa2a1227df3ea9a7c5a1bee55281</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says US oversight of Venezuela could last for years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-08/trump-says-us-oversight-of-venezuela-could-last-for-years/106211978</link><description>Donald Trump has said that "only time will tell" how long the United States will maintain oversight of Venezuela.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">009a8a43f1559dbff27c6077658d7fa7</guid></item><item><title>England vice-captain Harry Brook apologises for incident at New Zealand nightclub ahead of Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/harry-brook-scuffle-with-bouncer-before-new-zealand-odi/106212164</link><description>Harry Brook was fined $60,000 and has apologised for bringing "embarrassment" to the English cricket team in a scuffle with a bouncer shortly before the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65a3318f02eab2896e6476d757307460</guid></item><item><title>Rinky Hijikata suffers three-set loss against Giovanni Mpetshi Perricard at Brisbane International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/hijikata-mpetshi-perricard-brisbane-international-quarter-finals/106212468</link><description>Rinky Hijikata's three-set loss to big-serving Frenchman Giovanni Mpetshi Perricard means there are no Australians left in the Brisbane International singles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56035a169d6797e540a548b6b3663643</guid></item><item><title>Three people missing in Longwood bushfire amid 'catastrophic' fire danger for Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/catastrophic-extreme-bushfire-warning-for-victoria/106211318</link><description>Three people, including a child, are missing after a house was destroyed by the out-of-control Longwood bushfire in central Victoria, according to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10d03171fbffff94b09273cddafc14a5</guid></item><item><title>Victorians on edge as state experiences first catastrophic bushfire conditions since 2019</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/vic-catastrophic-fire-warning-bushfires-fri-walwa-longwood/106210230</link><description>Catastrophic fire danger warnings are in place across parts of Victoria's north and west today, with two significant fires already burning out of control and soaring temperatures forecast on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b31bf8a8081eb882e61131b27dd456c</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave and fire threat forecast for NSW, Victoria and SA as temperatures nudge all-time record highs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/heatwave-fire-threat-peaking-as-temps-hit-record-high/106211144</link><description>Southern states continue to sweat through one of the most intense heatwaves on record, and for many regions, including Melbourne and Sydney, the hottest weather is still to come.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcf6161ee66e70f17cefb19ef9dab4fa</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 9: Hungry Adelaide protesters demand beef in violent riot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/today-in-history-january-9-adelaide-beef-riot-great-depression/106195250</link><description>During the Great Depression, Adelaide residents were getting hungrier and more desperate by the day. Then the state government made a wildly unpopular decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e048fb9b1abfe3f20b4d7d07290cb97d</guid></item><item><title>JD Vance defends Minnesota shooting as self-defence amid immigration crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/minneapolis-shooting-fbi-bca-blocked/106212576</link><description>US Vice-President JD Vance says the shooting was justified and that 37-year-old mother-of-three Renee Nicole Good was a "victim of left-wing ideology".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">937d425141ba4a896aa30c8a33c94d21</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's comments about Greenland were once seen as a joke. Greenlanders are no longer laughing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/donald-trump-greenland-denmark-nato-comments-worrying-island/106210090</link><description>The United States has a long history of wanting to acquire Greenland, but people living on the island say Donald Trump's latest comments about annexation feel different.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">780d9c1f5e1d18550bf80d207f6c5b10</guid></item><item><title>How the internet reacted to the fifth Ashes Test at the SCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/how-the-internet-reacted-to-the-fifth-ashes-test/106198770</link><description>The internet went wild as Australia dominated with the bat, led by Travis Head and Steve Smith, and England crumbled in the dying embers of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab73112ebb189dad0b2e311cb6ccdeb6</guid></item><item><title>Solar to the fore as grid sails through heatwave and record demand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/solar-powers-australia-through-heatwave-conditions/106211394</link><description>For so long, the pounding sunshine of an Australian heatwave was the grid's biggest threat. It has now become its greatest asset.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae701b0cb782c015f079002489ef8776</guid></item><item><title>US Senate votes to limit Trump's power to order strikes in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/senate-votes-to-limit-trump-war-powers/106212508</link><description>The vote in the Republican-controlled chamber still needs to pass the US House, and has virtually no chance of becoming law due to Donald Trump's presidential veto.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a5427cd6d6d5921804e7ab4c06fb178</guid></item><item><title>Australian heatwave: Firefighters battling multiple out-of-control blazes across Victoria — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/fire-weather-heatwave-live-blog-victoria-sa-nsw/106212116</link><description>Multiple out-of-control bushfires threaten dozens of towns in central and north-eastern Victoria, with hot temperatures and strong winds resulting in "catastrophic" fire conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcbd0376d084f9e59fa8783cce3c308c</guid></item><item><title>Insect enthusiasts helping researchers keep an eye on bug populations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/qld-bug-hunt-insects-photos-research-citizen-scientists/106171252</link><description>Queensland insect enthusiasts are snapping photos of their backyard bugs to help researchers monitor native and invasive species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4f7610e986e7cd15889efebe22c7a82</guid></item><item><title>Locals, summer tourists swelter through heatwave in South Australia's Riverland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/sa-riverland-heatwave-hot-weather-peak-tourist-season/106205990</link><description>South Australia's Riverland will swelter through yet another day in the mid-to-high 40s on Friday and will have to wait until the weekend for a reprieve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">156f32643cce0f3fd5034709d9ff285a</guid></item><item><title>'High chance' of a tropical cyclone forming off Queensland's north-east coast bringing heavy rainfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/tropical-low-to-hit-far-north-queensland-late-friday/106211562</link><description>A tropical low off the Coral Coast could have the potential to become a tropical cyclone over the weekend, as residents across the far-north prepare for heavy rainfall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c9c9b6e59e8b4ac8d3a9d52215e0ad6</guid></item><item><title>Maya Joint gets Ash Barty's backing with teenager's Australian Open milestone confirmed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/joint-gets-barty-s-backing-ahead-of-aus-open-seeding/106212664</link><description>Teenage star Maya Joint will be the first home women's seed at the Australian Open since former world number one Ash Barty broke a 44-year title drought in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54395c014b677d61b32bba59eed839b6</guid></item><item><title>RBA plays the long game on inflation, so an interest rate rise could still be some way off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/rba-deputy-governor-andrew-hauser-interest-rates-inflation-janda/106210128</link><description>The Reserve Bank says inflation is "too high", but that doesn't mean it will necessarily rush to raise interest rates next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">822c83de4d34fdbaba8bbaad3b53d3a5</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan and foreign prisoners to be released following seizure of Nicolás Maduro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/venezuela-prisoners-to-be-freed-after-us-seizure-of-maduro/106212566</link><description>The president of the country's parliament says that Venezuelan and foreign prisoners will be released in the coming hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">162dbf5e6813226eb49bca2ac138a569</guid></item><item><title>Matildas and Arsenal star Kyra Cooney-Cross returns home in wake of mother's cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/matildas-star-cooney-cross-returns-home-to-face-family-tragedy/106212710</link><description>Arsenal's Australia international Kyra Cooney-Cross flies back to Australia to be with her mother, who has been diagnosed with stage 4 cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">022d27429b844ff00f76299de5f2a1ab</guid></item><item><title>Dubbo woman Molly Croft raises $2 million after battling cancer twice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/molly-croft-raises-2m-and-helps-others-find-their-rainbow/106095998</link><description>This 19-year-old from western NSW, who has been diagnosed with cancer twice, is now helping others "find their rainbow".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7680560ded4679aff964bf9d7446d06</guid></item><item><title>NT pokies clubs report member perks, lavish upgrades as 'community' benefits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/nt-pokies-community-contributions-member-perks-renovations-foi/106084120</link><description>Previously secret documents released under Freedom of Information laws have revealed how the Northern Territory's pokies clubs' community contributions are really being spent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b956be26d539f0a576209395e5c2ce80</guid></item><item><title>Rio Tinto stock tumbles on Glencore merger talks, dragging down ASX — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/asx-markets-business-live-news-jan-2025-9/106212732</link><description>Glencore has confirmed media speculation that the company is back in merger talks with Rio Tinto. Follow updates live on our business and finance blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35335a243eed68ad82bd29a3257dc72c</guid></item><item><title>Top tips for learning a musical instrument or taking up singing at any age</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/top-tips-for-learning-a-musical-instrument-or-taking-up-singing/106206612</link><description>You can pick up an instrument or learn to sing at any age. Here are some helpful tips from experts and ABC Classic audience members to get you started.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b6a800c527cc85e14d26b021f88d536</guid></item><item><title>Airport lost luggage auctions raise thousands of dollars for charity every year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/airport-lost-luggage-auctions/106078890</link><description>From tablets, headphones and laptops to prams, vacuum cleaners and even a prosthetic leg — these are the items being left behind each year at major airports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79e782929d619129a68f7b9ecd8c8977</guid></item><item><title>Man in anaphylactic shock on Virgin flight to WA's Pilbara saved by crew, another passenger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/selfless-act-saves-man-anaphylactic-shock-on-wa-virgin-flight/106209770</link><description>Pilbara resident Andrew Rawle found himself 30,000 feet in the air, unable to breathe due to anaphylactic shock, but was saved by the crew and the selfless act of another passenger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07f2dd24254e8cf0a23a06e972a26c2e</guid></item><item><title>Total fire ban to begin in the ACT for the first time in six years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/total-fire-ban-heatwave-declared-act/106212734</link><description>For the first time since the Black Summer bushfires, a total fire ban will be imposed in the ACT. The ban will be in place for the duration of Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91a761ebca8181ace8fef1f22f568f31</guid></item><item><title>Angela Jones's history-making ride from country upbringing to top of Queensland's jockey ranks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/angela-jones-journey-to-becoming-number-one-jockey-in-queensland/106158424</link><description>Angela Jones became the number one jockey in Queensland in 2025. Now, the determined young woman, who grew up on a central Queensland cattle farm, wants Group 1 glory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61a9fab622749cc9f453903462200fc3</guid></item><item><title>How The Pitt lured ER star Noah Wyle back into the emergency department</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/the-pitt-noah-wyle-er-r-scott-gemmill-john-wells/106118716</link><description>ER launched Noah Wyle's career in 1994. Thirty years later he's back in the emergency room — and scooping awards season — as Dr Robby in The Pitt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93a195925d2de69fb82fd3317eb6f950</guid></item><item><title>NetBlocks reports internet blackout imposed in Iran amid nationwide protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/internet-blackout-imposed-in-iran-amid-nationwide-protests/106213246</link><description>Human rights groups say more than 40 people have been killed in protest-related violence since last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd286bff3887cc0397c214ae6c0c3596</guid></item><item><title>Arsenal's Gabriel Martinelli apologises for 'disgraceful' act towards injured Liverpool player Conor Bradley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/martinelli-disgraceful-act-towards-injured-liverpool-player/106213400</link><description>Arsenal winger Gabriel Martinelli has apologised for shoving Liverpool's Conor Bradley, who was down with a serious knee injury, off the pitch during their Premier League clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">249ee65a474fdfd5395e9aa04686c802</guid></item><item><title>Rio Tinto in merger talks with Glencore, takeover could create world's biggest miner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/rio-tinto-in-talks-to-take-over-glencore-mega-miner-merger/106213252</link><description>Rio Tinto and Glencore are in takeover talks that could potentially lead to a combined mega-miner worth more than $US200 billion. Analysts are questioning whether Rio will be interested in Glencore's coal assets, having sold off its own in 2018.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">045687aff3f78cbc211b52c08acfbb59</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios not seeking Australian Open wildcard, saying he is 'not quite ready' for grand slam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/kyrgios-says-he-will-not-be-seeking-an-aus-open-wildcard/106213610</link><description>Returning from injury, Nick Kyrgios has spoken with Australian Open organisers and made the call not to use a wildcard to play singles this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c307000e133452ec9eef5fba817b560</guid></item><item><title>What we know about Australian Teagan Croft who will play Rapunzel in Disney's Tangled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/teagan-croft-to-play-rapunzel-in-disney-live-action-tangled/106213672</link><description>Australian actress Teagan Croft will take on the lead role of Rapunzel in Disney's Tangled. The 21-year-old will star alongside Milo Manheim in the live-action remake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e23c5ae58eb08fde143d918add4210f3</guid></item><item><title>The Bondi royal commission will be a long-term test of Albanese's leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/bondi-royal-commission-test-albanese-leadership/106213854</link><description>The prime minister's critics feel he failed to meet the moment in the immediate aftermath of the Bondi attack, but with the royal commission he has a chance to get it right.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">916f58de1d1e77dad7bbbe9ffc85cf2e</guid></item><item><title>Australia's population forecast to reach 28 million in 2026 despite fall in overseas migrants</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/australias-population-to-reach-28-million-in-2026/106213420</link><description>Australia's population is forecast to reach 28 million people in 2026 despite an easing of overseas arrivals following the post-COVID-19 migration peak.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f16364694bdcb7d5d4f01791e0da9534</guid></item><item><title>Total fire ban as extreme fire weather predicted for parts of eastern Tasmania this weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/total-fire-ban-east-coast-tasmania-danger/106213058</link><description>A total fire ban is in place for parts of Tasmania from Saturday, due to extreme fire weather predicted for the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0a5b1a9a096c99d5594002934f18fd4</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian author seeks to be reinstated to Adelaide Writers' Week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/sa-palestinian-author-calls-for-apology-over-writers-week-axing/106212878</link><description>Palestinian author Randa Abdel-Fattah has called for her appearance at Adelaide Writers' Week to be reinstated after it was axed, but SA's Premier has continued to back the decision, as dozens of authors cancel their appearances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bc84d20ac7f6de4042f859ef7f45602</guid></item><item><title>Grass fire burning in Wagga Wagga's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/grass-fire-burning-in-wagga-wagga-s-north/106214436</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b8856016b4a7c28344bcad2ae7feab4</guid></item><item><title>Surge in heat-related illness as temperatures continue to soar across south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/heat-illness-emergency-presentations-surge-heatwave/106213074</link><description>Emergency departments, medical centres and first responders are dealing with a surge in heat-related illness across Australia's south-east as temperatures soar to near record levels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b871b12491bc4d2dc8eaf82577c10a1</guid></item><item><title>Zone RV director accused of insolvent trading as early as 2023</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/zone-rv-insolvent-trading-creditors-report/106206468</link><description>Administrators of the collapsed luxury caravan manufacturer have threatened to sue David Biggar, whose company owes customers millions of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b78bc029fd01690b692b25691ea15cac</guid></item><item><title>Senior SA government officials reject claims of political interference into algal bloom causes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/sa-department-heads-reject-interference-claims-in-algal-bloom/106213376</link><description>Four of the most senior public servants working on South Australia's algal bloom have rejected allegations that departmental staff had been instructed not to investigate the cause of the ecological disaster until after March's state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">870976f9925aebd0a33e7f1bc1020da3</guid></item><item><title>Russia says it has fired its Oreshnik hypersonic missile at Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/russia-says-it-hit-ukraine-with-oreshnik-hypersonic-missile/106214842</link><description>A "massive" Russian night-time attack on Ukraine damaged 20 residential buildings in Kyiv and its suburbs, as well as Qatar's embassy, President Volodymyr Zelenskyy says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a8f4739db2dad29330326f7b3195830</guid></item><item><title>Ruffy residents describe devastation wrought by central Victoria's Longwood bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/ruffy-residents-describe-devastation-after-longwood-bushfire/106214024</link><description>During winter the trees and hills surrounding the small hamlet of Ruffy are beautiful and green, but now it has been "decimated" by an out-of-control bushfire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91f86b02b839c5bc83a16621b222b9da</guid></item><item><title>NSW premier 'cannot remember' fundraiser at centre of undeclared donation allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/nsw-chris-minns-responds-to-undeclared-donation-allegations/106213922</link><description>Premier Chris Minns did not dispute a report that 200 people attended a fundraiser dinner, but could not recall how an event of that size raised only about $6,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd496ac70a1c6e73ae9ad81456624a2d</guid></item><item><title>Police say alleged Mullewa shooter Kenneth Giles was not a licensed firearms owner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/kenneth-john-giles-mullewa-manhunt-police-update/106211998</link><description>Police say Kenneth Giles is not a licensed firearms holder, as the search for the 58-year-old continues across hundreds of thousands of kilometres of country WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41f19560ddd43979eeb6e959364495f0</guid></item><item><title>Accused scam kingpin Chen Zhi arrives in China after extradition from Cambodia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/accused-scam-kingpin-chen-zhi-extradited-china-cambodia/106213664</link><description>Accused scam boss Chen Zhi is extradited to China from Cambodia after being indicted by the United States over an alleged multi-billion-dollar fraud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">648a0ad4bdb7733943e6779b95d8d539</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/fins-financefri-090126/106215310</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8160784fdd2d14e6759eba9d94f19c14</guid></item><item><title>Philippines landfill collapse kills at least one person with dozens missing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/philippines-landfill-collapse/106215352</link><description>Rescuers managed to recover 13 people from the site overnight as efforts continue to try and find others trapped under the mountain of rubbish.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3337e38a952da9b0115befccbd54324</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters continue to battle multiple out-of-control blazes across Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/bushfires-victoria-homes-razed-people-missing/106214638</link><description>Three people who had been reported missing have been located and Victoria's premier has declared a state of disaster as fast-moving bushfires threaten dozens of towns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7d4864d07ae5d2799ef75cb49e29241</guid></item><item><title>Iranian leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei defiant amid growing nationwide protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/iranian-leader-defiant-amid-nationwide-protests/106215570</link><description>Iran's supreme leader Ayatollah Ali Khamenei has remained defiant amid nationwide protests, saying his regime would not back down in the "face of saboteurs."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7824ad9e3d4314266df80acbf92fb3f4</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 10: The Sopranos changes television forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/the-sopranos-first-episode-aired-january-10/106184120</link><description>Restaurant owners in New York would eventually complain of "the Soprano effect" when they lost trade on Sunday nights as patrons headed home to watch the show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffcb2a4fb64b3420356a8e83d5d0d0e0</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump is reshaping American power and the threat to international order is alarming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/trump-power-venezuela-greenland-international-law-morality/106214406</link><description>There have been plenty of examples of the Trump administration's contempt for legalities, diplomacy and alliances, but this week Trump and his lieutenants went further.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c22187d11c5335ce0bf87ef3d56a102</guid></item><item><title>Elon Musk's AI bot says it is limiting its ability to 'undress' users. Australians want an opt-out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/grok-ai-undressing-australia-women-children/106213644</link><description>For more than a week, X's AI bot Grok has been generating sexual images of women and children at the request of other users, even when they ask it not to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22ff953eef024151d04f32634fee90bd</guid></item><item><title>Cautious hopes Beijing lifting soft ban on South Korean pop culture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/china-ban-south-korean-pop-culture-could-lift-amid-warmer-ties/106205780</link><description>China has restricted access to South Korean pop culture since 2016, when Seoul received US anti-missile technology. Warmer bilateral ties are spurring optimism that will change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ba4fe5aa1d0f4321bc3f7f578639c8b</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave and extreme weather: Bushfire disaster in Vic; threat rises in NSW; cyclone forms in Qld — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/state-of-disaster-declared-bushfires-victoria/106215462</link><description>Out-of-control bushfires are continuing to rip through Victoria with at least 130 homes and buildings across the state lost and more than 300,000 hectares of land burned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4531b20bfb843f3cd9dc55a9cbfc4ffd</guid></item><item><title>Barmy Army turns Ashes defeat into Australian tourism win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/barmy-army-australia-cricket-england-ashes-tourism/106214260</link><description>The Barmy Army has continued the recent trend of UK travellers spending more time and money in Australia, despite a disappointing on-field performance from their side.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0e0cdaaf5650b5241200515e45b1db6</guid></item><item><title>NSW SES moves to embrace 'volunteers for a day' to boost members after May 2025 floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/nsw-ses-embraces-spontaneous-volunteering-from-mud-armies/106148252</link><description>Experts say volunteering is not in decline, but it is becoming more spontaneous. The NSW disaster agency is moving to embrace this after seven women mobilised 1,200 people to volunteer for a day in record-breaking floods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ec15e7a123bbf5e95ce4ac5c8fcc385</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave in southern states one of the most intense on record as Queensland braces for cyclone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/australia-weather-weekend-fire-threat-nsw-possible-cyclone-qld/106214346</link><description>The heatwave, which has engulfed southern Australia this week, has become one of the most intense on record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58204e4bff379826f49c6ba8cd360331</guid></item><item><title>BOM declares Cyclone Koji as category two system off north Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/queensland-tropical-low-expected-to-intensify-into-cyclone-koji/106213662</link><description>North Queensland residents are readying themselves as a category two cyclone moves towards them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31ff50af30cc18bf007aa03d6532275f</guid></item><item><title>The daily struggle continues in Caracas as Venezuelans dare to hope for change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/inside-venezuela-daily-struggle-continues-in-caracas/106215776</link><description>The ABC hears from residents of Venezuela's capital, Caracas, about the struggles of daily life and their hopes and fears after American intervention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46481d872f8a29319917daa1f987ff21</guid></item><item><title>The King of Rock and Roll transcends language and culture at the Parkes Elvis Festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/parkes-elvis-festival-toki-toyokazu-singing/106209036</link><description>Japanese tribute artist Toki Toyokazu is part of a growing international presence at the annual Parkes Elvis Festival, which also includes women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10fce8d3fb0882e55de283e43848800a</guid></item><item><title>Australia loses to Poland 2-1 in United Cup quarterfinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/united-cup-australia-loses-to-poland-in-quarterfinals/106215862</link><description>Alex de Minaur produces a signature tenacious display, but it is not enough to send Australia through to the United Cup semifinals in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be2d9f482580407d8766b7a4a3016264</guid></item><item><title>Talc Alf's carved artworks attract tourists travelling the Strzelecki Track in outback SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/talf-alc-art-gallery-off-strzelecki-track-in-outback-sa/106215944</link><description>Off the Strzelecki Track in outback South Australia lies the gallery of Alf Talc, so named for the artworks he carves out of soft, powdery talc.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df41f2abeace4c13f0d72aa4071eaece</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka defeats Madison Keys in Australian Open final re-match at Brisbane International</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/brisbane-international-aryna-sabalenka-defeats-madison-keys/106215886</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka says she is no longer thinking about last year's Australian Open final loss to Madison Keys after defeating the US star at the Brisbane International.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8180e2dc6d360a3580a056c9b69885ba</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of protesters gather in the streets of Tehran</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/thousands-of-protesters-gather-in-the-streets-of-tehran-/106215926</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da8bb09418c81a8759b9950ffcf2784b</guid></item><item><title>Wildlife ACT calls for more volunteers as demand soars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/behind-the-scenes-wildlife-carer-need-for-more-volunteers/106197866</link><description>There are about 40-50 active volunteer carers within ACT Wildlife, but the organisation says more are needed, especially as the temperature soars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f5a4332242278a963a96a5f5349515f</guid></item><item><title>Gladstone company taking centre stage in AI revolution, providing a critical mineral to cool computer chips</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/alpha-hpa-gladstone-high-purity-alumina-ai/106213676</link><description>The industrial hub is playing a key role in the AI industry as it pumps out a critical material needed to cool high-performance computer chips.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d9c1e88cea4d8966d5dcf9a4a5eddaa</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of alcohol products still without 'mandatory' pregnancy warnings, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/mums-drank-pregnancy-alcohol-warning-labels/106154908</link><description>New research shows thousands of alcohol products remain on Australian shelves without mandated pregnancy warning labels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4783e5564f11c66b51e1823883c1fc40</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island plastics pollution battle for turtles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/christmas-island-turtles-battle-plastic-pollution/106092234</link><description>A beach on a remote island, and home to nesting turtles, is annually overwhelmed by tonnes of plastic garbage. Christmas Island is doing what it can to help stem the never-ending tide of pollution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d3dcc3dcbe6121099810921fa255ce7</guid></item><item><title>NT town of Katherine home of Australia's best tasting tap water, nine years after PFAS detected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/katherine-pfas-australia-best-drinking-water/106184842</link><description>The tap water in the Northern Territory town of Katherine — which includes a "designer" mix of river water from the world-famous Nitmiluk National Park and mineral-rich groundwater — has been named Australia's best drop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">261a9a94bd6f12376ce7733c8591bf93</guid></item><item><title>New angle of moment woman shot by ICE agent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/new-angle-of-moment-woman-shot-by-ice-agent/106216104</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5343a72d71c36f3f4bff43a3c1efb1f</guid></item><item><title>New video emerges of ICE agent shooting Renee Nicole Good in Minneapolis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/new-video-shows-renee-good-shooting-ice-agent/106216052</link><description>The new footage, reposted by the White House on social media, shows the recording made by the agent responsible for the shooting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82569c5ee3cb9b43c0d81e97092b0ab9</guid></item><item><title>Coronial inquest into death of Indigenous woman identifies 'chain of failures' at Royal Darwin Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/nt-inquest-indigenous-woman-died-at-royal-darwin-hospital-rdh/106214552</link><description>The Northern Territory coroner has determined a series of human errors contributed to the 2022 death of an Indigenous woman at Royal Darwin Hospital, in the weeks after she sought a routine surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f42a17b1714b5d0d3ff6fc9d137f0e5</guid></item><item><title>History made as first woman Erin Tassell in emergency management role in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/erin-tassell-first-woman-in-fire-management-role/106214424</link><description>Behind every emergency in WA, from bushfires to whale rescues, a state duty officer is making critical decisions. New hire Erin Tassell is breaking new ground in a key government department.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6730a74e0ac97e410d1f9480fd22cfb</guid></item><item><title>Hollywood-backed Wrexham knocks Nottingham Forest out of FA Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/fa-cup-wrexham-beats-nottingham-forest-on-penalties/106216130</link><description>As actor and co-owner Ryan Reynolds watched on in the grandstand, Wrexham defeated Nottingham Forest on penalties to advance to the fourth round of the FA Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91bb5ae037795ce58b925a93a6f7f216</guid></item><item><title>Farmlands burn across Alexandra, Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/farmlands-burn-across-alexandra-victoria-/106216384</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b4b00b5df0c8569235cba051a3e411</guid></item><item><title>Scaled-down race cars, a few nerves and a tight-knit community at Narrogin speedway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/young-people-get-behind-wheel-of-race-cars-at-narrogin-speedway/106188714</link><description>A long-running project in the WA town of Narrogin gives young people the opportunity to get behind the wheel of race cars. Organisers say it is about more than just racing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">461f71dc0cafdc6667532c6c3939b30b</guid></item><item><title>NSW bakes through temperatures above 40 degrees as fire crews successfully contain blazes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/fire-danger-heatwave-winds-expected-across-nsw/106215426</link><description>Scorching temperatures lingered late into Saturday across NSW with the hottest place in the state's far west recording 44.6 degrees Celsius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b231cedc2fe401167227036f94b22b8e</guid></item><item><title>Trump tells oil executives Venezuela is 'open for business'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/trump-tells-oil-executives-venezuela-is-open-for-business-/106216412</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">334da6ddf305874670f9f9f64ad542f0</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says oil executives will have 'total safety' if they invest in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/donald-trump-calls-on-oil-executives-to-invest-in-venezuela/106216060</link><description>The US president has pivoted to portraying capturing former Venezuelan leader Nicolás Maduro as as a new-found economic opportunity for the US, seizing tankers carrying Venezuelan oil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dc2fcdae1c71862418dd85affd8a742</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's bushfires spread as two blazes burn out of control in Otways</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/bushfires-victoria-otways-harcourt-ravenswood-evacuation-orders/106216316</link><description>Fires in the Otway National Park are moving towards the town border of Colac, as firefighters continue to battle blazes across the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1eb719b39b488ae1230329f141585bab</guid></item><item><title>Marta Kostyuk crushes Jessica Pegula, Aryna Sabalenka powers past Karolína Muchová to reach Brisbane International final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/brisbane-international-semi-finals/106216472</link><description>Marta Kostyuk crushed world number six Jessica Pegula in less than an hour after Aryna Sabalenka powered past Karolína Muchová to reach a third consecutive Brisbane International final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e10e795e41fdde9877e558423899e1fc</guid></item><item><title>Australia will join G7 countries to discuss critical minerals in Washington next week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/australia-india-invited-to-g7-meeting-on-critical-minerals/106216434</link><description>India was also invited to attend the meeting, but it is unclear if it has accepted the invitation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5033c9e681d0a3e4dbd6b5122cd4832d</guid></item><item><title>Animals at Symbio Wildlife Park beating the heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/animals-at-symbio-wildlife-park-beating-the-heat/106216626</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dcbe6404c6ecf469ff1d372ddc74ebe</guid></item><item><title>Ravenswood local 'Catman' shares heartbreak after 'catastrophic' bushfire damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/ravenswood-bushfire-catman-damage/106216450</link><description>Approximately 50 structures have so far been destroyed in the Ravenswood and Harcourt bushfire, according to emergency services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1cab92c8e442ba1104092044e5fd339</guid></item><item><title>Video shows fire damage and spread in the Ravenswood-Harcourt fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/fire-damage-at-harcourt/106216668</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85ede2102be24b61a7ecac9f5c46a595</guid></item><item><title>Suspected copper thieves cut telecommunications to thousands in cyclone warning zone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/north-queensland-copper-thieves-cut-phone-internet-services/106216478</link><description>Thousands of North Queensland residents within a cyclone warning zone were without telecommunications services after suspected copper thieves cut cables.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc818474e3acca89ab765338c03368cc</guid></item><item><title>Former Adelaide Festival leaders pressure board to reinstate Palestinian author</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/adelaide-writers-week-board-letter/106216140</link><description>Nearly a dozen former leaders of the Adelaide Festival are calling for Randa Abdel-Fattah to be reinvited to Writers' Week, adding to a mounting crisis over the Palestinian-Australian author's exclusion from the literary festival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">419d86892f36312376cb6d948b7d5fd7</guid></item><item><title>Harcourt residents assessing damage after more than 50 structures lost in Ravenswood fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/harcourt-residents-assessing-fire-damage-50-structures-destroyed/106216128</link><description>Harcourt residents describe their devastation and gratitude in the wake of a massive blaze that swept through the town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41a20d508de1332022c43cad5ffab3d8</guid></item><item><title>Jakara Anthony wins gold, Matt Graham silver at Val Saint-Côme World Cup moguls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/jakara-anthony-wins-val-st-come-moguls-gold-matt-graham-silver/106216564</link><description>Jakara Anthony and Matt Graham both move to the top of the overall FIS Moguls World Cup standings with success at Val Saint-Côme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc6737a14624333a7254e0de0bc51b8c</guid></item><item><title>Scenes of destruction in Natimuk after Grass Flat fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/scenes-of-destruction-in-natimuk-after-grass-flat-fire/106216792</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8d99457fc813ac3e502a7f2e1f38727</guid></item><item><title>1964 ABC News report about Australia's cigarette habit and efforts to curtail the hugely lucrative tobacco industry.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/abc-news-report/106214418</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fd470326da86f22844c2a7e437e47a2</guid></item><item><title>RFS vision of bushfire burning at Brassknocker Firetrail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/rfs-vision-of-bushfire-burning-at-brassknocker-firetrail/106216834</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db8e70a5e4f29cb1266090a8566c5c8b</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Koji tracker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/tropical-cyclone-koji-tracker-north-queensland/106213640</link><description>Track the path of ex-Tropical Cyclone Koji and monitor wind speeds as the system makes landfall in northern Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e01cb181b9fdc2ab038764eefe8a0ef3</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja stars as Brisbane Heat beat Sydney Thunder in Big Bash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-10/bbl-brisbane-heat-beat-sydney-thunder-usman-khawaja-stars/106217066</link><description>Usman Khawaja's international career may be over, but he showed he is far from a spent force by stroking a fine 78 to help the Brisbane Heat to a BBL victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c207ff6a675044a194a5ef775cf96b0a</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, January 11: Smoking link to cancer announced in groundbreaking report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/today-in-history-january-11-smoking-cancer-link-/106185276</link><description>In 1964, a major scientific report laid bare the deadly risks of smoking, at a time when the tobacco industry had a stronghold on the public and government coffers. Delve into the ABC Archives to discover how Australians reacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f3b760fbe172c75b58503d89275571c</guid></item><item><title>Eloise Worledge was snatched from her bed. 50 years on her aunt is still looking for answers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/eloise-worledge-disappearance-50-anniversary-beaumaris/106207002</link><description>Fifty years after Beaumaris schoolgirl Eloise Worledge vanished, could new leads solve one of Australia's most haunting cold cases?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf4ad851f0d548a04588c6372c65d5a5</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open quiz: Can you get through this round in straight sets?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/australian-open-quiz/106213602</link><description>Take the covers off centre court! It's Australian Open time again. How well do you remember grand slams past?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a690bc29611ee04f1908e393963045b6</guid></item><item><title>Natimuk community counting its losses from fast-moving Victorian fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/natimuk-township-loses-structures-homes-from-victoria-fire/106216288</link><description>Residents of the township of Natimuk, population 500, have returned to find homes and businesses gone, but say its community spirit will shine brighter than ever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">394f62682a9f1d62c5eb528f785db0e3</guid></item><item><title>Has Trump landed a dud with his Venezuelan oil play?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/has-trump-landed-a-dud-with-his-venezuelan-oil-play/106214900</link><description>While debate rages over the legality and the potential fallout from America's incursion, there's been a quiet acceptance that it is all about oil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c33d1561d445544b079145ddf3e5d257</guid></item><item><title>Albanese and Allan unveil $19.5 million support package as crews take stock of Victorian fire devastation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/bushfires-victoria-longwood-otways-walwa/106216856</link><description>Anthony Albanese and Jacinta Allan announce a multi-million-dollar emergency relief package for those affected by Victoria's devastating bushfires, as authorities warn hundreds of structures have been lost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e3e9e246e6c576c1c48b9911fa8cd42</guid></item><item><title>Former members of Two by Twos call for financial transparency to access abuse compensation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/two-by-twos-christian-sect-child-sex-abuse-compensation-redress/106160220</link><description>Survivors of a secretive Christian sect, under investigation by the FBI, say it is hiding wealth through trusts, blocking access to abuse compensation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53db6860c0bfae7962745fe7350af472</guid></item><item><title>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Koji crosses north Queensland coast south of Ayr bringing intense rainfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/cyclone-koji-north-queensland-coast-warnings-flood/106216534</link><description>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Koji has crossed the north Queensland coast between the towns of Ayr and Bowen and has weakened into a tropical low pressure system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb9b746ab0173635b582a95ac5c4a288</guid></item><item><title>Heatwave live updates: Bushfire disaster in Victoria as Australia braces for more heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/bushfires-victoria-nsw-heatwave-live-coverage/106217152</link><description>Victoria Police say human remains have been found about 100 metres from a car along a fire-ravaged road in the Longwood bushfire area, near the central Victorian town of Seymour. Follow live</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acb9c066d8210639d9c8ba8dd9319e36</guid></item><item><title>From Madonna to Metallica, these are the big albums turning 40 this year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/1986-albums-turning-40/106186462</link><description>Pop and MTV ruled supreme but 1986 was also a banner year for hip hop and metal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05306a3fa6e1d11e44c9247761024678</guid></item><item><title>Endangered animal populations bounce back on Kangaroo Island thanks to predator-proof fence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/kangaroo-island-native-animal-populations-bounce-back/106209894</link><description>Five years after feral cats were removed from inside the Western River Refuge on Kangaroo Island, populations of endangered species have boomed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ed4f14a274779c62d099d330ae29b52</guid></item><item><title>Fr Oche singing Lord's Prayer in church</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/fr-oche-singing-lord-s-prayer-in-church/106211280</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89b5f0a8167a901d2053f0a42db401a5</guid></item><item><title>Fr Oche Matutina, performing with rock band Yellowbelly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/fr-oche-matutina-performing-with-rock-band/106211472</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d5009401fa73845313d13739dbf3b83</guid></item><item><title>Catholic priest swaps sermons for rock 'n' roll guitar solos in the Australian outback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/indonesian-catholic-priest-swaps-sermons-for-rock-n-roll/106096618</link><description>An Indonesian priest brings a deep love of rock 'n' roll to his pastoral care in western NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d84d083c89e34414fa2cbae127dec1a1</guid></item><item><title>NSW community bands hit hard as association misses out on vital government funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/nsw-community-bands-lose-government-funding/106196730</link><description>Wollongong’s collective of brass and wind bands have been putting on a show for locals for almost a century, but it is one of dozens of community bands across the state that faces an uncertain future due to a recent loss of funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fa89331aaf2258eff5338749a99d08e</guid></item><item><title>Suspect charged after six killed including seven-year-old girl in Mississippi shootings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/mississippi-shootings-leave-family-members-dead/106217418</link><description>A man is charged with murder after six people from the same family were killed in a series of shootings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5309a00fa4dc86c4e9ba2845bddc11bf</guid></item><item><title>The bombs in Afghanistan have stopped but its people now live under Taliban decrees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/life-for-women-and-girls-under-taliban-rule/106115402</link><description>Four years after the Taliban's return to power, security is no longer the defining issue in Afghanistan. Instead, one of the world's worst humanitarian crises is exacerbated by a series of overlapping disasters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d47b8de2f390cfaa84ce90c8187ccef</guid></item><item><title>How the 'Barbie' and 'ski-slope' nose trend is sweeping social media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/barbie-nose-trend-social-media/105967608</link><description>Tiny, sloped rhinoplasties are dominating pop culture. But some plastic surgery experts say "trend-associated" procedures like these are a concern.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99bd0ab51f30db7ff059bbc4ff82acc9</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Bree Walker claims World Cup monobob victory ahead of Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/world-cup-monobob-bree-walker-australia-wins-gold/106217414</link><description>With the Winter Olympics on the horizon, Bree Walker proves she is among the medal favourites in the monobob with a World Cup victory in Switzerland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84e8862d0672515637f26584a6b46c59</guid></item><item><title>Can spin bowling survive in pace-obsessed Australia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/future-of-spin-bowling-in-australian-cricket/106213212</link><description>After an Ashes series dominated by pace bowlers, what does the future hold for young spinners wanting to play Test cricket for Australia?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7d50c175dee070bd0124853f6491eaa</guid></item><item><title>Coco Gauff beats Iga Świątek but Poland advances to United Cup final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/united-cup-tennis-gauff-swiatek-us-poland/106217432</link><description>Coco Gauff gets on top of Iga Świątek ahead of the Australian Open, but the US star fails to stop Poland from reaching the United Cup final in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8241c7ff1abc94b0bf1fa4ed4bfaf6d4</guid></item><item><title>Floodwaters from Queensland bring life to remote NSW wetland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/floodwater-brings-narriearra-caryapundy-swamp-to-life/106136450</link><description>In a remote and isolated part of NSW, nature is enjoying a deluge of water still around from floods in Queensland last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cd922e8927464df3ee2214f5d28a73b</guid></item><item><title>Mystery grips small village of Ross after 'priceless' wool trophy stolen in museum heist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/stolen-zegna-wool-trophy-in-ross/106202202</link><description>For years, a prestigious trophy that represented Australia's ties to Italian high fashion took pride of place in a Tasmanian museum. But it is now missing after a 'targeted' overnight robbery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46871c8eb590cdcf83db5638c1b140ec</guid></item><item><title>Arsenal comes out in support of Kyra Cooney-Cross in wake of mother's cancer diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/arsenal-shows-support-for-kyra-cooney-cross/106217464</link><description>Arsenal players and supporters pay emotional tributes to Matildas star Kyra Cooney-Cross following her return to Australia to be with her mother, who has been diagnosed with cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cd8e980134097674a6aa51baa58a92a</guid></item><item><title>Search for alleged Mullewa gunman Kenneth Giles enters fifth day in WA's Midwest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/search-continues-for-alleged-mullewa-gunman-kenneth-john-giles/106215306</link><description>A search and rescue specialist details the significant hurdles faced by police as the manhunt for an alleged gunman in Western Australia's Midwest enters its fifth day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c333d9479bf292016497072d717ae7a3</guid></item><item><title>Australia wins World Cross Country Championships relay gold after Jessica Hull's anchor leg</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/australia-wins-cross-country-gold-medal-mixed-relay/106217508</link><description>Olympic medallist Jessica Hull guides Australia home in the mixed relay event at the world titles in Florida.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a06bfe83793d80a6ae82ba788f25bd13</guid></item><item><title>Middle Island underwater observatory once a star attraction for Great Keppel Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/great-keppel-island-underwater-observatory-star-attraction/105282860</link><description>It was once a star attraction alongside Great Keppel Island, with hundreds of tourists daily in the 80s and 90s, but these days snorkellers and fish are the only visitors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ec691adcfad7a9c65242cf297b16d68</guid></item><item><title>Tennis racquet stringer numbers take a hit in Australia while tournaments grow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/tennis-racquet-stringer-numbers-take-a-hit/106158244</link><description>Behind the scenes of the world's most elite tennis tournaments there is a team of people working on keeping the majors' racquets well strung.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e19b85d4afa7ebee66e1230d98b7492</guid></item><item><title>Regional healthcare disparities leaving lipoedema patients without adequate care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/lack-of-services-leaving-nt-lipoedema-patient-without-care/106187588</link><description>Women with lipoedema in the Northern Territory are struggling to access the care they need, forcing some to relocate for specialist treatment. The condition, often misunderstood, requires better medical support in regional Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cf3f553788b7739e7792aca653b52f5</guid></item><item><title>WA towns plan for 'overtourism' amid concerns attractions could become overcrowded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/busy-beaches-southern-wa/106211286</link><description>As WA's tourist towns experience an influx of summer visitors, some locals are worried their hometowns could become too crowded unless visitor numbers are controlled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82f776e2dfd9f857fd63cfc53fac3963</guid></item><item><title>Rodeo up-and-comers backed by veterans to make it on world stage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/youth-rodeo-mentoring-western-australia-cowboys-cowgirls/106014112</link><description>WA's brightest cowboys and cowgirls are being flown across the world to learn from champions of the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dca903a8a77ff22c1b3aad753210fc6b</guid></item><item><title>Large boat washes up at Bowen during Tropical Cyclone Koji</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/boat-rocks-bowen-cyclone-koji/106217574</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cbf6e495d485442dfb6d2e985c498ba</guid></item><item><title>Live updates: Ex-Tropical Cyclone Koji makes landfall in north Queensland, bringing heavy rain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/live-updates-tropical-cyclone-koji-north-queensland-bom/106212666</link><description>Ex-Tropical Cyclone Koji makes landfall in north Queensland as a tropical low, bringing heavy rain and damaging winds. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba89a60b104db62b9220c65fb7c39898</guid></item><item><title>Bob Weir, founding member of American rock band the Grateful Dead, dies aged 78</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/grateful-dead-founding-member-bob-weir-dies-at-78/106217686</link><description>Bob Weir's death was announced on Saturday in a statement on his Instagram page.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b178e464044d0565ff4d6653adda88c2</guid></item><item><title>Macclesfield beats FA Cup champion Crystal Palace 2-1 in major upset</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/fa-cup-champions-crystal-place-beaten-by-macclesfield/106217706</link><description>Non-league Macclesfield delivers one of the biggest upsets in FA Cup history by stunning defending champion Crystal Palace 2-1.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">278b23bc335caf167a6d70d2d9d5725d</guid></item><item><title>Thousands in US protest against ICE after fatal shooting of Renee Nicole Good</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/anti-ice-protesters-gather-around-the-us/106217540</link><description>The protests come after Renee Nicole Good was fatally shot by an immigration officer in Minneapolis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2853bc38e9c2a54fdfe435a02540edbb</guid></item><item><title>ABC reporter Jasmine Hines in north Queensland as ex-Tropical Cyclone Koji moves inland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/abc-reporter-update-from-north-queensland/106217852</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f26d6d82b4bc06097b59732b178bfc95</guid></item><item><title>Will meets Rascal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/will-meets-rascal/106134740</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">446fe9d60a3565e73974bdd9afe4b158</guid></item><item><title>Puppies of Muster Dogs champion find homes with next generation of farmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/muster-dogs-next-generation/106076694</link><description>In small towns scattered around Australia, five kids have hit the jackpot. They've each been given a puppy from a champion muster dog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6215e769acfa2f5006fc31c26bf83f23</guid></item><item><title>Boats run aground off Airlie Beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/boats-run-aground-airlie-beach/106217808</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d469729d44475ce06c4cee23977d2503</guid></item><item><title>Iranian protesters chant anti-government messages as authorities signal intensifying crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/iran-protesters-chant-anti-government-messages/106217578</link><description>Anti-government chants filled the streets of Iran's capital on Saturday night, as protesters pressed the biggest movement against the Islamic republic's rulers in more than three years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7db66be9c7bee782fc67cefaef55938a</guid></item><item><title>Tracking map of ex-cyclone Koji up until next weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/tracking-map-of-ex-cyclone-koji-up-until-next-weekend/106217888</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">534a9a0f57d41ac81bd1dc940bf5c9e7</guid></item><item><title>Destruction after bushfire in Harcourt, Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/destruction-after-bushfire-in-harcourt-victoria/106217892</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">010754ec10522854911105f298f54fbd</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters battle out-of-control bushfires in Victoria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/firefighters-battle-out-of-control-bushfires-in-victoria/106217788</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da520f9bf493f5b846a70fcd391d8af9</guid></item><item><title>Water gushing near Finch Hatton outside Mackay after Cyclone Koji</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/water-gushing-finch-hatton-tc-koji/106218012</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">392a41934287cc1c6f7358383bcc021d</guid></item><item><title>Rowing machine comes to life in Mackay during Cyclone Koji</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/rowing-machine-mackay-tc-koji/106217950</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e526cf0e0411ff39f21ee6728eb9f481</guid></item><item><title>Tahinlee and Bec Eden were at their home in Cannonvale when the system crossed.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/airlie-beach-vox-pops-after-ex-cyclone-koji/106218072</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e75b3f21d0f2f3719b5372f1b339cf2</guid></item><item><title>Locals in Acheron fighting the fire surrounding the Irvine's property.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/acheron/106217828</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0497da436d434d7f43b087b1bd2db025</guid></item><item><title>Family saves Acheron home after Longwood fire encircles property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/acheron-longwood-fire-locals-save-family-home/106217756</link><description>Everywhere you look around the Irvines' farm near Alexandra are signs of the fire that surrounded their home and burnt right up to the front porch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d13a19daef4d01956b938f4221cce743</guid></item><item><title>Sebastien Massart was on his catamaran at Airlie's Coral Sea Marina, when the system made landfall.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/locals-endure-ex-tropical-cyclone-koji-on-catamaran/106218068</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db6f37802c9cf5ce104a3945973874ff</guid></item><item><title>Aftermath of bushfire in Victoria’s Central Highlands</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/aftermath-of-bushfire-in-victoria-s-central-highlands-/106218114</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ce6e6ca4d68aec2809c4d2ba3abb2b0</guid></item><item><title>Planes drop fire retardant ahead of Walwa bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/planes-drop-fire-retardant-ahead-of-walwa-bushfire/106218120</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ba29b3dcd47430460aca3a0b36156a4</guid></item><item><title>Australia's biggest car festival wraps up in Canberra with record cars, revheads and a police probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/summernats-car-festival-ends/106217896</link><description>Australia's largest car festival draws to a close in Canberra, with record cars, championship wins, and a brawl that police are investigating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5aef3c8cba2834e3855e0b05acbfc52e</guid></item><item><title>Shaun Tan's Tales from Outer Suburbia, now adapted for TV, shows the magic of the everyday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/shaun-tan-tales-from-outer-suburbia/106159172</link><description>Writer Shaun Tan highlighted the magic and whimsy of everyday Australia in his book Tales from Outer Suburbia. He talks about finding inspiration in the mundane, and what it was like turning his tales into TV.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3edc4b4127f4c0bd736e41d9e0e2cd3f</guid></item><item><title>Jayden Deem explains the situation in Finch Hatton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/finch-hatton-flooding/106218178</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85479b62a5b23bab78c576a3571ba58c</guid></item><item><title>Police discover human remains near car in bushfire-ravaged area east of Seymour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/victoria-bushfires-human-remains-found-longwood-fire/106218144</link><description>Victoria confirms its first fatality in the bushfire emergency ravaging the state, with police discovering human remains east of the town of Seymour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f48177119b0657449c023ba885bfe11</guid></item><item><title>Volunteer firefighter's Alexandra home burns while he battles Victorian bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/cfa-volunteer-firefighter-discovers-burnt-home-during-shift/106217532</link><description>CFA volunteer Michael Harper discovers through the truck radio while on shift that his home is under threat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c0a6cb7dbb65315c1dc52db85da06df</guid></item><item><title>Winds push bushfire smoke north, triggering air quality and health warnings for Victoria and NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/smoke-and-air-quality-warnings-health-bushfires/106217952</link><description>Health experts and authorities are urging people living north of Victoria's bushfires to limit their time outdoors as a weather system pushes bushfire smoke across the state and into New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">358d63d080f9df3c2162496f14d5aef5</guid></item><item><title>Pioneer River at Mirani reaches major flood level</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/pioneer-river-at-mirani-reaches-major-flood-level/106218224</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">478ae7f4ccf66617d307544e697da9c1</guid></item><item><title>Fun2Learn childcare centre in Sydney's west shut by new regulator after decade of safety breaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/fun2learn-childcare-shut-after-decade-safety-breaches/106217916</link><description>Fun2Learn in Rosehill is the first centre to have its doors forcibly shut by the new child care regulator after it uncovered 41 breaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a8d675a2905333a32fb7d90181e6e1b</guid></item><item><title>ABC reporter Liam O'Connell is on the ground in Mackay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/liam-o-connell-cross-koji-mackay/106218276</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d4aa47897f57fb579feda60d7275cf7</guid></item><item><title>Tim Aquilina received a loud awakening in Mackay this morning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/mackay-home-damage/106218274</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48346437f219c8cce1d722217f80537f</guid></item><item><title>Festival board members quit after author's cancellation from Writers' Week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/fallout-amid-writers-week-cancellation-of-randa-abdel-fattah/106217646</link><description>The Adelaide Festival board's decision to cancel the appearance of Palestinian-Australian author Randa Abdel-Fattah from this year's Adelaide Writers' Week has prompted further fallout, with three board members stepping down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da2c4b2cf2ad5c5edceae8c85ba6aeb9</guid></item><item><title>Aryna Sabalenka wins second-straight Brisbane International women's final, beating Marta Kostyuk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-11/aryna-sabalenka-vs-marta-kostyuk-brisbane-international-final/106218052</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka has claimed her second-straight Brisbane International title, beating Marta Kostyuk 6-4, 6-3.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd6ca667c6147eec17022a291370ef01</guid></item></channel></rss>