<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 09:50:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rebuilding Juukan Gorge: Traditional owners turn to France for restoration plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/juukan-gorge-replica-rebuild-rio-tinto-ppk-france-inspiration/105949740</link><description>Five years after Rio Tinto destroyed a 47,000-year-old sacred rock shelter to expand an iron ore mine, an ambitious rebuild is underway drawing inspiration all the way from France.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de9425a9476d7c3af156b6d7b2c1414b</guid></item><item><title>Legal experts, civil libertarians warn the NSW government is 'eroding' the right to protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/nsw-protest-laws-eroding-right-to-protest-say-legal-experts/106006324</link><description>When 60 neo-Nazis lined outside NSW parliament last week, the premier's response was swift and familiar — steadily tightening the state's protest laws in response to flashpoint events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31ea4c2c9ef06864b01f04216911c228</guid></item><item><title>Endangered bandicoots given new home free of feral predators in regional NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/bandicoots-given-a-new-home-mallee-cliffs-national-park/105995106</link><description>Twenty endangered bandicoots are roaming south-west New South Wales in an effort to return bandicoots to the region after several species were wiped out in the late 1800s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c46dea045a97336604f93f035b9ad0b</guid></item><item><title>Sixers teenager Caoimhe Bray claims WBBL hat-trick in 24-run win over Thunder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/wbbl-sydney-sixers-thunder-caoimhe-bray-hat-trick/106014712</link><description>Sydney Sixers rising star Caoimhe Bray needed to be told she had taken a hat-trick, as the 16-year-old added another WBBL highlight in a thumping derby defeat of the Thunder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0d7e129714674d7783957c8ea49e2e2</guid></item><item><title>India and Pakistan have faced the deadliest terror attacks on their capitals in a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/india-pakistan-deadly-terror-attacks-in-delhi-islamabad/106013650</link><description>In just 48 hours, almost 30 people were killed and dozens more injured in the deadliest terrorist assaults on the capitals of both India and Pakistan in more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0e54e563cf82b482504d0bcfb5d5d51</guid></item><item><title>Survival camping isn't for everyone — so how would you go in the wilderness? Take the quiz to find out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/survival-camping-quiz-tasmanian-wilderness/105888688</link><description>For 18-year-old Rivi, knowing what gear to leave behind can be as important as knowing what to take with.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab49ce291cf03e60517a144569b2e9c7</guid></item><item><title>Rain brings relief across much of Victoria but the drought is 'certainly not over'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/victorian-drought-not-over-despite-relief-of-spring-rain/106004802</link><description>Dusty Victorian farms turn muddy as drenching rain brings much-needed relief.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87d1f24f3b4d20878cb22c831a1aa5d7</guid></item><item><title>Rose Byrne plays a mother on the edge in Mary Bronstein's If I Had Legs I'd Kick You</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/if-i-had-legs-i-kick-you-rose-byrne-movie-mary-bronstein/105977540</link><description>The Sydney-born movie star discusses how her creative partnership with If I had Legs I'd Kick You director Mary Bronstein has opened the Oscars conversation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a57ec37515d332a6074b6269009da5c4</guid></item><item><title>Sergey Lavrov was one of Vladimir Putin's top allies on the world stage. And then, he was gone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/mystery-surrounds-missing-russian-foreign-minister-sergey-lavrov/106008516</link><description>For more than two decades, Sergey Lavrov has been Russia's top foreign diplomat, representing the Kremlin's regime around the world, but late last month, he disappeared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45f8c3cacfd91b10388d63f50b589d5b</guid></item><item><title>Inspection of Weona Park horse stud found several serious animal welfare issues, just weeks before public outcry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/weona-horse-stud/106012012</link><description>Investigators warned the "situation" at a horse stud in the state's south "is likely to [be] the next welfare issue hitting the news".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff8f2c6eb64387a9de9b3397ae1d51b1</guid></item><item><title>Horned 'devil' bee found in remote Goldfields prompts call for further research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/horned-lucifer-bee-discovery-goldfields/105997548</link><description>The discovery of a new "lucifer" bee with devil-like horns sparks concerns over land clearing regulations in WA's Goldfields region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae67dce636b1d6d9780e5a16b4b27f80</guid></item><item><title>Amid ongoing drought in South Australia, these women are redefining resilience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/women-showing-up-for-community-during-drought/105926946</link><description>Dusty paddocks, with no grain crop to harvest, and scarce feed for the few animals left, is the reality of many South Australian farmers right now. Four women are redefining resilience and showing what it means to endure tough conditions despite it all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5497b2acddf11b8b1ea3f54f23673983</guid></item><item><title>Victorian farmer to auction father's vintage tractor collection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/victorian-farmer-to-auction-fathers-vintage-tractor-collection/105990840</link><description>Tony Forrest reflects on his father's love of old tractors as he prepares them for sale.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8c2f2f7c59d020c9c17b7e189a1935c</guid></item><item><title>Aldo Revaldo taken to hospital with suspected poisoning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/aldo-repaldo-taken-to-hospital-with-suspected-poisoning/106010560</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb1cad64e02ae52dcb0ae19ad430e102</guid></item><item><title>Indonesian school kids poisoned by free school lunches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/indonesian-school-kids-poisoned-by-free-school-lunches/106010538</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61fbcb16360c16afdcf8e5c097d19b79</guid></item><item><title>How free school meals gave thousands of children food poisoning in Indonesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/indonesia-free-school-meals-program-for-kids-in-schools-problems/106009984</link><description>Despite thousands of cases of food poisoning, Indonesia's government intends to expand a controversial program giving schoolchildren free meals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d079a30ad4ea57b0a6fa6d30e61416a4</guid></item><item><title>Accusations of secrecy, abuse of power fly as WA Labor wades through third term</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/wa-government-accused-of-secrecy-abuse-of-power/106010294</link><description>Accusations of secrecy and abuse of process have been levelled at the Western Australian government this week on several fronts. Are they blips on the radar or signs WA Labor is under strain?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">641b8039ba4f80240938b1dff54fec01</guid></item><item><title>Fourth case of measles confirmed after Jelly Roll concert at Brisbane Entertainment Centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/fourth-measles-case-confirmed-after-jelly-roll-concert/106014898</link><description>Authorities say a case had been identified in the Logan region after three cases linked to the concert at the Brisbane Entertainment Centre on October 24 were confirmed on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc09641cf8ec80e2d65bf674da768f83</guid></item><item><title>Wong won't put price tag on COP31 as final host decision looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/cop31-price-penny-wong/106014762</link><description>Foreign Minister Penny Wong has refused to say how much it would cost Australia to hold the COP31 climate conference, as negotiations over hosting rights enter the final stages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a300239a7111e75ab0cafa979cd434c</guid></item><item><title>More coloured sand recalls prompt ACT to close 70 schools over asbestos concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/more-coloured-sand-products-recalled-over-asbestos-fears/106014952</link><description>Kmart has recalled four coloured sand products over concerns of asbestos contamination, prompting the ACT education department to close dozens more schools.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0c60746dd4e3f1d8cbdf98f839bc448</guid></item><item><title>Government considers dramatic intervention to save Tomago smelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/government-considers-intervention-to-save-tomago-smelter/106015238</link><description>The federal government is considering a power-purchase agreement with Tomago to supply electricity at a stable price, after warnings the smelter may need to close because of rising power costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4939cc71d7e33335bf2c9f977ab8634a</guid></item><item><title>Former MP Nick Dametto declares victory in Townsville mayoral by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/townsville-mayoral-by-election-nick-dametto-declares-victory/106014032</link><description>Nick Dametto, a former Queensland MP, has won 61 per cent of the votes counted, succeeding in his campaign to become Townsville's next mayor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e93915c10ec838af548b5920da333d1b</guid></item><item><title>Coalition plans to strip climate from energy operator's objectives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/coalition-joint-net-zero-position-leaked-submission/106015290</link><description>Emissions reduction would no longer be an objective of Australia's energy operator under a Coalition plan endorsed by the Nationals and Liberals, prioritising affordability and reliability over climate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e121017def600970fa4dff5d9f2618b7</guid></item><item><title>Calls for federal government to help 'stranded Australians' waiting in hospital for aged care bed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/critical-shortage-of-aged-care-beds-calls-federal-government/106010318</link><description>About 1,000 people are waiting in Queensland public hospitals for more appropriate care, such as a place in aged care, with infrastructure failing to keep up with the need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4e9d39ecc3bdbcdbe884b027e9e26c2</guid></item><item><title>More than 90 patients stuck in Tasmanian hospitals waiting for aged care or NDIS support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/tasmanian-hospitals-bed-block-aged-care-ndis-funding-agreement/106015236</link><description>More than 90 Tasmanians who have been medically cleared to leave hospital are not able to because they are waiting for an aged care place or NDIS support. Premier Jeremy Rockliff says it's "not good enough" and is calling on the federal government to increase hospital funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4395de959a9953c7649153fbb7277ff3</guid></item><item><title>ACT closes 70 schools as more sand products recalled amid asbestos concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/act-to-close-schools-after-coloured-sand-recall-over-asbestos/106015398</link><description>The ACT will close more schools after additional coloured sand products were recalled by Kmart and Target, while the schools that were shut on Friday will reopen on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9518404fe2157f394c68f2bfa67ac72</guid></item><item><title>From 'female Donald Trump' to 'Wacky' Marjorie — how Taylor Greene's alliance with the president crumbled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/donald-trump-marjorie-taylor-greene-alliance-erupts/106015394</link><description>Once considered one of Donald Trump's most loyal soldiers, Marjorie Taylor Greene has found herself an outcast of the MAGA firm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce47c00f288f5b76e52c94fe74013bf6</guid></item><item><title>Renegades down Stars by four wickets as Devine sends down stunner in Scorchers win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/renegades-down-stars-scorchers-defeat-strikers/106015666</link><description>The Renegades get the better of the Stars in the Melbourne derby, while Sophie Devine bowls one of the balls of the season in the Scorchers' defeat of the Strikers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ec6f32af3d9f60d49cdfd034530342e</guid></item><item><title>Zac Lomax released by Eels for 'opportunities outside NRL', fuelling speculation of R360 switch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/lomax-released-by-eels-fuelling-speculation-of-r360-switch/106015696</link><description>Parramatta star Zac Lomax is released from the final three years of his NRL contract, fuelling speculation of a move to breakaway rugby competition R360.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e096c75a6ce2bd66a948cea80f34803</guid></item><item><title>Energy chiefs say net zero 'irreversible' even though bills unlikely to fall 'for a decade'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/energy-ceos-say-transition-irreversible-despite-rocketing-costs/106015292</link><description>Amid swirling debate among conservative politicians over decarbonisation, energy bosses have warned against turning away from net zero despite cost pressures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30ce8fd67aeb676bb34fe21971b4fd65</guid></item><item><title>Ambulance response times sluggish despite Tasmanian ramping 'ban' promise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/tasmanian-ambulance-ramping-ban-no-impact-on-response-times/106013750</link><description>The Tasmanian government's "ban" on ambulance ramping was announced with much fanfare in 2024 — but there has been no effect on ambulance response times, and patients are still facing long waits in hospital emergency departments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8584855324c23e23803258f1744a5898</guid></item><item><title>Why 'not just living for the weekend' may be a social media trend for good</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/not-living-for-the-weekend-social-media-trend/105999240</link><description>Emma Dickeson says her "school night" adventures are about devoting time and attention to the things that energise you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42759f841e6bf8bfce2e2a4594556426</guid></item><item><title>Vang Vieng backpacker hostel implicated in Laos methanol deaths set to reopen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/laos-hostel-implicated-in-methanol-tragedy-set-to-reopen/105978414</link><description>The Laos hostel accused of serving alcohol contaminated with methanol that killed six people — including two young Australian women — last November is set to reopen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4a08d18a14a827e06668bbd131f50c9</guid></item><item><title>Laos methanol poisoning survivor 'turning grief into action'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/laos-methanol-poisoning-survivor-turning-grief-into-action/106007590</link><description>A survivor of last year's Laos mass methanol poisoning has started a campaign to educate travellers on the dangers of the toxic form of alcohol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5926b3d2a458b4519574ccc128a7360</guid></item><item><title>Tony Abbott admits he was fighting the urge to thump journalist in 2011 interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/tony-abbott-addresses-stare-off/106010356</link><description>In 2011, Tony Abbott was questioned over his use of the phrase "shit happens" when discussing the death of an Australian soldier in Afghanistan. Instead of responding, he stared at the journalist, fighting the urge to thump him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c2aef2912e0cdefb0225e24ff2af31b</guid></item><item><title>The strange macho appeal of fossil fuels in a world struggling to reach net zero</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/macho-appeal-of-fossil-fuels-in-a-world-struggling-with-net-zero/106011600</link><description>The strange macho appeal of fossilised vegetation means that 30 years of annual United Nations meetings to stop the planet heating any more have been a bust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d07adbbaa77ec7a1ebd1bd5822d3206</guid></item><item><title>Indian counterterrorism agency arrests alleged co-conspirator in Red Fort suicide bombing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/man-arrested-over-deadly-delhi-red-fort-explosion/106016028</link><description>India's National Investigation Agency says two men behind last week's deadly car blast in Delhi were from Kashmir, a region that has been a source of tension between India and Pakistan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e53842f29d91924a30d3bdb5722563d5</guid></item><item><title>WA testing lab inundated by families' and retailers' concerns about asbestos-contaminated sand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/wa-hazard-testing-lab-overrun-with-asbestos-sand-requests/106015136</link><description>Concerned families and retailers are inundating a materials testing laboratory with enquiries, since news broke that asbestos had been detected in decorative and coloured sand for children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21052cae1747cefb9fccbf348f33cb3f</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley scrabbling to retain leadership after net zero capitulation puts one advantage at risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/ley-puts-one-advantage-at-risk-scrabbling-to-keep-leadership/106011602</link><description>It was only a week ago that the moderates in the Liberal Party were flexing their muscle privately (and some publicly), threatening a divorce with the Nationals and to walk the plank if net zero was dumped. Neither threat ever materialised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0db26107892679ddf443db6d1c4ef15c</guid></item><item><title>Operational dates for Northern Water project pushed out by several years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/northern-water-project-timeline-pushed-back/105995628</link><description>Completion of the South Australian government’s Northern Water desalination plant and water pipeline is now forecast to occur in 2032.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3321bf605b72948ab339039081d26fc</guid></item><item><title>Numbers suggest England's Ashes preparation does not make a difference</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/ashes-england-preparation-first-test-historical/106012450</link><description>Has England compromised its pre-Ashes preparation by playing only one three-day warm-up match against its own reserve team before the first Test in Perth? The numbers say no.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64090b0afb139b2e1d6c0f0cee876498</guid></item><item><title>Doorbell footage shows aftermath of Waterloo police death in custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/doorbell-footage-shows-aftermath-of-waterloo-police-/105920758</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e184ab3c3060da415367dd412aa44871</guid></item><item><title>Police mental health unit under the spotlight after the deaths of 10 people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/nsw-police-mental-health-responses-criticism-from-coroners/105914846</link><description>An officer who headed the NSW Police unit training the force in mental health responses once committed misconduct in a case where a mentally ill man was fatally shot by police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12f3f7fd35e360033cf2335d8bb2a05f</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr rested as Chelsea drops Women's Super League points</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/sam-kerr-rested-chelsea-drops-wsl-points-arsenal-draw/106016282</link><description>English champs Chelsea decide to rest Sam Kerr for their WSL clash against Liverpool but appear to pay the price with a 1-1 slip-up at Liverpool.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43246472ac0ff91330de097de8b29e25</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Moderates rally behind Ley's leadership as Albanese labels Liberal energy policy 'nonsensical' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/federal-politics-live-blog-nov-17/106011986</link><description>Sussan Ley says she is not worried her leadership is on the rocks after a bumpy week for the opposition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1edf4ee95bd1bd8bcca418a35172957b</guid></item><item><title>Police seize record number of bladed weapons amid knife crime concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/vic-police-seize-record-number-of-knives/106016252</link><description>Police have confiscated more than 15,000 bladed weapons this year amid heightened community concern over knife crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6be37f5517622fde62452efb39f973a</guid></item><item><title>Maya Joint's fighting qualities praised in Billie Jean King Cup win over Brazil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/maya-joint-s-fighting-qualifies-praised-in-bjk-cup-win/106016324</link><description>Australia advances to the qualifying stage of the Billie Jean King Cup after Maya Joint and Kimberly Birrell dug deep to defeat Brazil and top their group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c08e333a529694f7ed6bdb93ce9ab748</guid></item><item><title>Locals brace for timber industry job losses amid creation of Great Koala National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/job-losses-in-timber-industry-to-create-koala-park/106004814</link><description>A third of Herons Creek’s population on the NSW mid north coast faces possible redundancy as the timber mill struggles to survive the logging moratorium to create the Great Koala National Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9af06d114671af8f00a4cf766aa9abe</guid></item><item><title>Jannik Sinner beats Carlos Alcaraz in ATP Finals in latest Sincaraz rivalry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/jannik-sinner-beats-carlos-alcaraz-in-atp-finals/106016348</link><description>Jannik Sinner has defeated world number one Carlos Alcaraz 7-6 (4), 7-5 in the ATP Finals title decider, defending his crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e22513592369347affdecc29fa48dd1</guid></item><item><title>Groote Eylandt's unique rehabilitation program offers alternative to NT prison system amid record incarceration rates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/groote-eylandt-nt-rehabilitation-program-nt-prison-crisis/106007976</link><description>As the NT's prison population soars to new highs, Anindilyakwa elders on Groote Eylandt are delivering a unique rehabilitation program that provides participants with physical and psycho-educational programs, as well as new skills and employment opportunities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c264b98767b14288601b3656e660f24</guid></item><item><title>Unique rehabilitation program offers alternative to prison system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/stateline-groote-eylandt-rehab-centre-alternative-to-prison/106015402</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">039031c507c111d5767aa5572109796c</guid></item><item><title>Esperance community fights for more change, a decade on from deadly bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/deadly-esperance-fires-10-year-anniversary/106011936</link><description>A decade on from bushfires that claimed four lives, this community says not enough has been done to ensure they are safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26fef5c10f539bb8ef24c281e054fc28</guid></item><item><title>Iran begins cloud seeding to induce rain as it faces worst drought in decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/iran-cloud-seeding-worst-drought-in-decades/106016566</link><description>Cloud seeding involves spraying particles such as silver iodide and salt into clouds from aircraft to trigger rain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2ac4d6818d3c9412a85d4a3f80ca6df</guid></item><item><title>Calls for greater education as growers in WA's south-west brace for polyphagous shot-hole borer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/growers-brace-for-impact-of-polyphagous-shot-hole-borer/106015566</link><description>Growers in this major food bowl are nervous for their future, as the state focuses its shot-hole borer efforts on outer-Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50f4a3a5e7ce5cf47c88150724bea96c</guid></item><item><title>South Africa beat India by 30 runs in low-scoring first Test boilover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/south-africa-beat-india-in-first-test-boilover/106016596</link><description>South Africa upsets India on a turning pitch at Eden Gardens, with spinner Simon Harmer taking eight wickets in a man-of-the-match performance for the World Test Champions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f15a3e3dceaa4fad6333648dc1958129</guid></item><item><title>These young men escaped restless boredom that led to chaos and crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/from-youth-crime-to-mentoring-with-football-and-skateboarding/105895098</link><description>Nye was getting into trouble and making bad choices when he was handed a lifeline that helped him turn things around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e607803765cf9a6e1b25808c6b5ddc53</guid></item><item><title>Koala mapping near Mudgee discovers strong population and ideal habitat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/mudgee-koala-mapping-finds-critical-population/105977120</link><description>Scientists mapping koala habitat in the NSW central west find it is larger than previously thought, but concerns remain over expansion plans at a nearby coal mine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">084df53a2828bc45a1af61c81e23d553</guid></item><item><title>Ireland celebrates after Troy Parrott secures last-second World Cup qualifier victory over Hungary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/ireland-beats-hungary-in-last-second-of-world-cup-qualifiers/106016698</link><description>Ireland keeps its hopes alive of making the World Cup finals for the first time since 2002 with a stunning comeback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0fecaa98eb474ea98596755ff77fd05</guid></item><item><title>When is the 2025 AFL draft? Here's your guide to bidding, trades and the official pick order</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/afl-draft-2025-everything-you-need-to-know-guide/106017028</link><description>Another AFL draft has arrived, offering dozens of teenage footballers the chance to realise their dreams. Here is everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95c3159204fc6f2fc50d5996c5f009b6</guid></item><item><title>From Blue Poles to Gina Rinehart, the most controversial artworks in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/controversial-artworks-australia/105984714</link><description>Art can stir strong feelings in people, both good and bad. These artworks fell in the latter, provoking great controversy in Australia, and telling us a lot about who we are as a nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2c66a5a1b1ff5afbc408c2410615cc7</guid></item><item><title>Gen Z protests in Mexico City brings thousands out against crime and corruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/mexico-gen-z-protests-gain-momentum-against-crime-corruption/106016816</link><description>The demonstration was mostly peaceful but ended with some young people clashing with the police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d288f9b9c30370a39087f65efadb877f</guid></item><item><title>Sam Konstas picked to open for Prime Minister's XI against England in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/sam-konstas-picked-to-open-for-prime-minister-xi-england/106017212</link><description>Sam Konstas will return to the scene where he made his case for Test selection last summer, with the axed opener given a chance to face England with the Prime Minister's XI.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3473b1050834fe6d4191bbba1937ae0</guid></item><item><title>Paralympic gold medal winner Paige Greco dies, aged 28</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/paralympic-gold-medal-winner-paige-greco-dies-aged-28/106017286</link><description>Australian Paralympian Paige Greco, who won Australia's first gold medal of the 2020 Tokyo Paralympic Games, has died aged 28.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39fe1f64b531a269cb3986cf717522a6</guid></item><item><title>China's seafood import rules behind a partial closure of Tasmania's rock lobster fishery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/tasmania-rock-lobster-fishery-antibiotic-florfenicol-salmon/106016448</link><description>The Tasmanian government closed two zones within the state's rock lobster fishery just hours after the commercial season opened. The closure is in response to concerns about an antibiotic being used by salmon companies and the rock lobster industry's reputation in overseas markets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b69359e0def6b5ab9dacf255531f62d1</guid></item><item><title>Why the ACT has gone further than other jurisdictions in closing schools over coloured sand asbestos concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/why-the-act-has-closed-schools-over-asbestos-sand/106016514</link><description>The ACT has closed 70 schools over the coloured sand asbestos scare. Why is it the only jurisdiction to do so?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c01cfca034233367a3ea078fd54beb00</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann gets full forensic copy of Toowoomba rape accuser's phone after court order</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/bruce-lehrmann-gets-full-copy-toowoomba-rape-complainant-phone/106017160</link><description>A judge rules in favour of Mr Lehrmann, who has been seeking a full copy of the woman's phone for several months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d69499f6cb9e2c763c6a0e7d6cd62945</guid></item><item><title>US flagship aircraft carrier arrives in Caribbean as part of massive military build-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/us-aircraft-carrier-carribbean-venezuela/106016932</link><description>Following the arrival of a 100,000 tonne warship in the Caribbean, as part of a massive military build-up, President Donald Trump has hinted that the US "may be having some discussions" with Venezuelan President Nicolás Maduro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">594992e9b8c375933e7230409adc2c58</guid></item><item><title>Mackay Base Hospital expansion paused as contractor withdraws from site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/mackay-base-hospital-expansion-paused/106016520</link><description>Brisbane contractor BESIX Watpac will leave the Mackay Base Hospital construction site in Queensland as a report finds the cost of a 128-bed expansion has more than doubled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcec71f0845df5a45558dc3a585ca88d</guid></item><item><title>Contractor dies in workplace accident at BlueScope Steel blast furnace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/worker-killed-at-port-kembla-steelworks/106017806</link><description>A worker in his 20s has died after he was hit by a steel beam while working on the upgrade of a blast furnace at the Port Kembla steelworks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f46bbc3019d6ea669a84a982c7167269</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump calls on Republicans to vote to release Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/trump-calls-epstein-vote/106018036</link><description>President Donald Trump has called on his fellow Republicans in Congress to vote for the release of files related to the late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df4f580cc759e73761cec529a1b9db13</guid></item><item><title>Victorian youth offenders allowed to leave state for Gold Coast trip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/victorian-youth-offenders-take-trip-to-gold-coast/106016812</link><description>Two violent youth offenders serving a community corrections order in Victoria have been allowed to travel interstate for a taxpayer-funded trip, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25757467b6df9c4b7a36eea296ea7f4a</guid></item><item><title>Sharing COP presidency with Türkiye 'not an option', says Albanese</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/albanese-sharing-cop-presidency-with-turkiye-not-an-option/106017904</link><description>As Chris Bowen lands in Belém with the clock ticking on a resolution, Anthony Albanese says the rules against co-presidency for the COP are clear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9794fb3c53b4519304b21822dc905b0b</guid></item><item><title>Should I kick my diet soft-drink habit? Where do I start?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/should-i-kick-my-diet-soft-drink-habit-where-do-i-start-/106007994</link><description>You don't have to give up diet soft drinks altogether. But being mindful of how much soft drink you drink, and how often, can help you make healthier choices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8ad2c096503d0bd2d35b8a08f58567a</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese writes to states, telling them to rein in public hospital spending</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/anthony-albanese-tells-states-to-rein-in-hospital-spending/106017654</link><description>Health ministers are furious with a letter from the prime minister demanding they rein in spending if they want a public hospital funding deal honoured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84ca8710050bda5c8532914dceb9e7e4</guid></item><item><title>Mother of 15-yo victim addresses getaway vehicle driver involved in fatal crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/jaydon-chauveau-parliament-house-crash-victims-mother/106018240</link><description>The mother of the 15-year-old boy who died in a car crash near Parliament House last year has spoken to one of the perpetrators involved during a court sentencing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e4acca9f9c94b514a08d980a507acad</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government denies dingoes could be kept as pets under contentious reclassification</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/dingo-reclassification-biosecurity-regulations-queensland/106000986</link><description>Queensland is considering changes that would remove restrictions on keeping dingoes and while the government says that will not mean people can keep them as pets, experts fear it could be an unintended outcome.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4338424fa0fdeae0ef247600ca95736</guid></item><item><title>Police charge 750 people with DV offences in four-day blitz, as services call for funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/nsw-police-domestic-violence-arrest-blitz-services-need-funding/106016234</link><description>More than 750 people have been charged under Operation Amarok XII, though support services say they are desperate for funding to match this police response.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3a6e988937537bc47818d31a73c8279</guid></item><item><title>Caroline Flack: Search for the Truth raises questions about assault charges and British tabloid ethics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/caroline-flack-documentary-revelations-media-police/106018362</link><description>In a two-part series, the mother of television presenter Caroline Flack examines the final months of her daughter's life and what she believes to be the mishandling of the criminal case against her daughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a12a6552a4b1f5a4fd8d1f21aa0b176</guid></item><item><title>Late Yolŋu leader Paul Gurrumuruwuy Wunungmurra honoured with PhD for anthropology, filmmaking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/paul-gurrumuruwuy-wunungmurra-phd-for-original-research/106013740</link><description>World-renowned anthropologist, filmmaker and Arnhem Land Indigenous leader Paul Gurrumuruwuy Wunungmurra has become the first Yolŋu person to be honoured for his work with a PhD for original research.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b19ee00b267d8622be272dec4ca318ee</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos sand contamination also affecting New Zealand, after 70 Australian schools close</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/asbestos-sand-contamination-new-zealand-school-closure/106017844</link><description>After asbestos was found in a range of coloured sand, early childhood centres and schools in Australia and New Zealand are hurrying to dispose of potentially contaminated products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfa35953b42e65748b152a39baccd75a</guid></item><item><title>WA bikie Dayne Brajkovich fined $500 over Nazi swastika facial tattoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/dayne-brajkovich-charged-over-modified-nazi-tattoo/106018884</link><description>A Western Australian bikie known for his distinctive facial tattoos is fined after tattooing a Nazi swastika on his chin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">affeccbcca1602af51398276256b7837</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian private mental health service The Hobart Clinic reopens after 17-day closure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/tasmanian-mental-health-hospital-hobart-clinic-reopens/106016912</link><description>A $2 million transitional funding injection from the Tasmanian government has allowed The Hobart Clinic to treat patients for six more months while it comes up with a sustainable business model.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fddd37d2b51ab0986ed2914f7d3cf0b</guid></item><item><title>Jury in trial of Rajwinder Singh, charged with murder of Toyah Cordingley, taken to beach where her body was found</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/qld-toyah-cordingley-trial-rajwinder-singh-cairns/106016662</link><description>The jury was taken by bus to Wangetti Beach, north of Cairns, where Ms Cordingley's body was found buried in a shallow sand grave in 2018.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4cf89665461f09e93ed8302da6a4ca7</guid></item><item><title>Arsonist sentenced to time served, community corrections order for synagogue attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/angelo-loras-synagogue-arsonist-court/106019188</link><description>Angelo Loras pleaded guilty to setting a fire to the East Melbourne Hebrew Congregation synagogue on July 5.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26ddc60f622e661b2ff3dc56add29a3f</guid></item><item><title>South African man who attended Neo-Nazi rally outside NSW parliament has visa cancelled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/verify-neo-nazi-rally-participant-visa-revoked/106018130</link><description>The federal government has revoked the visa of a man who attended the far-right National Socialist Network protest at NSW's parliament house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b76921ba7f888c119b8ec7bca1ab37b</guid></item><item><title>Australian beef producers welcome end to Donald Trump's import tariffs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/beef-producers-welcome-end-of-tariffs/106018228</link><description>Shoppers at home and abroad are unlikely to see any immediate change in the price of Australian beef as tariffs that did little to curb demand in the first place are lifted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c0295fa27b30c3d32c17b6c75d5199f</guid></item><item><title>Quick and easy summer dinners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/easy-healthy-summer-dinners/105822526</link><description>The busy end of year calls for simple dinners that are ready in 35 minutes or less.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c150e5b10f059167f94843c91f1d296</guid></item><item><title>Homes searched, knife found in Melissa Trussell, Rosemary Brown cold case probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/melissa-trussell-rosemary-brown-suspects-homes-searched/106018670</link><description>Police search two homes linked to a suspect in the investigation into the murder of Adelaide woman Rosemary Brown and the disappearance of her 15-year-old daughter, Melissa Trussell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49277d0ab0c89ed8c7a1f87b5026936d</guid></item><item><title>Dozens of Canberra schools to reopen, 25 remain closed over coloured sand asbestos contamination concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/dozens-canberra-schools-remain-closed-coloured-sand-asbestos/106019038</link><description>Dozens of public schools in the ACT will reopen or partially open on Tuesday, but 25 remain closed for all students.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">403edecc55dd3b941ebf562588a5450e</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Liberal leader Brad Battin facing leadership challenge as soon as Tuesday morning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/victoria-brad-battin-liberal-leadership-challenge/106019530</link><description>The opposition leader was informed by a delegation of MPs that he had lost the support of the party room, less than 12 months into his tenure as leader and just over a year out from the state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe4dbfb2be9f670da14edcbe68247616</guid></item><item><title>Offenders 'targeting' elderly residents at home in series of assaults in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/elderly-residents-attacked-at-home-in-alice-springs/106016890</link><description>Three elderly Alice Springs residents have been assaulted at their Sadadeen homes within a 10-day period this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">665e2c7aab825f76c7c849d34092d77b</guid></item><item><title>Black swan 'Jandal' released in Alice Springs after recovering from suspected dog attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/alice-springs-black-swan-released-after-dog-attack/105974208</link><description>An unlikely patient in Alice Springs is returned to the water treatment ponds two weeks after being found injured from a suspected dog attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ac67925c2602e1c59871b9efe0f6a00</guid></item><item><title>Man sentenced over 'disgusting' death threats to Senator Fatima Payman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/man-sentenced-over-fatima-payman-death-threats/106016600</link><description>A Victorian court has sentenced a man to a community corrections order after he sent death threats to Australian senator Fatima Payman via email.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">640101d01f3a096ee8a29760edfa8aaf</guid></item><item><title>Queensland former rugby league player Trevor Gillmeister charged over alleged assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/trevor-gillmeister-charged-police-assault/106019636</link><description>The retired rugby league player was charged with public nuisance, assault and obstructing police after an incident in Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f6f85b5bce2b6c43a1f9cf197be9752</guid></item><item><title>Identities of three NT residents charged with fraud over alleged $71 million Defence contract scheme revealed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/three-face-darwin-local-court-afp-alleged-defence-contract-fraud/106017382</link><description>Three Northern Territory residents who were charged on Friday over allegations of a $71 million Defence contract fraud scheme have been granted bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09d5797db5f8c8a2f8f195ebb35d3c28</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106018274</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98779dd691f5cd97ed5db0d8fb719e54</guid></item><item><title>Man sentenced over 2024 drowning death of UTAS student Deepinderjeet Singh</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/sentencing-2024-hobart-waterfront-drowning-deepinderjeet-singh/105627554</link><description>A 19-year-old has been sentenced to four years in jail after pleading guilty to the 2024 drowning death of student Deepinderjeet Singh, after he pushed him into the river at Hobart's waterfront.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3f25a9516c5e08696038b56d31951a3</guid></item><item><title>Brendan Doggett poised for Test cricket debut in first Ashes Test against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/brendan-doggett-ashes-test-selection-perth/106020038</link><description>Fast bowler Brendan Doggett says he learned he could make a Test debut while waiting to bat in South Australia's Sheffield Shield run chase last week against Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8502ae382f2de6c019d1618216d6f0e</guid></item><item><title>Mary Fowler's resilience in face of mental health struggles hailed by Matildas coach Joe Montemurro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/mary-fowler-matildas-mental-health-joe-montemurro/106019580</link><description>Mary Fowler is unlikely to be back on the pitch with the Matildas until next year at the earliest, but coach Joe Montemurro is making sure to stay in close contact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4088e4edf783bb36f9dab8b7ce4f910a</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man denied bail over alleged car park sexual assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/lal-ro-puia-denied-bail-alleged-car-park-sexual-assault-canberra/106019956</link><description>A 30-year-old man is behind bars after prosecutors alleged he pursued a woman into an underground car park where he tried to sexually assault her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e1b803cc93d12e0512551e191882c32</guid></item><item><title>Several Tasmanian non-government schools closed, others partially closed due to coloured sand recall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/tasmanian-catholic-schools-shut-tuesday-coloured-sand-recall/106020206</link><description>At least six non-government schools have closed, and six others partially closed on Monday due to the national recall of coloured sand products over asbestos contamination, with others slated for closure on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fbea7ca273f5cb2f2e20576efc392e4</guid></item><item><title>High chance of a cyclone forming off the NT coast this week, potentially impacting Darwin, BOM forecasts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/nt-cyclone-high-chance-of-forming-near-darwin-bom-forecast/106017076</link><description>The chance of a cyclone forming off the Northern Territory coast this week is now high, the Bureau of Meteorology is forecasting, with Darwin potentially impacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32d729a1060a2c6721f7f34b552bdea8</guid></item><item><title>Bangladesh's ousted PM Sheikh Hasina sentenced to death for student crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-sentenced-to-death/106020478</link><description>A Bangladesh court has sentenced ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina to death after finding her guilty of crimes against humanity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">178548480ecd805a14632813c78b7a83</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins completes bowling session before first Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/pat-cummins-completes-bowling-session-before-first-ashes-test/106020424</link><description>Australia captain Pat Cummins completes a full bowling session at training just four days before the start of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7efacbc1a9c820d6f1197e4a721fbc1</guid></item><item><title>Rio Tinto scraps $215m research centre and BioIron product after decade of development</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/rio-tinto-scraps-wa-green-steel-bioiron-product/106019692</link><description>Mining giant Rio Tinto scraps a $215 million research centre and green steel project touted last year as a key staging ground for the world's net zero transition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51ffe8af4b14a77380de2ca43c97d8d5</guid></item><item><title>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley guarantees she will remain leader until next election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/opposition-leader-sussan-ley-guarantees-leadership/106020032</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley may be under siege, but says she has no doubts she will remain party leader until the next federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f004c86a7822636864959b0d1b52cdaf</guid></item><item><title>Explosion on Polish railway line to Ukraine an act of sabotage, Polish PM says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/poland-railway-line-explosion-act-of-sabotage-donald-tusk-says/106020652</link><description>The track is a vital link for supplies to reach Ukraine, with the incident the latest in a wave of similar attacks across Europe since Russia's invasion began.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75b80ebec4b1bf4f4d88f3cf14306a45</guid></item><item><title>Australian man Johnson Wen jailed after grabbing Ariana Grande at Wicked: For Good premiere</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/australian-jailed-for-grabbing-ariana-grande/106020466</link><description>Johnson Wen, who is alleged to have disrupted other global sports events and concerts, has shown "a pattern of behaviour", according to a Singapore court judge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecc3872a900d455284a7f911d5c0cae4</guid></item><item><title>BBC 'determined to fight' looming Trump lawsuit over speech edit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/bbc-says-it-will-defend-against-trump-lawsuit/106020752</link><description>The US president says he could sue the British national broadcaster for as much as $US5 billion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">535a31ce8ec0759c2495b4724c9dbbed</guid></item><item><title>Japan attempts to cool tensions with China as diplomatic spat over Taiwan continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/japan-moves-to-calm-tensions-with-china-over-taiwan-comments/106020928</link><description>Tokyo has sent a senior foreign ministry official to Beijing to try and ease tensions, that have seen threats made against Japan's prime minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d213f775764726d9b8161d108b5cb60</guid></item><item><title>Five Ukrainians killed and kindergarten destroyed in latest Russian strikes, as Zelenskyy signs French fighter jets deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/ukraine-latest-five-killed-in-russian-strikes/106020804</link><description>Moscow is intensifying its strikes on Ukraine, targeting the country's energy infrastructure ahead of winter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36682733860153242d788774f884c9f4</guid></item><item><title>At least 18 people killed in Indonesian landslides as rescue efforts continue to find more than 30 others missing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/indonesia-landslides-cilacap-banjarnegara-rescue-continues/106021038</link><description>Multiple landslides have engulfed communities in Central Java, with hundreds of emergency workers involved in the rescue operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">625a097599cde81c977cf6239b709a89</guid></item><item><title>The Ashes quiz: Test your knowledge ahead of the 2025/26 Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/the-ashes-quiz/105954056</link><description>Ahead of the 2025/26 Ashes series getting underway on November 21 in Perth, test out your knowledge in our fiendish Ashes quiz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c23d2aa29854277ae713a18dc1ce0f7</guid></item><item><title>What price power? How electricity became a political weapon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/how-electricity-became-a-political-weapon-in-australia/106017144</link><description>A decade and a half after an energy company CEO outlined his greatest fears for Australia's economic future — no carbon price — the nation again appears set for a renewed battle over climate policy and power generation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4345b97848a444c0296bfbc0178c05da</guid></item><item><title>Drone vision of Ukraine's Pokrovsk as Russia advances</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/drone-vision-ukraine-pokrovsk-russia-advance/106002526</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">265674cdfc115cfb62a334f5ebd1df4b</guid></item><item><title>Video shows troops entering Pokrovsk, Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/social-media-vision-shows-troops-entering-pokrovsk-ukraine/106002652</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4d6642663b12b5f661d69f548166e25</guid></item><item><title>How Russia is ramping up its efforts to take strategic Ukrainian city Pokrovsk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/russia-ramping-up-efforts-to-take-ukraine-city-pokrovsk/105998184</link><description>Recently released video shows a "Mad Max-style" convoy entering Pokrovsk in Ukraine's east on motorcycles and in ramshackle cars, in what experts say is part of Russia's latest push to take the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24c7c7aeca812cd75b9a6b137698a419</guid></item><item><title>Nirvana’s MTV Unplugged: How a near-disaster became an iconic live performance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/nirvana-mtv-unplugged-in-new-york-live-album-history-kurt-cobain/106004264</link><description>It was nearly a disaster, but Nirvana going acoustic for MTV ended up being one of the most iconic live performances ever and cemented Kurt Cobain as a tortured genius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd684fbce58f9676f21b2f33b346196a</guid></item><item><title>Lost at sea: The harrowing hours of the deadliest Sydney to Hobart race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/sydney-to-hobart-1998-tragedy/105686076</link><description>The fleet of the 1998 Sydney to Hobart yacht race set sail from the harbour city, unaware they were travelling directly into the path of a huge storm and unrelenting swell that would throw the race into disarray and claim six lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2e3bc8203f33a6235d72740fa054717</guid></item><item><title>Renewable energy generators need to cut supply to stay sustainable. Here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/why-renewable-generators-need-to-cut-production-when-sun-is-up/105981004</link><description>When there is an oversupply of solar and wind power, energy producers are paying more to deliver electricity to households than they get paid. Here's what we know about how it affects you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">107c6c268ba2af68933ea4d9201c4b51</guid></item><item><title>Inside the AFL's infamous 2020 'COVID draft' as teams and players battled impacts of lockdowns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/afl-2020-covid-draft-feature-lockdowns-struggles/105993190</link><description>It is the AFL draft that has become a cautionary tale to clubs. Five years on from the infamous 2020 draft, here is the story on the tumultuous year from those involved in it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15222eb0ee497abf146d967106d5a525</guid></item><item><title>'Aussie Cossack' Simeon Boikov says staff at Russia's Sydney consulate are trying to push him out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/simeon-boikov-complains-of-conditions-in-sydney-russia-consulate/106019604</link><description>Simeon Boikov, the pro-Putin propagandist hiding from authorities in the Russian consulate in Sydney, launches an extraordinary attack on his hosts, saying they are subjecting him to "prison-like conditions" in a bid to "push me out".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f63e5782371fbc5228021a621c4d1df2</guid></item><item><title>The long road to the House of Representatives vote on the Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/what-we-know-about-the-vote-to-release-epstein-files/106017078</link><description>The US House of Representatives is poised to take a significant step in the mammoth saga of the so-called "Epstein files". Here's how we got there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5620839042534a3657f3a6b3a927719c</guid></item><item><title>Most toys purchased online in Choice investigation failed button battery safety standards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/button-batteries-safety-warning-choice/106019258</link><description>The consumer group is warning parents to be wary of the dangers of button batteries in seemingly harmless products aimed at children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8670e5a1b5214ef0778640473aabb626</guid></item><item><title>Ava Costa's sharing shed tries to get disability equipment to people when they need it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/ava-costa-the-sharing-shed-disability-equipment/106018336</link><description>Ava Costa's spinal injury sparked an outpouring of support from the gymnastics community. Now the teenager wants to ensure others can spend less time in hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c454a46fa07629d8e18b51f4e0b3fe6b</guid></item><item><title>Rio Tinto pauses plans for $3.7b lithium mine but Serbians remain concerned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/rio-tinto-jadar-valley-mine-paused-amid-huge-opposition/106020944</link><description>Rio Tinto may have mothballed its proposed $3.6 billion lithium project in Serbia's Jadar Valley, but opponents have vowed to keep fighting until the mining giant leaves the area for good.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d46a4bc7d782c94f6b5239ede5e86862</guid></item><item><title>Figures show areas with high Indigenous populations have more poker machines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/data-on-pokies-in-indigenous-communities/105999308</link><description>New figures show there are 50 per cent more pokies in areas with an Indigenous population of at least 10 per cent. Gambling groups say it is "not surprising".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60a1e17c594345399bcc01e64e02698d</guid></item><item><title>Queensland racing industry review delayed as government withholds landmark report</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/queensland-racing-review-delayed-over-month/106007056</link><description>The report was supposed to be released in mid-October until an industry event was abruptly cancelled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f717b940c87cc4adf0af2cfe264a1f1</guid></item><item><title>Queensland parents divided on recall of decorative sand over contamination concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/qld-asbestos-sand-parents-split-stressed-unbothered/106018662</link><description>While some Queensland parents are angered by the nationwide recall of coloured sand that may have traces of asbestos, others are less concerned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2fa2ba2d633edf7b85b57c60f73eeae</guid></item><item><title>Businesses urge Labor and Coalition to 'work together' on environmental reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/business-groups-epbc-work-together-on-environmental-reform/106020174</link><description>The next few days are viewed as critical to landing a deal on the proposed reforms to update the EPBC Act, amid hopes the Liberals will be more motivated to bolster their environmental credentials after ditching net zero.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">784e3f72a9fa1c34bf9f70ab2c8ac3e4</guid></item><item><title>Contest over Canberra man Michael O'Connell's murder charge, manslaughter or freedom heads to High Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/michael-oconnell-danielle-jordan-murder-runover-ute-high-court/106020354</link><description>In 2022, a woman died after being run over by a ute outside her house. The legal case about exactly what happened and who's responsible is now heading to the High Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b6a053f5e7a40296193891c20155deb</guid></item><item><title>Slain paramedic Steven Tougher's wife speaks out on mental health, a year after killer was detained</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/wife-slain-paramedic-steven-tougher-speaks-out-on-mental-health/106019350</link><description>One year after Steven Tougher's killer was found not criminally responsible due to mental impairment, his wife says she has learnt to accept it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22823b1bd9aa206012027d726db2131a</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Penny Wong says Laos methanol deaths investigation 'not good enough' — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/federal-politics-live-blog-nov-18/106021156</link><description>Penny Wong has demanded "full accountability" and "transparency" from Laos over the methanol deaths of two Australian women last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9711363dc0c2ad174f43c7175b164842</guid></item><item><title>Layne Beachley and Oscar Piastri earn awards at Sport Australia Hall of Fame</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/layne-beachley-oscar-piastri-receive-sport-australia-awards/106021168</link><description>Seven-time world champion Layne Beachley has received the Dawn Award at the Sport Australia Hall of Fame Awards for her efforts in improving women's surfing, while Oscar Piastri has won the annual Don Award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">099f73fbbd41f08105481dce1819bed2</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian duo Beau Webster, Jake Weatherald vie for Ashes Test spot in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/tasmanian-duo-battle-one-ashes-test-spot-webster-weatherald/106021218</link><description>Teammates for Tasmania, Beau Webster and Jake Weatherald will be locked in a battle to play for Australia in the first Test of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8845419c1784350ec40f62288341cb6</guid></item><item><title>Alex Greenwich moves to fast track medicinal cannabis driving reforms in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/nsw-alex-greenwich-medicinal-cannabis-driving-bill-motion/106019210</link><description>Independent Sydney MP Alex Greenwich says it is time to "get the ball rolling" on medical cannabis reforms in NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a5e88c6268a2b624857a0f619017fcb</guid></item><item><title>Man charged over alleged hit-and-run that killed 17-year-old girl at Margate, north of Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/qld-teenage-girl-killed-hit-and-run-redcliffe/106021216</link><description>A 58-year-old man has been charged over the death of a teenage girl, who was just a month away from turning 18 when she was struck in an alleged hit-and-run.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bf2e594904c807f29d926edeaf94074</guid></item><item><title>Landowner concerned about site rehabilitation as Murray Zircon shuts operations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/murray-zircon-mine-closed-with-promise-to-rehabilitate/105973222</link><description>A mine in South Australia's Murray Mallee is ceasing operations and says it will rehabilitate the site back to its original condition. However, the site's owner says the land will never get back to what it was before mining.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d676c8d6d8249e35ac4a7caeead00ae9</guid></item><item><title>Darebin asks AFL for lifeline as club faces financial pressure to stay in VFLW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/darebin-falcons-face-financial-pressure-vflw-aflw-vfl/105818748</link><description>Darebin nurtured AFLW stars Daisy Pearce and Darcy Vescio, but financial constraints could force the independent club out of the VFLW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">700f22852a6c9f923402cc61bdee9239</guid></item><item><title>Lleyton Hewitt's Davis Cup win over Rodger Federer saw off AFL switch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/lleyton-hewitt-afl-switch-halted-by-roger-federer-win/106021256</link><description>An epic Davis Cup win over Roger Federer in 2003 convinced Australian tennis great Lleyton Hewitt to not go ahead with a stunning career change. Two-time grand slam champion Hewitt is one of seven inductees into the Sport Australia Hall of Fame.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6739ec89ad2b2b91e1e11afaa081385</guid></item><item><title>ASX falls 2 per cent as CBA boss says 'unlikely' interest rates will move in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/asx-market-sump-worst-since-liberation-day-tariffs-nov-16/106020676</link><description>The Australian share market posts its worst one-day loss since the fallout from Donald Trump's Liberation Day tariff announcement in early April, with more than $59 billion wiped off the value of listed companies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39fba32a36ed3896857ba6a9d3cd8627</guid></item><item><title>Man shot dead by police after threatening woman and stabbing man at Caboolture</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/qld-police-shoot-man-dead-after-caboolture-stabbing-threats/106021312</link><description>Police have shot dead an armed man found threatening a woman north of Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27a19950eee31cf745172e5c2d6bd9e9</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Liberal MPs choose Jess Wilson as new opposition leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/victorian-liberal-leadership-spill-battin-wilson/106021260</link><description>Jess Wilson says it's "time for a new direction" for the party after she ousted Brad Battin, marking a historic milestone as the state's first female Coalition leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2801b9bd1e0989854ca69aa70c3e64f</guid></item><item><title>Judge finds 'profound' missteps in Trump-appointed attorney's James Comey probe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/missteps-fbi-probe-james-comey/106021286</link><description>Donald Trump's critics describe Mr Comey's charges as part of a campaign by the president to chill opposition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec70dc4c05022756be40b729790ac22e</guid></item><item><title>UN Security Council backs US plan for an international stabilisation force in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/un-security-council-approves-plan-for-gaza/106021610</link><description>The UN Security Council approves a US plan for Gaza that authorises an international stabilisation force to provide security in the devastated territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a081270b2d27b47e9bf8ea92b87f75a</guid></item><item><title>TPG Telecom says Sydney person died after outdated phone software blocked Triple Zero calls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/nsw-tpg-telecom-sydney-person-samsumg-triple-0-death/106021692</link><description>TPG Telecom says a Sydney customer died after outdated software blocked a Samsung phone from making Triple Zero calls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dea78879d3540ec8b0cbd886a458d35</guid></item><item><title>Emotional scenes at Moss Vale site hearing over proposed plastics factory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/moss-vale-site-hearing-over-proposed-plastics-factory/106019648</link><description>Normally confined to four walls, the Land and Environment Court holds a site hearing in the NSW Southern Highlands to hear residents' concerns about a proposed recycling plant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abec674d125082e6230833490d7485b7</guid></item><item><title>When is the ARIAs awards ceremony? Where can I watch it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/arias-australian-music-awards-where-to-watch/105995312</link><description>The Australian music industry awards will be celebrating some of the best acts in the country this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07890810d76bc99b56d9f7bcd6df57e4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says he will sign bill to release Epstein files if it passes Congress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/donald-trump-would-sign-jeffrey-epstein-files-bill/106021282</link><description>The bill — to direct the US Justice Department to release its documents about late sex offender Jeffrey Epstein — now looks set to sail through the House of Representatives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64ce961156f1d882a2423edba210e6b1</guid></item><item><title>Rio Tinto to cut production at Gladstone Yarwun Alumina Refinery, impacting 180 jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/rio-tinto-cuts-production-at-gladstone-yarwun-alumina-refinery/106021782</link><description>Rio Tinto reveals it will cut alumina production at its Gladstone refinery by 40 per cent, as concerns are raised about the future viability of the facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d83c713d69add3a3e357e66a7f50abe9</guid></item><item><title>Coloured sand is being disposed of across the country due to asbestos contamination concerns. How much risk does it actually pose?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/type-asbestos-found-coloured-sand-schools-closed-act-sa-tasmania/106021238</link><description>Dozens of schools remain closed in the ACT, Tasmania and South Australia today as the clean-up and disposal of potentially asbestos-laced coloured sand continues. What risk does it actually pose?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f754e246024da0a3576ac2c3c64e511</guid></item><item><title>Two hikers at Mount Anne winched to safety after becoming stranded in Tasmania's Southwest National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/rescue-tasmania-south-west-mount-anne/106021974</link><description>Police say the two interstate women were "reasonably prepared" but worsening weather meant they were cold, wet and unable to continue their journey.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28ed3825e57eb0f73842f3f36a130029</guid></item><item><title>Lachlan Young sentenced to 28 years' jail for murdering Hannah McGuire in Ballarat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/lachlan-young-jailed-for-hannah-mcguire-murder/106021422</link><description>Lachlan Young strangled Ms McGuire in their Sebastopol home, then placed her body in her ute and set it alight in bushland on Ballarat's outskirts, staging the scene to look like a suicide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e4fed2205e16feada35208342060058</guid></item><item><title>Tributes flow after death of Paralympic champion Paige Greco, aged 28</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/tributes-flow-paralympic-champion-paige-greco/106021934</link><description>Heartfelt tributes from across the Australian sporting landscape have flooded social media after the death of Paralympic and world champion para-cyclist Paige Greco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f7af1000f773288afafa4addd1701bd</guid></item><item><title>Jake Paul and Anthony Joshua's boxing match is a dangerous betrayal of the sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/jake-paul-vs-anthony-joshua-boxing-match-netflix/106021412</link><description>Nobody plays at boxing. But Jake Paul's upcoming contest against a bona fide, former two-time unified heavyweight champion of the world smacks of a game about to go seriously wrong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">236aee0df8d9b848b87e56b1ef80d128</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos scare widens as more than 350 SA schools detect recalled sand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/hundreds-of-sa-schools-detect-sand-linked-to-asbestos-scare/106021664</link><description>The number of public education sites in South Australia that have reported coloured sand linked to an asbestos contamination scare rises above 350, but authorities say there is no plan for closures at this stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ec8f43cdaf64676c821b8f00d82ea1d</guid></item><item><title>Man shot by police in Cairns after reportedly approaching them with a knife</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/cairns-police-shooting-armed-knife-kanimbla/106022872</link><description>Police have shot a man in Far North Queensland after he reportedly approached them armed with a knife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfa52887260681af8aed2c1f97b6e2b3</guid></item><item><title>Sydney father who pleaded guilty to murdering 3yo son to be sentenced next month</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/sydney-father-pleads-guilty-to-murder-of-3yo-in-riverwood-2023/106020266</link><description>The 48-year-old man pleaded guilty to murdering his three-year-old son in a unit in Sydney's south-west two years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18a4affa70229c36580ddc8beab3d779</guid></item><item><title>More schools to reopen in Canberra on Wednesday as coloured sand clean-up continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/schools-still-closed-in-canberra-as-coloured-sand-clean-up/106022660</link><description>More schools will reopen in Canberra on Wednesday with a list of current closures to be updated this afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22858175e2a35e1652224ec2c9370bd6</guid></item><item><title>AFL draft 2025 club by club preview: Your team's picks and potential targets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/afl-draft-2025-club-by-club-preview/105992174</link><description>With the AFL draft just around the corner, see which picks each club has to work with and the players they could select.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dd86e4ed42dd2930cabb8c36b4aff59</guid></item><item><title>Cyclists, pedestrians diverted to Causeway amid closure of Boorloo Bridge in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/boorloo-bridge-closed-after-lightning-cable-incident/106022532</link><description>The Boorloo Bridge, which connects Perth's inner southern suburbs with the CBD, will remain closed until Thursday after lighting fell from the structure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33afea7dbfe9de316a0fe32f604c2748</guid></item><item><title>South African who attended Sydney neo-Nazi rally taken into immigration detention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/nsw-sydney-neo-nazi-protest-matthew-gruter-immigration-visa/106022886</link><description>Matthew Gruter spends the night in a detention centre after having his visa revoked for attending a protest organised by the National Socialist Network.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b55085cf0e4fe26db00c91c6ba3bd2</guid></item><item><title>Category two cyclone predicted off NT coast by Thursday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/tropical-low-cyclone-nt-bureau-of-meteorology-/106023036</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology has issued its first forecast track map for a tropical low over the NT, showing the system is expected to strengthen into a category two cyclone by Thursday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a6c322a2a62ea9ae943397610bd552c</guid></item><item><title>Legal Aid NT to stop taking on new criminal cases due to funding shortfall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/legal-aid-nt-stops-taking-new-criminal-cases-funding-issues/106017800</link><description>Legal Aid NT says it will refuse all new criminal clients who are not already in custody, including children as young as 10, due to funding constraints.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cd4a15833d61ee1b80362093545bd9a</guid></item><item><title>Off-duty pilot who tried to cut a flight's engines midair will not serve additional prison time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/off-duty-pilot-who-tried-to-cut-flights-engines-wont-serve-time/106023336</link><description>A US judge has ruled that a former Alaska Airlines pilot who tried to disable the engines of a passenger jet mid-flight while riding off-duty in the cockpit will not serve additional prison time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd15a01e343a0ac6a58266a693d8e9ae</guid></item><item><title>The Australian music groups celebrating major milestone anniversaries in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/australian-music-groups-major-milestones-2025/105999894</link><description>Improvising with headlights, a sold-out debut and championing new music are some of the impacts these Australian music groups have made in their decades-long existence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">645e25ee987fda0c6bf4553d7cd6f8f6</guid></item><item><title>Gippsland's Willem Duursma set to become fourth family member to join AFL/AFLW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/willem-duursma-tipped-for-top-afl-national-draft-pick-west-coast/105999938</link><description>Willem Duursma's dancing feet could carry him all the way to the number-one pick at tomorrow night's AFL National Draft.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc905c920ae77b121913d5fcd4067338</guid></item><item><title>CFMEU inquiry hears 'cycle of lawlessness' and violence operated in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/qld-cfmeu-inquiry-hearings-begin-brisbane/106021686</link><description>A probe into the CFMEU has begun in Brisbane, examining allegations of bullying, violence and misogyny at the powerful construction union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4eb5700572cb8f721ce8d74f45776a83</guid></item><item><title>Eli Katoa to miss 2026 NRL season after Melbourne Storm star's brain surgery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/eli-katoa-to-miss-2026-nrl-season/106024440</link><description>Melbourne Storm star Eli Katoa will miss the 2026 NRL season as he continues his recovery from head knocks that forced him to have brain surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5232341e3582eed41e32b4e562d739c</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu council repeals law banning menstruating women from selling food</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/vanuatu-menstruating-women-ban-selling-food-markets/106017328</link><description>A Vanuatu provincial government says it will repeal parts of its new bylaw banning menstruating women from preparing and selling food at markets and roadside stalls after the decision sparked a public outcry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">034f538d5d412c8217577c70505f422b</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos contamination of children's sand was a fluke discovery in an Australian lab</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/asbestos-sand-contamination-chance-discovery-in-australian-lab/106022486</link><description>An Australian lab discovered asbestos in children's play sand by chance and regulators only found out about it because of a podcast interview, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62364137d29d39242b79167919e508a9</guid></item><item><title>Inside The Hood Contender, Australia's controversial amateur fighting competition trying to save men's lives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/inside-the-hood-contender-controversial-amateur-fighting/106006086</link><description>The organiser of this fight club says it saves lives. But critics say it is putting young men at serious risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72aefa26eb296ef6083bcca281a4094a</guid></item><item><title>CSIRO to cut up to 350 research jobs in major overhaul</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/csiro-cuts-350-research-jobs/106024498</link><description>After 440 positions were slashed last year, the CSIRO has announced more staff cuts across the country in a bid to remain financially viable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0416ad87616bb5deb09ddba2a6777aae</guid></item><item><title>Alleged manslaughter victim had cuts, bruises and off-smelling school lunches, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/witness-tells-jenni-wilmott-trial-of-bruises-on-jasmine/106022204</link><description>A girl who died, allegedly as a result of criminal neglect by her mother, had attended school with bruises and had lunches that "didn't seem" edible, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">200b8d964744d280dff85a7aabe60469</guid></item><item><title>Court hears details of Dawood Zakaria murder as man charged over attack denied bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/dawood-zakaria-death-jacob-el-masri-bail/106007962</link><description>Details of how a Sydney underworld figure was tracked by his would-be killers have been revealed for the first time in court as it emerged a 19-year-old charged vowed to an associate: "brother I would never snitch".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3a8778634dd58a741863ab34b881531</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions recruit Neasa Dooley wanting to add more Irish success in AFLW preliminary final against Carlton Blues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/neasa-dooley-brisbane-lions-aflw-preliminary-final-carlton/106024288</link><description>No stranger to the big stage, Brisbane's Neasa Dooley wants a piece of what her fellow Irish imports have been selling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b39d76b6c1f3e81e97d4b65690c26dad</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast rejects plans for more than 100 affordable units due to car park concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/councillors-reject-plans-for-more-than-100-affordable-units-/106022472</link><description>Gold Coast councillors reject plans for more than 100 affordable housing units over concerns about car parks and neighbourhood character, despite nearby light rail and a growing need for social housing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdccb39c5930924d6306298859d5614b</guid></item><item><title>Judge blocks use of National Guard in Memphis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/judge-blocks-use-of-national-guard-in-memphis/106023888</link><description>A Tennessee judge has blocked the use of the National Guard in Memphis, but also put the order on hold, giving the government five days to appeal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf7c320ab23bd2b565bb5781058f9dba</guid></item><item><title>What it's like being a male early childhood educator amid the childcare crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/what-it-is-like-being-a-male-educator-amid-the-childcare-crisis/105995392</link><description>While the childcare crisis has left me concerned about my own child's safety, as a male early childhood educator, I'm also worried about the future of men in the sector, writes Ben.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a62aba2abcb529305bf54887ade96ce5</guid></item><item><title>Parents in 'childcare desert' left scrambling as Playtime Preschool enters voluntary administration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/playtime-preschool-broken-hill-enters-voluntary-administration/106021714</link><description>One of the few childcare operators in Broken Hill has closed its doors indefinitely with 24 hours warning after entering voluntary administration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">645912bd0d8354ef6ba596b69e3361b2</guid></item><item><title>Rajwinder Singh, charged with the murder of Toyah Cordingley, was 'very stressed' on day body found, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/rajwinder-singh-murder-trial-toyah-cordingley-friend-evidence/106022864</link><description>Rajwinder Singh, who has pleaded not guilty to the murder of 24-year-old Toyah Cordingley, is on trial in the Supreme Court in Cairns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d72c34bbcda696d66ad81a349650f80c</guid></item><item><title>Defence inspector inadvertently omitted 10 consultations held with NACC chief Paul Brereton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/defence-inspector-omitted-consultations-with-nacc-chief/106023634</link><description>A previous disclosure that the head of the federal corruption watchdog had been consulted 11 times has been corrected to 21.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1781d5607362739f541e7ff802db05f6</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Liberals' first female leader Jess Wilson must prove the party is worth fighting for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/jess-wilson-victorian-liberal-leadership-spill-analysis/106024016</link><description>Victoria's first female Liberal Party leader is facing a gargantuan task to unite her party and prove the opposition is worth voting for, Richard Willingham writes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4938f4f27a6b73a13b48845792efb884</guid></item><item><title>BlueScope AGM held in shadow of Port Kembla steelworks fatality, minute’s silence held</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/bluescope-agm-fatality-whyalla-gas/106023286</link><description>Shareholders and executives observe a minute’s silence at BlueScope’s AGM for the young worker killed at Port Kembla steelworks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">145511701e866a9689d26c9f84090755</guid></item><item><title>Plan for 24-hour McDonald's near primary school rejected by Bendigo council</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/strathfieldsaye-fast-food-mcdonalds-outlet-rejected/106022544</link><description>Parents in the regional Victorian town of Bendigo celebrate after a planned 24-hour McDonald's development is knocked back by the council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12dea80311680ffb03a0b5fd4650ec26</guid></item><item><title>Sydney waste water likely origin of debris on Central Coast beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/beach-greaseballs-likely-from-sydney-waste-water-system/106022634</link><description>Sydney Water is working to determine the source of high levels of grease and oil that caused debris balls to wash up on beaches across Sydney and the Central Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c33b5671c318dc726c5b28ea01fd417</guid></item><item><title>COP30 decision by South Korea to shut down coal a reckoning for Australian exports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/south-korea-coal-plant-closure-warning-on-australian-exports/106021660</link><description>In a move that has been welcomed by climate campaigners, South Korea has vowed to phase out coal, sparking a warning for Australian exporters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a1e49f91f32ca80234fe2254283c60c</guid></item><item><title>Queensland man to face murder trial over house fire death of Damian Bradley Ramsay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/man-to-face-murder-trial-for-pacific-haven-house-fire/106021440</link><description>A court has heard a man charged with arson over a fatal house fire admitted to lighting the fire and threatened to burn down his own family home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d6f2de016b5c4b6870c67e8f3276a45</guid></item><item><title>Numerous Tasmanian public, Catholic and independent schools to close from Wednesday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/catholic-public-independent-tasmanian-schools-closed-asbestos/106022702</link><description>More than 50 Tasmanian schools will either close or be partially closed from Wednesday in response to ongoing public health concerns relating to asbestos in coloured sand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f7a4638311fad228f17b1ee6e4650f</guid></item><item><title>Remote Aboriginal community of Tjuntjuntjara challenges local government election result</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/tjuntjuntjara-election-dispute/106019700</link><description>A remote Aboriginal corporation lodges a formal dispute over the outcome of a local government election decided by just one vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9ca57d6c316de3bf92b08f85b9f4912</guid></item><item><title>WA Police reveal number plate recognition trial in operation at Westfield Carousel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/number-plate-recognition-westfield-carousel-police-trial/106018682</link><description>Cameras that record the number plates of all the vehicles that enter one of Perth's biggest shopping centres are being used to track criminals, WA police have revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebd7e3fa125d9e1e4cf208cf6aa9b90c</guid></item><item><title>Supreme Court hears narrow scope of disagreement in Dimboola murder trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/dimboola-murder-jodie-hill-thomas-clarke-supreme-court/106024476</link><description>Dimboola woman Jodie Hill's murder trial has begun in the Supreme Court over the death of John Hunter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dd6e868587eca392e4cb66432966732</guid></item><item><title>Senator Fatima Payman calls on prime minister to denounce online trolls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/senator-fatima-payman-calls-on-pm-to-denounce-online-trolls/106024908</link><description>After the man who threatened her life via email was sentenced in court earlier this week, Senator Fatima Payman is being targeted by online abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2ebeb36f39a44d81191de3588d46754</guid></item><item><title>Most restrictive abortion bill in the US being considered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/most-restrictive-abortion-bill-in-the-us-being-considered/106024856</link><description>Restrictions on IUDs and IVF and decades of imprisonment for having an abortion could become the reality for some women living in South Carolina if the legislation passes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ef3cb80551fe490d0f6301954d7ffb7</guid></item><item><title>Woman jailed for stabbing AFP officer with pen at Perth Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/woman-jailed-stabbing-afp-officer-pen-perth-airport/106023694</link><description>A woman who stabbed a federal police officer at Perth Airport with a pen in a "vicious" attack is sentenced to more than two years in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f01fd3e9456814f1e651af4ae78c828b</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos contamination identified in imported coloured sand products</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/asbestos-contamination-identified-/106025112</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45782c7e825f6e9ae891619789b5b041</guid></item><item><title>Are tiger prawns labelled as being Australian, really from Australia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/are-your-australian-tiger-prawns-really-from-australia-/106025136</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b04250e60ba47b3ca2f1c4c23e21254</guid></item><item><title>P-plater in unregistered and unroadworthy vehicle jailed over fatal crash which killed cyclist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/pplater-unregistered-vehicle-killed-cyclist/106024292</link><description>A P-plater in an uninsured, unregistered and unroadworthy vehicle hit and killed a cyclist last year. Today, he was jailed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a77ce2cc2c6e2b469baee49a550b9277</guid></item><item><title>Woman 'devastated' after alleged violent offender released into community without tracker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/gps-tracker-removal-family-domestic-violence/106022824</link><description>The former partner of a man accused of raping and strangling her says she fears for her life after he was released on bail without a GPS tracking device.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3496916b4e2e1736143d100133e58100</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese heralds WA gallium project as 'game changing'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/anthony-albanese-hails-wa-role-in-us-critical-minerals-deal/106024178</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese visits the future West Australian gallium processing plant site, central to the United States critical minerals deal, heralding it as a "game changing" project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c597633a766fbe2ac505dfff6094f877</guid></item></channel></rss>