<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 03:27:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Update your ABC News homepage for more local stories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2020-09-03/update-to-abc-news-homepage/12579988</link><description>We've got an ABC News homepage for you. Adjust your settings for the right mix of local and national news.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">146f1699ce6b1b7420a91b6bb80d0309</guid></item><item><title>The ABC and Four Corners investigated Rupert Murdoch many times. Here's what we found</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2023-09-23/rupert-murdoch-investigated-by-four-corners-what-it-found/102891668</link><description>With a career spanning 70 years, Rupert Murdoch is no stranger to facing the same kind of interviewing and investigative treatment that he has dished out in his media outlets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db2e5063e1852909dda0107e3a9d14af</guid></item><item><title>Call for button battery redesign after new study reveals horrific injuries and fatalities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/button-battery-warning-danger-deaths-lithium-swallow/103986966</link><description>A new study reveals the horrific injuries suffered after swallowing or inserting button batteries but manufacturers aren't prioritising their redesign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46ab5f96ade65908ecf6b7be8673e61f</guid></item><item><title>Reserve Bank restructure closer to reality after Treasurer Jim Chalmers offers olive branch to Angus Taylor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/reserve-bank-restructure-closer-to-reality/104260250</link><description>The Reserve Bank of Australia is a step closer to its biggest restructure in three decades after the treasurer offers an assurance to his Coalition counterpart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e920ec5b24583b8f74962ecc7f9c2585</guid></item><item><title>Does Queensland deserve to be known as the cowboy state?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-10-24/are-queenslanders-a-bunch-of-cowboys-state-election-october-26/104507758</link><description>With the abortion debate making Queensland's election campaign national news, many Australians might be thinking 'cowboy' is a label applying to more than just supporters of the NRL team, writes Matt Eaton.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">964ef8031221c6406a0bac965cfb8856</guid></item><item><title>How police caught the bicycle bandit after almost two decades on the run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-12-21/how-police-caught-the-bicycle-bandit-kym-parsons/104706666</link><description>Over 10 years, the notorious "bicycle bandit" terrorised innocent bank tellers at gunpoint. His identity remained a mystery for almost two decades until police used a game changing forensic technique to unmask the culprit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bf9ebc0e3702a64f3216333b9d6eab9</guid></item><item><title>DNA leads to breakthrough in 1979 cold case murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-03-13/dna-leads-to-breakthrough-in-1979-cold-case-murder/105049878</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bdb48b2c0ddbfedc41a90b7b18ceb4f</guid></item><item><title>Australia's growing cohort of tenants fear they will rent forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-16/australias-growing-tenant-cohort-fear-forever-renting/105127148</link><description>Home ownership rates in Australia have been falling for decades, and with rental vacancies at record lows and prices at historic highs, many fear their dream of owning a home may be out of reach. Some experts say rental caps could help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f35fe439f533ac9522c679c7e37187</guid></item><item><title>Cost of living, housing among key concerns in SA marginal seat of Boothby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/boothby-cost-of-living-federal-election-2025/105190262</link><description>At this year’s federal election, the South Australian seat of Boothby is one of the state’s two marginal seats. As part of the ABC’s “Your Say” campaign, we spoke to residents in the electorate about their biggest concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dfd66b0605d29b960082ff52f18c170</guid></item><item><title>Energy projects in South West WA threaten votes for major federal parties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-21/energy-projects-south-west-wa-federal-election-labor-liberals/105152524</link><description>Australia's two major parties have tied their federal election fates to controversial energy projects in WA's South West where the issues have polarised voters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8962a53de05f0293b3a104690022111a</guid></item><item><title>Mobile coverage is an election issue in regional areas. What's been promised?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-23/telecommunications-mobile-coverage-federal-election-promises/105080674</link><description>For many regional and remote Australians, reliable mobile coverage can be life-saving. They are desperate for both sides of politics to take meaningful action towards eliminating black spots.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ceda72e552d98e5f293d3c037efeefa</guid></item><item><title>NSW politicians will vote on abortion this week. Here's what could be changing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-05-13/nsw-politicians-to-vote-changes-abortion-bill-what-are-they/105282854</link><description>A bill to expand abortion services in New South Wales will face a crucial vote in the lower house this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bcc740aa63aa8c3a693a1d07108ea38</guid></item><item><title>Baby of brain-dead mother Adriana Smith delivered in US state of Georgia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-06-19/adriana-smith-death-baby-born-georgia-abortion-laws/105436824</link><description>Adriana Smith was pronounced brain dead in February but due to Georgia abortion laws, doctors say they were forced to keep her on life support for months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51ad1589a50216ec77880f4209f0255a</guid></item><item><title>Trading in Chaos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-07-21/trading-in-chaos/105555600</link><description>Four Corners is the home of Australian investigative journalism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b78966f2058af840bb9888316b147ea1</guid></item><item><title>Gillick competency, the courts and parental consent: What are the steps for a teenager to get an abortion?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-05/qld-teenage-abortion-gillick-competency-courts/105601718</link><description>According to Australian law, children are empowered to make their own decisions about the healthcare they receive — regardless of parental consent — so long as they fully understand what is being done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24346a7264b5a1d4fa15a95045b675a9</guid></item><item><title>Queensland forensics lab in 'sustained crisis', with 'failure in leadership' leading to toxic culture, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-05/queensland-forensics-lab-dna-bungle-budowle-report/105614062</link><description>It's the second damning report into Queensland's state-run forensics lab to be released in as many days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c97b7b81eccf154b47600d247faaaad</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Supreme Court judge rules 11-year-old girl should be allowed to have abortion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-08-19/queensland-11-year-girl-abortion-allowed-supreme-court/105672370</link><description>The court heard the girl has "repeatedly" expressed the view that she does not want to continue with the pregnancy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">528f94d5509440e200dd604602191683</guid></item><item><title>Environmentalists want new dump site for dredged mud around Magnetic Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-11/magnetic-island-world-heritage-area-dredged-mud/105739090</link><description>Tourists flock to Magnetic Island to see its unique coral reefs, but locals say underwater visibility is getting worse — and some blame dredging.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">402c451164dd97863a3e4caaa889864c</guid></item><item><title>Supreme Court gives Queensland hospital permission to terminate 12yo girl's pregnancy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-13/qld-hospital-gets-court-permission-for-abortion-on-12yo-girl/105770196</link><description>A 12-year-old girl in residential care in Queensland should be allowed to have an abortion, a court rules, after a judge found she was not capable of making the decision herself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86cd5589ba9855a3f68a146a74e238ad</guid></item><item><title>How to pick a champion chicken at the Royal Melbourne Show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-01/how-to-pick-a-champion-chicken-at-the-royal/105841660</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b3dcda59f617c747cdbd847da174251</guid></item><item><title>Tourism operators seek more funding to mitigate algal bloom impact in SA over summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-08/tourism-operators-seek-more-incentives-to-mitigate-algal-bloom/105862594</link><description>Tourism, seafood industry and community representatives are calling for greater funding, education and travel incentives ahead of the release of the South Australian government's upcoming Summer Plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e5b120fcb56d82bd8c6da140631dca</guid></item><item><title>Dolphin on the Pilbara coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-24/dolphin-on-pilbara-coast/104800612</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b832a330a814a05ce02203ec52f5da42</guid></item><item><title>The key role a 'lost' reef is playing in South Australia's algal bloom fight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/native-oyster-reefs-restored-algal-bloom-recovery-sa/105943318</link><description>A marine ecologist's discovery two years ago sparked a restoration project and has become a key element in South Australia's response to a devastating algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6da4b9d6a96705189c11b0f39230daf7</guid></item><item><title>Boys' netball movement gains pace on Sunshine Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-22/sunshine-coast-all-boys-netball-competition/105867122</link><description>From regional Queensland to state level, boys' netball is gaining momentum and reshaping the future of the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6163db43d0ecb3dc1cb9bd8e17a7ebb</guid></item><item><title>Sydney's M4 tunnel shut over fears concrete roofing could fall onto vehicles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-04/sydney-m4-motorway-closed-traffic-gridlock-lengthy-delays/106101312</link><description>Drivers have been stuck in Sydney's M4 tunnel for several hours over fears part of its concrete roofing could tumble onto traffic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b61ce1a4a066050b2fb0af18eb1007dc</guid></item><item><title>Criminals are trying new methods to get drugs into Australia but authorities say they are always watching</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-07/attempted-drug-imports-sea-australia-mothership-smuggling/106073102</link><description>The alleged use of an international livestock ship to smuggle drugs into Western Australia last month prompted a media storm, but one expert says it is just one among a "dizzying variety" of methods criminals are trying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4191a2f6367c22bebf14314f40b9247</guid></item><item><title>Victims of paedophile Ashley Paul Griffith call for more action after review finds he could have been stopped</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-09/ashley-paul-griffith-victims-parents-speak-of-ongoing-trauma/106117326</link><description>The parent of one victim of childcare paedophile Ashley Paul Griffith says they're still dealing with ongoing trauma, as a Queensland review finds his offending could have been stopped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e7daeedbb7310a87eb8e68fbd9d1cab</guid></item><item><title>How long does it take to fix an underperforming school?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-12/boonah-high-agriculture-education-turnaround/105983794</link><description>A Queensland high school has re-engaged students by embedding agriculture into the curriculum and building strong local industry ties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06b4dcb5993bb0060e638f96fbbe9c04</guid></item><item><title>UK's Duke of Marlborough charged with intentional strangulation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/duke-of-marlborough-charged/106155930</link><description>Charles James Spencer-Churchill, 70, who is known as Jamie Blandford, is the 12th Duke of Marlborough, one of Britain's most senior aristocratic families.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cb8793bf68c1b94a68e587165a1594a</guid></item><item><title>Australian man Lamar Ahchee sentenced to 12 years in prison for role in Bali cocaine-smuggling plot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/lamar-achchee-sentenced-12-years-in-jail-cocaine-smuggling/106160268</link><description>An Australian man is sentenced to 12 years in a Bali prison for his role in trafficking cocaine into the country in Lindt chocolate wrappers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a17afa13de67b8c5f7cad4c9dc04de23</guid></item><item><title>Bedford creditors vote to hand over reins to The Disability Trust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/bedford-creditors-vote-in-favour-of-new-operator/105943028</link><description>Creditors have voted to support the sale of Bedford to NDIS provider The Disability Trust, which would guarantee the jobs of 1,100 workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9a922696cb7e31d90763393c14da8bb</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files contain new photo of former prince Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-20/new-photo-former-prince-andrew-mountbatten-windsor-epstein-files/106166672</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor, the former prince, appears in the first tranche of the so-called Epstein files.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6eecd6194d73f15e27e79dd511e68c0</guid></item><item><title>Images removed from Epstein files less than a day after being posted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/images-removed-from-epstein-files-less-than-a-day-after-posted/106167464</link><description>At least 16 Jeffrey Epstein-related files, including a photo of US President Donald Trump, disappear from a US Department of Justice webpage within a day of being posted, with no explanation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1169e04c29c15212ffa478f90262da2</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu nationals celebrate faith and friendship in Bundaberg under the PALM scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-21/vanuatu-workers-sunday-worship-in-bundaberg/106128564</link><description>Moving to another country to provide for your family is not an easy choice but singing, hugs and faith make it easier for these Pacific island workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c95e3f6e5fb06f7cab8d6e5b783370a9</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Heat beats Adelaide Strikers by seven runs, thanks to debutant Tom Balkin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-28/heat-call-on-lightning-fast-debutant-in-rollicking-bbl-win/106182342</link><description>Injury to Shaheen Afridi leaves debutant Tom Balkin to bowl the final over, and the 21-year-old delivers to help Brisbane Heat to a seven-run BBL win over Adelaide Strikers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf24169f767377c226a5fad18d15e2da</guid></item><item><title>Human-operated Tokyo robot venture allows housebound people to work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-31/tokyo-robot-tourism-business-cafe-housebound-workers/106177054</link><description>Ory Yoshifuji's Tokyo business employs housebound individuals to operate robots as waitstaff at a cafe and as personal tour guides in the city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee5510266f87235181771f4e5e3fa9b7</guid></item><item><title>On her 44th birthday, Princess Catherine is quietly reshaping royal life after cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-09/princess-catherine-wales-birthday-44-reset-normal-royal-life/106206914</link><description>Catherine turns 44 today as she resets royal life with fewer public appearances, tighter boundaries and a strong emphasis on family life — a choice shaped by loss, illness and the pressure of being next in line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3759ffc377b5207d302e17af450cd6f</guid></item><item><title>United Employment collapse leaves disability workers $6 million short in missing pay, super and entitlements</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-15/united-employment-ndis-labour-company-collapse-millions-owing/106148800</link><description>Up to 500 workers are fighting to recoup pay, super and entitlements after the collapse of a large disability support provider operating in New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b24742333e24e23481242e1515f727f</guid></item><item><title>Twenty-four parkruns in 24 hours no sweat for Albany runner Ben Castlehow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-16/ben-castlehow-ran-24-parkruns-in-24-hours-in-albany/106229186</link><description>An Albany man runs roughly three marathons in laps of a hilly parkrun to raise funds for a charity that helped him through a tough time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4d7ae86cfa2992a2d74c0dc629c557b</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Police seize firearms, drugs in Townsville bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-19/queensland-police-seize-firearms-drugs-in-townsville-bust/106244838</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a2c4c7945220150fcc8231b476b56cd</guid></item><item><title>Prince Harry's court battle against British tabloids reaches final chapter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/prince-harry-returns-to-court-in-battle-with-british-tabloids/106246678</link><description>Prince Harry has returned to court in London in his third and final attempt to tame the British tabloids through the legal system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">370456cf33716b09f3e36a9a21e41ba5</guid></item><item><title>How lifting gave me back the power to feel good at sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/how-powerlifting-gave-me-back-the-power-to-feel-good-at-sport/106234088</link><description>As a child, Julie "wasn't one of the sporty kids". A safe gym environment and then a supportive powerlifting community helped her realise that wasn't actually true.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2abbef65f571e75069d3d1abdc6f375</guid></item><item><title>Women's captain departs football club after men's offensive Silly Saturday costumes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/box-hill-north-fc-womens-captain-leaves-club-after-men-behaviour/106190266</link><description>A women's senior football captain has stepped away from her local club after photos of the senior men's leadership team were posted online during their "Silly Saturday" post-season celebrations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ffb103fdb7886c68801e2562aeef8ca</guid></item><item><title>One Nation's ambitious plan raises stakes for major parties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-20/pauline-hanson-one-nation-polling-state-election-mainstream/106244024</link><description>While she's made no secret of her desire to eventually unseat Anthony Albanese, the One Nation leader's immediate electoral strategy is to gain ground at upcoming state elections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9378de660f955ea3ba520a0ae352651f</guid></item><item><title>Trash and treasure trike proves powerful tool for brain health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/trash-treasure-trike-broken-hill-brian-slater-brain-health/106234034</link><description>Brian Slater, 77, is heeding advice to "use it or lose it" as he devotes his retirement to cognitive challenges that keep his mind healthy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b18a19aba6c1c38aadd2e1cbd0a8bc9</guid></item><item><title>Sheep under the eye of AI</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/using-ai-to-count-sheep/106250690</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c5af840e880887503748d0dd1f0eb2a</guid></item><item><title>Crime gangs restocking shops 'up to 10 times a day' with illegal cigarettes and vapes, WA police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-21/behind-the-scenes-of-wa-s-illegal-tobacco-business-model/106252960</link><description>WA's police commissioner says the restocking is happening faster than authorities can seize the products, as tobacco black market violence escalates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c85e3ad402b68eddf68bb31ca5929a65</guid></item><item><title>Former Broome pub manager jailed for six years over rape of staff member</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-23/broome-pub-manager-stewart-burchell-sentenced/106037710</link><description>Stewart Patrick Burchell is jailed for six years, found guilty by jury trial of raping a staff member and indecently assaulting several others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfd31eca85588a6872ef20bdd2788feb</guid></item><item><title>Prince Harry takes on the Daily Mail in High Court privacy showdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/prince-harry-duke-sussex-daily-mail-court-case-principle-anger/106261250</link><description>The Duke of Sussex takes on the publisher he believes poisoned his childhood, his marriage, and his peace of mind in a legal battle driven by anger as well as principle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0734b45ec2433eaff1d6c9115bfcbc11</guid></item><item><title>Fortescue breaks ground on Pilbara's first wind farm in move to decarbonise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-24/fortescue-begins-construction-on-pilbaras-first-wind-farm/106245178</link><description>A mining company in Western Australia's Pilbara region is one step closer to decarbonising its iron ore production after starting construction on the region's first wind farm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5760d1f6700c62fb3199b3a3d87dbc2f</guid></item><item><title>How the Perth Scorchers sit alone as Australia's greatest Big Bash League franchise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-27/perth-scorchers-dynasty-big-bash-league-greatest-team/106270210</link><description>Six titles in 15 seasons is an extraordinary record, but what is the secret of the Perth Scorchers' incredible success?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cd7f9b19a171993894a9d15386d5c7f</guid></item><item><title>'Predatory' former Logan teacher jailed for child sex offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-29/predatory-teacher-jason-seung-hak-lee-logan-child-sex-offences/106283910</link><description>The former Logan teacher, 30, has been handed a 5-year sentence after pleading guilty to multiple child sex offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8da2c6ce2847559254b32f4c3916b7f</guid></item><item><title>Shoppers remember 'old days' at grocery store that has operated since late 19th century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-30/shoppers-memories-at-maclean-grocery-store/106093338</link><description>A New South Wales grocery store has been operating since before there was refrigeration, electricity and even Vegemite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13022bd7c8867c23fb979d67f3523425</guid></item><item><title>Beckham saga is an age-old heartache with an uncomfortably modern twist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/virginia-trioli-template/106252054</link><description>Cutting ties with your parents isn't a new phenomenon but having it painstakingly documented across social media is a contemporary problem.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab0df9a75b077d3b19090787e9d7ff93</guid></item><item><title>Fruit tree netting installations to increase over next decade as heatwaves persist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/heatwaves-mean-netting-installations-for-fruit-crops-to-increase/106278420</link><description>Sales of netting to protect fruit crops from extreme weather have increased in the past five years as researchers warn heatwaves will continue to impact agriculture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">687d8d67030a8be834892249633a7b71</guid></item><item><title>Farmers reeling as estimated $20 million in livestock perish in Victorian fires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/victoria-fires-20-million-dollars-in-livestock-losses/106286870</link><description>The fires wiped out swathes of farmland and killed tens of thousands of livestock.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f4f9c7afa70e9016b09cfa15b85d082</guid></item><item><title>The surprising history behind the Australian Open men's singles trophy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/mary-mcgillivray-australian-open-warwick-vase-history/106245576</link><description>Carlos Alcaraz and Novak Djokovic go head-to-head today in the men's singles final. Not many people know they are competing for a trophy based on an Ancient Roman artefact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80fb56ea79c2fd74f6fe1dfd873e866c</guid></item><item><title>Matildas legend Sarah Walsh says South Korea boycott would be 'devastating' for Asian Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/south-korea-asian-cup-boycott-would-be-devastating/106293118</link><description>Asian Cup organisers say they are hopeful the South Korean women's team will partake in next month's tournament despite threats of a boycott due to "harsh and unreasonable conditions" under the nation's federation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75e3b8d87e450e562dd01bacf28f760c</guid></item><item><title>Where in your home is best to set up a work space?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/where-is-best-to-set-up-home-office-workspace/106279734</link><description>From garages to cupboards, we asked experts on things to consider before you choose where to set up a home office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">737207bd9fb86c2996d3d75fd5c289aa</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic praises Carlos Alcaraz after Spaniard wins first Australian Open title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australian-open-carlos-alcaraz-novak-djokovic-final/106293372</link><description>Despite the hollow feeling of defeat, 24-time major winner Novak Djokovic heaps praise on Carlos Alcaraz following the Spaniard's history-making Australian Open victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87c4c2aa20dbeaeb5ed2b49f3037427b</guid></item><item><title>Norwegian rape trial rocks the royal family and grips the public</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/norways-monarchy-braces-as-princess-son-rape-trial-begins/106290156</link><description>This week, Marius Borg Høiby, the stepson of Norway's future king, will face trial on a string of rape, drug and abuse charges, and it has the whole country talking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9ca20ad3386ff60069b66e182bbc9d0</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Ferguson called Epstein a 'legend', told him to 'just marry me', new emails show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/fergie-emails-epstein-files-legend/106297980</link><description>The former Duchess of York's friendship with the late sex offender is back in the spotlight after the latest release of documents about the Epstein case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e97603600426faf0b2647f43f40bee8</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroo Island's sea lions.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/kangaroo-island-s-sea-lions/106152240</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6da9b03c3506f606888829ac56721a3</guid></item><item><title>Citizen scientists look for hope as the algal bloom persists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/kangaroo-island-citizen-scientists-algal-bloom-fight-sa/106131388</link><description>On Kangaroo Island – where the bloom has washed death ashore for almost a year – a group of citizen scientists are focusing their efforts on "what’s still out there".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86498380fc9493692055ee20a3b6a5ed</guid></item><item><title>What I wish my manager knew about my mental health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/mental-health-workplaces-what-i-learnt/106055796</link><description>I've spent my working life in what I like to call the "honesty gap". This kind of creative disclosure became a necessary art form to maintain my work life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47eccac2b29345ae6a93d60b94b9933b</guid></item><item><title>Federal parliament condemns attempted bombing at Perth/Boorloo Invasion Day rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/lidia-thorpe-motion-invasion-day-alleged-bomb-attack-parliament/106298440</link><description>Federal parliament officially condemns the attempted bomb attack at Perth's Invasion Day rally on its first sitting day, acknowledging the harm caused to the First Nations community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0103b72fa857b451dd3fc06e27901fd9</guid></item><item><title>Austin Appelbee speaks after 'superhuman' swim off Quindalup to save family in Geographe Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/teen-speaks-after-saving-family-in-geographe-bay/106298798</link><description>A WA mother says asking her teenage son to swim 4 kilometres through rough seas to get help after their family was swept out to sea, was "one of the hardest decisions" she has ever made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">498dc56b9b0ded2fcee4d47f8ec5eafd</guid></item><item><title>Central Coast Mariners star Annalise Rasmussen signs with Italian powerhouse Juventus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/annalise-rasmussen-central-coast-mariners-signs-with-juventus/106300846</link><description>A-League leading goal scorer Annalise Rasmussen leaves the competition immediately to join Italian powerhouse Juventus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5824f89d8ddce116ae033a1edcb9862</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Ferguson offered Jeffrey Epstein woman with 'great body' after his release from prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/sarah-ferguson-emails-to-jeffrey-epstein-revealed/106302466</link><description>Emails contained in the Epstein files show former British royal Sarah Ferguson told the convicted child sex offender she knew a "single" woman with a "great body" he should meet, weeks after his 2009 release from prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8216f6d90bb222bab0daa5d9f345c016</guid></item><item><title>Art exhibitions to see this summer, from Ron Mueck to Hobart Current and Olafur Eliasson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/art-exhibitions-ron-mueck-hobart-current-olafur-eliasson/106295866</link><description>From Aussie expat Ron Mueck's hyper-realistic sculptures and Icelandic Danish artist Olafur Eliasson's thought-provoking installations to the best contemporary artists in Tasmania, here are three exhibitions to see.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">298caa8ff84eba3f4959fca7878c20aa</guid></item><item><title>Humpty Doo locals help relocate crocodile from side of highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/humpty-doo-locals-help-relocate-crocodile-from-side-of-highway/106304366</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3e0a3ff3c023e3ab1ba031de41c6426</guid></item><item><title>Back to school for Northern Territory construction workers after Charles Darwin University blunder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/back-to-school-for-territory-construction-workers/106306240</link><description>Dozens of carpentry apprentices in the Northern Territory will be forced back to TAFE after an error saw them declared qualified to work on construction projects without completing required units of study.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a9b8af3f0adf0f58a66327083cef79e</guid></item><item><title>Albanese, Ley condemn alleged act of terror targeting Indigenous protesters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/albanese-ley-condemn-alleged-invasion-rally-terror-act/106309170</link><description>The prime minister and opposition leader have both condemned the alleged attempted bombing of an Invasion Day rally more than a week ago, after police revealed it was being prosecuted as a terror incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5627852046870a17972ecd39ceb5004e</guid></item><item><title>Gus Lamont disappearance from Oak Park Station near Yunta: What has happened so far</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/timeline-of-gus-lamont-oak-park-disappearance/106309554</link><description>It is now more than four months since Gus Lamont went missing from his family's home in South Australia's outback, with the case being declared a major crime on Thursday. Here's what has happened so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c458d64bdef26badd7b278d4e3d5058</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds defeat Jamaica in first netball Test match in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/diamonds-defeat-jamaica-in-adelaide/106311692</link><description>The Diamonds made a flying start with the initial six goals in a comprehensive 72-41 victory at the Adelaide Entertainment Centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be741f4d1fb677fd340efe1016d77511</guid></item><item><title>NSW Liberal leader Kellie Sloane talks Chris Minns, polls, slogan bans and Bondi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/nsw-liberals-kellie-sloane-talks-minns-polls-slogans-and-bondi/106310818</link><description>The leader of the NSW opposition says the trait behind Premier Chris Minns's popularity is also his greatest weakness, declaring the Coalition is "absolutely in the game" to win next year's state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">799edd3b53920580ddc28a03d66a91d5</guid></item><item><title>Major search underway for missing man after empty boat found off Gold Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/missing-man-search-after-empty-boat-found-off-gold-coast/106313582</link><description>A cross-border search has begun for a man after an unoccupied boat was found about 50 kilometres off the Gold Coast early on Friday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35fac26af162794bc4dd4fcc9dcce89d</guid></item><item><title>Gus Lamont's grandparents 'absolutely devastated' by major crime declaration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/gus-lamont-grandparents-release-statement/106314122</link><description>The grandparents of missing four-year-old boy Gus Lamont say the family has "cooperated fully with the investigation and want nothing more than to find Gus and reunite him with his mum and dad".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61b66feeae95a94497e72683ac842ff0</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia's government directs education funds to meals program as teachers struggle on low wages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/indonesia-government-directs-education-funds-to-free-meals/106307002</link><description>Temporary teachers in Indonesia paid low wages criticise a government decision to direct one third of yearly education funding to the president's flagship free meals program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06d0ac084c483586e077bca8379edf61</guid></item><item><title>RecipeTin Eats' Nagi Maehashi is normalising taking time off for pets. Here's why that matters.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/recipetineats-nagi-maehashi-time-off-work-care-for-dog-dozer/106313752</link><description>Experts say our pets have become such an important part of our lives that it's important to take a step back from responsibilities, if possible, when they are sick or dying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9cbd7b56d7377cd2c066ce8db744bca</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Snook, The Newsreader and Bring Her Back triumph at AACTA Awards — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/aacta-awards-2026-live-blog-winners-sarah-snook-celeste-barber/106295178</link><description>Australia's answer to the Oscars — the AACTAs — lit up the Gold Coast tonight, with horror Bring Her Back and The Narrow Road to the Deep North dominating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">473742d5b25ca33648f2c7c0647748d5</guid></item><item><title>Latest Epstein files documents reveal links to multiple monarchies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/epstein-files-rock-global-monarchies/106316380</link><description>The latest release of the so-called Epstein files has revealed the convicted child sex offender was in contact with members of — and people close to — monarchies across Europe and the Middle East.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96f0f632ab3802486dbc61abcadd585b</guid></item><item><title>How Super Bowl half-time moments became flashpoints from the 'wardrobe malfunction' to caged kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/super-bowl-half-time-show-janet-jackson-justin-timberlake/106307184</link><description>For a show that lasts roughly 13 minutes, the Super Bowl half-time performance has fuelled decades of conversation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5ff29a641957847844fbaf70655c0c1</guid></item><item><title>United States send India a T20 World Cup scare before Suryakumar Yadav settles hosts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/india-survives-massive-scare-from-minnow-us-in-t20-world-cup/106318592</link><description>India is briefly left reeling at 6-67 against an underdog United States team, but captain Suryakumar Yadav helps the hosts avoid a horror start at the T20 World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b4cfa036b792e7378042063ed8c7311</guid></item><item><title>Piper James's parents say dingo management reform needed to prevent further deaths on K'gari</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/piper-james-parents-call-for-more-dingo-warnings-on-kgari/106317706</link><description>Piper James's parents are leaving Australia with their daughter's ashes and a determination to ensure she hasn't died in vain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ccf19d954997c8989ad2001fd781236</guid></item><item><title>Search effort winds down for missing Gold Coast fisherman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/search-effort-winds-down-for-missing-gold-coast-fisherman/106317158</link><description>The cross-border search for a 44-year-old fisherman missing off the Gold Coast for three days has been scaled back and transitioned into a recovery phase after his boat and EPIRB were found but there were no signs of life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d96380fd0253d981572e15eef15233a9</guid></item><item><title>Two Australians reach big air final after tense qualifying runs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-08/winter-olympics-day-two-live-blog-updates/106319558</link><description>Olympic medallist Tess Coady and fellow Australian Meila Stalker reach the snowboard big air final, after a dramatic day where American superstar Lindsey Vonn crashes in women's downhill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eabe2255ae86c9fbbf5b0a4f952c27ac</guid></item><item><title>Coalition's rushed reunification does not solve their respective branding problems</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/coalition-reunification-liberals-nationals-sussan-ley/106304664</link><description>The Coalition has reunited, but the new agreement does not address underlying party tensions nor the surging fragmentation of the right.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4015c0b9e86f13b0cbf1a5cc8413b8c5</guid></item><item><title>Five simple steps to saving cash (while still having a life)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/finance-tips-saving-money-new-year/106303046</link><description>Saving money is not about beating yourself up. It's also not about depriving yourself of all sources of joy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59b760f5e77d65279a49b68106aa5c6d</guid></item><item><title>Deua River Valley and Cobargo still rebuilding six years after Black Summer bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/cobargo-deua-river-still-rebuilding-after-black-summer-bushfires/106273804</link><description>Residents who lived through the 2019-20 bushfires on the NSW South Coast say this summer's fires triggered traumatic memories, and highlighted the recovery and resilience projects that remain unfinished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75a6395d574e8ce915a53455bd5abe17</guid></item><item><title>Aussie stars as Seahawks use ferocious defence to claim Super Bowl win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/super-bowl-lx-live-blog-seahawks-vs-patriots-bad-bunny/106320762</link><description>The Seattle Seahawks overawe the New England Patriots in Super Bowl LX as punter Michael Dickson becomes the second ever Australian NFL champion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fad6557763c143875756ac2daf86b7c</guid></item><item><title>Search ends for 'very loved' Gold Coast fisherman Ash Haigh after almost five days lost at sea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/search-ends-loved-gold-coast-fisherman-ash-haigh/106321162</link><description>Queensland Police has suspended the cross-border search for missing Gold Coast fisherman Ash Haigh after an extensive air and sea operation found no signs of life, with his sister describing him as a "very loved" family man.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b728597ddaf78153709b4ea9a825a3a8</guid></item><item><title>Police and protesters clash in Sydney rally against Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit to Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/crowds-protest-israeli-president-isaac-herzog-in-australia/106321716</link><description>Thousands of people attend protests across the country against Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit to Australia in the wake of the Bondi terror attack, with demonstrators in Sydney sprayed with pepper spray and led away in handcuffs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf9c9e3b1bab97471914ed882c6b5903</guid></item><item><title>ASIO was told about Bondi shooter's terrorist links years before attack, former spy claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/bondi-shooting-spy-claims-told-asio-terror-links-four-corners/106306092</link><description>The former undercover agent spied on the Akrams when he infiltrated a Sydney IS terror cell for Australia's intelligence agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38e7d75b35ff2d3c4a5b6be5b9bb9d73</guid></item><item><title>'Massive' Indonesian ghost barge washes up on tiny Torres Strait island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-09/mystery-indonesian-ghost-barge-washed-up-in-torres-strait/106323116</link><description>The barge drifted into Australian waters from Indonesia after breaking from its moorings during bad weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08b39ef063e5e2f00075ab3cf9dbea37</guid></item><item><title>First national plan to address violence against Indigenous women and children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/first-nations-national-plan-domestic-violence/106321570</link><description>The first standalone national plan to tackle domestic violence against First Nations women and children was "hard fought for by Aboriginal women", an advocate says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">439229df164e08d1955a3db80571a298</guid></item><item><title>Ghislaine Maxwell will only talk if Donald Trump grants clemency, lawyer says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/ghislaine-maxwell-will-only-talk-if-trump-grants-clemency/106324720</link><description>The jailed accomplice of sex predator Jeffrey Epstein refuses to answer questions for the US Congress — but her lawyer says she will cooperate if granted clemency by the president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">204920be92b87248239c7364a66b65c0</guid></item><item><title>DNA breakthrough uncovers link between cold-case sexual assaults on Central Coast beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/central-coast-sexual-assault-cold-cases-dna-breakthrough/106324982</link><description>Police say they have identified a vehicle suspected to have been driven by a man who sexually assaulted a number of women on the Central Coast between 1997 and 2000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42bd8e57df2c6392230a1651955e40e4</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026 quick guide: What to watch on Day 4, Tuesday, February 10</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/winter-olympics-2026-daily-guide-day-4matt-graham-jakara-anthony/106320694</link><description>Find out what's on at the Winter Olympics in Milan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c39e879c6be4500d56c80aa209f85717</guid></item><item><title>Sydney man avoids jail over 'abhorrent' social media posts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nsw-man-avoids-jail-over-threatening-pm-via-social-media-posts/106326690</link><description>A Sydney man who made "abhorrent" social media posts that promoted sexual violence and threatened the prime minister has been spared time in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17d442d03f2268671f08f95e7ebe2047</guid></item><item><title>Shark filmed in deep Antarctic waters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/shark-filmed-in-deep-antarctic-waters/106321640</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4eb3f0f8027a13b7cb77a572c9acacff</guid></item><item><title>Cam Bolton fractures neck as training falls rule two Aussies out of Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/winter-olympics-2026-live-milano-cortina-moguls-ice-hockey/106326694</link><description>Australia's Cam Bolton and Misaki Vaughan are ruled out of the Games after training falls, while reigning Olympic gold medallist Jakara Anthony advances to the women's moguls final at the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf10d0c49b40e45eace54bd9ee12cefa</guid></item><item><title>Celine Cremer search in Arthur River finds more bones and missing backpacker's car key</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/car-key-teeth-found-search-celine-cremer-tasmania/106323260</link><description>Tasmania Police say a car key found in the Arthur River has been "formally verified" as belonging to missing backpacker Celine Cremer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f44f7b3c1d64c6fe98c04e84cabd033d</guid></item><item><title>Police warn against 'false hope' as cold case search bones identified as 'non‑human'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/bones-found-in-yatina-search-not-human/106325728</link><description>Bone fragments found during a private search for evidence relating to the disappearance of two girls in 1973 are "not human remains", according to police, who have issued a public warning against actions that create "false hope".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8578a06110098fdaac062e5d7e5de7e0</guid></item><item><title>Three key moments in police clashes with Sydney protesters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-10/nsw-police-israel-herzog-protest-town-hall-key-moments/106325680</link><description>Competing narratives have emerged from NSW Police and protesters who were at Monday night's demonstration near Sydney's Town Hall. ABC NEWS Verify has gathered footage and spoken to witnesses in an early attempt to examine what happened in detail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55bfcaef3544b431846d0937470d213b</guid></item><item><title>Protesters were punched, pushed, and arrested but were NSW Police actions excessive?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/verify-police-use-of-force-town-hall-protest/106328358</link><description>What is reasonable? It's a question being asked by some after footage of clashes in Sydney's CBD, during a rally against Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc032833c827cf116d697c6b10faca22</guid></item><item><title>How to reduce loneliness while working remotely</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/how-to-reduce-loneliness-while-working-remotely/106286338</link><description>Working remotely can be a lonely experience. Here's what you can do about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07ee38b05fb1af72edee6be374ac35ed</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor resigns from Liberal frontbench ahead of expected leadership spill — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/federal-politics-estimates-albanese-ley-herzog/106328310</link><description>Angus Taylor has resigned from the shadow frontbench ahead of an expected Liberal leadership spill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9652a4c3a8e2cd737e83d0b30398df6</guid></item><item><title>Milano Cortina 2026 is the most gender-equal Winter Olympics ever, aside from Nordic Combined</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/winter-olympics-2026-milan-cortina-nordic-combined-inequality/105991114</link><description>Nordic Combined is the only sport at any Olympic Games — summer and winter — that does not have an event for women. It's an omission that is putting the entire future of the sport at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1a0f1fcfce4eb1284b220db9b93d2fd</guid></item><item><title>Perth Festival opens with outdoor music, light sculptures and stories shared via old red telephone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/perth-festival-opens/106328574</link><description>Australia's longest running arts event, the Perth Festival, began on the weekend with Humans of New York-style videos in which locals tell their stories using an old red telephone on a bridge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">471448dd08cd988b876b0d8d841cb742</guid></item><item><title>Dinosaur dig on Victoria's Bass Coast uncovers more than 60 bones and fossils</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/dinosaur-dig-at-inverloch-finds-bones-and-fossils/105904132</link><description>A collection of more than 60 dinosaur bones and fossils are unearthed from rocks at the site of a fossil dig in Victoria's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d67f1ab883871846b55d6387f0f8bd4a</guid></item><item><title>New video sheds light on beginning of altercation between police officers and Town Hall protester</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/-white-shirt-man-town-hall-protests-punched-new-video/106332094</link><description>A new video filmed by a bystander and shared with ABC NEWS Verify shows the full minute before two police officers began punching a protester, shedding light on the beginning of the altercation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4fecc044fc46d6003450c9200ac8eba</guid></item><item><title>Australian dollar reaches '40-year high' against Japan's yen, as cheap holidays fuel tourism surge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/australian-dollar-japanese-yen-currency-exchange-rate-tourism/106332346</link><description>Australia's exchange rate with Japan has grown increasingly favourable to tourists, which have surged to record numbers and topped more than one million visitors in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7abbc35d9096aae897d046e36ccf9990</guid></item><item><title>RBA deputy governor defends central bank from critics, wonders if Australia is more inflation-prone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/rba-deputy-governor-says-rba-not-criticise-government-policy/106331502</link><description>RBA deputy governor Andrew Hauser says central banks should not criticise normal government spending choices, but he wonders if Australia's economy is more inflation-prone because it is so finely balanced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f806f14f928362b28b219b82a640327b</guid></item><item><title>Labor tries again on super taxes, but yet to secure Greens support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/labor-tries-again-on-super-taxes/106331524</link><description>A second attempt to raise taxes on high super balances has been presented to parliament, but will require the support of the Greens to secure Senate passage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a466ab31df35bf825a2dc9c0feee1d03</guid></item><item><title>PM condemns 'white supremacy ideology' behind alleged Invasion Day terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-11/prime-minister-closing-the-gap-speech/106332998</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has condemned the "racism and hatred" and "white supremacy ideology" behind the alleged terrorist attack on the Invasion Day rally in Borloo/Perth last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e3643c30243d9459a9602b299a97cc4</guid></item><item><title>Britney Spears sells rights to music catalogue in reported $281m deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/britney-sells-rights-music-catalogue-primary-wave/106333696</link><description>Spears is the latest music star to sell the rights to their work, a decade after the release of her ninth and last studio album.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46d37ff06c7881b67f6362f876d81145</guid></item><item><title>Military response to alleged cartel drone incursion briefly closes El Paso Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/faa-closes-airspace-around-el-paso-airport/106333810</link><description>US officials say a sudden 10-day ban came into effect around El Paso International Airport after cartel drones from nearby Mexico breached American airspace.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06473436525f8abf18f0d4e972c40d40</guid></item><item><title>Several Liberals considering their options as race for leadership heats up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/angus-taylor-supporters-sussan-ley-liberal-leadership-spill/106333642</link><description>Angus Taylor's decision to quit the front bench ahead of an expected leadership spill has several Liberals considering whether to throw their hat in the ring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bba6b7e2bc707e5854d76d47b7af8765</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor is moving to challenge Sussan Ley — but not on his terms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/angus-taylor-sussan-ley-leadership-timing-not-wanted/106331132</link><description>Angus Taylor was holidaying in Europe when his colleagues began manoeuvring to topple Sussan Ley. A leadership spill this week wasn't what he or Sussan Ley wanted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32d6f00ceb18364ee804ea3ff647cbdf</guid></item><item><title>Transparency concerns as Bougainville's Panguna mine that sparked civil war on path to reopen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/bougainville-signs-secretive-deal-to-reopen-panguna-mine/106331778</link><description>The Autonomous Bougainville Government signs a secretive deal to reopen the huge Panguna gold and copper mine that sparked a catastrophic civil war three decades ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a5ff00e0503cc102c30c6e22dae858</guid></item><item><title>The Antarctic landscape around Wilkes.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/ice-pan/106325710</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed39452a4bc4f2e1b38930e52f5444d7</guid></item><item><title>Australia's toxic legacy at Wilkes Station in Antarctica</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/wilkes-station-in-antarctica-a-toxic-legacy/106281888</link><description>The ABC has been given rare access to an abandoned Australian base in Antarctica that continues to pose a threat to the environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86fbd4ded36d272a381c32bb0d71bd55</guid></item><item><title>Old Bureau of Meteorology website still getting thousands of clicks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/old-bom-website-drawing-traffic-months-after-new-page-launch/106326812</link><description>The new BOM website is still drawing criticism, with 400,000 users turning to the old site, despite $1.15 million in recent updates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6571b8e0e99bb64c79240519d9e09619</guid></item><item><title>A look at the ballistic missile program Iran refuses to negotiate on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/iran-ballistic-missile-program-weapons-us-talks-trump/106307798</link><description>Iran has spent decades building the largest and most diverse ballistic missile stockpile in the Middle East and is refusing US demands to put limits on the weapons program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43b81c86e32420037a6e9d60aa99108f</guid></item><item><title>Animal abuse charge takes one year as RSPCA prosecutions in Queensland drastically decline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/queensland-rspca-drop-in-prosecutions-animal-cruelty/106277220</link><description>A man has been charged with animal cruelty a year after neighbours first made a complaint to the RSPCA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cd8515cd059d1ed39c4f1b8f6e3e75d</guid></item><item><title>Lando Norris quickest on day one of F1 preseason test, Oscar Piastri drives well and Max Verstappen impresses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/f1-preseason-test-bahrain-norris-piastri-verstappen/106333906</link><description>McLaren's Formula 1 world champion Lando Norris was fastest on the first day of preseason testing in Bahrain, but Max Verstappen and Red Bull caught the attention with pace and plenty of laps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba0e6f82ba0e8d4236049cdf992c4cb9</guid></item><item><title>Canada school shooter identified as 18-year-old woman Jesse Van Rootselaar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/canadian-shooter-identified-in-school-attack/106333992</link><description>Police identify the person who carried out a school massacre in a remote Canadian community as an 18-year-old woman with mental health issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3aa7b080fb4f452119e946dd95e8524</guid></item><item><title>Live: Senior Liberal says party at 'change or die' moment ahead of vote on leadership tomorrow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/federal-politics-live-blog-sussan-ley/106333952</link><description>Angus Taylor has confirmed he will challenge Opposition Leader Sussan Ley for the leadership at the meeting. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c870442734b3073dc8ba7593b59edcb</guid></item><item><title>"We are so proud": Virginia Giuffre's brother speaks to the ABC</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/virginia-giuffre-s-brother-speaks-to-the-abc/106333504</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">915807d53e98dcc971fc5f788216a2ce</guid></item><item><title>Pam Bondi grilled over Epstein files as survivors express fury over redactions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/pam-bondi-faces-congress-questions-over-epstein-files/106329688</link><description>US Attorney-General Pam Bondi faces furious questions over the censorship of names in the Epstein files at a heated hearing before a committee of Congress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f6370664d2895327e9152794883f228</guid></item><item><title>Multiple people rescued in Alice Springs, one still stranded, as town inundated with floodwater</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/alice-springs-flooding/106334186</link><description>Northern Territory emergency services are still working to reach one person isolated by flooding in Alice Springs, after rescuing multiple people this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">974987dd658c3b905e9414c4680b93fd</guid></item><item><title>Dispute over West Bank football pitch sparks international campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/west-bank-football-pitch-at-the-centre-of-a-dispute/106325786</link><description>A campaign to save a West Bank football pitch from demolition has gone global. The sport's most powerful bodies, as well as social media influencers, have intervened to pressure Israeli authorities to reconsider its destruction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">833c5b5cb80156058addeda78d62d0e6</guid></item><item><title>Backpackers and migrants reliant on employers at 'high risk' of harassment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/temporary-migrant-worker-threat-workplace-harrassment/106310972</link><description>Temporary migrants reliant on visas are at high risk of workplace harassment, according to the Migrant Justice Institute.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e458e22a0f3082d857fd1868caa83d1</guid></item><item><title>Mackay MP who crossed floor to oppose LNP ban on abortion debate defends actions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/nigel-dalton-crosses-floor-abortion-debate/106334698</link><description>Mackay MP Nigel Dalton crossed the floor on Tuesday to vote with Katter's Australian Party to end a parliamentary ban on abortion debate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7af1877d708465b9f166d5233952c8b6</guid></item><item><title>Albemarle's lithium refinery in WA's South West placed on care and maintenance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/albemarle-kemerton-lithium-refinery-shut-down/106334822</link><description>A multi-billion-dollar lithium refinery in WA's South West has been shut down, affecting about 275 workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5062fb4ce50ee697f9ff892aa55a778c</guid></item><item><title>What young people think of One Nation's rising popularity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/what-young-people-think-of-one-nation/106330036</link><description>Recent opinion polls have found that, for the first time, One Nation is the second-most popular party with voters, overtaking the Coalition. So what do teenagers think of One Nation and do they still trust the major parties?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf4dfc3768ab9cb8e02d5cdd6d73aba9</guid></item><item><title>Warrnambool pub fined $150k for numerous gambling regulation breaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/warrnambool-pub-fined-150000-for-gambling-regulation-breaches/106334576</link><description>The breaches included three instances of failing to interact with a patron showing signs of distress that may have related to gambling harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d00408e0652d27652cac54ce09ebfb21</guid></item><item><title>Labor releases audio of Liberal MP backtracking on $495 million cost of living policy at private event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-12/labor-releases-audio-of-liberal-backtrack/106334676</link><description>South Australia's Treasurer says the Liberal Party has secretly dumped its major $495 million policy less than six weeks out from the state election, with the Opposition arguing it has to wind back Labor's tax due to state budget blowouts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41c94a52edb47ae2f974cc0fddf1c2cb</guid></item></channel></rss>