<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 10:16:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Prime minister and SA premier announce $800 million deal for 17,000 new homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/prime-minister-and-sa-premier-announce-800m-housing-deal/106290888</link><description>Funding for water infrastructure, urban renewal projects and first-home buyer schemes has been announced in a partnership between the Commonwealth and the state government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f79ccb35961ad839a0f5eeea304cfbeb</guid></item><item><title>Journalist Don Lemon charged with federal civil rights crimes over anti-ICE church protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/journalist-don-lemon-is-charged-with-federal-civil-rights-crimes/106290910</link><description>Former CNN news anchor Don Lemon enters a not guilty plea and is released from custody after being arrested during an anti-ICE protest he says he was covering as an independent journalist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9930505d4a6f8af7be82ef6df10510b6</guid></item><item><title>Darwin Lord Mayor Peter Styles says NT Electoral Commission lost his election donations disclosure information</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/nt-darwin-lord-mayor-peter-styles-ntec-lost-donations-return/106289926</link><description>Darwin's Lord Mayor, Peter Styles, says the Northern Territory Electoral Commission lost an envelope containing his campaign donations disclosure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca8f7ab8f3d62b5b023928d665cd97c3</guid></item><item><title>Charity founder Yas Daniel Matbouly charged over alleged sexual assault, rape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/qld-police-charge-gold-coast-charity-founder-yas-daniel-matbouly/106287188</link><description>The 50-year-old founder of the Serving Our People charity, headquartered on the Gold Coast, has been charged with more than 50 offences following investigations into multiple allegations of sexual assault.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f8ca087a6732ef462d52911ae32c23e</guid></item><item><title>First Nations people say 'silence' on alleged Perth bomb attack weighs heavily</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/perth-bomb-attack-analysis-first-nations-people/106289032</link><description>Underwhelming public responses in the wake of the alleged attack on an Invasion Day rally in Perth leave First Nations people across Australia feeling their "pain matters less".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26210817d2dec571fe2f10b0a8a13636</guid></item><item><title>Woman found outside Woodlands house with life-threatening injuries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/woman-critical-after-woodlands-assault/106291092</link><description>A 44-year-old woman is rushed to hospital with life-threatening injuries after allegedly being stabbed at a home in suburban Perth overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b701a1983ebb4946f7cc5acd315121b</guid></item><item><title>Why Asian countries are joining Trump's Board of Peace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/asian-powers-join-trump-board-of-peace/106277784</link><description>Analysts say Asian countries such as Indonesia and Vietnam have signalled support for US President Donald Trump's new Board of Peace, not because they expect changes in Gaza, but to gain access to US trade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54bcd99c95f91eae912c5147f3036cd4</guid></item><item><title>Tyra Banks's 'hot ice cream' went viral. Don't expect to see it called that anymore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/hot-ice-cream-tyra-banks-sydney-food/106283144</link><description>Reviews have said it "tasted like soggy biscuits" and was "a weird sensation to sip through a straw". Taste aside, something bugged me. How can you call something ice cream if it's not iced?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3f517f5dea71c2574d23fd042540f1e</guid></item><item><title>Mosman Park murder-suicide described as 'heartbreaking' by WA premier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/mosman-park-murder-suicide-update/106291350</link><description>WA Premier Roger Cook says the deaths of a family of four at their Perth home in an apparent murder-suicide is both "heartbreaking" and "unimaginable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4812bbd856390ab2fac934a1f31c8951</guid></item><item><title>Myanmar election won by military-backed party in widely condemned poll marred by violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/myanmar-election-won-by-military-backed-usdp-party/106290376</link><description>The military's political party wins the vote in a result regarded as a forgone conclusion, with critics arguing threats and violence forced people to the ballot box in a country wracked by civil war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4d99c203ab0a5661b5ba91b73c4e306</guid></item><item><title>Why is my migraine worse in summer?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/why-is-my-migraine-worse-in-summer/106281460</link><description>For people with migraine, summer can be a double-edged sword. You may be able to relax but glare, heat, and changes to sleeping and diet can make attacks more likely or more severe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d8c4e5b1b9584c8c07b53821e59f20c</guid></item><item><title>Cricket NSW announces coach Greg Shipperd sacked from state, Sydney Sixers roles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/legendary-coach-axed-by-sydney-sixers-cricket-nsw/106291418</link><description>Legendary cricket coach Greg Shipperd is sacked from his dual state and BBL roles in a major shake-up at Cricket NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d533075b7de708058edc0e511918889</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of posing as talent agent to lure young actors into sex acts granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/sydney-man-allegedly-posed-as-talent-agent-to-lure-actors/106290734</link><description>The 57-year-old told a Sydney court he posed as a Disney executive because he was "lonely" but only ever shouted people coffee or dinners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da67a7f8f3533ef02db0099d4ef523ba</guid></item><item><title>England cricketer Harry Brook says he lied about New Zealand nightclub incident to protect teammates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/brook-says-he-lied-to-protect-england-teammates-in-nz-incident/106291544</link><description>England's ODI and T20 captain Harry Brook issues a statement admitting he lied over the nightclub incident on his side's tour of New Zealand last year, saying other teammates were present when he was hit by a bouncer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64ae042267d6a7bbb7770372074c7055</guid></item><item><title>Venezuela announces amnesty bill that could lead to mass release of political prisoners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/political-prisoners-venezuela/106291540</link><description>The government did not release the text of the bill on Friday, leaving it unclear who will qualify for release.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74a46326579e9090f1375ef006068c95</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins ruled out of T20 World Cup as Steve Smith snubbed despite strong form</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/cummins-and-smith-out-of-t20-world-cup/106291628</link><description>Pat Cummins will miss the T20 World Cup after failing to recover from his back injury, while Steve Smith, fresh from a blistering BBL cameo, isn't named in Australia's final 15-man squad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e543265a51a8eca00555db2df533a2bb</guid></item><item><title>Elena Rybakina's Australian Open final win over Aryna Sabalenka proves she's no one-hit wonder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-01-31/rybakina-no-one-hit-wonder-australian-open-triumph/106291474</link><description>A consistent and composed Elena Rybakina claims her maiden Australian Open title by beating world number one Aryna Sabalenka in a thriller three years after her breakout Wimbledon win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c1517e375519258beec806f2d5275af</guid></item><item><title>Sprinklers made Australia green. But what happens when the water runs out?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/sprinkler-water-resources-garden-green-desert-reticulation/106244818</link><description>Billions of litres of water are sprayed onto household gardens every day during summer, allowing cities to stay green. Now water is running low. Has the sprinkler had its day?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7bd543c8a54fc02b5ca85916292fcc6</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: Come on trivia titans, it's time to show me what you've got</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/106282854</link><description>I love that you just keep coming back for more humiliating defeat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a99b42d451ac274f9cf1e781633f3f6f</guid></item><item><title>Who is Stephen Miller? Donald Trump's powerful right hand and immigration policy architect</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/stephen-miller-donald-trumps-immigration-policy-architect/106272938</link><description>From a young age, Stephen Miller was campaigning for ideas that were extremely conservative and extremely strange for a teenager from California. Now, he's running Donald Trump's immigration agenda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b671cce8e7fb915bdd4d0763eea894bb</guid></item><item><title>Woman hospitalised after Juniper prescribes weight-loss drugs her GP refused</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/woman-hospitalised-telehealth-provider-weight-loss-drugs-juniper/106273356</link><description>Claire Munch says she was hospitalised with an eating disorder after a telehealth provider approved weight-loss drugs her GP had refused — and that even after she complained, she was later sent marketing promotions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a297fd29d6c11e941d169586df4c0075</guid></item><item><title>How Olympian Michael Klim reinvented himself and his definition of success after muscle-wasting disease CIDP</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/reinvention-of-olympic-swimmer-michael-klim/106098230</link><description>Olympian Michael Klim forged his reputation on strength and athleticism. But after being blindsided by an incurable muscle-wasting disease, he was forced to reinvent himself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3913461b6ef8196fe3dae0375b59dd8</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan claims T20 World Cup warm-up series with 90-run thrashing of Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/pakistan-thrashes-australia-in-t20-world-cup-warm-up/106291668</link><description>Pakistan thrashes Australia by 90 runs to claim an unassailable 2-0 series lead in the T20 World Cup warm-up series in Lahore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">170a571b206b8fe09583c919f03cba70</guid></item><item><title>The surprising history behind the Australian Open men's singles trophy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/mary-mcgillivray-australian-open-warwick-vase-history/106245576</link><description>Carlos Alcaraz and Novak Djokovic go head-to-head today in the men's singles final. Not many people know they are competing for a trophy based on an Ancient Roman artefact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80fb56ea79c2fd74f6fe1dfd873e866c</guid></item><item><title>NSW government to abolish 'good character' evidence at sentencings of convicted offenders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/nsw-to-abolish-good-character-at-sentencing-convicted-offenders/106287368</link><description>Abolishing the use of "good character" evidence as a mitigating factor for offenders during sentencing proceedings will reduce trauma for victim-survivors, the state government says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31e43969d6f45a4a59c750621dd765d9</guid></item><item><title>Sabalenka done with tennis for a bit and Nadal picks between Alcaraz and Djokovic — quick hits from the Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/australian-open-2026-quick-hits-sabalenka-rybakina-womens-final/106291656</link><description>Aryna Sabalenka doesn't "want to think about tennis" after another brutal loss in the women's final and Rafael Nadal picks his men's champion. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">827c3ffac8e939da10bde1ee1c02d0dd</guid></item><item><title>Leon Ford and Celia Pacquola show why it's always the reluctant dads who need pets most in Dog Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/dog-park-celia-pacquola-leon-ford-interview/106263024</link><description>In the new cathartic drama/comedy starring Leon Ford and Celia Pacquola, dogs are the answer to everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77e3d407b9bf5c223080f596cb2325d9</guid></item><item><title>Algal bloom brings 'sense of grief' to parts of Yorke Peninsula</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/yorke-peninsula-algal-bloom/106277644</link><description>While Adelaide is largely having a reprieve from the algal bloom, it is a different story on the south-west tip of the Yorke Peninsula with locals reporting fish kills and discoloured water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">141470f73cb79ed8f6973637e1715275</guid></item><item><title>Canberra public housing tenants' human rights were breached by plans to move them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/act-public-housing-tenants-human-rights-breached-plans-move-them/106289288</link><description>An ACT Supreme Court judge quotes from Cicero and the movie The Castle, as she rules in favour of three Canberra public housing tenants who claimed plans to move them breached their human rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b2bd78e9081afa7438b914b1adab915</guid></item><item><title>New Epstein documents reveal details about his friendship with former prince Andrew</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/new-documents-reveal-details-about-epstein-andrew-friendship/106292352</link><description>The royal family faces a fresh round of embarrassment after the latest tranche of Epstein files reveal unsavoury details about the convicted sex offender's relationship with Andrew.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca64175170556e6cb019b6bb50476993</guid></item><item><title>Author Shailee Thompson merges horror and romance in debut novel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/how-to-kill-a-guy-in-ten-dates-merges-horror-and-romance/106219254</link><description>Debut author Shailee Thompson's new novel How to Kill a Guy in Ten Dates follows cinephile Jamie Prescott, who has to rely on her extensive knowledge of what not to do in a slasher situation when a speed-dating event she attends turns deadly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1765da7a9e9b32fe4f069c481bbe5179</guid></item><item><title>Tasty lunch-box recipes to make the back-to-school weeks easier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/lunch-box-recipes-for-back-to-school/106263052</link><description>As kids head back into classrooms, we've put together some recipes to help their school lunch boxes come home empty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b85905e4db4a43bb35fac858c33e3f4d</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania Police search for Celine Cremer 'paused', as wait on DNA results from human remains continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/celine-cremer-search-paused-as-wait-on-dna-results-continues/106292406</link><description>Following a second day of searching in harsh terrain, Tasmania Police says it has "paused" efforts to find more items linked to missing backpacker Celine Cremer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">082a7d6024d4450ae9f16eab7a034ee6</guid></item><item><title>Rockhampton gathers for walk against violence after alleged rape of female runner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/rockhampton-community-walk-after-alleged-attack-at-yeppen-lagoon/106286464</link><description>The Rockhampton community comes together in a show of emotional support after a young woman was allegedly sexually assaulted and nearly drowned by a stranger on a walking track.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">938dfb9987e8fe33abe54b6448a97d82</guid></item><item><title>Liberal frontbenchers dismiss prospect of imminent challenge to Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/liberals-dismiss-prospect-of-imminent-leadership-challenge/106292412</link><description>Shadow treasurer Ted O'Brien says it is his "assumption" that Liberal frontbencher Angus Taylor still supports Sussan Ley, despite days of speculation that he's planning to challenge for the leadership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f6fa8387542401146de5ac8835ab6f4</guid></item><item><title>Trump administration eyes US Pacific territories as it moves towards deep-sea mining</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/trump-administration-seabed-mining-pacific-territories/106272964</link><description>A Trump administration push to begin deep-sea mining is gathering momentum — and stirring alarm in United States Pacific territories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cba1500e673e715190fab09dc62b80f</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open 2026 final: Carlos Alcaraz, Novak Djokovic meet in titanic battle of generational greats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/australian-open-2026-final-carlos-alcaraz-novak-djokovic-preview/106292358</link><description>More tennis history will go on the line when Novak Djokovic and Carlos Alcaraz clash in an Australian Open final of the highest stakes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47b34221b40ea9102c5ef26ee54c1ae7</guid></item><item><title>A summer of extremes unfolded across Western Australia in January 2026 — see the photos</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/january-2026-in-pictures-western-australia-perth/106239010</link><description>From bushfires and chaotic scenes, to moments of serenity, January 2026 captured Western Australia in all its extremes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e199bf18dac2c037329cfbd743fee71</guid></item><item><title>A 'chia seed' trend on TikTok promotes a 'quick fix' to weight loss, but is it safe?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/chia-seed-trends-social-media-tiktok-explainer/106274220</link><description>The health benefits of chia seeds have been well publicised, but health and internet experts are urging people to not believe everything you see on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">323bc9928f884477c6208f8e6701bf7f</guid></item><item><title>Darwin mayor throws support behind 21-storey civic centre, with current building to be demolished</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/darwin-civic-centre-construction-site-update-after-worker-injury/106281930</link><description>A future landmark of Darwin's CBD is extending skyward, as senior Darwin council figures rebuff concerns from within council that its finances could be affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da1c5ac38c7ae87d64ee38d35bd665c9</guid></item><item><title>Risso's and pantropical spotted dolphins seen off Port Macquarie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/rarely-seen-dolphins-port-macquarie/106288194</link><description>Deepwater dolphin species make a rare appearance on the NSW Mid North Coast, delighting scientists and marine wildlife enthusiasts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b35d7255829358ded47b9444ffa791f</guid></item><item><title>Inside the brand strategy behind the Beckham family drama — and who controls the narrative now</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/inside-the-brand-strategy-behind-the-beckham-family-drama/106284834</link><description>In a modern crisis, experts say control doesn't always come from speaking louder — but from knowing when, where and how briefly to speak at all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02c12da6214ed41b16eafa530a0cd912</guid></item><item><title>The Australian national anthem is already sung at most NT schools. So, what is the new mandate really about?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/national-anthem-mandate-nt-schools-analysis-culture-wars/106290008</link><description>The NT government's national anthem mandate in public schools made headlines this week — but little will be changing on the ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">034a43d17c81ac801c1755439d78ab15</guid></item><item><title>Half of Adelaide University's Magill campus to be sold for housing, retirement units, aged care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/magill-university-campus-to-be-sold-for-housing-aged-care/106292672</link><description>South Australia's premier announces the future of Adelaide University's Magill campus, which sits on the boundary of two marginal Liberal-held electorates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e193029ad44654085cb191cee6aa9ce</guid></item><item><title>Australian Open champion Elena Rybakina eyeing more success after victory over Aryna Sabalenka</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/australian-open-champ-elena-rybakina-hungry-for-success/106292894</link><description>Newly-crowned Australian Open champion Elena Rybakina isn't content with a second grand slam title following a rampant run through the Melbourne Park draw.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19131440f09cecc15b1f695e4a6279d3</guid></item><item><title>Lily Allen has made a huge comeback — soon she'll be in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/lily-allen-australia-tour-hottest-100-interview-west-end-girl/106281950</link><description>The British singer made her triumphant return to the annual countdown with two tracks from her latest album West End Girl.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8417be1c3cac2641d258357cf5b590c5</guid></item><item><title>'Job finished' for Carlos Alcaraz as he wins first Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/australian-open-2026-final-live-novak-djokovic-carlos-alcaraz/106293114</link><description>Carlos Alcaraz is the youngest man to complete the career Grand Slam, beating 24-time major winner Novak Djokovic in the Australian Open final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db5395806a137569df9a8c8c169ed98e</guid></item><item><title>Matildas legend Sarah Walsh says South Korea boycott would be 'devastating' for Asian Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/south-korea-asian-cup-boycott-would-be-devastating/106293118</link><description>Asian Cup organisers say they are hopeful the South Korean women's team will partake in next month's tournament despite threats of a boycott due to "harsh and unreasonable conditions" under the nation's federation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75e3b8d87e450e562dd01bacf28f760c</guid></item><item><title>Alex Volkanovski retains featherweight championship with decision victory over Diego Lopes at UFC 325</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/ufc-325-alex-volkanovski-result-diego-lopes/106292786</link><description>Alex Volkanovski's win over Diego Lopes at UFC 325 was enough to retain the world featherweight title and give Australia's greatest ever MMA fighter and his fans exactly what they were looking for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4ec31460e2d01a0dffda082acfa4753</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan spinner Usman Tariq dismisses Australia's Cameron Green's gesture about his action in second T20I</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/pakistan-spinner-usman-tariq-dismisses-cameron-green-gesture/106293176</link><description>Pakistan spinner Usman Tariq responds after Cameron Green appeared to mimic his action in Australia's comprehensive T20 loss in Lahore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d15be44ae0c50a4f29a58f43967333e5</guid></item><item><title>The Grammys are on Monday morning — here's how to watch and who to look out for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/2026-grammy-awards-how-to-watch/106292918</link><description>From Kendrick Lamar to Lady Gaga, here are all the nominees and performers to look out for at the Grammys this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a670c4146c04d2e64346e5bfd02b9c46</guid></item><item><title>Clive Palmer rejects Steve Bannon influence claim in latest Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/palmer-denies-bannon-claim-of-election-campaign-influence/106293074</link><description>Clive Palmer denies newly surfaced claims that his 2019 federal election campaign was influenced by a senior advisor to US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c9c965c6b8ceddec345b1fe91952665</guid></item><item><title>Carlos Alcaraz has his never-before moment by beating Novak Djokovic in his own house</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/carlos-alcaraz-defeats-novak-djokovic-australian-open-final/106293160</link><description>Carlos Alcaraz has defeated Novak Djokovic in a pulsating Australian Open final, becoming the youngest man with a career Grand Slam in the process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fea8ff00f86caf09279b2d1a402cc482</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic drops retirement hint, suggests 2026 could be his final Australian Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/australian-open-novak-djokovic-hints-2026-could-be-his-last/106293450</link><description>Novak Djokovic did not go into detail on what he meant, nor did he confirm a plan to retire this year, but he chose his words carefully on centre court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55495032c4ad20750eb9060adf5c00fd</guid></item><item><title>Preparations underway at Gaza's Rafah crossing a day before Israel says travel will resume</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-01/preparations-begin-to-open-rafah-crossing-gaza/106293400</link><description>Although Gaza has four other border crossings, they are shared with Israel, and many Palestinians see Rafah as their gateway to the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39ca33ab90341a9b3e743f0e4e50c5a3</guid></item><item><title>Where in your home is best to set up a work space?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/where-is-best-to-set-up-home-office-workspace/106279734</link><description>From garages to cupboards, we asked experts on things to consider before you choose where to set up a home office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">737207bd9fb86c2996d3d75fd5c289aa</guid></item><item><title>The economy should be the focus but Coalition incompetence is a gift to Labor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/parliament-sitting-week-opposition-leadership-albanese/106292656</link><description>The trip to the tennis is a sign of the PM's own sense of confidence. It's a move that is only made by a man who clearly has his mojo back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c593ab0ab132b37b64e32310b4178b72</guid></item><item><title>Unnecessary interest rate cuts derailed the national housing affordability project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/rba-interest-rate-hikes-housing-affordability-inflation/106292572</link><description>The great unspoken truth about central banking and monetary policy is that while it's aimed at consumer prices, its most direct impact is on house prices, which are arguably the most important prices of all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">705c4a8fa185827bbf36e710e0045156</guid></item><item><title>David Littleproud to survive spill, but Sussan Ley’s future uncertain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/littleproud-to-survive-but-leys-future-uncertain/106292926</link><description>Leadership speculation has engulfed both the Liberal and National parties since the minor party walked away from the Coalition agreement two weeks ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">406bc1fc714d945bda9cd70c727e52cd</guid></item><item><title>Inside Donald Trump's ICE detention centre boom — and the families caught in the crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/inside-donald-trump-ice-immigration-detention-centres/106291428</link><description>The Trump administration's rapid expansion of ICE detention centres has led to inhumane conditions, record deaths and allegations of abuse, civil rights watchdogs warn.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52f5e36189e84aa9080af3889b48a316</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic praises Carlos Alcaraz after Spaniard wins first Australian Open title</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australian-open-carlos-alcaraz-novak-djokovic-final/106293372</link><description>Despite the hollow feeling of defeat, 24-time major winner Novak Djokovic heaps praise on Carlos Alcaraz following the Spaniard's history-making Australian Open victory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87c4c2aa20dbeaeb5ed2b49f3037427b</guid></item><item><title>Alcaraz and Djokovic thrill Rafa and a 'boring' heckle delights Rod Laver Arena — quick hits from the Australian Open men's final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australian-open-2026-quick-hits-alcaraz-djokovic-mens-final/106293202</link><description>Rafael Nadal gives his seal of approval and Novak Djokovic collects the one trophy missing from his cabinet as his Melbourne Park fortunes flip. Here are the quick hits from the Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">021aed1707e51a762d3e47daa401edd9</guid></item><item><title>'Cynical and targeted' Russian strike on Ukrainian bus kills 12</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/russian-strike-on-ukrainian-mining-bus/106293870</link><description>A series of attacks across Ukraine comes ahead of US-brokered trilateral talks between Ukraine and Russia set for the coming week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">724ae21f29cfd5e4c2040513215b3f6a</guid></item><item><title>Can your dog read your next move? These are the cues they use</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/how-your-dog-is-reading-you-muster-dogs/106135294</link><description>Your dog is constantly reading you and using it to their advantage. These are the cues they use to foresee your next move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14cb399bd94a27ee10f8af48e186764f</guid></item><item><title>Australia suffers heaviest T20 defeat, Pakistan to boycott World Cup match against India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australia-suffer-heaviest-t20-defeat-ahead-of-world-cup/106294032</link><description>Australia slumps to a 3-0 T20 series defeat in Pakistan, leading into this month's World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef92527b1d63bad547ff9ee72d16943d</guid></item><item><title>Fossilised dinosaur footprint identified after more than 60 years in palaeontologist's collection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/fossil-footprint-identified-sauropodomorph-brisbane/106284466</link><description>A fossilised dinosaur footprint that lived in a professor's personal collection for more than six decades is identified.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88a12fdc9933141548eab8ae1e20acdb</guid></item><item><title>Littleproud to meet with Ley after seeing off leadership challenge — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/federal-politics-live-nationals-liberals-littleproud-ley/106294026</link><description>Nationals leader David Littleproud is set to meet with opposition leader Sussan Ley after seeing off a leadership challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6aaf21d015dfe4bbd3da77507bf0f21d</guid></item><item><title>Mary Fowler returns to the pitch as Manchester City hammer Chelsea in Women's Super League</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/mary-fowler-returns-for-manchester-city-wsl/106294082</link><description>Matildas star Mary Fowler returns to football after a nine-and-a-half-month injury lay-off, as Manchester City thumps Chelsea in the Women's Super League.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6fddfef04c27a8081d5b0c66234c26b0</guid></item><item><title>Nightcliff Tigers premiership player sues AFL over 'catastrophic' concussion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/nightcliff-tigers-premiership-player-sues-afl-over-concussion/106283472</link><description>Nightcliff Tigers dual-premiership player Trent Melville is suing the AFL in the NT Supreme Court after suffering "catastrophic injuries" in a head clash with another player in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4c704a3421497d9ee1e5418101723c9</guid></item><item><title>Parents say NSW government closing schools without oversight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/regional-parents-warn-of-schools-closing-without-consultation/106282754</link><description>As the gates shut at five tiny schools across regional New South Wales, residents fear the loss will be felt far beyond the classroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee9246f9b5a6e0f33fb5f914e51990a2</guid></item><item><title>Arsenal wins FIFA Women's Champions Cup as Matilda Caitlin Foord scores winning goal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/arsenal-wins-fifa-women-champions-cup/106294178</link><description>Arsenal have become the first women's world soccer champions, with Matildas star Caitlin Foord clinching the title for the Gunners in extra time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36c845121e5ef062d10a0177da74cc9b</guid></item><item><title>Australian Winter Olympics team staff test positive for COVID-19 ahead of 2026 Milano Cortina Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/winter-olympics-2026-australia-staff-covid-19/106294228</link><description>Australia's Winter Olympics preparations will continue with minimal fuss in northern Italy despite two members of staff testing positive for COVID-19.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebcb1d60ddcf15933696489d39206f3b</guid></item><item><title>Calls for volunteers as hundreds of cygnets found stranded at sea in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/swans-stranded-at-sea/106291506</link><description>Wildlife volunteers in WA's South West are urging people to get involved in caring for hundreds of baby swans found abandoned over summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87bf4eaef7940afc8fbd4850d2955686</guid></item><item><title>Rescued cygnets released back into the wild</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/rescued-cygnets-released-back-into-the-wild-/106293172</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">000dddad5b22b87f6a73cd761e52491d</guid></item><item><title>Will the RBA increase interest rates today?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/will-the-rba-lift-interest-rates/106286450</link><description>The market thinks the RBA is likely to lift interest rates on Tuesday, but the market has been wrong before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fc57310152dd2391271ca96efcd8141</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate alleged sexual assault of boy in Adelaide park toilet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/police-investigate-sexual-assault-of-boy-at-flagstaff-hill/106294376</link><description>Police say a teenage boy was sexually assaulted at a toilet block in Adelaide's south on Saturday by another young male who had asked for help to "look for his lost mobile phone".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abbcd6c5b67780d0e36db7a2cd29e70a</guid></item><item><title>Bad Bunny makes Grammys history with Album of the Year win — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/68th-grammy-awards-live-updates-winners/106288902</link><description>Debí Tirar Más Fotos is the first Spanish-language record to win Album of the Year at the Grammy awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a88755bbc9bfeab625c4992dd0387c0</guid></item><item><title>2026 Grammy Awards red carpet: Sabrina Carpenter, Olivia Dean arrive in style for the ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/grammys-2026-red-carpet-fashion/106294278</link><description>The best and most memorable red carpet looks at the 68th Annual Grammy Awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">daeb2fcb28fae6863657b83025630e93</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, February 2: Balto and the dogs of 1925's Great Serum Run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/today-in-history-february-2-balto-nome-serum-run-of-1925/106200774</link><description>Children of an icebound Alaskan town were dying. The journey to save them would be treacherous, freezing, and in these dogs' paws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee0becf2af32bee92f962dde0284bfce</guid></item><item><title>From Sabalenka to Djokovic and 'animals in the zoo', here are the best quotes from the Australian Open 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australian-open-2026-best-quotes/106291648</link><description>From tennis stars pushing for more privacy, to Djokovic saying he feels like an old man and a Kyrgios F-bomb, there have been some funny and weird quotes at this year's Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">092b0db1619ef3d506d5e88441d9fb8c</guid></item><item><title>Liam Conejo Ramos returns to Minnesota after being detained by ICE on way home from preschool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/liam-conejo-ramos-and-father-released-return-to-minnesota/106294570</link><description>Five-year-old Liam Conejo Ramos, whose detention by federal agents as he returned from preschool sparked outrage across the United States, has been released from immigration detention, according to a US congressman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">519a373b59f667b2f02344c2344e5d02</guid></item><item><title>Australian monobob star Bree Walker welcomes pressure at 2026 Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australian-monobob-star-bree-walker-2026-winter-olympic-games/106294878</link><description>The g-force felt hurtling down the bobsleigh track is the only pressure Bree Walker is feeling despite the Australian speed demon entering the Winter Olympics as one of the gold-medal favourites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">802275741ac10d99b8f9a2bd75d0123e</guid></item><item><title>Grammy winners 2026: Bad Bunny takes home Album of The Year, Olivia Dean Best New Artist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/2026-grammys-winners-list-kendrick-lamar-olivia-dean/106294398</link><description>The 68th Grammy Awards main ceremony has happened in Lose Angeles. See who won what here.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f57b87937c11bb8b07ffe60a4bcb7e5e</guid></item><item><title>Norwegian rape trial rocks the royal family and grips the public</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/norways-monarchy-braces-as-princess-son-rape-trial-begins/106290156</link><description>This week, Marius Borg Høiby, the stepson of Norway's future king, will face trial on a string of rape, drug and abuse charges, and it has the whole country talking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9ca20ad3386ff60069b66e182bbc9d0</guid></item><item><title>Cleveland man charged over death of three-week-old baby south of Brisbane in 2024</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/man-charged-murder-newborn-death-south-brisbane/106295760</link><description>Police have charged a man with murder over the death of a newborn baby south of Brisbane more than 18 months ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f72549d4460eaddc34bca2ceb6ab2f1</guid></item><item><title>Former Queensland Origin player Joshua McGuire's child assault case before Brisbane court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/queensland-joshua-mcguire-court-alleged-child-assault/106295560</link><description>The case against a former Queensland State of Origin player accused of assaulting a child has come before a court for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">470f049fe337a9354f1961c7db347987</guid></item><item><title>Sydney police officer allegedly armed himself with bat and assaulted pair over 'knock and run' game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/nsw-cop-jonathan-beard-assault-knock-and-run/106295572</link><description>A senior police officer is accused of arming himself with a bat and assaulting a pair of young men who knocked on his front door and hid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c000b9ba7f0843d0dab695c0b42ac9c4</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Travel Management founder Jamie Pherous resigns amid overcharging scandal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/corporate-travel-jamie-pherous-resignation/106294550</link><description>Corporate Travel Management boss Jamie Pherous has exited from all his executive and board roles as he moves to a "strategic advisory role."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c02e7d1dc69ed80588946088c0865378</guid></item><item><title>Shaun Michael Dunk mental competence murder trial begins in SA Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/shaun-michael-dunk-mental-competence-murder-trial-begins/106294382</link><description>A trial to determine if a man was mentally competent at the time he killed a woman in Adelaide hears that he "always wanted to know what it was like to kill someone". Warning: This story contains content some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff1e8f2db98af9c926cfe7ed557dfe3b</guid></item><item><title>Found a PCOS 'cure' on social media? It might not be for you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/pcos-cures-myths-and-other-mistruths-to-be-wary-of/106286496</link><description>Advice on how to "manage", "treat" and "heal" PCOS is easy to come by online, but experts say a more personalised approach is usually what's needed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38340fdb3fa30f7c96f4dea3e5531ef0</guid></item><item><title>Australian woman killed in ski lift accident at popular snow resort in Japan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australian-woman-killed-in-ski-lift-accident-in-japan/106295672</link><description>Police in Japan confirmed to ABC News the woman’s name is Brooke Day, from Queensland's Sunshine Coast, who was taking a lift at the Tsugaike Mountain Resort when she became caught and suffered critical injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1c35785da8d7211c080f4cd9346f02a</guid></item><item><title>'Lucky' fishermen rescued after boat fire near Binalong Bay, Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/tasmanian-boaties-set-fire-to-items-on-board-to-raise-alarm/106294694</link><description>Two boaties stranded at sea for eight hours after their tinnie caught fire chose a survival plan police described as "highly unrecommended" — to set it on fire again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6902805b042b374f2d868a23640d1c6</guid></item><item><title>Grammys 2026: Bad Bunny, Billie Eilish slam ICE at music's biggest awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/grammys-2026-bad-bunny-billie-eilish-ice-speech/106295626</link><description>The 2026 Grammys blended protest, celebration and cultural change as artists confronted powers that be, embraced diversity and reshaped the night's biggest awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdcdf266663abf7ab5a05d2412ba7808</guid></item><item><title>TasWater's proposed 8.8 per cent bill increase knocked back by regulator</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/taswater-bill-increase-knocked-back-by-regulator/106295926</link><description>Tasmanian households have dodged a bullet, with the state's economic regulator refusing TasWater's proposed annual fee hikes of 8.8 per cent for the next four years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bbd39bdf9d1991991530e75ea729a06</guid></item><item><title>Boy, 13, makes 'superhuman' swim to save family swept out to sea in Geographe Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/geographe-bay-rescue-boy-superhuman-swim/106296100</link><description>A 13-year-old boy has been hailed a hero after swimming four hours through rough seas to get help for his mother and two siblings, who were swept out to sea on an inflatable paddleboard in WA's South West.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09b506eaaea53e3da37f0b9e9e7f28a7</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files suggest Mandelson kept paedophile informed on Rudd's mining super profits tax</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/peter-mandelson-on-rudds-mining-super-profits-tax-epstein-files/106295236</link><description>Newly released documents show British Labour peer Peter Mandelson kept sex trafficking paedophile Jeffrey Epstein informed about the campaign against Kevin Rudd's proposed mining tax.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95fb4bfa0f3719c1888a413777024d0e</guid></item><item><title>Chicago Bulls star Josh Giddey overlooked for NBA All-Star game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/josh-giddey-misses-out-on-nba-all-star-selection/106296640</link><description>Chicago's Josh Giddey has fallen short in his quest to become just the second Australian to play in the NBA All-Star match after he was overlooked by selectors despite his excellent form.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c204ce608a1d574d2ceb74788c9c90b5</guid></item><item><title>Mosman Park suspected double murder-suicide prompts calls for greater support for families with high-needs children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/mosman-park-murder-suicide-reaction-disability-support/106291002</link><description>A suspected murder-suicide in Perth has put the spotlight on families with high needs children, with speculation that the Clune family were not getting the support they needed in the lead up to their deaths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd4f898364abe030c24f15ba48adef3b</guid></item><item><title>Woman who fatally hit and drove away from Alexx Wright, 19, sentenced to three years' jail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/woman-jailed-over-jurien-bay-fatal-hit-and-run/106287472</link><description>A 45-year-old woman is sentenced after fatally striking a 19-year-old with her car in WA's Midwest and failing to stop and offer assistance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">740115aa9a0cbd1853da5a6219277e6f</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Cam Myers becomes youngest ever winner of Wanamaker Mile indoor race in New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/cam-myers-wins-wanamaker-mile-new-york/106296836</link><description>Australia's Cam Myers becomes the youngest ever winner of the prestigious Wanamaker Mile, with the 19-year-old powering to victory in New York.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fe231aa9ecc5e5875525ccd47c21618</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106295914</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9aea76966b496e7fe2244d92555ca47</guid></item><item><title>Police granted Julian Ingram bail despite safety concerns, court documents reveal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/julian-ingram-triple-murder-suspect-released-before-shooting/106294472</link><description>Accused triple-murderer Julian Ingram was granted bail by police despite concerns being raised over the safety of potential victims and the community. The 37-year-old remains on the run from police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6dca2ae340889564ebe0789a23ab161</guid></item><item><title>WA to launches trial of free full-time kindergarten at five public schools. Here's how it works</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/wa-full-time-kindergarten-trial-begins-five-schools/106296000</link><description>As WA kids headed back to the classroom after summer holidays, five of the state's public schools begin a trial of free full-time kindergarten.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">513c4d7de4bd82c0a85d5a1e091e8f62</guid></item><item><title>Properties under threat as uncontrolled Deep Creek bushfire burns south of Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/deep-creek-fire-threatening-properties-south-of-adelaide/106296654</link><description>An Emergency Warning has been issued for people in the area of a fast-moving, uncontrolled bushfire burning near Cape Jervis, south of Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63724c95f9f1d024509e6578e5b8097c</guid></item><item><title>Ley and Littleproud hold 'civil' talks but yet to agree terms for Coalition reunion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/ley-and-littleproud-hold-coalition-crisis-talks/106297282</link><description>The federal Liberal and National leaders held eleventh-hour crisis talks after David Littleproud survived an unlikely challenge from as disgruntled backbencher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb521b68bf1b98170a5f6585eac6792e</guid></item><item><title>WA man to serve at least 21 years in jail for 'brutal' murder of father</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/john-matthew-gallagher-sentenced-murder-father/106296134</link><description>A man who committed a "horrific" attack on his father in regional WA, recording some of it and posting it online, will have to serve at least 21 years for murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0313e11d9859a7118e3e4acbb4103f27</guid></item><item><title>Cory Bernardi to contest SA state election for One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/cory-bernardi-to-lead-one-nation-sa-state-election/106297448</link><description>Former federal Liberal senator Cory Bernardi will lead One Nation's Legislative Council ticket at the upcoming state election in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82327f03ddfe8f054bc1364e0c41712e</guid></item><item><title>Katherine River peaks just below flood levels, with more rain on the way</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/katherine-river-flood-preparation-as-more-rain-forecast/106297438</link><description>The Katherine River peaked just below the minor flood level on Monday, but the Bureau of Meteorology says the situation could change with more rain expected in coming days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">548fd1d9c6f55a683fe4c6890b0976e2</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Court to be first female head of ASIC, Treasurer Jim Chalmers announces</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/sarah-court-appointed-asic-chair/106297512</link><description>This position will give Ms Court significant influence over Australian corporate culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">896634fa2fd826de486ac299ad09a264</guid></item><item><title>Dalai Lama's Grammy win slammed as 'anti-China' by Chinese government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/china-says-dalai-lama-grammy-win-anti-china/106297758</link><description>The 90-year-old, who lives in exile from his Tibetan homeland, says he accepts the award with "gratitude and humility" but it has sparked a furious response from China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e426129bd0771d848581ce4d4df41338</guid></item><item><title>Slow movement at Gaza border after Israel reopens Rafah crossing to Egypt in key step for truce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/gaza-s-border-crossing-to-egypt-reopens-in-a-key-step-for-truce-/106297578</link><description>Gaza's key Rafah border crossing with Egypt has been reopened. However, Israeli authorities have allowed fewer than 30 Palestinians to enter or exit the territory on the first day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3a2935cad2a7efdca4abc00e400c76b</guid></item><item><title>Trump administration to unveil rare-earths mineral stockpile to counter China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/trump-to-launch-rare-earth-minerals-stockpile/106297862</link><description>A $US12 billion ($17.2 billion) investment from the US Export-Import Bank is attracting attention from major American car companies, and comes as Washington seeks to break China's dominance of resources key for military and computing applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50a65bd5efb49ce8caca71a7d4661053</guid></item><item><title>Keir Starmer orders investigation into Peter Mandelson's ties to Jeffrey Epstein</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/starmer-orders-investigation-into-mandelson-ties-to-epstein/106297984</link><description>Documents released reportedly show Peter Mandelson sent Jeffrey Epstein briefing notes meant for then-British prime minister Gordon Brown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7404eab633f20ee2010991632232846</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Ferguson called Epstein a 'legend', told him to 'just marry me', new emails show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/fergie-emails-epstein-files-legend/106297980</link><description>The former Duchess of York's friendship with the late sex offender is back in the spotlight after the latest release of documents about the Epstein case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e97603600426faf0b2647f43f40bee8</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump announces trade deal between US and India with tariffs slashed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/trump-says-us-india-trade-deal-agreed-to-with-modi/106298034</link><description>The US president says his social media platform that a deal had been struck, which includes a reduction of tariffs on Indian products in exchange for New Delhi no longer buying oil from Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f94a01b98bae6193dbbfae37ee176e55</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane baby coffee assault tests Australia-China relations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/brisbane-baby-coffee-assault-australia-china-relations-beijing/106294458</link><description>Sixteen months after a stranger poured scalding coffee over a baby in a Brisbane park, China's decision to send a working group to Australia marks the first tangible shift in a complicated case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e117a579109e547bee7eb4bc5d3fff4</guid></item><item><title>In Antarctica's hostile environment, survival experts keep people safe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/the-dangers-of-working-and-living-in-antarctica/106295598</link><description>Antarctica can be a dangerous place to live and work, but to mitigate the risks, a team of survival specialists is contracted to keep Australia's expeditioners safe on the ice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5499b2f21580cf9255e2bf4dc9a230c</guid></item><item><title>How decluttering your digital streaming subscriptions can save you money this year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/how-decluttering-your-digital-subscriptions-can-save-you-money/106294296</link><description>With Australian households now holding an average of 3.7 digital entertainment subscriptions each, doing an audit on what you're using and whether it's providing value can be a good place to start when looking to cut costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c13fa3915e6c9c3a59644cc8b377541</guid></item><item><title>Travel quiz, February 3: Can you work your way around the world with these questions?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/travel-quiz/106251032</link><description>Where is Burning Man held each year? And which of these attractions is the tallest?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1272e192e705cbb0ee35439850dd4343</guid></item><item><title>One Nation condemned for 'spot the Westerner' video</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/one-nation-state-secretary-posts-spot-the-westerner-video/106295436</link><description>A One Nation party official has filmed strangers on Melbourne's streets claiming the city "doesn't look like a Western nation at all".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20d4263316c8c7b4be43bc2ea7f38d9f</guid></item><item><title>If the Reserve Bank starts the year with a rate hike, you can't say it didn't warn us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/if-rba-hikes-interest-rates-you-cant-say-it-didnt-warn-us/106295546</link><description>Could RBA economists conceivably see inflation returning to target without a rate hike? We'll know this afternoon, and while it's not the dominant view, it's not a fringe one, either.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d881ee61aa57aa94f39c3577ccc7cbb</guid></item><item><title>Should I take a fish oil supplement for my heart, joints or mood?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/should-take-fish-oil-supplement-heart-joints-mood/106281540</link><description>Fish oil is one of the most popular dietary supplements. It's often promoted for protecting the heart, boosting mood, reducing inflammation, and supporting overall health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65db459e18e709e4acbdb0e1c9cf9b19</guid></item><item><title>Amber Wraith's parents say medical professionals dismissed her suicidal thoughts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/amber-wraiths-parents-say-suicidal-thoughts-downplayed-dismissed/106213582</link><description>A hospital has apologised to the parents of 19-year-old Amber Wraith, who took her own life in 2022. Her family hopes her death will prompt changes in the way mental health patients are treated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2a360c9e244c2fecc308c79af403c7b</guid></item><item><title>Dezi Freeman search continues as Victoria Police vow hunt 'will not stop'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/dezi-freeman-five-day-search-mount-buffalo-national-park/106294902</link><description>Victoria Police is continuing to search bushland in the Mount Buffalo National Park for traces of alleged gunman Dezi Freeman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b107d824efc5c91b447ad06397cce400</guid></item><item><title>Panic selling hits gold as analysts warn of potential 'regime change' in financial markets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/panic-selling-hits-gold-as-analysts-warn-of-market-regime-change/106296154</link><description>The precious metals market collapses following the appointment of new US Federal Reserve chair Kevin Warsh, and some analysts say it signals a significant shift in the world's financial markets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3d569257b28f20ad7ac4eeb4d9ccf63</guid></item><item><title>Where do you spend your money? Tell us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/audience-callout-cost-of-living/106295774</link><description>We are keen to understand how the cost of living is being felt across Australia. What are your biggest expenses? Are you making cutbacks? Do you afford yourself luxuries?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93c007436aad1470a52310d87ce96a29</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroo Island's sea lions.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/kangaroo-island-s-sea-lions/106152240</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6da9b03c3506f606888829ac56721a3</guid></item><item><title>Citizen scientists look for hope as the algal bloom persists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/kangaroo-island-citizen-scientists-algal-bloom-fight-sa/106131388</link><description>On Kangaroo Island – where the bloom has washed death ashore for almost a year – a group of citizen scientists are focusing their efforts on "what’s still out there".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86498380fc9493692055ee20a3b6a5ed</guid></item><item><title>Australian Climate and Homelessness Alliance to help rough sleepers through extreme weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/australian-climate-change-homelessness-alliance/106226294</link><description>Tim knows firsthand the struggles of being homeless and navigating the weather, but it's experiences like his which will be the focus of a newly formed Australian Climate and Homelessness Alliance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ee4b360629767c864633ca83a3fa33b</guid></item><item><title>Victorian GPs to be trained to diagnose and treat ADHD in adults and children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/victorians-with-adhd-gps-diagnose-treat/106297198</link><description>General practitioners in Victoria will soon be able to diagnose and treat ADHD in adults and children in a move the state government says will cut lengthy wait times and save thousands of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">626bf10fde7d1333d29aa19d33772b5b</guid></item><item><title>Josh Hazlewood to miss start of T20 World Cup, Mitch Marsh shrugs off Pakistan loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/josh-hazlewood-to-miss-start-of-t20-world-cup-for-australia/106298116</link><description>Speedster Josh Hazlewood will miss the early stages of the T20 World Cup as captain Mitch Marsh shrugs off Australia's lamentable capitulations in their warm-up series in Pakistan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b56ebcc0ef744c39d942e4f6467aeb6f</guid></item><item><title>Children with brain cancer given hope in trial of personalised vaccines across eight Australian hospitals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/brain-cancer-vaccine-trial-for-children/106294532</link><description>The four-year trial of about 70 children with "dismal prognoses" in eight hospitals across Australia will test the safety and effectiveness of the experimental treatment designed to harness the immune system to attack a child's tumour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd9820b0bf9253cde4f11cb68c42b639</guid></item><item><title>ACT election data suggests neither Liberal nor Greens voters would want a coalition between the parties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/act-election-voter-data-greens-liberals-coalition/106294870</link><description>Greens voters overwhelmingly preference Labor over the Liberal Party across the country — and a look at the data from the 2024 ACT election suggests there's no reason to think that would be different in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53db3562aaf24beff1f311b356101d70</guid></item><item><title>High Court to consider if Victoria's strict cap on individual political donations is discriminatory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/high-court-consider-victoria-individual-political-donations-cap/106297046</link><description>Two independent Victorian political candidates will ask the High Court to overturn a state law capping political donations to just under $5,000 but allowing an exception for the major parties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a432293ac4cfa7a887e76b721678ae23</guid></item><item><title>Nationals sit on crossbench as PM grilled on cost of living — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/federal-politics-live-ley-littleproud-albanese-parliament/106296954</link><description>The Nationals have taken their seats on the crossbench in Question Time in the House of Representatives as the prime minister is grilled on the cost of living.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea3b636720f686897748561f89147016</guid></item><item><title>Sita Walker's debut novel, In a Common Hour, takes place across a single hour at a state high school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/sita-walker-author-in-a-common-hour/106272552</link><description>Sita Walker, an English teacher from Brisbane, explains how she tackled her first work of fiction, set in a single hour at a state high school.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04fa39d46b8cdc0621342a7ae8b5a249</guid></item><item><title>Spanish figure skater Tomas-Llorenc Guarino Sabate says Minions music barred due to copyright issue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/tomas-llorenc-guarino-sabate-olympic-minions-copyright-issue/106298168</link><description>Spanish figure skater Tomas-Llorenc Guarino Sabate says he will not be allowed to use the music from the Minions film franchise that he has skated to throughout the season at the Milano Cortina Games due to a copyright clearance issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd82cc6e98ea73dad0ceec84b42cffa1</guid></item><item><title>Seaspray beach residents push back on wind farm turbines 10km from shore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/seaspray-against-offshore-wind-blue-mackerel-turbines/106123752</link><description>A tiny coastal community in Victoria's east is battling an international wind energy giant that wants to build 60 to 70 turbines in the ocean 10 kilometres from shore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31b11189f57ab299838aee739a3fa3db</guid></item><item><title>Aussie dollar climbs as RBA raises rates and leaves door open to more hikes — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/asx-markets-business-live-news-03feb-2026/106298200</link><description>The Reserve Bank has hiked the cash rate 0.25 percentage points to 3.85 per cent, in its first rate rise in more than two years. The Aussie dollar rose back above 70 US cents after the decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b42f830cea274bb82911f5597fb674b0</guid></item><item><title>Deep Creek fire remains uncontrolled after nearing caravan park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/hundreds-of-firefighters-battle-deep-creek-fire/106298126</link><description>A bushfire on South Australia's Fleurieu Peninsula has had its warning level again downgraded, but the Country Fire Service says it has burned more than 1,900 hectares and remains uncontrolled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84a80fa2115f4ce09d778692466088b2</guid></item><item><title>Behind the music of hit Australian indie game Hollow Knight: Silksong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/christopher-larkin-hollow-knight-silksong-music-at-acmi/106127840</link><description>The video game soundtrack will be performed live for the first time by Orchestra Victoria at ACMI in February.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56a776d3a39c7522f7d9a4501e65808a</guid></item><item><title>Townsville health authorities report rise in pregnant women drinking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/pregnant-women-drinking-in-townsville-report/106289078</link><description>A sharp rise in pregnant women drinking alcohol in Australia's largest northern city might be linked to the impact of last year's floods, health authorities say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eae5e5d2bd19515e8636e51dbb982756</guid></item><item><title>Tributes flow for long-time ABC host James Valentine after cancer forces retirement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/james-valentine-tribute-long-time-abc-radio-cancer-retirement/106296950</link><description>Listeners and former colleagues share treasured memories of a veteran broadcaster who has announced his retirement due to cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0d468fec3b5614e674d134292a20d31</guid></item><item><title>Belinda Bencic and Elina Svitolina make history as two mothers sit in WTA top 10 for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/belinda-bencic-elina-svitolina-wta-top-10-ranking-mothers/106298230</link><description>For the first time in women's tennis, two mothers are ranked inside the world's top 10 simultaneously.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e8a5c61f4dab9ec33ffdbe9458a4894</guid></item><item><title>Denmark volunteers unite for coastal rehabilitation in wake of destructive tourist season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/denmark-volunteers-unite-for-coastal-rehabilitation/106292930</link><description>Volunteers have completed phase one of their plan to restore the dunes at a beloved beach in regional WA where four-wheel drives have destroyed parts of the unique habitat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbeea4a0fe66b3b831e30a05c1bae24a</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island Flying Fox</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/christmas-island-flying-fox/106289522</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e397d549949703d7d5ef7213a34e0406</guid></item><item><title>Rare photo captures Christmas Island flying fox ferrying pup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/rare-photo-captures-christmas-island-flying-fox-ferrying-pup/106284950</link><description>Often compared to a "teddy bear", advocates hope the special snap of an endangered flying fox carrying its pup will shine a light on the Christmas Island animal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c88e0ee70cafc37e3aa2c4c11c901e9</guid></item><item><title>Takeaways from the many mentions of Donald Trump in newly released Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/donald-trump-mentioned-in-epstein-files-thousands-of-times/106297878</link><description>Donald Trump's name appears many times in the Epstein files — including on an FBI list of men who are named as subjects of "salacious information". So what have we learned about the US president?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c6fdfd17bf7e45e891cef6bc9effcb7</guid></item><item><title>Bright light blazing across Victorian skies believed to be Starlink satellite debris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/bright-light-seen-in-victorian-skies-not-meteor-but-space-debris/106298226</link><description>Keen observers reported a "massive, bright orange meteor" streaking across the sky, but one astronomer says it was likely to be space debris from a Starlink satellite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf496c8b7acbbc3bb9ba4bb62a74099d</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr is back for the Asian Cup, half a lifetime after winning it as a teenager</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/matildas-captain-sam-kerr-is-back-for-the-womens-asian-cup/106291550</link><description>Matildas captain Sam Kerr was just 16 when she helped the team win the Women's Asian Cup — their first, and to date only major trophy. Now she's leading the side at home, ready for another shot at glory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4773abd5659955aee0a061ec54f6d43</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies Rugby World Cup matches revealed against All Blacks, Hong Kong China and Chile</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/wallabies-rugby-world-cup-games-all-blacks-hong-kong-china-chile/106298576</link><description>Australia's home Rugby World Cup campaign will kick off against debutants Hong Kong China rather than bitter rivals New Zealand, who also feature in the same pool.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18bc99a334146dcdad380878f346971e</guid></item><item><title>Nusantara Beat to bring 'psychedelic' take on Indonesian folk music to WOMADelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/nusantara-beat-psychedelic-take-on-indonesian-music-womadelaide/106295532</link><description>All members of Amsterdam-based band Nusantara Beat have Indonesian heritage, so what better way to connect with those roots than through a very different take on the archipelago's traditional music?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3790e5030aee437d9cf14b7b9b3dc9a9</guid></item><item><title>NT to introduce strongest penalty for domestic violence murder in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/nt-government-increases-non-parole-dv-murder-life-sentence-jail/106298466</link><description>Domestic violence killers in the Northern Territory are set to serve longer prison sentences without parole than others charged with murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">125be98a2433ae5ef325c08b7627540a</guid></item><item><title>Model revealed for Thriving Kids, the NDIS alternative for some children with developmental delay or autism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/thriving-kids-model-released-autism-developmental-delay/106287786</link><description>The federal government has released the model for its Thriving Kids program, aimed at setting up services and supports run by states and territories outside the NDIS.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84c3588ab95c5d928665807132dd1d9f</guid></item><item><title>Police say Today show host Savannah Guthrie's mother has been abducted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/savannah-guthrie-mother-missing-fbi/106298394</link><description>Police have declared a crime scene after the mother of US TV personality Savannah Guthrie went missing from her home. Here's what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b1e09fc0e5282660968f77d31aad382</guid></item><item><title>Ley offers temporary exile for Nationals who breached shadow cabinet solidarity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/ley-offers-littleproud-terms-to-reunite-coalition/106298840</link><description>Sussan Ley has given David Littleproud a list of non-negotiable conditions, which if accepted could see the Coalition reunited before the end of the week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67c3d67fdd53ef007e0684cb60dbcf76</guid></item><item><title>Teachers in NSW schools face sack for hate speech in classrooms, premier says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/hate-speech-crackdown-in-nsw-schools-chris-minns/106299244</link><description>Teachers or school staff found to have breached bolstered NSW hate speech laws face tough sanctions, including the possibility of being fired.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60a12fc172920c4c7bc302f26bccc97f</guid></item><item><title>Bill and Hillary Clinton agree to testify before US House of Representatives on ties to Jeffrey Epstein</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/bill-hillary-clinton-testify-congress-epstein-investigation/106299282</link><description>The decision could head off a planned vote in the Republican-led House of Representatives to hold the two prominent Democrats in contempt of Congress, which could potentially lead to criminal charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5498c54eff5c36f7996a5f9a719d814d</guid></item><item><title>Greg Roser to serve life sentence as woodchipper murder appeal rejected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/gympie-woodchipper-murder-appeal-greg-roser/106298968</link><description>In 2022 Gregory Lee Roser was found guilty of murder after beating a man with a metal bar and then placing his body in a woodchipper.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f2d843cf45488490446ca5fe32d825d</guid></item><item><title>Major potato company Zerella plans NT expansion with proposed Katherine seed farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/potato-company-zerella-plans-nt-katherine-expansion/106296502</link><description>Potatoes have not been grown in the Northern Territory at commercial scale for many years but could change if a planned seed potato venture goes ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7f85bf9c4ee325502a9239ed174836a</guid></item><item><title>Cadia goldmine faces Supreme Court class action over contamination claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/rural-community-launches-class-action-against-major-goldmine/106295724</link><description>Landowners in central west NSW are behind an environmental class action against one of the world's biggest goldmines, alleging contamination of more than 2,000 properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">726e02a66a85295017adc0738a39598c</guid></item><item><title>NSW protest restrictions extended ahead of Israel president's visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/nsw-police-protest-laws-israel-president-isaac-herzog-sydney/106298050</link><description>The NSW Police commissioner announces restrictions on protests will be extended, ahead of planned demonstrations against the upcoming Sydney visit of Israel's president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">463559519f7a8d9aa80aa9c06ff0a848</guid></item><item><title>Parents of Brooke Day, 22, preparing to bring daughter home after Japan ski lift death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/brooke-day-mourned-japan-ski-lift-death/106298942</link><description>The parents of a Queensland woman who died in a horror ski lift accident in Japan say she was an advanced snowboarder who had completed safety training.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72d53878eac64487e6a8f0188e6ed02d</guid></item><item><title>One Nation SA candidate Cory Bernardi says party will be the 'strongest voice of opposition'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/cory-bernardi-criticises-two-party-duopoly-in-sa/106298630</link><description>One Nation's lead candidate for South Australia Cory Bernardi has taken aim at the "two-party duopoly" in the state, with Pauline Hanson issuing a warning to Labor that her party would be "coming for your seats".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9af4b39e7c80b0b90f6edb40c7e34d27</guid></item><item><title>Former Hobart Matriculation College student sues department, teacher over child sexual abuse allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/child-sexual-abuse-hobart-matriculation-college/106299166</link><description>A woman is suing a former accounting teacher at the then-Hobart Matriculation College, alleging he raped her when she was a 16-year-old student in the 1980s and offered her cash to terminate a pregnancy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25e86a600c067e6cce4df8fe9bac1e79</guid></item><item><title>VicHealth given a lifeline as opposition vows to block health promotion agency's axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/vichealth-political-battle-opposition-blocks-health-agency-axing/106299646</link><description>The Allan Government's plan to merge VicHealth with the health department hits a major political roadblock, with the state opposition vowing to vote against the move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e1d46db59eda6fd1473a741b04abd78</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man pleads guilty to murdering partner who died from significant injuries in their home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/canberra-man-pleads-guilty-murdering-partner-tiffany-spence/106299854</link><description>A Canberra man pleads guilty to murdering his long-term partner on what was due to be the first day of his two-month long ACT Supreme Court trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21210f76aeb357d09da967035929d90a</guid></item><item><title>Mortgage repayment calculator: How much extra you could be paying now the cash rate is 3.85 per cent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/mortgage-repayment-calculator-rba-feb-2026/106298746</link><description>Tell us your loan size, term and interest rate, and our mortgage repayment calculator will work out how much extra you may have to pay on your loan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">520e983395db574fe59bb4ebb1d0c810</guid></item><item><title>RBA lifts interest rates by 0.25pc as inflation rises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/reserve-bank-lifts-interest-rates-february-2026/106298696</link><description>RBA lifts interest rates by 0.25 per cent, to 3.85 per cent, after inflation rose "materially" in the second half of 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42f190caa823d3fb1803e159ff505609</guid></item><item><title>South Sydney recruit David Fifita will lean on Wayne Bennett in an effort to rebuild his NRL career</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/david-fifita-south-sydney-rabbitohs-wayne-bennett/106300192</link><description>After a season lost to injury, newly minted South Sydney backrower David Fifita will lean on Rabbitohs coach Wayne Bennett in an effort to reclaim his status as one of the NRL's most dangerous players.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e598bd46e833e1c28273dbde317f83d</guid></item><item><title>Who is Deni Avdija? Israel's first NBA All-Star, who received a personal message from Benjamin Netanyahu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/deni-avdija-explainer-benjamin-netanyahu-nba-all-star/106299002</link><description>Deni Avdija's breakout season with the Portland Trail Blazers earns him an NBA All-Star nod as well as a message from Israel's president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6738933db0b47fd47e5149e9fe3f629</guid></item><item><title>Treasurer asks ASIC to restrict public access to company directors' home addresses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/company-director-addresses-restricted-asic-jim-chalmers/106299932</link><description>The Australian Securities and Investments Commission moves to dramatically restrict public access to the residential addresses of company directors at the request of Treasurer Jim Chalmers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60107a43f86082b98a4b37261658c873</guid></item><item><title>Child safety officers took no action over 16-month-old’s worsening scabies, inquiry hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/child-safety-inquiry-queensland-toddler-undiagnosed-for-months/106299804</link><description>A 16-month-old child with "persistent" scabies did not receive a medical diagnosis for up to eight months due to inaction by Queensland's child safety department, an inquiry has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4d8d256118cab78d6faddca9d3c5daa</guid></item><item><title>What I wish my manager knew about my mental health</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/mental-health-workplaces-what-i-learnt/106055796</link><description>I've spent my working life in what I like to call the "honesty gap".This kind of creative disclosure became a necessary art form to maintain my work life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47eccac2b29345ae6a93d60b94b9933b</guid></item><item><title>Perth man accused of backing Bondi attackers facing more firearms charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/perth-man-accused-of-backing-bondi-attackers-faces-more-charges/106299954</link><description>A Perth man who allegedly stated support for the Bondi shooters appears in court to face new firearms charges, with his lawyer flagging a bail application.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">173892de45dae16b058f9c7fc901fae1</guid></item><item><title>Piper James's family arrives in Australia to farewell 19yo who died on K'gari</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/piper-james-parents-arrive-at-kgari-fraser-island/106295146</link><description>The parents and close friends of Piper James, 19, who died on K'gari (Fraser Island) last month, arrive in Australia to say their final farewells.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">346c6b703b2e9541c37736d64cd99c7a</guid></item><item><title>Search underway for missing bushwalker David Elliot in the Blue Mountains</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/nsw-missing-bushwalker-search-blue-mountains/106300230</link><description>Police have released an image of 71-year-old David Elliot as part of a multi-agency search when he failed to return from a 30-kilometre walk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dd912d4b0d8727aa1c4e9089bcd31c9</guid></item><item><title>Federal parliament condemns attempted bombing at Perth/Boorloo Invasion Day rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/lidia-thorpe-motion-invasion-day-alleged-bomb-attack-parliament/106298440</link><description>Federal parliament officially condemns the attempted bomb attack at Perth's Invasion Day rally on its first sitting day, acknowledging the harm caused to the First Nations community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0103b72fa857b451dd3fc06e27901fd9</guid></item><item><title>Australian Nurse working in Gaza for MSF says looming ban on aid organisation 'abandons' vulnerable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/wa-nurse-in-gaza-says-msf-ban-abandons-vulnerable/106300002</link><description>Broome nurse Rebecca Smith says a looming ban on Doctors Without Borders due to registration issues will harm the most needy patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20f121a9c3bb78edbfd306a9bafd6fb1</guid></item><item><title>SA Parole Board says commissioner made 'error' in overturning Snowtown killer's release</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/commissioner-error-snowtown-killer-release-parole-board/106299260</link><description>New documents accuse the Parole Administrative Review Commissioner of making a mistake by not allowing the SA Parole Board to participate in a review of a decision to release Snowtown serial killer James Vlassakis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d814fb5bba5684e70e7e7dab1658125e</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Mardi Gras pulls plug on party weeks out from parade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/nsw-sydney-mardis-gras-party-axed-financial-loss/106301046</link><description>Chief executive of the Sydney Gay and Lesbian Mardi Gras, Jesse Matheson, announced the post-parade celebration will not go ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0da779dd70ea8a433ef837cd0fafc67e</guid></item><item><title>Austin Appelbee speaks after 'superhuman' swim off Quindalup to save family in Geographe Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/teen-speaks-after-saving-family-in-geographe-bay/106298798</link><description>A WA mother says asking her teenage son to swim four kilometres through rough seas to get help after their family was swept out to sea, was "one of the hardest decisions" she has ever made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">498dc56b9b0ded2fcee4d47f8ec5eafd</guid></item><item><title>'Mass exodus' from Cambodian scam compounds a 'humanitarian crisis'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/mass-exodus-from-cambodian-scam-compounds/106282530</link><description>Cambodia has witnessed a "mass exodus" from the country's online scam operations in recent weeks amid growing international pressure and the extradition to China of an alleged kingpin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acfa4a7d9b13b747a8a1bb4f5be6460b</guid></item><item><title>'Spas' and 'saunas' used to reintroduce green and gold bell frogs to the ACT in world-first trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/green-gold-bell-frog-reintroduced-canberra-sauna-spa/106300276</link><description>Scientists are reintroducing hundreds of green and gold bell frogs into the ACT, nearly 50 years after they became locally extinct.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eac749c15bba47b68d9086997972e13</guid></item><item><title>Water Corporation makes 'error' in early publication of new desalination plant location in Albany</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/nanarup-chosen-as-site-for-desalination-plant/106297216</link><description>The long-anticipated decision on a site for a desalination plant near Albany has been shared on the Water Corporation's webpage in an "administrative error" ahead of the official announcement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06455ee2bbbab3d9fbe2d078ffaa1dea</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's Integrity Commission finds local councils may be failing to regularly disclose gifts and donations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/tasmanian-local-government-integrity-commission-gifts-review/106298634</link><description>Crayfish, a bottle of whiskey and pieces of timber are among the items on one local council's gift register, but the integrity commissioner finds some councils may be receiving a lot more than they are disclosing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa03c21e66f3d4ee9e7bdd9ad9ebbdfb</guid></item><item><title>Nightmare on Martin Place as RBA outlines horror interest rates scenario</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/rba-decision-to-raise-interest-rates-horror-scenario-outlined/106300520</link><description>The good news is the economy ended 2025 in relatively good shape — with growth starting to pick up, the economy transitioning away from government-led spending, and a historically strong jobs market. Unfortunately, that's where it ends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">079ab8a94c5849a572eae7be29c3f6dc</guid></item><item><title>13yo boy recounts swim through rough seas to help his family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/13yo-boy-recounts-swim-through-rough-seas/106301382</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1612708736c8b1bc1031a984088bb8e</guid></item><item><title>Two alleged Brothers 4 Life gang members charged with firearms offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/sydney-brothers-for-life-gang-arrest-gun-charges-alleged-members/106301166</link><description>More than a decade after the gang wreaked havoc on Sydney's streets, two of its alleged members have been charged with firearms offences by the Raptor Squad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9b78baafd1d746b8d51a4167d3aa80e</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth, Westpac, NAB, ANZ respond to RBA's interest rate hike</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/banks-respond-to-rba-interest-rate-hike/106300676</link><description>The Commonwealth Bank responds to the Reserve Bank of Australia's decision to increase the cash rate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c66b92954470fe787e0746b783d8cae</guid></item><item><title>Staff at Tasmania's Ashley Youth Detention Centre 'at breaking point', worker says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/ashley-youth-detention-centre-staff-walk-off-job/106300596</link><description>Workers from Ashley Youth Detention Centre in Tasmania's north take "unprecedented" industrial action, walking off the job for two hours over ongoing safety concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc1598f6176e1dd768a8b7313b8be010</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian government reveals three-year plan to address violence in schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/tasmanian-governments-plan-to-address-violence-in-schools/106298632</link><description>After reports violence on school grounds almost doubled in recent years the Tasmanian government has developed a three-year action plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2453db99e44c94e3901cb99225795bab</guid></item><item><title>Central Coast Mariners star Annalise Rasmussen signs with Italian powerhouse Juventus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/annalise-rasmussen-central-coast-mariners-signs-with-juventus/106300846</link><description>A-League leading goal scorer Annalise Rasmussen leaves the competition immediately to join Italian powerhouse Juventus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5824f89d8ddce116ae033a1edcb9862</guid></item><item><title>Commissioner slams attempts to use complex needs as 'justification' for Mosman Park murder-suicides</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/disability-commissioner-comments-mosman-park-murder-suicide/106301532</link><description>Australia's disability discrimination commissioner condemns "dangerous narratives" surrounding the deaths of teenage brothers Leon and Otis Clune, saying the burden of disability should never be a justification for family violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">136a95000792af616c7187752b307f5a</guid></item><item><title>Foreign boat pictured in Queensland creek as alleged illegal fishers reach mainland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/foreign-fishing-boat-pictured-cape-york-peninsula-creek/106300516</link><description>Breaches of Australia's northern border continue to escalate, with an alleged illegal fishing boat having been photographed deep inside a creek in Far North Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">549bf7925cbd1b784492af091391f728</guid></item><item><title>To stop the rate hikes, Chalmers might have to ditch the 'I didn't do it' game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/chalmers-must-move-beyond-denying-blame-for-rate-hikes/106301560</link><description>When the news broke that rates would increase, the treasurer's main priority was to prove it wasn't his fault. That won't satisfy voters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">674fede48d6785b58808b56edd9ee6b9</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106301786</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">634e1d6cb3e7070dc32fa57f4e0714bb</guid></item><item><title>China bans hidden car door handles amid safety concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/china-bans-hidden-door-handles-over-safety-concerns/106301632</link><description>The hidden car door handles that have been popularised by Tesla will be banned from next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfb5454da2bb74f2c42ee7ee0ec02df1</guid></item><item><title>Aerial crews were able to spot the family.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/aerial-crews-were-able-to-spot-the-family-/106301828</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">647a1b1bfea6d0ba41302b67aef24a29</guid></item><item><title>Interest rates rise for the first time in over two years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/how-will-this-latest-interest-rate-hike-affect-mortgage-holders-/106301480</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3db59824d3617cff1b2050cc3b2e1e49</guid></item></channel></rss>