<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 11:42:01 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>New research shows impact of lead poisoning on ancient humans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/new-research-shows-impact-lead-poisoning-ancient-humans/105899188</link><description>A new study claims lead might be the reason why Homo sapiens came to dominate the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12aa86f8c8828a99bbdb6054ea89c8c1</guid></item><item><title>Dangerous flammable cladding still not removed from dozens of NSW high-rise apartment buildings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/government-yet-to-fix-cladding-on-dozens-of-apartments-re-scheme/105900296</link><description>Dozens of high-rise apartment buildings across the state are still covered in flammable cladding as the NSW government's scheme has failed to fix them on schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">900570fd41fc7cafb3f056a176d7d52c</guid></item><item><title>Specialist health services shortfall for women in regional WA leave many struggling for support</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/women-missing-out-on-specialist-health-services-in-regional-wa/105866424</link><description>Faced with a lack of specialist women's health services, women in regional WA are researching their own conditions and volunteering to raise awareness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a46a1f1f255a795ba616233f2bb18c5</guid></item><item><title>How a 15yo autistic boy tinkering in his bedroom triggered WA's biggest ever data breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/joshua-unwittingly-triggered-major-wa-health-data-breach-autism/105455250</link><description>Joshua's "passion project" with a radio scanner led to one of WA's most significant public health data breaches. His story highlights the challenges confronting autistic people caught up in the legal system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13c71de037de480416dd879b9c6eab51</guid></item><item><title>Younger candidates out to bring change in WA local government elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/young-candidates-seek-change-in-wa-local-government-elections/105888820</link><description>In the last local government elections in WA, the average age of candidates running for councils was 53 years old — but these young candidates are keen to lower that figure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">612d6039eb66ee2883e4b90a17276dfe</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government seeks private market interest to develop riverside precinct in South Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/qld-riverfront-precinct-south-brisbane-private-sector/105902488</link><description>The government says construction could begin from March 2027 and has suggested the site could feature over 4,000 homes, as well as "event lawns" and promenades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71e510b6fa92de09ab4aec4b9b044d41</guid></item><item><title>McLaren's 'papaya rules' may be over as Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris battle for the F1 drivers' championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/mclaren-papaya-rules-oscar-piastri-lando-norris-f1/105855110</link><description>"Papaya rules" have dominated Formula 1 for two seasons, but with both McLaren drivers in the heat of a world championship battle, Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris may no longer prioritise what is best for the team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c1dd9f6429245aceb6baaa21e041d3e</guid></item><item><title>Starmer criticises police decision to ban fans of Israel's Maccabi Tel Aviv from Aston Villa match</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/football-maccabi-tel-aviv-fans-banned-police-aston-villa/105902590</link><description>Fans of Israel's Maccabi Tel Aviv are banned from attending next month's Europa League match against Aston Villa in Birmingham over "public safety concerns".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">effc61153d88fcce13575af2eb2a3f1c</guid></item><item><title>Ace Frehley, founding member of rock group KISS, dies at 74</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/ace-frehley-guitarist-kiss-dies-aged-74/105902920</link><description>The original lead guitarist of the glam rock band captivated audiences with his elaborate makeup and smoke-filled guitar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70f68f5def708160810eec0ad80e8354</guid></item><item><title>King Charles marks land rights milestone in first visit to London's Australia House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/king-charles-commemorates-40th-anniversary-of-uluru-handback/105902056</link><description>King Charles marked the major milestone in Aboriginal land rights alongside Uluru-Kata Tjuta's traditional owners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7d5382ea3e29445cd53373bb9eda014</guid></item><item><title>SA Education Department fined after teen fell from school playground swing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/sa-education-department-fined-playground-swing-fall/105900366</link><description>South Australia's Education Department has been fined $225,000 after a student at a special school fell from a swing which had not had a comprehensive safety inspection for eight years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cdc7ec760bf1e318791fcad162c615f</guid></item><item><title>Defence in talks to support Gaza peace plan but Australia says no request yet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/defence-in-talks-with-us-to-support-gaza-peace-plan/105902742</link><description>Australia's defence force has had discussions with the Unted States to provide support for its Gaza peace plan but the government says no formal request has been made yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd80619b996f35eb17de143a6b7e07dc</guid></item><item><title>Virtual emergency department a lifeline for patients in regional areas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/virtual-emergency-department-option-for-patients-remote-areas/105371852</link><description>A virtual emergency room app created during the pandemic could help bridge healthcare gaps in regional Victoria. But more patients need to dial-in and use the resource.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cce3e05039289d83c6bdbae0a5d4e7b</guid></item><item><title>How wild bird poo testing in northern Australia is helping keep eggs on the shelves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/bird-flu-poo-testing-in-northern-australia-keeps-eggs-on-shelves/105894598</link><description>Hundreds of kilometres from the nearest supermarket, Indigenous rangers in Australia's remote north are working to keep eggs on your breakfast table.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">126bc279f84d1b05bc9d6ac31fa6b513</guid></item><item><title>Bears kill record number of people in Japan amid scores of attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/record-number-of-bear-attacks-in-japan/105902770</link><description>At least seven people have been killed by bears in the country since April and many more have been injured as the hungry animals venture into human territory to find food.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41b4b93bb120166534952debb22263e8</guid></item><item><title>US dangled threat of Tomahawks for Ukraine, then Russia called to negotiate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/us-tomahawk-long-range-missiles-supply-ukraine-russia-talks/105884192</link><description>US President Donald Trump threatened to send Tomahawk missiles to Ukraine if Russia did not return to peace talks, but analysts say the long-range weapons are not the game-changer they are made out to be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab37297fc9b45cbc08d59856d14f85f4</guid></item><item><title>Renters despair in 'landlord's market' where no-grounds evictions and frequent rent rises are legal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/nt-rental-housing-standards-no-grounds-eviction-rent-rises/105900204</link><description>Renters and experts are calling for change in one of just two Australian jurisdictions where renters can be evicted for no reason and the only place where landlords can raise rents more than once a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73136c6fb3e9f3567290edd360f36a95</guid></item><item><title>'No doubt' Anthony Albanese and Donald Trump will discuss critical minerals: Chalmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/albanese-trump-chalmers-critical-minerals-deal/105903392</link><description>Anthony Albanese will "no doubt" use a meeting with Donald Trump next week to discuss critical minerals, the treasurer says as he dismisses a call for Australia to "decouple" with China over rare earth materials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fe4351ff10e966c7a84c8e260555fa8</guid></item><item><title>Pacific Championships set to start without Australia as strong Samoa and Tonga teams take on New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/pacific-championships-stars-embrace-their-island-heritage/105903826</link><description>Emerging superpowers Samoa and Tonga will field formidable teams loaded with NRL talent in the third edition of the Pacific Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07fb63cc9e9ec53c5f2664aaf516d600</guid></item><item><title>WA's insolvent Griffin Coal ramps up operations as taxpayer bailout deadline looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/insolvent-wa-griffin-coal-ramps-up-operations/105901120</link><description>The receiver of a WA coal mine says it is ramping up operations in a final attempt to trade out of insolvency before millions of dollars in taxpayer support dries up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2e888ffc914c66fe0fec7316e9144da</guid></item><item><title>Pet-friendly flights are taking off in Australia. Here's what to know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/pet-friendly-flights-what-to-know/105903876</link><description>The first pet-friendly commercial flights have taken off in Australia this week. Here's what you need to know about the new service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4379a2d55c184d75fb0dbc167127d3db</guid></item><item><title>Cameron Green ruled out of Australia vs India ODI series, Marnus Labuschagne called into squad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/cameron-green-ruled-out-of-australia-vs-india-odi-series/105904798</link><description>Cameron Green has been ruled out of Australia's ODI series against India, just over a month out from the start of the Ashes series against England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfecd41bffae6db1aa484dbde8addcc6</guid></item><item><title>Family of murdered Darwin man Tony Rowe describe 'massive hole' of father's absence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/family-murdered-darwin-man-tony-rowe-by-timothy-hunt-impact/105904050</link><description>Family members of Tony Rowe — who was murdered on the outskirts of Darwin in 2022 — have read emotional victim impact statements to the court ahead of killer Timothy Hunt's sentencing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8adc5da1876325d1a54d3a1b9c74771e</guid></item><item><title>David Pye on bail after being refused anxiety drugs in custody, Nick Martin trial hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/david-pye-trial-told-of-nick-martin-killer-iraq-terror-link-/105903116</link><description>An accused murderer and bikie gang member on trial in WA's Supreme Court amid heightened security is granted bail because he is unable to get access to anti-anxiety medication behind bars, it is revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d458f503d4b0f4c89690a3b91078a89e</guid></item><item><title>Ways to increase safety on a first date and red flags to watch for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/red-flags-on-first-date-safety-tips/105805388</link><description>Both people involved in a date are responsible for creating a safe environment, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f5f2638f6ee24d2f8b7347e8441dce8</guid></item><item><title>Accused killer Jason Thomas King takes stand in Molendinar landlord Susan Walker's murder trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/jason-thomas-king-murder-trial-landlord-continues/105904754</link><description>Jason Thomas King has pleaded not guilty to the murder of his landlord Susan Walker on the Gold Coast in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">561483c094963904fd07393e184bed8f</guid></item><item><title>Endemic frog and gecko species identified on Dauan Island in Torres Strait</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/frog-gecko-species-found-dauan-torres-strait/105790146</link><description>Two new frog species and a banded-patterned gecko are believed to have sheltered among the boulders of Dauan, in the Torres Strait, for millions of years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02d7af04ef02838cbdfc93bff8ff13f8</guid></item><item><title>Inquest hears of grief, trauma from families of Eugowra locals after record-breaking 2022 flood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/eugowra-inquest-day-five/105902498</link><description>Families speak of loss, trauma on final day of the coronial inquest into the deaths of Les Vugec and Diane Smith.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dcae5aba593220ee08189da0bc90ff1</guid></item><item><title>After three trials Hunter Valley man jailed for covering up Carly McBride's 2014 murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/james-cunneen-sentenced-for-murder-cover-up/105462274</link><description>Hunter Valley man James Anthony Cunneen has been sentenced to six years jail for covering up a murder after helping his friend to dump a woman's body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b74dbad40fbab690ff260ffadfa040df</guid></item><item><title>Video released of moments leading up to strip search that breached Aboriginal woman's human rights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/julianne-williams-strip-search-canberra-jail-video-release-court/105905888</link><description>The ACT Supreme Court has made public confronting video showing the moments leading up to a strip search that violated an Aboriginal woman’s human rights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdcb7325932b405b24aab30e15587062</guid></item><item><title>Three teens charged over Wakeley church attack on bishop hit with violent extremist material charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/wakeley-church-stabbing-teens-face-extremism-material-charges/105905428</link><description>Three of the five young people charged in relation to the alleged stabbing of a Bishop at a church in Sydney's west last year have been charged with additional offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c73ef4a1ef617bb06598d16d3f448ae5</guid></item><item><title>Wayne Swan steps down as Labor president urging party to focus on membership boost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/wayne-swan-labor-president-leaves-role-politics/105905064</link><description>Labor party president Wayne Swan will step down next July and has warned the ALP must boost membership if it is to survive into the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75e127f2e28c7f78ce730de287d98398</guid></item><item><title>Wittenoom asbestos contamination prompts legal threat from Banjima traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/wittenoom-asbestos-litigation-documentary/105886444</link><description>After decades of disconnection, the traditional owners of Wittenoom say they are prepared to take legal action to ensure the area is properly remediated so they can return to country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">713ee52afb0c4689f99c025841f00428</guid></item><item><title>Friday the pelican captured and washed after three-week chase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/friday-the-pelican-captured-and-washed-after-three-week-chase/105906028</link><description>Friday the pelican evaded capture for weeks. But a long-overdue bath is for her own good.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08e29ab2dd99920f8f64165e8034ff2b</guid></item><item><title>Strict conditions imposed on future LIV Golf site at North Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/strict-conditions-on-north-adelaide-golf-course-redevelopment/105905844</link><description>South Australia's Aboriginal affairs minister has imposed 31 strict conditions on the government's planned redevelopment of the North Adelaide golf course.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc6d01343d110faca4bb8653ade74cc5</guid></item><item><title>Chinese national charged with foreign interference granted bail despite concerns she could flee country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/act-chinese-national-charged-foreign-interference-granted-bail/105906106</link><description>A woman accused of covertly gathering information for the Chinese government has been granted bail in Canberra, despite police warning she could try to flee the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f8a82b873c67ac845e029c6fb5fd2f1</guid></item><item><title>Scott Boland bowls Victoria to Sheffield Shield victory over NSW, ahead of Ashes against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/scott-boland-bowls-victoria-to-sheffield-shield-victory-over-nsw/105905076</link><description>Scott Boland has produced a man-of-the-match performance, bowling Victoria to a 38-run win over New South Wales in their Sheffield Shield clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">729329d9bae119b36c0706d109492cf3</guid></item><item><title>Inquest recommends road safety reforms after cyclist killed by partially blind driver</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/robert-hall-inquest-findings-handed-down/105903390</link><description>A coroner has recommended changes to national driving fitness standards following the death of cyclist Robert Hill who was hit and killed by a partially blind driver on a country highway seven years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58795b8a47c2e0572a629a78ac6f936c</guid></item><item><title>Premier David Crisafulli apologises for 'poor choice' comment about Melbourne stabbing attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/qld-premier-david-crisafulli-melbourne-stabbing-comment-apology/105906370</link><description>David Crisafulli apologises for a remark about crime, made on the same day footage emerges of a random stabbing attack in Melbourne's CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cfc9ef57f9baede516fe09e6c82b709</guid></item><item><title>Australia Diamonds defeat New Zealand Silver Ferns 69-52 in game one of Constellation Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/australia-diamonds-defeat-new-zealand-silver-ferns-69-52/105905070</link><description>Australia has stormed to a commanding win in the first Test of the Constellation Cup series, defeating New Zealand 69-52.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f36860ee433d3f4861c1144ddc36164e</guid></item><item><title>AFLW Round 10: Port Adelaide Power defeat Hawthorn Hawks, West Coast Eagles down Geelong Cats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/aflw-round-10-power-hawks-eagles-cats/105906400</link><description>Port Adelaide defeats Hawthorn to record its fourth win of the AFLW season, while West Coast moves closer to a maiden finals appearance with victory over Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae0cbd52bca8dc6756cd2ffe42c3b8bd</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide United defeats Sydney FC 2-1, Brisbane downs Macarthur on A-League Men opening night</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/aleagues-men-adelaide-sydney-brisbane-macarthur/105906556</link><description>Adelaide United begins its season with a 2-1 win over Sydney, while Brisbane coach Michael Valkanis sees son Dimitri sent off in the Roar's 1-0 defeat of Macarthur.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82bb437ece317276dd69493b6848e7ad</guid></item><item><title>Russia convicts 15 captured Ukrainian soldiers on terrorism charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-17/russia-convicts-15-captured-ukrainian-soldiers/105906652</link><description>Fifteen captured Ukrainian soldiers from the Aidar battalion have been sentenced in a Russian court to up to 21 years in a penal colony.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b7ddec1dccff7c0b1c93ead771afa46</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's Trump meeting comes amid global geopolitical circus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/gaza-ceasefire-deal-donald-trump-anthony-albanese-trade-tariff/105884238</link><description>All signs suggest Anthony Albanese will be sticking with Plan A in his meeting with the US president on Tuesday, rather than becoming a prop for the bigger global circus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7369e04e283103228bfcf69dddc12dd2</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew giving up his royal titles and honours after speaking with King Charles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/prince-andrew-to-give-up-royal-titles-and-honours/105907098</link><description>King Charles's brother has come under significant pressure after being linked to the late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein and his ties to China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b88d507f6b73a3388229f325fd5168e</guid></item><item><title>Creating deepfakes has never been easier, so what should parents do?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/creating-deepfakes-is-easy-what-should-parents-do/105902982</link><description>Some parents may feel distressed and ill-equipped to tackle the issue of image-based abuse and deepfakes. This is what to watch out for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">136e26003e31a95432cd2b1c4b32704d</guid></item><item><title>Video appears to show March for Australia organiser coordinating with Neo-Nazi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/march-for-australia-organiser-coordinates-with-neo-nazi/105902754</link><description>A previously unreported video has emerged appearing to show a key March for Australia organiser coordinating with a Neo-Nazi at the first rally in Sydney in August, ABC NEWS Verify has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc104ef4e2d70260f456bb05e05b9a6c</guid></item><item><title>Administrative Review Tribunal swamped by surging demand, more than 100 members short</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/administrative-review-tribunal-overwhelmed-surging-demand/105893728</link><description>The Administrative Review Tribunal was set up to resolve issues with its predecessor, but has struggled with staffing and long wait times over its first year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fd2f156e95340a969daa8b6003273f1</guid></item><item><title>Education department admits not enough done to stop Dubbo College Delroy aide harming children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/systemic-failure-to-investigate-nsw-dubbo-school-staff/105807290</link><description>The NSW government says it should have taken allegations of wrongdoing by a male school staff member more seriously. That failure left those who reported it so isolated their mental health spiralled and never fully recovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c22f6955d77c23cb8f7c088405ad508</guid></item><item><title>Wall Street sell-off could mean hip-pocket relief for millions of Australians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/insurance-companies-caught-in-global-sector-sell-off/105906164</link><description>Australia's big insurance companies were sold off heavily on the share market on Friday after a wave of anxiety hit the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e35eee1242809cb384df7776dc560ebc</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's family reportedly made hundreds of millions from crypto after White House return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/how-trump-family-profits-from-cryptocurrencies/105445400</link><description>US President Donald Trump and his family have reportedly amassed hundreds of millions of dollars from cryptocurrencies. Here is what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d405316e27218a44724818a9f9ff772a</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou defends record as pressure builds at Nottingham Forest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/ange-postecoglou-launches-passionate-defence-of-record/105907112</link><description>Amid growing pressure of his poor start at Nottingham Forest, Ange Postecoglou delivers a five-minute defence of his record as a manager.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1863ae28c5532d8ed98a6a975abd634</guid></item><item><title>Fire authorities warn of 'above average' fire season as NSW starts to warm up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/nsw-above-average-fire-season-bushfire-risk-weather/105900120</link><description>Fire authorities warn of above average fire season in NSW despite previous modelling showing a wet summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52eaca3898c563789480ae66f0c7a43f</guid></item><item><title>Brad Battin under pressure as Liberal MPs weigh up second leadership spill in less than 12 months</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/brad-battin-victorian-liberal-leader-analysis/105904104</link><description>The Victorian Liberals could be headed for their third leader in less than 12 months, with MPs internally dissatisfied with the performance of current leader Brad Battin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c7498fe9c9833ab207d978dc7164bb6</guid></item><item><title>Is the transfer of Australia's best young soccer players a good thing?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/soccer-a-league-player-transfers/105893566</link><description>Are A-League soccer fans right to be frustrated when its best young players are sold off, or should they accept it is a 'selling' league?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0e06963459d7a95465fff2d57464f52</guid></item><item><title>Young people with chronic pain feel 'unheard', misunderstood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/young-people-living-with-chronic-pain/105898314</link><description>Chronic pain affects one in five Australian children. Two young people who experience it want more people to understand their conditions and better support for all children in pain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">946486ae5287caf11084ac18ee24e69e</guid></item><item><title>Lack of housing in remote NT community Borroloola forcing families off country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/borroloola-housing-lack-forcing-families-leave-country/105895586</link><description>Remote NT residents are calling on the government to fund new housing in the Gulf community of Borroloola, fearing limited access to appropriate homes has forced families to move off country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df22bcf01f5fa2c70abd461d204c6d03</guid></item><item><title>James Duckworth returns to ATP Tour semifinal four years after his last</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/james-duckworth-atp-tour-astana-open-semi-final/105907190</link><description>Four years since he last reached an ATP tournament semifinal in Kazakhstan, Australian James Duckworth is back in the last four at the Almaty Open</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dceb858841c1c847c349b2a7432508b3</guid></item><item><title>Hospital in the Home program helping young man with agoraphobia who 'cut himself off from the world'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/hospital-in-the-home-northwest-tasmania-mental-health/105789004</link><description>Tom French's agoraphobia meant he couldn't leave the house to access the mental health care he needed, but a Hospital in the Home program means the care is coming to him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1b964e8ba63ca42e36daf1af0d1b9c8</guid></item><item><title>The face of Brisbane is changing — but should thousands of homes be developed in a flood zone?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/visy-montague-road-riverfront-precinct-thousands-of-homes-floods/105904030</link><description>Plans to build a riverfront precinct in a flood-prone area of Brisbane have urban planners and locals wary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d506b00fbc8d45eff04ef30c465454e6</guid></item><item><title>Tool's Maynard James Keenan on touring Australia, making wine and martial arts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/tool-australia-tour-2025-maynard-james-keenan-interview/105865706</link><description>The alt-metal band's frontman is a world-class multi-tasker. He tells us how he balances it all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">501350518724f7dcac6393cd0c095da6</guid></item><item><title>Western Australia starts harvesting what could be a record-breaking grain crop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/western-australia-harvest-record-grain-crop-expected/105900332</link><description>Farmers in Western Australia have begun harvesting a grain crop that could set a new record. It is a different story on the other side of the Nullabor though.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a84a87f36461e65b587de7b1fd2f66c6</guid></item><item><title>Greek-inspired lamb kebabs with olive potatoes baked in the oven - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/easy-oven-baked-lamb-kebabs-with-olive-potatoes/105291672</link><description>The lamb is fuss-free and full of flavour. No barbecue needed — the oven takes care of everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97732d3bb23552f5f8a4e4e0fa75a14b</guid></item><item><title>From a Springsteen biopic to a doggy horror: here are the movies out in October</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/october-movie-wrap-what-to-watch/105893300</link><description>From the highly anticipated Bruce Springsteen biopic to a horror movie from the viewpoint of the family pup, here are the films filling up cinemas in October.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f217a9477d3de1211d4744ae2ba19bd8</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne's record-setting AFLW winning streak is clear in the numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/north-melbourne-setting-aflw-standards/105905842</link><description>Having developed the program layer by layer since joining the AFLW in 2019, North Melbourne's disciplined, professional style of footy is forcing the rest of the league to rise to their level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3f69ec228f1094f89b081dd9d305cb5</guid></item><item><title>Cool weather prescribed burn on WA's south coast should be expanded, environmental group says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/call-to-expand-cool-weather-burns-to-protect-the-environment/105896512</link><description>The success of a small, autumn prescribed burn on WA's south coast has prompted calls to replace the regular program to reduce environmental damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">164585befee231bbcfbedee418ccc7bd</guid></item><item><title>NT's top judge tells government not to interfere with court independence, in leaked email</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/nt-judge-accuses-government-of-interfering-with-court-operations/105904858</link><description>A leaked email shows the Northern Territory's highest-ranking judge wrote to a government department asking it not to interfere with the Supreme Court's independence. A courts spokesperson has since said the email was the result of a misunderstanding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69ad31302102fadb90b3e422f9c25327</guid></item><item><title>Phoebe Litchfield learning from opening partner Alyssa Healy at Women's Cricket World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/phoebe-litchfield-alyssa-healy-womens-cricket-world-cup/105907312</link><description>Alyssa Healy has joined an elite band of women batters with 7,000 international runs, and Australia's captain is giving her brilliant young opening partner something to aim for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a50f38a0dacc4756881494b6edf4d5e</guid></item><item><title>Minister flags compulsory voting in local government elections, 4-year terms amid low voter turnout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/compulsory-voting-flagged-for-wa-local-government-election/105901804</link><description>Voting in council elections could become mandatory in Western Australia if the turnout for this weekend's poll continues to plummet, the local government minister warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90ce7dc5327df5d0b3904814e2638839</guid></item><item><title>Heavy horsemen keep farming traditions alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/heavy-horsemen-keep-farming-traditions-alive/105887988</link><description>Aleks Berzins is farming the land in the same way his grandfather did, using draught horses for jobs now widely done by machines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f47d3bf2b7c8199053c352b6aaf54536</guid></item><item><title>Coroner finds snakebite death of 11yo Tristian Frahm preventable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/coroner-finds-snakebite-death-of-tristian-frahm-preventable/105907556</link><description>The death of an 11-year-old Queensland boy from a snakebite may have been prevented had he received early medical attention, according to the findings of an inquest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7845efcc529ff7078aaecea2c035d784</guid></item><item><title>Gungahlin United Football Club to fold after losing NPL licence, leaving 2,000 grassroots players club-less</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/gungahlin-united-fc-fold-capital-football-licence-revoke/105907530</link><description>Just last year, the club won the league, and a former president was jailed for stealing $20k. Now they are going to fold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b94409bd3e5cff77f2199cae368e6fbf</guid></item><item><title>Who is Prince Andrew? Why is he giving up his royal title?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/why-prince-andrew-gives-up-royal-titles-duke-of-york/105907380</link><description>The third-born child of Queen Elizabeth II will still be referred to as a prince and is expected to continue living in his Windsor mansion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08536e709980d0a36f65e1774362c22d</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce hasn't quit the Nationals yet but he's got one foot out the door</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/speers-analysis-barnaby-joyce-has-not-quit-the-nationals-yet/105907744</link><description>In declaring he won't be recontesting his lower house seat and letting speculation run that he might jump ship for One Nation, Barnaby Joyce is declaring he's had enough with the Nationals under David Littleproud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f61bd6ea4984b1bc51fdcb3bae580b</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos defeat Crows by 40 points to move closer to winning record as Saints, Dockers and Demons notch victories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/aflw-demons-swans-kangaroos-crows-giants-dockers-blues-saints/105907762</link><description>North Melbourne moves one victory away from equalling the all-time VFL/AFL and AFLW winning record with a 40-point drubbing of Adelaide as St Kilda moves closer to a maiden finals appearance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3036c640f5f12f4b89b3526d94476ea</guid></item><item><title>NT chief minister claims tough-on-crime approach has led to 'significant' crime drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/nt-chief-minister-claims-tough-on-crime-led-to-crime-drop/105906588</link><description>NT Chief Minister Lia Finocchiaro says the Country Liberal Party's tough-on-crime approach "is working". But after two teens broke into a play centre and left a trail of destruction, operator Steve Mason is not convinced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ceb1811e211ef03f608859e94141ede6</guid></item><item><title>Chinese Communist Party's Central Committee set for major shake-up at plenum meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/xi-inner-circle-major-shakeup-ccp-meeting-beijing/105885472</link><description>A key meeting of the Chinese Communist Party Central Committee is expected to include a major shake-up of President Xi Jinping's inner circle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41655c3a7bf399a2c8c3669a0f55d79b</guid></item><item><title>Collingwood cult hero Mason Cox not offered new contract for 2026 AFL season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-18/mason-cox-leaves-collingwood-magpies/105907852</link><description>Mason Cox, the first American to become an AFL regular, confirms he will not be with the Magpies in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faaa19652e592fb7fd468bdd25c33d4d</guid></item><item><title>Nottingham Forest sack manager Ange Postecoglou immediately after loss to Chelsea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/ange-postecoglou-sacked-nottingham-forest/105908162</link><description>Nottingham Forest sacked the winless manager moments after their 3-0 defeat by Chelsea on Saturday local time, which left the club 17th in the standings and on the brink of slipping into the relegation zone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57c551c6fd2ddff4af0d49de00cd0a77</guid></item><item><title>China's economic slowdown has become its diplomatic weapon in the Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/china-economy-pacific-australia-united-states/105884758</link><description>For Australia and the US, the Pacific is no longer a comfortable backyard — it's a battleground of credibility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2b0e48dd4fde1249a89b421640ef595</guid></item><item><title>The deep Indigenous history of Australia deserves to be up in lights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/deep-time-indigenous-history-65000-years/105693082</link><description>We've flipped the script to put Indigenous Australians back at the centre of telling their own stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1b24be62527f979869b9fe019461e17</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese is set to sit down with Donald Trump. What can he learn from other world leaders?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/anthony-albanese-sits-down-with-trump-what-can-he-learn/105894690</link><description>As other world leaders have discovered, a visit to Donald Trump's White House can become an unpredictable, if not uncomfortable, encounter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4b6d1356ae3c998aaee4553a3793db7</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew's decision to give up his titles may have been quietly orchestrated by members of his own family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/is-prince-andrews-decision-enough-to-stem-damage-to-monarchy/105907688</link><description>With the swirl of news around Prince Andrew this week, something had to be done; the question was whether he would do it himself or if his brother would be forced to show him the door.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b77456c907ef9b548850123a9b10fa3e</guid></item><item><title>BOM's first long-range summer forecast shows increased chance of extreme heat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/bom-summer-weather-forecast-hot-and-dry-with-high-fire-risk/105899594</link><description>Hot nights coupled with high daytime temperatures could see Australia heading into an extremely hot summer, BOM's first long-range forecast indicates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f141a77feebbff9dd877f9c172a7d949</guid></item><item><title>Native mussel restoration project supported by Victor Harbor community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/mussel-bed-rebuilding-at-encounter-bay-after-algal-bloom/105887684</link><description>Victor Harbor was one of the first areas affected by SA's harmful algal bloom. Now its citizens are funding and supporting research into rebuilding native mussel populations as it looks to the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5482853b2341d466e8d2331ff929036a</guid></item><item><title>After Ukraine, Finland hopes it won't be Putin's next target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/inside-finlands-preparations-for-russian-invasion/105859992</link><description>Blasted into the bedrock, deep below the streets of Helsinki, these massive bunkers are currently used for recreation. Their primary function, however, is much more sinister: preparing for a Russian invasion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3896c79d12d96bc2c66108ed2320d926</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz Kids: Who says trivia is just for grown-ups? It's time to put your thinking cap on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/hard-quiz-kids-weekly-trivia-tom-gleeson/105894882</link><description>Hard Quiz Kids is here again, and we're gifting you a bunch of straightforward questions. Don't embarrass yourself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eae196e3bd245bc87722d2b719e6f741</guid></item><item><title>China's 'special forces'-style tourists packing big itineraries in small budgets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/china-hong-kong-special-forces-style-travel-sleep-mcdonalds/105902602</link><description>Young Chinese tourists with limited time and money are travelling 'special forces'-style — inspired by the efficiency, endurance, and intensity of military units.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecc8983a388385cd9855eaf49fa6fe2b</guid></item><item><title>How Mother Teresa helped Steve Waugh channel his 'power' for children in need</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/steve-waugh-on-meeting-mother-teresa/105671818</link><description>When Steve Waugh retired from cricket, he knew he wanted to use his influence to make a difference. It was meeting Mother Teresa that made him realise his new path.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f532c8e947e73fb6c25eb280850294d</guid></item><item><title>Aussie Bird Count brings together students, photographers and nature-lovers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/aussie-bird-count-students-volunteer/105903124</link><description>A primary school teacher is getting her students involved in a volunteer-led bird count, to gather a snapshot of birds across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1902614b6d2d117e4440091bf145ffb</guid></item><item><title>'No Kings' protest crowds gather across the US against Donald Trump's leadership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/no-kings-protests-across-us-against-donald-trump/105908510</link><description>Organisers say the rallies reflect frustration over the Trump administration's prosecutions of the president's perceived enemies, immigration raids and the sending of troops into US cities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">844c41c111bff92bc93ef28915c54a4f</guid></item><item><title>Cheap energy driven by rooftop solar means larger solar farms could be unviable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/cheap-solar-household-energy-pushing-solar-farms-out-of-market/105898336</link><description>Australia's renewable energy push has resulted in a surge in household solar power. But what does that mean for private solar farms?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36014b920dd1bc4459bb64a96d7ea4d1</guid></item><item><title>Sheffield Shield round two quick hits: Marnus Labuschagne confirms form ahead of Ashes, Scott Boland bullies and spinners offer reminder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/sheffield-shield-summary-marnus-labuschagne/105907142</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne's magical early season form continues with the bat, Scott Boland and a pair of spinners offer a reminder of their skill, while Sam Konstas turns on the flair at round two of the Sheffield Shield.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">054ff0d8e5945ea2d312a9468fd3278e</guid></item><item><title>Iconic house for sale for only second time in 193-year history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/iconic-house-for-sale-for-only-second-time-in-193-year-history/105838914</link><description>Classical musicians Richard and Suzy Miller count their circa-1832 home as one of their greatest creative achievements as they prepare to leave it for someone else to love.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0cb817277090afe4c3ee03c0a1fb2c2</guid></item><item><title>James Duckworth falls at Almaty Open semi-final stage against Daniil Medvedev</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/james-duckworth-falls-almati-open-semi-final-daniil-medvedev/105908658</link><description>Australian seed-slayer James Duckworth has finally met his match in Almaty, where Daniil Medvedev dug deep to beat him in three sets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0d127a1f537ae19f3d552f01bce600f</guid></item><item><title>North Queensland by-election to provide snapshot of state's politics a year on from LNP victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/qld-hinchinbrook-by-election-analysis/105902784</link><description>The looming by-election in Hinchinbrook will not have a significant impact on the makeup of Queensland parliament, but it will give insight into the state of play of politics a year after the LNP swept to power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">172765f854cdca401a9862668704f49f</guid></item><item><title>It's been called Canberra's 'forever government' — but ACT Labor's brand is growing tired</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/act-canberra-forever-government-but-labor-brand-growing-tired/105904332</link><description>It's been a year since Canberrans re-elected an ACT Labor government for a seventh consecutive term — but as budget pressures bite, analysts say Labor's stocks are suffering from brand fatigue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ee3cbb31b12feb0dbf9a314f57eeb6d</guid></item><item><title>Mike Hewson creates controversial children's playgrounds. Explore his latest creation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/mike-hewson-takes-kids-four-storeys-underground/105896640</link><description>This designer's "risky playgrounds" are often divisive. His latest is four storeys underground in a former World War II oil tank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5af465a6bbf0383d41c1060eddfa1af6</guid></item><item><title>New Tasmanian Integrity Commission head will decide whether to release report from six-year investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/tasmanian-integrity-commission-finishes-six-year-investigation/105894390</link><description>Seven years after allegations were made against a practitioner who was allegedly misusing public resources, Tasmania's Integrity Commission has finalised its investigation into the matter. However, the report has not been released to the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c5fd50bb3ddf358b3e61158eed83e42</guid></item><item><title>Social media promotion of raw milk 'misleading and dangerous'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/raw-milk-trend-worries-experts/105636166</link><description>A public health expert says social media content creators are undermining years of scientific research by promoting raw milk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be479a18a9b8b5bd2c9c5515b5b11008</guid></item><item><title>Dodo and iPrimus hack impacts more than 1,600 home internet, email and mobile customers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/dodo-hack-impacts-internet-email-and-mobile-customers/105908674</link><description>More than 1,600 Dodo and iPrimus home internet and mobile customers were impacted by a hack of the telco's email and mobile services, the company confirms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2023f6e78d453f5b1767f6b78873787c</guid></item><item><title>GPs with extra skills who want to work in Tasmania say there are no suitable jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/rural-generalists-tasmanian-health-service-say-no-suitable-jobs/105907346</link><description>Rural generalists are GPs with training in emergency care and one other advanced skill area. While Tasmania has a training program for rural generalists, doctors say their skills are not properly recognised by the Tasmanian Health Service.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa38354b32d3f313d4fb620c7e2db87f</guid></item><item><title>International chefs share signature flavours as part of Lambassador program</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/international-lambassadors-arrive-in-australia-for-lamb-lessons/105903950</link><description>A delegation of international chefs from 11 countries have landed in Australia to gain a deeper understanding of locally produced Australian lamb.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71e07198c67015e99c324d0292653818</guid></item><item><title>Nationals leader wants Barnaby Joyce to 'stay', amid rumour of One Nation defection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/nationals-littleproud-barnaby-joyce-stay-party-one-nation/105908722</link><description>Announcing he would not re-contest his seat of New England for the Nationals, Barnaby Joyce cited an irreparable breakdown with his party leader David Littleproud. Mr Littleproud says he still wants Mr Joyce to stay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9848481613384650c56cadeda692b7be</guid></item><item><title>National Disruption Group to be established to crush tobacco black market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/national-distruption-group-tobacco-black-market/105908764</link><description>A new "National Disruption Group" will be convened to stamp out the exploding illicit tobacco market and other "converging" threats, the home affairs minister has announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cc3bdda511d1e9aa7bb583dee35ef1e</guid></item><item><title>Five suspected rat poison cases detected in south-east Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/qld-rat-poisoning-symptoms-reported-to-hospitals/105908798</link><description>Queensland Health is investigating after five people were hospitalised with symptoms of ingesting rat poison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e5b91d5e833fa2e54a07c383a89f60</guid></item><item><title>Ange Postecoglou's Nottingham Forest stint a classic case of wrong place, wrong time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/ange-postecoglou-nottingham-forest-wrong-team-brian-clough/105908712</link><description>Ange Postecoglou was on a hiding to nothing at Nottingham Forest, his sacking the result of terrible recruitment and a knee-jerk appointment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0adc426b55b3caeb01dc1561cdfadbc</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan and Afghanistan agree to immediate ceasefire after peace talks in Doha</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/pakistan-afghanistan-agree-to-immediate-ceasefire-doha-talks/105908852</link><description>A week of fierce border clashes has seen the worst violence between the two countries since the Taliban seized power in Kabul in 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ae3ed5418e4616f7f9a9cc4b9feaba5</guid></item><item><title>'Green bans' saved Sydney's historic buildings and taught economists a lesson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/green-bans-sydney-1970s-unions-nimby-yimby-milton-friedman/105903850</link><description>The "green bans" in the 1970s saved many of Australia's historic buildings and our cities are richer for them. But a famous economist didn't like them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abdb337970b734f91db4e99387b96c1a</guid></item><item><title>Trent Dalton's Boy Swallows Universe wins the Top 100 Books countdown — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/top-100-books-of-the-21st-century-radio-national-live-updates/105900036</link><description>Trent Dalton's debut novel Boy Swallows Universe has won Radio National's Top 100 Books of the 21st Century countdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a93d820be1134030d36a0450e5827bd4</guid></item><item><title>How Claire's decision to be 'one and done' was rocked by divorce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/how-claire-feels-about-being-one-and-done-after-divorce/105870074</link><description>After a traumatic birth, followed by mental and physical health challenges, Claire was "one and done". But divorce made her think twice about her decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c4071ab0f2b41bc5ba8af85bdc44b4</guid></item><item><title>North Adelaide golf course safeguards fall short, some Kaurna community members say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/liv-golf-aboriginal-heritage-reaction/105908982</link><description>As the Malinauskas government proceeds with its $50 million North Adelaide golf course upgrade, some Kaurna elders are grappling with the prospect that the redevelopment could uncover Aboriginal remains.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9101d5e10e56032ae087ac48805699a</guid></item><item><title>The story of the 1970 West Gate Bridge disaster features in Melbourne Theatre Company's 2026 season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/melbourne-theatre-company-mtc-2026-season-anne-louise-sarks/105896178</link><description>The people impacted by Australia's worst industrial disaster are at the centre of West Gate by Dennis McIntosh, one of seven new Australian plays coming to Melbourne Theatre Company in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de0ad7e53c23dbee737f8a5d0098d29e</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Reynolds to remain City of Perth Lord Mayor as counting continues in WA local government elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/wa-local-government-election-results-perth-lord-mayor/105905464</link><description>Bruce Reynolds has held onto the title of City of Perth Lord Mayor, while early figures from WA's local government elections show voter turnout is below what authorities hoped for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a54bf02a0f8001516a58239517b18816</guid></item><item><title>Wadeye traditional owners say Yidiyi cultural festival brings community together as 'one family'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/wadeye-nt-yidiyi-festival-2025-brings-community-together/105908796</link><description>Traditional owners of the remote NT Aboriginal community of Wadeye say the community has been brought "together as one family" at this year's Yidiyi cultural festival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d233684dc20b0f2b15cd1d575b533874</guid></item><item><title>Bulldogs keep finals hopes alive with 66-point Suns trouncing, Lions and Tigers pick up wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/aflw-bombers-lions-magpies-tigers-suns-bulldogs/105909452</link><description>The Western Bulldogs hammer Gold Coast by 66 points to keep their finals flame flickering, while Brisbane returns to the top four with victory over Essendon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">220f543ca713782ae1e2a21e7e2fa7c0</guid></item><item><title>If we're going cashless, why do we still pay card fees?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/if-we-re-going-cashless-why-do-we-still-pay-card-fees-/105909604</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99d81835be593f4489d729ef0cd5668f</guid></item><item><title>Possible space junk found near Western Australian mine site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/wa-space-debris-reentry-investigation/105909612</link><description>Suspected space debris is believed to have crashed near a WA mine site, with the Australian Transport Safety Bureau confirming the object was not from a commercial aircraft.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07160fd72846f9d8cf600d6423dfba11</guid></item><item><title>Trent Dalton's Boy Swallows Universe wins Radio National's Top 100 Books of the 21st century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/top-100-books-trent-dalton-boy-swallows-universe/105872764</link><description>The results are in — Trent Dalton's Boy Swallows Universe has won Radio National's inaugural Top 100 Books of the 21st Century.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cef78d8d8b4ac4e460acf0badccc758</guid></item><item><title>Pope Leo XIV canonises Papua New Guinea's first Catholic saint Peter ToRot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/papua-new-guinea-first-catholic-saint-canonised/105908782</link><description>Peter ToRot, a Papua New Guinea man killed in prison in 1945 for standing up for monogamous marriage at a time when polygamy was practised has been canonised a saint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b144cc28b792f0d2dfcd4dee91332e0a</guid></item><item><title>Australia cruises to seven-wicket victory over India in rain-shortened ODI</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-19/odi-australia-defeats-india-by-seven-wickets-perth/105909904</link><description>Surviving a series of rain delays in Perth, Australia records a seven-wicket win over India in the first of three men's ODI matches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bfda650a8c1f1f7cac905e46ef4fbd7</guid></item><item><title>F1 United States Grand Prix: Oscar Piastri's championship lead trimmed, Max Verstappen beats Lando Norris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/f1-live-united-states-grand-prix-oscar-piastri-lando-norris/105894158</link><description>Max Verstappen has dominated from pole position to claim his fifth grand prix win of the season, as Oscar Piastri's lead of the Formula 1 drivers' championship was trimmed for the fourth consecutive weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bcdd6bd358bd86dd0f6bfeea97ab54e</guid></item><item><title>If AI and crypto aren't bubbles, we could be in big trouble</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/ai-crypto-bubbles-speculative-mania/105884508</link><description>Speculative manias where the first investors win because there isn't a bust are rare occurrences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">283c30df2984a269ddf09fef3456e7d6</guid></item><item><title>Reused signature among string of issues as home owner left with unfinished build</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/reused-signature-among-string-of-failures-on-home-build/105792444</link><description>When Matthew Mapley questioned why the bank had paid his builder for unfinished works, it said it had his written authority — except he hadn't signed it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">145bbaf8d8739f0ee1789f78d179e3e6</guid></item><item><title>How much do you know about Australia's epic 65,000-year history?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/deep-time-first-nations-history-australia/105906578</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7068111e58813c1ec3717ff7a0ba5b0</guid></item><item><title>How much do you really know about Australia's epic 65,000-year history?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/deep-time-indigenous-history-introduction/105907302</link><description>First Nations people have survived and thrived through an ice age and massive landscape changes — as well as sharing the land with giant animals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fac48bc54ea66e8592dfbaf1bfce506</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce says One Nation 'not barking mad' on net zero, but will not reveal if he will defect</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/nationals-no-mass-defection-barnaby-joyce-one-nation/105909238</link><description>Barnaby Joyce says that, "unlike others", One Nation's approach to climate change is not "barking mad". But the Nationals MP says he remains with his party — for now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba1192292768a0257d6e65e047ca10d2</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese's meeting with Donald Trump could hardly be timed better</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/albanese-trump-meeting-timing-critical-minerals/105909072</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is about to set foot inside the gilded cage of the Oval Office — and the timing could hardly be better.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d20e6cfd5af8252e5277f8c4a4af005</guid></item><item><title>Olympic BMX champion Saya Sakakibara still fears racing after brother Kai's horrific crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/saya-sakakibara-bmx-champ-on-facing-her-fears/105873744</link><description>When Saya Sakakibara saw her brother nearly die in a BMX crash, fear took hold. It nearly broke the star siblings' Olympic dream.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdae19b5295afb8401bfc230766e6f52</guid></item><item><title>Over a dozen unis are using AI to catch AI — and getting it wrong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/universities-using-ai-to-detect-students-cheating/105905804</link><description>At least a dozen Australian universities are using AI to detect AI. But they're not always catching cheats. Instead, they're wrongly accusing students of academic misconduct.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5ac54c938944764d045af8b0b3883b9</guid></item><item><title>20 per cent HECS cut does not address 'underlying problems', uni students and graduates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/20-per-cent-off-australian-hecs-debt-but-underlying-problems/105888952</link><description>A 20 per cent reduction on HECS debt is a welcomed relief for some 3 million Australians with a student loan. But those who paid their HECS early or are yet to rack up a debt will miss out on the support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b09ab14b2ad609ce96fc07e9706db7c3</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia's President Prabowo Subianto has just marked one year in office. Here is what has happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/prabowo-subianto-one-year-indonesia-democracy-under-pressure/105899812</link><description>A year after Indonesian President Prabowo Subianto won the election, the families of Indonesians arrested in recent protests are expressing dissatisfaction with his leadership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b83a02a5ebdccb4bcb096e6d4cfd0d6e</guid></item><item><title>Teenager who died by suicide sent final message to Gold Coast health service, but it went unanswered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/neve-wright-gold-coast-health-service-death-calls-investigation/105902752</link><description>The ABC has uncovered the case as part of an examination of Gold Coast Hospital and Health Service's treatment of mental health patients and their suicides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80b94bbccc9715cedfe4fc21a97e430c</guid></item><item><title>Rabbit populations boom in parts of Australia as ideal conditions see pests return</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/rabbit-populations-on-rise-in-southern-australia-after-rain/105903702</link><description>A resurgence of rabbit populations following recent rainfall is driving experts to urge for increased control measures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f0b63e3021992436e68289f3f87b2a2</guid></item><item><title>Daniil Medvedev wins Almaty Open, Elena Rybakina closes in on WTA Finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/atp-wta-tours-daniil-medvedev-elena-rybakina-win/105910582</link><description>Daniil Medvedev claims his first ATP Tour tournament win since 2023, while Elena Rybakina's push to reach the WTA Finals gathers momentum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d27928b89915e24efb9812cfeeed4e7</guid></item><item><title>ASX closes higher supported by banks while gold stocks sold off, China's economy continues to slow — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-october-20/105909396</link><description>The ASX gained 0.4 per cent as investors rotated out of miners and gold and into banks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5928ef0e0c4f7a369dea8bcc22702546</guid></item><item><title>All the numbers behind Radio National's Top 100 Books of the 21st century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/top-100-books-radio-national-trent-dalton-numbers/105876550</link><description>The winner for the Top 100 Books has been announced. What do the votes behind it say about us?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eceddbdf78c0567b7386f67a77686872</guid></item><item><title>Millions being spent as Australia prepares for deadly H5 strain of bird flu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/australia-prepares-for-deadly-h5-strain-of-bird-flu/105906562</link><description>The bird flu outbreak that saw millions of chickens culled and a national shortage of eggs has been declared eradicated, but scientists warn a much deadlier strain of avian influenza could arrive this spring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e83ea2739e1cc6e0699c27dab01c0b6a</guid></item><item><title>Healthscope under fire over proposal to farm millions in employees' tax benefits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/healthscope-proposal-for-workers-tax-benefits-under-fire/105894910</link><description>In-receivership hospital group Healthscope is taking radical steps to stay alive, converting to a charity and proposing to take up to 90 per cent of a benefit intended to reduce workers' taxable income.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54fe6626e9683e97ff7c755dc0f3b158</guid></item><item><title>Israel says ceasefire and aid to resume after airstrikes kill 26 in Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/israel-says-gaza-ceasefire-and-aid-to-resume/105910598</link><description>Israel says it has resumed enforcement of the Gaza ceasefire plan after it was "violated" by Hamas following a wave of Israeli strikes that killed 26 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b15241284c0d7f497581843777ebda8</guid></item><item><title>Multiple sclerosis support group tries to fill gaps as Northern Territory services dwindle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/multiple-sclerosis-support-group-tries-fill-nt-service-gaps/105839144</link><description>Being diagnosed with multiple sclerosis can often be an isolating experience, and even more so for those in Darwin who lack access to on-the-ground supports. Despite these barriers, a group of local women have created a support group to help fill the service gap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14749aee6ee20b3feba95efcd80cf469</guid></item><item><title>Drone view of Sheikh Radwan in Gaza City.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/gaza-city-drone-footage-3/105908302</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b263724c512ca695564de394cef74bc</guid></item><item><title>Drone footage reveals Gaza City's destruction as people return home during ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/drone-footage-reveals-gaza-city-destruction/105906708</link><description>One week into the ceasefire in Gaza, Palestinians are returning to destroyed homes and trying to find shelter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3949b76fa29fedb2ce2ac2c7ac488821</guid></item><item><title>England records four-run Women's World Cup win over India to join Australia in semifinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/cricket-world-cup-england-defeats-india-to-reach-semifinals/105910632</link><description>England secures its Women's World Cup semifinal spot with a tense four-run win over tournament co-host India at Indor's Holkar Stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca127f26cc1b519429233a14a7576b44</guid></item><item><title>Tourism dollars roll into Carnamah a year after arrival of big tractor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/worlds-biggest-tractor-tourism-wa-midwest-town-carnamah/105893574</link><description>One year on from its opening, the orange icon has brought people from all over Australia — and the world — to WA's Midwest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e006f37718ddfa2b762776c7387048c2</guid></item><item><title>Police probing claims Prince Andrew tried to smear sexual assault accuser Virginia Giuffre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/police-looking-into-claims-prince-andrew-smear-virginia-giuffre/105910618</link><description>British police say they're probing claims that Prince Andrew asked an officer to dig up dirt for a smear campaign against his sexual assault accuser Virginia Giuffre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e42ba0d11b99fb0e6ffb5ef188a4743</guid></item><item><title>Caravans clog suburban streets sparking calls for new laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/caravan-street-parking-congestion-motion-put-forward-to-state/105905046</link><description>Queensland councils put forward a motion calling on the state government to implement strict laws on caravan street parking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43fef001bb1c8713271d0be4b79c9222</guid></item><item><title>India backs Virat Kohli to rebound after ODI duck against Australia in Perth series opener</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/cricket-odi-india-australia-virat-kohli-duck/105910756</link><description>Virat Kohli failed to score in the opening men's ODI in Perth. However, his India teammates expect their ex-skipper to quickly recapture his best form.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bc80acf1d0f546076475e758c726a92</guid></item><item><title>Holiday from Hospital virtual reality to transport patients to Australia's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/holiday-from-hospital-virtual-reality-program/105904452</link><description>A leukaemia survivor designs a VR program that will help patients travel to some of Australia's iconic locations from their hospital beds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86e927a78d6931f5a5bc765a1bd0349f</guid></item><item><title>Richmond is starting to play good footy. But in AFLW's short season there's no time left to build momentum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/richmond-aflw-short-season-limits-chance-to-build-momentum/105910676</link><description>After a 0-7 start to the season, Richmond are starting to notch wins on the board. But it's too late for much momentum to build in the short women's season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">069e771beb7b5a18b4ca2823e445cde9</guid></item><item><title>Some scientists challenge logic of Victoria's fuel reduction burns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/scientists-challenge-fuel-load-burns-victoria/105666680</link><description>Dry winter conditions have resulted in extra fuel reduction burns in regional Victoria ahead of the fire season. But some scientists are asking if fuel burns are the best way to reduce fire risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24063f01e48736dadc0cd1dc663f5536</guid></item><item><title>Severe winds and hail hit WA's Kimberley as wet season approaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/wild-weather-batters-far-north-wa-unusual-hailstorm/105909234</link><description>Wild weather hit the Kimberley over the weekend, with some residents witnessing hail falling on their lawns despite it being a 38-degree day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">759b0e13b14ba30ecea0dbed924de7c7</guid></item><item><title>Victorian police minister defends use of rubber bullets, pepper spray at Melbourne protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/police-minister-defends-use-of-force-at-melbourne-protest/105910874</link><description>Victoria's police minister backs the police response to protests in Melbourne's CBD on Sunday, when demonstrators were hit with rubber bullets and pepper spray.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26957d5a4aa63566b917429161520d6c</guid></item><item><title>F1 standings: Oscar Piastri says too early for McLaren to prioritise drivers as Max Verstappen continues charge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/f1-championship-standings-2025-piastri-verstappen-norris/105910856</link><description>Formula 1 championship leader Oscar Piastri says McLaren does not need to prioritise one driver over the other, as four-time world champion Max Verstappen continues to narrow the deficit to both.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6b6dbcdc3ff000bf792dec04e4a387f</guid></item><item><title>New childcare centres might ease waitlists in regional Victoria, but worker shortages endure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/childcare-worker-shortages-regional-victoria/105861138</link><description>Hundreds of children in a regional Victorian city are on childcare waitlists, but centres say they cannot open to full capacity as they struggle to find qualified staff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f8b17ce3da65fae957a913f9d8b696d</guid></item><item><title>Warning over rare but deadly virus after bat bites Pilbara woman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/pilbara-bat-bite-lyssavirus-treatment/105903464</link><description>A Pilbara resident says an attempt to save a small bat stuck in her house has resulted in painful treatment for a deadly virus that can be passed onto humans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7649b3e7c5d127072e9734a5e6389db2</guid></item><item><title>Melt Festival is giving queer artists a space to be themselves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/melt-at-pip-queer-arts-festival-stand-up-comedy/105876434</link><description>Brisbane's Melt Festival has rapidly expanded in the past decade, inviting numerous venues into the celebration of queer artistry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82f95541593c2dd6615f166a0fa29834</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr backed by Matildas coach Joe Montemurro to make impact in friendlies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/matildas-sam-kerr-joe-montemurro-wales-england-friendlies/105911490</link><description>Sam Kerr will return to the Matildas fold off the back of limited minutes at Chelsea, but coach Joe Montemurro is confident she will shine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55b775730bad08a65eaa25450f51842f</guid></item><item><title>Mossman sugarcane industry on its last legs as haulage deal ends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/mossman-sugarcane-mulgrave-mill-transport-costs-too-high/105905656</link><description>A deal between Mossman sugarcane growers and a mill 100 kilometres away has been deemed unviable, leaving farmers without a place to send their product after this season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4f1c7e046b4e98aead821af1d28a44d</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the Louvre jewellery heist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/what-we-know-about-the-louvre-jewellery-heist/105910640</link><description>Here are the details on the items stolen in the Louvre heist that unfolded in broad daylight in Paris.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d269eaf9f556b0ba4f01c08707826645</guid></item><item><title>Limp Bizkit bandmates pay tribute to bassist Sam Rivers after death at 48</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/limp-bizkit-bandmates-pay-tribute-to-bassist-sam-rivers/105911436</link><description>Fred Durst takes to social media to say he has shed "gallons of tears" since finding out about the death of his "truly wonderful" bandmate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1d63bc89303f861e3b31723c1277a98</guid></item><item><title>Cargo plane slides off runway at Hong Kong International Airport, two people dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/hong-kong-airport-cargo-plane-crash/105911458</link><description>The flight arriving from Dubai was landing at Hong Kong International Airport when it skidded off the runway, leading to the deaths of two men in a vehicle on the ground, according to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">949790ffe37f5f7d2047c0e6ac8b0cee</guid></item><item><title>Australian Olympic champion Kaylee McKeown breaks world short course record</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/swimming-kaylee-mckeown-breaks-world-short-course-record/105912014</link><description>Australia's five-time Olympic gold medallist Kaylee McKeown sets a world short course record in the women's 200 metres backstroke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">402b6aa0b6c8c60ddfcda2c6439f5872</guid></item><item><title>Former Toowoomba Chronicle journalist Peter Hardwick sentenced over indecent treatment of child</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/qld-former-journalist-peter-hardwick-child-indecent-treatment/105911288</link><description>Peter Hardwick is sentenced after pleading guilty to two counts of indecent treatment of a child under the age of 12.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5215ec6b2a4623b1d02131cfd00d22d9</guid></item><item><title>The story of Budj Bim has been handed down for thousands of years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/story-of-budj-bim-handed-down-for-thousands-of-years/105906498</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a104339b1170d68a3dbc3cbda90877b</guid></item><item><title>Murujuga's rock art gallery dates back to more than 40,000 years ago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/murujuga-s-rock-art-gallery-dates-back-40-000-years/105906586</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f1a0ed52440b4bf96b20d9583ec18ed</guid></item><item><title>Deep Time, a story 65,000 years in the making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/deep-time-launch-live-blog/105911270</link><description>ABC's Story Lab team has created an interactive tool to help Australians better understand the ancient history of our continent and its First Nations peoples. Look back at our blog to see how it works.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9204ef8f5d9eebc4f3e76e50be4721ac</guid></item><item><title>Shane Wanganeen pleads guilty to criminal neglect following son's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/shane-wanganeen-pleads-guilty-to-criminal-neglect/105911944</link><description>A South Australian father has pleaded guilty to the criminal neglect of his seven-year-old son, who died after not being treated for pneumonia in 2022. WARNING: Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander readers are advised this article contains the name of a person who has died.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3dddd8946d0112422d50d9ca6f97346</guid></item><item><title>Black Swans rowing crew from WA records win at Head of the Charles Regatta in Boston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/black-swans-rowing-crew-posts-win-at-head-of-the-charles-regatta/105912280</link><description>A group of West Australian former high-level rowers are still in shock after claiming a win at the world's biggest and most famous rowing event — The Head of the Charles Regatta in Boston.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c9029515cc34eb9eab3a0a5e60e4e01</guid></item><item><title>Samoa down to 17 fit players after Pacific Championships loss to New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/samoa-to-call-in-replacements-after-brutal-kiwi-defeat/105912418</link><description>Samoa's brutal loss to New Zealand leaves them needing to call fresh troops into their squad, with the Pacific powerhouse down to just 17 fit players.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b4e1cb8410d3d6e41561f33c4befb1e</guid></item><item><title>Tatiana Dokhotaru told mum she was 'very afraid' of ex-partner before her death, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/nsw-danny-zayat-murder-trial-tatiana-dokhotaru-mother-olga/105911540</link><description>Danny Zayat has pleaded not guilty and is facing a Supreme Court trial over the alleged murder of Tatiana Dokhotaru in May 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ff4265f79917f345faf843c0c7d1395</guid></item><item><title>Central Land Council CEO Lesley Turner sues senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price over defamation claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/nt-clc-lesley-turner-sues-senator-jacinta-nampijinpa-price-court/105911056</link><description>A seven-day Federal Court defamation case, alleging senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price "trampled" the reputation of an NT land council leader, has begun in Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8420ac7f16d0a99cba30c47990ca4485</guid></item><item><title>Has Australia just killed its cultural cringe?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/books-100-cultural-cringe-australian-literature/105911414</link><description>How wonderful for Australian writers to receive this recognition from the very people who consume their work, as part of ABC Radio National's Top 100 Books countdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6955af048b4c6e6460e149afd7da2d97</guid></item><item><title>Election campaign donation laws would have blocked $8m in Climate 200 funding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/climate-200-donations-millions-blocked-election-reforms/105910960</link><description>Climate 200 would have been blocked from making $8.34 million in donations to independent candidates if new election donation laws were in place at the 2025 poll.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a105858ce5aba7b87125fcecf773b3e4</guid></item><item><title>New England voters divided by Barnaby Joyce's flirtation with One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/barnaby-joyce-future-uncertain-as-new-england-voters-react/105910950</link><description>Support for the politician remains strong in his electorate despite his apparent flirtation with One Nation, a party enjoying a surge in popularity in the seat of New England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5fd341f9bae412bf8bef068aa17b4f9</guid></item><item><title>Space junk found near WA mine linked to Chinese rocket launch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/space-junk-chinese-rocket-jielong-newman-bhp-iron-ore/105912162</link><description>Suspected space junk which crashed near an iron ore mine in remote WA has been linked to a Chinese rocket launch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24854cc69cdd74ae88771488846a683b</guid></item><item><title>Bonza's financial backer 777 Partners co-founder charged with fraud</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/bonza-us-financier-charged-500-million-alleged-fraud/105910734</link><description>The FBI investigation resulted in 777 Partners co-founder Joshua Wander being charged with stealing US$500 million from lenders and investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e392cffcb519df7c5888daa3070bb23a</guid></item><item><title>What will happen to the stolen Louvre jewellery? Experts say it is unlikely they will ever be seen again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/what-will-happen-to-stolen-louvre-jewellery/105912134</link><description>Knowing exactly what they were after, four thieves entered the Louvre Museum and successfully stole precious jewellery. Here's what experts say comes next for the historical items.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9248d75139427fb48c8baeaa35b4d977</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire concerns for communities in south-east Tasmania ease</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/bushfire-concerns-for-communities-in-south-east-tasmania-ease/105912988</link><description>Two bushfire emergency warnings for Nugent in south-east Tasmania have been downgraded, with residents told they can "return with caution".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d070f75d2b926a985ce39294222a70ac</guid></item><item><title>Patients at centre of suspected rat poisoning cluster in south-east Queensland are all from Logan. This is what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/south-east-qld-rat-poison-cluster-from-same-city-logan/105912822</link><description>South-east Queensland authorities are continuing to investigate the source of the cluster, with contact tracing underway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70d8c5b4606af35b4f66793f5f9df39a</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew is no longer the Duke of York but will likely remain a prince. Here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/how-does-being-stripped-of-a-royal-title-work/105911378</link><description>The second son of the late Queen Elizabeth II will no longer be called the Duke of York, but he still remains a prince and in the line of succession, despite calls for his remaining title to be stripped. Here's why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcc480b17f85a98ca2b072bb33bf703f</guid></item><item><title>Temporary bans on fishing popular species floated to address dwindling populations off WA coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/wa-fishing-bans-floated-address-species-shortages/105913198</link><description>A temporary ban on fishing iconic species, including WA dhufish and pink snapper, could be on the table as the state government scrambles for solutions to WA's at-risk fish populations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57ce6ad300f7bec9a9eaa714428b06db</guid></item><item><title>Mitch Marsh dismisses suggestion he should open for Australia in the first Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/six-beers-deep-marsh-s-ashes-plan-is-not-about-opening/105912940</link><description>Michael Vaughan wants Mitch Marsh opening the batting for Australia in the Ashes but it would require a serious leap of faith from Test selectors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84ef3c8bde1f51f97c40040a93279935</guid></item><item><title>NSW police searching for armed bank robber who threatened Bendigo Bank staff and customers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/wentworth-bendigo-bank-robbery-pole-theft/105912580</link><description>Police are still hunting for a man responsible for a bank robbery in south-west New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7ceb98ad6ecd78e46c01e18bbad2d2d</guid></item><item><title>Australian and New Zealand shearers set new world record with 2,301 sheep shorn in eight hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/gun-team-of-five-shearers-sets-world-record/105912092</link><description>A new world record for sheep shearing has been set in southern New South Wales by a team of five shearers who clipped on average a sheep a minute for eight hours straight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b36cd1f4f8cf1bdadc6b189339ea62d</guid></item><item><title>Fast and easy dinners for busy weeknights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/fast-easy-low-effort-dinners-busy-weeknights/105731730</link><description>Make life easier with some of our simplest dinner recipes, including a 15-minute creamy pasta and air-fryer salmon fillets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca82c101073b2325f491bf70e520a749</guid></item><item><title>Voter turnout dips again at 2025 WA Local Government elections amid calls for mandatory voting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/wa-council-elections-turnout-results/105911966</link><description>The number of West Australians who voted at the weekend's local government elections is slightly down on previous years, following calls for participation to become mandatory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">504f2098aa38fa7e3529412db62fa9b2</guid></item><item><title>Chinese fighter jet released flares 'very close' to Australian aircraft</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/chinese-fighter-jet-released-flares-close-to-australian-aircraft/105913308</link><description>Defence Minister Richard Marles says the incident was "unsafe and unprofessional" and the government has made representations to China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d5d4ce46fc1b59552abe10865158072</guid></item><item><title>Work begins on UNSW's billion-dollar Canberra campus in the 'education capital'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/work-begins-on-unsw-camberra-campus-expansion/105911670</link><description>Once complete, the new UNSW campus will be an education hub for thousands of students and staff, and is expected to provide a much-needed injection to the city's economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2bcb88310b1f23f8d036712ff2ef416</guid></item><item><title>ACT Chief Minister Andrew Barr says it has been a 'challenging first year' in minority government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/act-chief-minister-andrew-barr-one-year-in-minority-government/105912376</link><description>The ACT's chief minister brushes off criticism that his government is "tired", but acknowledges the 12 months since the election have been "difficult" for the territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc10b94fa7ea07f36073003ea1fef5b2</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanians buffeted by spring winds, but conditions not unusual, BOM says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/tasmanians-buffeted-by-spring-winds-conditions-not-unusual/105912682</link><description>Springtime typically means gardens come to life and the winter chill eases — for Tasmanians, it also means whatever isn't nailed down might get blown away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6eaa5247e8e932d2697776dbceea8aa</guid></item><item><title>John Simmons was convicted of fraud but no one stopped him being a military advocate who ripped off vulnerable veterans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/military-advocates-scamming-vulnerable-veterans/105895360</link><description>A convicted "fraudster" has been able to represent vulnerable veterans, scamming them in the process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70c17c42fa3605238095524dfa9bb2f4</guid></item><item><title>The moment authorities move a piece of space junk that crashed in Western Australia.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/space-junk-removal/105913574</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72a4417dd8cbbba89ec350034e6936d5</guid></item><item><title>Scott Pendlebury launches legal action against former financial adviser over alleged secret withdrawals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/afl-collingwood-scott-pendlebury-sues-financial-adviser/105913420</link><description>The Collingwood player alleges Jason Sourasis, who helmed A-League club Western United before its collapse, misappropriated more than $2 million over a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6ecd6960b929b61007c9f264fb6ae95</guid></item><item><title>Inquest finds death of Mount Barker man waiting for ambulance 'potentially' preventable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/coroner-finds-death-of-john-kennedy-potentially-preventable/105910896</link><description>The cardiac arrest death of a man who waited more than 20 minutes for an ambulance could have been "potentially" prevented if a paramedic had not interfered with the dispatch process and had help arrived sooner, a South Australian coroner has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee1d0e0a27105e5d015c0ea287fb1521</guid></item><item><title>Amazon cloud unit AWS experiences major global outage disrupting hundreds of platforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/amazon-aws-experiencing-online-outage/105913856</link><description>Amazon's cloud unit AWS has experienced a major global services outage that also disrupted hundreds of other platforms, including Robinhood, Snapchat, Roblox and Perplexity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f69822d7088a0b7e47296f3179cb8d7f</guid></item><item><title>Nashir Hassani forced to pay fine after impersonating security guard at Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/court-fake-melbourne-grand-prix-security-guards/105913682</link><description>Nashir Hassani was fined $4,000 after sneaking into the Formula 1 disguised as a security guard using fake identification and a hi-vis vest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90c30d9350054176ea781422f208ce6c</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine accuses Russia of detaining scientist ahead of Antarctic conference in Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/ukraine-accuses-russia-of-detaining-scientist-antarctic-hobart/105912586</link><description>A diplomatic row has broken out at an international conservation conference in Hobart after Ukraine accused Russia of detaining one of its scientists for alleged security threats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d362443d4d5959aa919960ff002394b</guid></item><item><title>Amazon says outage issue is 'fully mitigated' as sites return to normal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/amazon-cloud-systems-outage-live-blog/105913922</link><description>Amazon's cloud unit AWS experiences an outage that has also disrupted several other global platforms, affecting customers worldwide. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e5c9b9fc33267262cf63410c49b768e</guid></item><item><title>Coroner probes death of Alice Springs psychiatric patient who was repeatedly sedated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-20/nt-kumanjayi-brogus-inquest-psychiatric-patient-sedation/105912198</link><description>NT Coroner Elisabeth Armitage is investigating the death of a 33-year-old Alice Springs mother of three who was unable to be revived after repeated medical sedations in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f45eb3e7586382d4b06686c776d0362c</guid></item></channel></rss>