<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 21:40:14 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>What is 'Solastalgia' and how are climate-affected communities tackling it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/climate-change-anxiety-first-nations-communities-respond/105793766</link><description>If you're overwhelmed by emissions targets, climate change and environmental collapse, start small and look to First Nations practices to help your wellbeing and the world around you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bff8375209835a394c77e6936900b17</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz: So you think you're a trivia guru? Go on, prove it!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/hard-quiz-weekly-trivia/105792900</link><description>I like your trivia enthusiasm, but be careful — you're about to taste defeat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9d47761db7567cf5151ee9c4083f408</guid></item><item><title>Scrubs is getting a reboot just in time for the hospital procedural revival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/scrubs-reboot-the-pitt-cheat-sheet/105793612</link><description>In a sea of hospital-based TV, long-running sitcoms Scrubs is often highlighted as one of the most realistic options. Now the reboot has been confirmed, and off the back of The Pitt’s big Emmy wins, we look back at the beloved show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f7cc2efbfa7b3a4841ebb5cb0fb4b85</guid></item><item><title>Street artist Rone's new 90-metre mural a visual love letter to Geelong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/tyrone-rone-wright-new-mural-captures-geelong-faces/105762354</link><description>The faces of 14 people will be immortalised in an enormous mural on the side of a new building in Geelong by locally born, globally renowned artist Rone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28ac13e735d6c51ed4a4df9593e87271</guid></item><item><title>How skateboarding became a family affair for Townsville single dad Jay MacAskill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/qld-skateboarding-becomes-family-single-dad/105774582</link><description>For almost eight years, Jay MacAskill's skateboard was collecting dust at home — until his daughter found the skate park around the corner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ab26eabc2acb19d8f736401a36cb5d2</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberals' star candidate in spotlight after AI algal bloom 'admin error'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/ai-liv-golf-algal-bloom-comments-put-frank-pangallo-in-spotlight/105787864</link><description>When Frank Pangallo announced he was joining the Liberal party, he vowed to put the blowtorch on a first-term government riding high in the polls. But barely four weeks later, the blowtorch is firmly on Pangallo instead, writes Leah MacLennan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bd3524d93d528173e52862abfbcd325</guid></item><item><title>Man charged after police say they found $1 million in a cardboard box in his vehicle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/man-charged-one-million-dollars-found-in-vehicle/105798924</link><description>Police say they were conducting a random breath test when they came across the cardboard box full of cash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6bea49a1770bf96655779c1d9b348e3</guid></item><item><title>Inside Ninga Mia, a forgotten community in the shadow of Kalgoorlie the city of gold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/ninga-mia-kalgoorlie-mining-aboriginal-reserve-homelessness-gold/105774862</link><description>There's an eerie silence in Ninga Mia, a once thriving community on the edge of Kalgoorlie. The Aboriginal reserve is a microcosm of the cycle of displacement endured by many First Nations people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eafa5daeccecbae05c7c9ef093e72c5</guid></item><item><title>Koori Court marks 20 years in Mildura as Victoria approaches treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/twenty-years-of-koori-justice-in-mildura-victorias-north-west/105784288</link><description>Mildura marks two decades since its Koori Court opened, as Victoria sees mixed results in the push to reduce Indigenous incarceration and offending rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d57275cbeb1abf5d81f15d9fb2c32b08</guid></item><item><title>Life on Aboriginal reserve remembered by Carnarvon traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/aboriginal-reserve-memories-carnarvon-traditional-owners/105510728</link><description>In 1975, an anthropologist wrote his thesis on Carnarvon's rich Aboriginal reserve. Decades later, traditional owners revisit the work to contribute to "big truth-telling" documentary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf8bb607751e84f71648e4dfa5cd44a</guid></item><item><title>Australian-born singer drops out of Russian-hosted Intervision song contest after 'political pressure'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australian-born-singer-drops-out-of-russian-hosted-song-contest/105799020</link><description>Vassy dropped out of the contest at the last minute after coming under what Russian organisers said was "unprecedented political pressure from the government of Australia".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6f53824a2ed40b9ae66bd7ebdb25e1a</guid></item><item><title>Penola High School's agriculture program revives community and enrolments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/penola-high-school-ag-program-revives-falling-enrolments/105787042</link><description>Cory O'Connor's three-week teaching placement turned around his hometown high school. Now he's receiving an award for the agriculture program he started there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">800678cadea15a18ec482186c893d046</guid></item><item><title>Penrith Panthers hammer Canterbury-Bankstown Bulldogs to keep NRL premiership five-peat hopes alive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/nrl-semifinal-live-updates-bulldogs-vs-panthers/105799314</link><description>Penrith has crushed Canterbury-Bankstown after a phenomenal first half to claim a 46-26 victory, keeping their hopes of a fifth-consecutive NRL premiership alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73ad6ec14b559cb36a842edc842a9431</guid></item><item><title>Penrith's win over Canterbury was a reminder there is no team like them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/panthers-bulldogs-nrl-finals-cleary-galvin-too/105799368</link><description>Canterbury is a team built in Penrith's image, but the Panthers served Canterbury a stark reminder that there can be only one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43391fdd3b75eadfd140d1ee7f293931</guid></item><item><title>Older Australians to pay up to $50/hour for basic care at home under aged care changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/older-australians-to-pay-for-showers-under-home-care-changes/105796118</link><description>Older Australians entering the aged care system will have to pay for "non-clinical" services such as showers and help with medication under wide-ranging changes taking effect in November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fad2ebda86259a9a52aff0b346c39071</guid></item><item><title>Dementia-linked protein lower in people reporting vigorous exercise, study finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/how-exercise-can-reduce-risk-of-developing-dementia/105783238</link><description>Scientists have, for the first time, linked exercise with a particular protein in the blood that is associated with brain health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1927e46b141094965051ff5e6c95b5c2</guid></item><item><title>Murray River flood may not be to blame for SA algal bloom, Senate inquiry hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/murray-river-flood-link-to-algal-bloom-questioned-senate-inquiry/105733848</link><description>Scientists have questioned the link between the 2022-23 floods and South Australia's ongoing harmful algal bloom, despite the state government listing it as one of the three primary causes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e88db31a70e241e8774222579aebebdc</guid></item><item><title>Ben Graetz is amplifying voices through drag and music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/stateline-ben-graetz-is-amplifying-voices-through-drag-and-music/105800476</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">630db041a99b34f065b43cfd99120d2d</guid></item><item><title>World leaders are meeting at the UN General Assembly this week. Here are four things to watch for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/united-nations-general-assembly-what-to-watch-for-in-new-york/105800440</link><description>World leaders are arriving in New York for the UN General Assembly — and for the first time, Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is among them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">761958b8abcd8c47c96a8d78d674b211</guid></item><item><title>Easy and healthy dinner recipes for spring</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/easy-healthy-recipes-for-spring-dinners/105660408</link><description>If you're looking for light dinner ideas as the weather warms up, we have plenty of easy options. Think veggie-filled frittatas and beef taco bowls with a few healthy swaps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c28e2a7be5345c5402fc685acca89162</guid></item><item><title>Is AI impacting your career or life plans? Has its rapid rise got you rethinking your future? The ABC wants to hear from you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/ai-artificial-intelligence-future-job-career-impact/105762606</link><description>Whether you’re a student halfway through a degree or a mid-career manager planning the next five years, artificial intelligence (AI) is reshaping lives across the country. If you've been feeling its effects, the ABC wants to hear from you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc9fb0b057b73e053ee1ce795957b20a</guid></item><item><title>Super Netball's Sunshine Coast Lightning enters new Global Sports Fund Management Group ownership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/super-netball-sunshine-coast-lightning-new-ownership/105801344</link><description>Almost a decade after being co-founded by the Melbourne Storm and University of the Sunshine Coast, Super Netball's Lightning is entering a new era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">725e5769d7aa41a90979ec4d3e47f5bd</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos undecided on halves combination ahead of prelim final against Penrith</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/hunt-on-for-broncos-as-mam-mind-games-begin/105803392</link><description>Brisbane coach Michael Maguire continues to experiment with his halves combinations on Monday as Ezra Mam takes another key step towards a return from injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94b206b4a39973e74852b877af401757</guid></item><item><title>Brownlow Medal 2025: All the best fashion looks from AFL's night of nights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-red-carpet-wrap/105802436</link><description>Just after the fashion from this evening's Brownlow Medal? We've got you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8922390581e8430e878c1aa384dd8e2d</guid></item><item><title>Latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/latest-financial-news/105804002</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a2a0a2b0118f619ddf3cb8e2061e8e4</guid></item><item><title>More than $4 million in drugs seized across WA's far north in ongoing operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/kimberley-police-seize-meth-ammunition-and-other-drugs/105804038</link><description>Police in the Kimberley say an ongoing investigation has seized millions of dollars' worth of ammunition, methylamphetamine and other drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29a62dd5dae99250a80b3b8152cf6465</guid></item><item><title>The public hospital patients who ended up paying abortion clinics for miscarriage care</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/qld-mater-miscarriage-care-catholic-hospital-abortion/105781022</link><description>Brisbane women have told the ABC they paid an abortion clinic for their chosen miscarriage care rather than getting it at their large public hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34accc25ffd487a2e3cb32cdcd8a582d</guid></item><item><title>Moment Matt Rowell announced as 2025 Brownlow medallist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moment-matt-rowell-announced-as-2025-brownlow-medallist/105805032</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4336530cc59f3c10ad2c74d7b058cebe</guid></item><item><title>Matt Rowell delivers Brownlow Medal acceptance speech</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/matt-rowell-delivers-brownlow-medal-acceptance-speech/105805042</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2002bf4ac5caada0dc95c1432e61966</guid></item><item><title>Doctors concerned easily accessible illegal cigarettes are causing smoking rates to increase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/act-easy-access-to-illegal-cigarettes-seeing-high-smoking-rates/105803450</link><description>Doctors say smoking rates are at levels they haven't seen in a decade due to easy access to illegal cigarettes that are a "quarter of the price" of legal cigarettes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">150ad4af75b20ef2e67ba79a215e5c20</guid></item><item><title>Man Ray and Max Dupain's photography on display together for the first time in new Heide exhibition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/man-ray-max-dupain-photography-exhibition-heide-melbourne/105790024</link><description>Surrealist photographer Man Ray revolutionised 20th-century visual culture. In Australia, a local photographer was exploring similar territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">318bfee371103375fcc23430352eccfd</guid></item><item><title>Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera being robbed overshadowed Matt Rowell's Brownlow Medal win, and could change the voting process forever</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/afl-matt-rowell-nasiah-moment-brownlow-medal-voting-analysis/105804320</link><description>It is not often that the AFL's night of nights gets hijacked by a moment not involving the winner of the Brownlow Medal. This is exactly what took place when Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera was seemingly robbed in broad daylight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dfdde5b406fc68132f52c264d89b4c9</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire survivors still camping years later amid construction backlog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/mallacoota-builders-struggle-five-years-after-black-summer-fires/105562838</link><description>Five years after devastating bushfires swept through Mallacoota, some survivors are still making do with tents and camp kitchens amid a backlog of construction jobs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1121db6b9066459f003795b1fb706907</guid></item><item><title>Ousmane Dembélé wins men's Ballon d'Or as Aitana Bonmatí joins elite club featuring Lionel Messi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/football-ousmane-dembele-ballon-d-or-bonmati-salah-yamal/105805184</link><description>French forward Ousmane Dembélé caps off a dream season with football's most prestigious individual award as Spain's Aitana Bonmatí continues to add to her legacy as one of the best women's players of all time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e69e7f3a1af9871429f380161b57a49e</guid></item><item><title>NSW police suspend investigation into murder of homeless man Reginald Mullaly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/police-suspend-investigation-into-reginald-mullaly-murder/105800932</link><description>Police have suspended an investigation of a homeless man's brutal murder in Bathurst a decade ago, prompting a fresh plea from his family for information.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b768354a6a3c6bade70c04eb09c0541d</guid></item><item><title>NSW Police officer charged with assault over protest arrest of former Greens candidate Hannah Thomas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/nsw-officer-charged-assault-hannah-thomas-greens-arrest/105805966</link><description>Hannah Thomas was among a group of pro-Palestinian protesters who demonstrated outside a manufacturing facility in June when she sustained a serious eye injury during her arrest for failing to comply with a move on direction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ffd2b5888a415cc414e269d4943cf29</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of hitting 42yo with vehicle in Kalgoorlie appears in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/detectives-from-major-crime-investigate-kalgoorlie-mans-death/105801802</link><description>A 29-year-old man has faced court today after detectives from WA Police's Homicide Squad charged him with murder, two days after the death of a man in the state's Goldfields.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46cd053682653a831ef9b4ab4db28ca6</guid></item><item><title>Man known as 'Moore Park Rapist' pleads guilty to series of sexual assaults in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/moore-park-rapist-glenn-cameron-pleads-guilty-sexual-assaults/105806986</link><description>Glenn Cameron has remained in custody since he was arrested in February last year and charged with more than 30 offences in relation to eight victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c631b0b48e05bf34d6cd7b4127803d77</guid></item><item><title>Kevin Bacon on the importance of music, philanthropy and acting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/kevin-bacon-take-5-actor-music-philanthropy-interview/105793360</link><description>He's a prolific fixture on our screens who's famously six degrees from almost anyone. But Kevin Bacon is also a passionate musician and philanthropist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45104e05b24001759cca6f2985a81b97</guid></item><item><title>David Crisafulli stands by election commitments as mining companies criticise coal royalties in State of the State address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/qld-2025-state-of-state-address-david-crisafulli/105805172</link><description>In his first State of the State address, Premier David Crisafulli says the government is "open for business", but not interested in companies that abandon Queenslanders in "the name of shareholder interests".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a04cca3c658daa48746b610150b5bf46</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage tragedy: What we know and how events unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/timeline-on-optus-triple-0-outage-what-we-know/105805890</link><description>The first sign something was wrong came late on Friday afternoon. Now we have a clearer picture of how the triple-0 outage unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c548c42002e87e4dd015358e8d8279e9</guid></item><item><title>Sale of Australia's biggest sheep station at Rawlinna finally gets WA government approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/sale-of-australias-largest-sheep-station-at-rawlinna-station/105807106</link><description>The WA government has finally signed off on the sale of Australia's largest sheep station almost seven months after UK-based Consolidated Pastoral Company announced plans to buy Rawlinna Station.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">453798f3baadfee94d513f7ea0e7efc3</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie's spray at 'muppet', 'coward' Liberal colleagues after post bemoaning loss of Aussie car making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/andrew-hastie-car-making-coward-muppet-liberals/105808280</link><description>Senior Liberal Andrew Hastie has taken aim at colleagues who questioned a social media post where he bemoaned the loss of Australian car making, calling them "nameless cowards" and "muppets".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa8f233e21c3cb087597a2e4648810dd</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm's Jahrome Hughes and Ryan Papenhuyzen return for NRL preliminary final against Cronulla</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-23/storm-jahrome-hughes-against-cronulla-broncos-panthers/105808480</link><description>Melbourne recall three big guns, led by star half Jahrome Hughes, as their NRL title hopes go on the line in Friday night's preliminary final against Cronulla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1926a9906773436f42474dc790c296f5</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Ragasa lashes Taiwan, with at least 15 dead and 152 missing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/super-typhoon-ragasa-taiwan-dead-missing/105809264</link><description>The most powerful storm so far in 2025 is now heading towards the Chinese mainland, prompting widespread disruption and warnings of sea surges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e86c797982ae3107e7d7d8203132df06</guid></item><item><title>Incoming triple-0 reforms may not have helped prevent Optus failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/triple-0-reforms-may-not-have-helped-optus-failure/105807524</link><description>The federal government has yet to pass legislation to empower a new coordinator for the emergency services line, but experts say tougher conditions are needed on the telco itself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">196d665b157a51d6ce3440ca5be81bfc</guid></item><item><title>Could artificial intelligence and a universal basic income eliminate 'meaningless jobs'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/will-we-need-a-universal-basic-income-to-deal-with-ai-job-losses/105747954</link><description>COVID showed just how "fragile" our economic security is. As artificial intelligence potentially takes jobs from humans, a universal basic income might be a solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5953e2ae7f84df41d0ff5021a284652b</guid></item><item><title>Australians are moving to Tasmania to escape climate change, but the island state is not immune</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/australians-moving-to-tasmania-to-escape-climate-change/105785996</link><description>Jack and Anna swapped the humidity of Queensland for chilly days in Tasmania, but is Tasmania really the climate refuge many think it is?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0ff7fbad477aed99626b4746b82c14c</guid></item><item><title>England names squad to face Australia in men's Ashes series 2025/26</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/england-name-squad-to-face-australia-in-men-s-ashes-series/105809606</link><description>England will bring a strong pace bowling attack, but several members of the squad, including captain Ben Stokes, are under injury clouds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d0a0a9cfab837e21e9251c67e841c3</guid></item><item><title>Mal Lanyon chosen as next NSW Police Force commissioner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/mal-lanyon-new-commissioner-of-nsw-police-force/105701914</link><description>Deputy Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon has been chosen to head up the NSW Police Force, replacing commissioner Karen Webb.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cd3192bee4641f04f5b65931d5fe5d6</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's meeting with Trump matters for AUKUS and the role of the US in the Asia-Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/anthony-albanese-donald-trump-meeting/105801298</link><description>Trump clearly disagrees with Albanese on Palestine and the reality of climate change, but it's not on the scale of the beef he has with other countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1daf71c6599467c19439c0e23875de0e</guid></item><item><title>Artemis program on track to take astronauts around the Moon: NASA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nasa-artemis-program-on-track-to-take-people-to-the-moon/105809764</link><description>NASA's first crewed flight in its Artemis program — a trip around the Moon and back — is on track for launch in April 2026 and could potentially be moved up to February, the space agency says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87a63c967423b595bde610ff51e979b6</guid></item><item><title>Why the legacy of the 2023 NRL grand final hangs over the Broncos and Panthers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/panthers-broncos-nrl-preliminary-final-grand-final-cleary/105809026</link><description>On Sunday, the Broncos and Panthers will face off in the finals for the first time since the 2023 grand final, but the memory of that night still hangs over both sides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad8624f8c74a64751af52bbcd1e11c56</guid></item><item><title>Canberra golf course redevelopments providing both much-needed housing and financial lifelines for struggling clubs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/golf-course-redevelopments-providing-housing-financial-lifelines/105799100</link><description>With the ACT government pushing for greater urban density, golf courses in inner Canberra suburbs are becoming attractive sites for redevelopment to provide much-needed housing and a way for struggling clubs to bolster their budgets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b488a99ab4311911d8fa6f87e596dc4c</guid></item><item><title>Gender-based violence services prepare for increased calls on AFL grand final weekend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/increased-rates-of-gender-based-violence-during-football-finals/105809996</link><description>Ahead of the AFL grand final, national violence prevention organisation Our Watch is calling for the sporting community to address the increased risk of violence facing women during football finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4d5c539ddee700b75c82661684fb340</guid></item><item><title>Camp Mystic plans to reopen next summer, a year after floods killed 27</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/camp-mystic-plans-to-reopen-a-year-after-flood-deaths/105810114</link><description>Camp Mystic also announces plans for a memorial dedicated to "the lives of the campers and counsellors lost on July 4th".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">496ec39f957a1a61a68f959f6319b508</guid></item><item><title>Man behind iconic ABC TV programs, Graham White, dies aged 93</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/graham-white-abc-tv-and-radio-pioneer-dies-at-93/105806806</link><description>Graham White was a pioneer of Australian radio and television and played a key role in the creation of numerous television series, including A Big Country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54c9a84115c56f73f0923751c300a0e1</guid></item><item><title>When is the 2025 AFL grand final? Here's what time it starts and where to watch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/when-is-the-afl-grand-final-time-where-to-watch-explained/105809976</link><description>Wondering what time the AFL grand final starts and how you can watch it live? We've got you covered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b35be59cc10e4e0032348864c66bd1c7</guid></item><item><title>Despite past controversy, NSW Police commissioner Mal Lanyon has a strong backing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/nsw-police-commissioner-mal-lanyon-premier-chris-minns-analysis/105810774</link><description>For newly-announced Police Commissioner Mal Lanyon, Wednesday morning would have been both one of his proudest moments, and his most uncomfortable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed72f9bcc7ce20d2d722b8b43d539719</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel returns, addressing Charlie Kirk and 'un-American' axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/jimmy-kimmel-returns-thanking-supporters-speaks-to-free-speech/105808410</link><description>Despite the late-night host's return, several US ABC affiliates did not air the episode, excluding an estimated one-quarter of American households.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac8b78a8e557c0d2a91d42ed04e2eed</guid></item><item><title>How #RedundancyDiaries are busting the stigma of being let go</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/busting-the-stigma-on-redundancy-by-sharing-online/105751880</link><description>Camille says being made redundant was hard, so she began sharing her experiences on TikTok hoping to help others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69e9a0930ebbcb9805519c817968e9ee</guid></item><item><title>AFL boss hints at Brownlow voting shake-up after Nasiah Wanganeen-Milera controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/afl-boss-hits-at-brownlow-voting-shake-up-after-controversy/105812086</link><description>Voting for the Brownlow Medal has been a hot topic again in the wake of Monday night's count, with the AFL open to letting umpires have access to statistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5d9c582b445942c6c11e6f1591db872</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions trust Lachie Neale to make right call ahead of AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-24/brisbane-lions-lachie-neale-right-afl-grand-final-call/105813604</link><description>All eyes are on Lachie Neale's bid to make a remarkable grand final return from injury, and his teammates will back him to make the right call.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b33183c69e679601c3ad83c2c662b7b</guid></item><item><title>One dead in 'targeted' shooting at Dallas immigration centre, DHS says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/multiple-dead-at-dallas-ice-shooting/105814138</link><description>Police were first alerted to the incident at 6:40am on Wednesday, local time, and later found the shooter on a nearby roof dead from an apparent self-inflicted gunshot wound.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41372aed6a1e8513347f563b066ef004</guid></item><item><title>Australia's social media ban wins praise from Europe at UN event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/united-nations-general-assembly-social-media-ban/105814246</link><description>Australia's willingness to take on the social media giants is drawing significant international interest, winning the support of the European Commission president at a forum in New York.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13cbd1fcaa9fc632384fa2b086577151</guid></item><item><title>Australia in a 'dangerous place' as AI adoption ramps up, prompting calls to protect jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/australia-in-dangerous-place-as-ai-adoption-ramps-up/105807430</link><description>Artificial intelligence is coming for our jobs — but will it take them away, or just give us a powerful new assistant?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48e1ecb4ff4fc7a8cb46b98272af471f</guid></item><item><title>Hastie downplays 'mischievous' leadership speculation – as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/federal-politics-live-sept-25/105812720</link><description>Liberal frontbencher Andrew Hastie brushes off suggestions he is a threat to Sussan Ley's leadership after a series of outspoken social media posts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a1855533ef7e4ee2263abc39c01aed0</guid></item><item><title>AFL super fans prepare for the grand final clash between Geelong and Brisbane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-football-fans-brisbane-lions-geelong-cats-2025-premiership/105812254</link><description>From a unique tattoo to a personalised burger, the AFL grand final is more than just a game for these super fans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85ea949cc04c0beee30263008e182e01</guid></item><item><title>Families demand inquiry into NSW Police handling of missing persons cases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/families-of-missing-persons-call-for-probe-into-police/105693338</link><description>Nikii Smith is one of 10,000 people who signed a petition calling for a NSW inquiry into the handling of missing persons cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86bd1e4db1094cebb0f4277ff0ad4c3b</guid></item><item><title>Family calls for change amid frustration at seven-year coronial inquest wait</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/anger-at-seven-year-coronial-inquest-wait/105805234</link><description>Robert Hall was killed when he was struck by partially blind driver John Charles Robertson on the Horrocks Highway in 2018. It has been a long wait for the family ahead of the release of coronial findings into his death next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dedbef63ba8aa61b8045e0d358939858</guid></item><item><title>Rodeo attendees told to practise safe sex as STIs continue to rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sti-cases-continue-to-rise-indigenous-overrepresented-in-data/105809704</link><description>Health providers in outback Queensland are taking a light-hearted approach to promoting safe sex, as new data shows sexually transmitted infections are on the rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a991448f6d24b7d59719d012fdc3e584</guid></item><item><title>Police launch fresh search of WA outback over Ray and Jennie Kehlet cold case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/wa-police-search-sandstone-kehlet-cold-case/105813086</link><description>Detectives are this week revisiting the site in WA's outback where the body of prospector Ray Kehlet was found. His wife Jennie is still missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eda36c180ee83ef793f5a6e386ed8ef6</guid></item><item><title>Former AFL boss Andrew Demetriou insists league would embrace a gay men's player</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/andrew-demetriou-says-afl-a-safe-space-for-gay-players/105813820</link><description>Former AFL boss Andrew Demetriou says the public would embrace a gay men's player and rejects that the AFL is an unsafe environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d77a4e9f1c05a3808354f694994d6ee</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous teen speaks out against heckling of Welcome to Country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/indigenous-writes-essay-against-heckling-welcome-to-country/105808140</link><description>An Indigenous high school student's essay on the Anzac Day heckling of an Indigenous elder by far-right supremacists has earned her a nationally recognised award.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d0978c16ddeb79e39b966dd2e565459</guid></item><item><title>Magnitude-4.1 earthquake rattles Tasmania from Maydena to Hobart</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/tasmania-rattled-with-magnitude-4-1-earthquake/105814558</link><description>Tasmania records a magnitude-4.1 earthquake in the state's south-west that was felt from Maydena to Hobart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84775edf57cd76c9bc0ca385f3b919d5</guid></item><item><title>Who is Samoa's new prime minister, Laaulialemalietoa Polataivao Fosi Schmidt?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/new-samoa-prime-minister-election/105789496</link><description>Supporters are fervent in their enthusiasm for Samoa's new prime minister, but voters who are more sceptical of Laaulialemalietoa Polataivao Fosi Schmidt, question his motives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">625c6497fc8280a6929fa5f29c6e97f3</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of new dust-related lung disease cases recorded in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/new-cases-deadly-lung-disease-recorded-in-queensland/105800886</link><description>Nearly 300 workers from mines and work sites have had cases of lung cancer, black lung and other illnesses recorded by the state's dust disease register in the space of 12 months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2884483a655c30376f0362816224a66</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final sprint won't feature all teams, as Gout Gout and Harry Garside to feature at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-grand-final-sprint-gout-gout-and-harry-garside/105814536</link><description>The AFL announces that only seven AFL players will run in the traditional grand final sprint, with Olympic boxer Harry Garside also joining in.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90c0207e2a6dabd51c17d24fbfdde78c</guid></item><item><title>Macquarie to repay Shield investors after super platform failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/macquarie-admits-to-shield-contraventions/105814728</link><description>Macquarie commits to repaying thousands of Australians who invested hundreds of millions of their retirement savings in the collapsed Shield Master Fund amid admissions it contravened the Corporations Act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6ef3dcad386254cfbd1a1063f29bbf1</guid></item><item><title>Katanning drivers fear the worst as untagged livestock roam roads</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/katanning-farmers-fed-up-with-livestock-wandering-rural-roads/105753144</link><description>A Katanning school bus driver and local farmers are calling for urgent action to address a growing danger posed by wandering livestock on rural roads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13a15cf930e91758bba06110e305613a</guid></item><item><title>ARIA Award nominations 2025: Ninajirachi, Dom Dolla, Amyl &amp; The Sniffers lead the pack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/aria-award-nominations-2025-aria-nominees-full-list/105815074</link><description>All the contenders are hopefuls vying for ARIA Awards glory at the music industry's glitzy ceremony, taking place next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">959594b1e7f091dd3de19e45dc3888ab</guid></item><item><title>Dramatic footage shows sinkhole swallowing up road in central Bangkok</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/sinkhole-swallows-road-in-central-bangkok/105814850</link><description>Social media footage shows powerlines being pulled down into the 50-metre deep hole and vehicles teetering on the edge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">341b949dae61cd2058ac47c271016c61</guid></item><item><title>Liberal candidate Gisele Kapterian abandons court challenge for Sydney seat of Bradfield</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/liberal-gisele-kapterian-abandons-bradfield-court-challenge/105815662</link><description>Gisele Kapterian abandons her court action challenging the election result in the federal Sydney seat of Bradfield.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72e919021e6b203c2c61364023ef65cb</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese addresses UN on climate goals, Gaza and Australia's security council bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/albanese-united-nations-general-assembly-speech/105815200</link><description>The prime minister uses his UN speech to talk up Australia's emissions plan after Donald Trump called climate change a "con job", and confirms Australia is still seeking a temporary seat on the body's security council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a232f435066d64bce12998bbb55c68d5</guid></item><item><title>Nicho Hynes shrugs off personal barbs ahead of NRL preliminary final between Melbourne and Cronulla</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nicho-hynes-cronulla-sharks-nrl-preliminary-final/105815774</link><description>Accused by some of being too nice and not nice enough by others, polarising Cronulla star Nicho Hynes "doesn't give a rats" about criticism that comes his way anymore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab3262fd8438997bf3566bc3f3afd340</guid></item><item><title>New head of Queensland's troubled DNA lab says backlog of testing could take years to clear</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/queensland-dna-lab-forensic-lab-mick-fuller-investigation/105815548</link><description>More than 170 rape kits caught up in the Forensic Science Queensland laboratory's backlog will be sent offshore next week for vital forensic testing, as the facility's new boss says it will take years to clear them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f10104713dca5809a4ee3120e1d5a35</guid></item><item><title>Seasonal farm worker from Samoa pleads guilty to rape on Arrawarra beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/arrawarra-rape-farm-worker-pleads-guilty/105800896</link><description>The 27-year-old worker from Samoa changed his plea after hearing the victim give evidence at trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5297df5ebdb4d1df00f40eba4157b444</guid></item><item><title>Scott Selwood takes break from AFL after 'personally challenging year'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/scott-selwood-steps-away-afl-collingwood/105815996</link><description>Scott Selwood will take time away from football, stepping down as an assistant coach with Collingwood, following a year marked by personal tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41d251b3ccf71ca56edd70b60deeeab9</guid></item><item><title>AI image recognition technology used to detect traffic offences raises privacy concerns, Queensland audit finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/ai-image-technology-phone-speeding-offences-privacy-audit-qld/105815134</link><description>Queensland's transport department uses AI in its cameras to detect mobile and seatbelt offences, but a new audit has ordered called for a review into how that's done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11d46c909160642ceb7265e8809e201c</guid></item><item><title>Breastfeeding in public is protected in Australia. So why are mothers still facing discrimination?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/why-are-we-still-asking-mothers-to-hide-breastfeeding/105789046</link><description>Last week a breastfeeding mother was asked to leave a Virgin Australia lounge for pumping. Experts says while there is a level of awareness that breastfeeding in public is protected, some people in the community still view it as "inappropriate".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5341713f4b5168cc3ed1630a81ef91c6</guid></item><item><title>Snoop Dogg says AFL grand final is 'a way of life' ahead of headline show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/snoop-dogg-afl-grand-final/105816718</link><description>Snoop Dogg has strutted into the MCG for his official appearance ahead of a fascinating, somewhat controversial, AFL grand-final entertainment set.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b66d08f7f421a2cabf591d770048f0f</guid></item><item><title>Denmark PM apologises to indigenous Greenlanders who faced forced contraception</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/denmark-pm-apologises-to-greenland-over-contraception/105816090</link><description>The apology by Mette Frederiksen in Greenland’s capital, Nuuk, hopes to close a traumatic chapter in Greenland's history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10e2f68d02a379a76e33cb0667531d03</guid></item><item><title>Perth grandmother Donna Nelson loses appeal over Japan drug smuggling conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/donna-nelson-loses-japan-drug-smuggling-appeal/105804346</link><description>Convicted drug smuggler and Perth grandmother, Donna Nelson, loses her appeal against her conviction for smuggling two kilograms of methamphetamine into Tokyo Airport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47b528f98203d1300e8e1b40978bdddc</guid></item><item><title>Trio of space weather satellites launched to study the Sun's violent side</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/nasa-launch-three-spacecraft-sun/105815108</link><description>NASA successfully launches multiple satellites designed to get a better understanding of the Sun's influence on Earth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59a16bd185eeee6f5d85c73a75953dbf</guid></item><item><title>TGA approves new brain stimulation device for treatment of depression</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/brain-stimulator-device-approved-for-treatment-of-depression/105816064</link><description>Some international users of Flow Neuroscience's device have labelled the wearable tech as a game-changer in treating depression, but not everyone is convinced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d613860a63e9e5d904cc9b6ac0bd749</guid></item><item><title>Key takeaways from day two at the UN General Assembly's world leaders week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/united-nations-general-assembly-day-two-takeaways/105814272</link><description>The world's most powerful people are meeting in New York this week. Here are the key takeaways from the UN summit's second day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddb580a737f4f04170f65ae765ac9dd6</guid></item><item><title>Celebrity crocodile wrangler Matt Wright set to appeal guilty verdict on five grounds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/matt-wright-set-to-appeal-guilty-verdict-on-five-grounds/105816918</link><description>Matt Wright’s lawyers have confirmed they will file a notice of appeal within the next 48 hours, indicating it will be based on five different grounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">235091d5d14d90d64ed46d67022a1cf6</guid></item><item><title>Liberal veteran Amanda Vanstone chides Andrew Hastie for not being a team player, warns of runaway ego</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/andrew-hastie-warned-of-division-amanda-vanstone/105817288</link><description>A doyenne of the Liberal Party and veteran of leadership battles dating back to the 1980s Howard–Peacock era has chided Andrew Hastie for not being a team player.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7155a17bde099fcac4270569e823ea49</guid></item><item><title>Matildas strike force could benefit from having both Sam Kerr and Michelle Heyman firing fit up front</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/matildas-could-have-sam-kerr-and-michelle-heyman/105817900</link><description>A fit-again Sam Kerr doesn't necessarily spell the end for Michelle Heyman's time in the Matildas, if anything the A-League star can't wait for her return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c878d14058b221a67d55c4c8bdc80e94</guid></item><item><title>Lachie Neale and Rhys Stanley named in AFL grand final teams as Jarrod Berry fails to recover from shoulder injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/afl-grand-final-geelong-brisbane-lions-team-selections-live-blog/105812378</link><description>Brisbane's co-captain returns just weeks after doctors gave him as little as a five per cent chance of featuring in his third straight grand final as Geelong welcomes back a familiar face to take the place of Tom Stewart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd6e232727e7d0a979b313cd8bef11d5</guid></item><item><title>Horse trainer Dwayne Schmidt jailed for raping and impregnating 13yo girl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/horse-trainer-raped-and-impregnated-13-year-old-girl/105813440</link><description>New South Wales horse trainer Dwayne Schmidt is sentenced to more than three years in jail for raping and impregnating a 13-year-old girl.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cff6a74bc32102a2a7bdba358773bf49</guid></item><item><title>Coroner finds Monash Health provided unreasonable care before toddler Dio Kemp's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/coroner-finding-into-death-of-dio-kemp/105816186</link><description>Three-year-old Dio Kemp was taken to Monash Medical Centre four times over 10 days before she died of sepsis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b865829bea191edfe0af886035c9e4</guid></item><item><title>Mass puffer fish deaths and red-bell jellyfish bloom put Pilbara coast on alert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/pilbara-coast-alert-jellyfish-bloom-toxic-puffer-fish-deaths/105815554</link><description>Hundreds of dead puffer fish are found on a Pilbara beach, as an epic red-bell jellyfish bloom prompts a warning from the region's ports authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39c787a5232b58cd251e6bebea3ae077</guid></item><item><title>Jerry Robertson found guilty of murdering partner with sledgehammer in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/jerry-robertson-found-guilty-of-dv-murder-of-woman-alice-springs/105806492</link><description>An NT Supreme Court jury finds an Alice Springs man guilty of murdering his female partner in July 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">693256933f0d4ab5bb1c7eda5803141d</guid></item><item><title>Fourth NZYQ member issued Nauruan visa as Labor steams ahead with deportation plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-25/fourth-nauruan-visa-issued-to-nzyq/105817222</link><description>The former detainee was returned to immigration detention on Thursday and could be the first person transferred under the multi-billion-dollar deal inked with Nauru earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad0acd68e16e51eb3bff42b299e11dc0</guid></item><item><title>China's 'soft' 2035 climate target frustrates experts amid rapid renewable growth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/chinas-new-climate-target-is-both-historic-and-inadequate/105814784</link><description>China baffles climate experts by setting the bar low with its 2035 emissions reduction target amid speculation the renewables superpower will most likely exceed its ambitions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9faa430fbc4d58914719cd9df045ca3</guid></item><item><title>China aid and investment returns to Solomon Islands's Malaita province after ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/china-aid-solomon-islands-malaita-road-development/105789780</link><description>The Solomon Islands's province of Malaita made global headlines five years ago when it banned Chinese investment. But today, a new China-funded road project is on the way — and the people are all for it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aef86fbb6ca57b72f9ef6089dc9580e9</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners slam state premiers for 'disgraceful' call to push ahead with Santos gas project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/peter-malinauskas-under-fire-over-santos-gas-project-gomeroi/105817448</link><description>The debate over Santos's Narrabri gas project reignites, with traditional owners condemning 'disgraceful' comments made by two state premiers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ff7b86ab36f41d01a1fc6371f793a89</guid></item><item><title>Imported potatoes threaten Tasmanian growers, as companies look for cost savings overseas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/imported-potatoes-price-cuts-threaten-australian-potato-industry/105815458</link><description>Cheap potato imports from India and China are threatening the livelihoods of Tasmanian growers, as stalled negotiations with potato giant Simplot leave some farmers about to plant this year's crop without a contract.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddc6d456a4e47433bae32855e5b52bae</guid></item><item><title>2025 AFL season quiz: Twenty questions before the AFL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/afl-2025-season-quiz/105806256</link><description>There are just four quarters of footy left in the 2025 men's AFL season, so now is as good a time as any to see how much you remember about the year just gone with our quiz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63ca7ae077d47b2b6fd2fe7c3941c026</guid></item><item><title>AFL popularity growth fuels calls to move the Barassi Line separating codes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/barassi-line-rugby-league-aussie-rules-tathra/105782938</link><description>Initially laughed off, these pioneers from Victoria were determined to challenge Australia's sporting status quo, and their legacy continues today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">853354932de7c66115ea465660b6ef08</guid></item><item><title>Sudden 30C temperature rise over Antarctica upends Australia's spring outlook</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/weather-pattern-could-disrupt-australia-for-months/105817572</link><description>Temperatures above Antarctica have risen by 30C, in a rare event that could potentially flip Australia's spring weather for months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c3c265c0efd53b23c81e306c0bfbd10</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian Authority president thanks Australia, but points to decades of failure, in UN address</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/united-nations-palestinian-authority-mahmoud-abbas-speech/105819446</link><description>Mahmoud Abbas addresses the UN by video after the US refuses him a visa, as Donald Trump vows he will "not allow" Israel to annex the West Bank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25b349c3dbf1286a48e6bc697929c1ae</guid></item><item><title>FBI finds notes by ICE shooter saying he wanted to target agents, not detainees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/ice-shooter-wanted-to-target-agents-not-detainees-fbi-says/105819378</link><description>The FBI has searched the home of the man who opened fired on an Immigration and Customs Enforcement facility in Texas, finding notes that say he was acting alone and intended to target agents, not detainees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3796b636d369ed92c9beb50a3697283</guid></item><item><title>ASX closes up, Singtel boss flown in to meet Australian government over triple-0 failure — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/asx-markets-business-live-news-26-sept-2025/105819610</link><description>Singtel confirms its CEO will join the Optus chair and CEO in meeting the communications minister as the triple-0 fallout rumbles on. Meanwhile, despite a poor opening, the ASX regains ground to finish the week higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4be65eb1cbcd8e56b4e7411bef244b6b</guid></item><item><title>Robert Carlyle on the hacking scandal that brought down a Murdoch paper</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/uk-phone-hacking-scandal-robert-carlyle-the-hack/105810728</link><description>Robert Carlyle plays an integral role in The Hack, co-starring David Tennant, which digs deep into the News of the World phone-hacking scandal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a90e196287202fbd21af9cda9ac6774</guid></item><item><title>Former Arsenal-contracted player Billy Vigar dies aged 21 after sustaining brain injury during a game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/billy-vigar-dies-at-21-after-head-injury-in-soccer-match/105819594</link><description>Tributes flow for Billy Vigar, after the former Arsenal-contracted player dies from a brain injury sustained during a match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c247b6a9b1480f06a4e319acbb2b00a8</guid></item><item><title>Bondi's Sculpture by the Sea offered $200,000 lifeline after financial woes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/bondi-sculpture-by-the-sea-to-go-ahead-2025-due-to-lifeline/105819510</link><description>Sculpture by the Sea was facing cancellation with organisers forced to make an urgent public plea for last-minute funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6b9cfa8185df988b1552b57c5404e42</guid></item><item><title>Well-known Adelaide tailor Joseph Uzumcu fined for smoking outside CBD shop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/joseph-uzumcu-adelaide-tailor-fined-smoking/105818722</link><description>A well-known Adelaide tailor has been issued a fine by the Adelaide Magistrates Court for smoking outside his CBD business to cope with stress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dd54fb0496462acf91c278ecc303fb5</guid></item><item><title>Trump has signed an executive order on TikTok. What does that mean?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/donald-trump-signs-tiktok-executive-order-what-does-that-mean/105819550</link><description>Donald Trump has signed an executive order that he says will allay security concerns regarding Chinese influence on social media platform TikTok.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56898e42bde26b739d92f79a2ebd6d02</guid></item><item><title>Foster carer shortage in WA's Kimberley forces children away from country</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/foster-carer-shortage-in-kimberley-forcing-kids-off-country/105815878</link><description>A shortage of foster carers in regional WA is pushing vulnerable children, especially First Nations kids, thousands of kilometres from their families, culture and country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ce81c66ef721335c43f5ba3654f32c4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump imposes 100 per cent tariffs on branded pharmaceuticals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/trump-100pc-tariff-on-drugs-us-politics-/105820198</link><description>The United States will impose a 100 per cent tariff on imports of branded or patented pharmaceutical products from October 1, unless a pharmaceutical company is building a manufacturing plant in the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">739af64d542d4f460697eb9a7951741d</guid></item><item><title>Scientist wins peace prize for farmer-managed natural regeneration work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/tony-rinaudo-wins-luxembourg-peace-prize-regenerative-farming/105666674</link><description>A Victorian scientist whose farming technique has revolutionised agriculture in Niger is awarded an international peace prize.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdd4d1ecb9ea1ba749bbf16d1448e605</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle Ocean Baths the setting for new headphone theatre production, Meet Me at the Baths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/meet-me-at-the-baths-ang-collins-newcastle-new-annual-festival/105809954</link><description>A new headphone theatre production is set among the swimmers and sunbakers at a NSW city's much-loved ocean pool.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27e003348ea3b7a57ee535f59076db94</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final preview — how Geelong's unpredictable set up and late term heroics have set them up for a flag</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/afl-grand-final-preview-2025-geelong-profile-against-brisbane/105819810</link><description>From an innovative ruck set up to an uncanny ability to play out the quarter, the perennially competitive Cats are knocking on the door of another flag.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b332a9a8fd34aa68b5306baa1efb2624</guid></item><item><title>Branxholme Wallacedale Saints under 11s celebrate a win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/branxholme-wallacedale-saints-under-11s-celebrate/105812870</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d1e354fadc4bffdd99339a039272e54</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane hellbent on ending horror NRLW finals run ahead of preliminary final clash with Newcastle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/nrlw-finals-broncos-knights-brigginshaw-upton/105820672</link><description>The Broncos have been almost untouchable through the 2025 NRLW season but the club's poor finals record in recent years means they can not afford to get ahead of themselves leading into this week's preliminary final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d248af9a48662ba232728304794119fd</guid></item><item><title>Australian doctors become unofficial correspondents from hospital in Gaza City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/australian-doctors-al-shifa-gaza-hospital/105813828</link><description>In a ruined hospital and with little medication, two Australian doctors say the situation inside Gaza City is a "nightmare".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfe47390104719cccc9dafc8afd130a0</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final preview — how corridor control and the hard ball can lead Brisbane to back-to-back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/afl-grand-final-preview-lions-look-for-back-to-back/105820830</link><description>They've had to deal with adversity all year, but the Lions are one step away from historic back-to-back flags — here's how they can do it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39ffbe3a1c41d9fda76aa7ad5e261837</guid></item><item><title>Even without Trump's tariffs, Australian farmers are losing out on billions of dollars</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/non-trade-barriers-trump-australian-farmers/105820528</link><description>Even without Trump's tariffs, Australian farmers and exporters of agricultural produce are already losing out on an estimated $4 billion of annual export trade each year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8da56250820715f66334662c60347158</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu minister tells Australia to respect China policing deal, rebukes Pat Conroy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/vanuatu-tells-australia-to-respect-china-policing-deal/105820502</link><description>Vanuatu's internal affairs minister says Australia needs to respect his country's plan to sign a new policing agreement with China, and has taken a swipe at Pacific Minister Pat Conroy as controversy over the proposal rumbles along.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">050f43efa5f6288d7a00530de579d990</guid></item><item><title>Geoff Ayling, composer of some of Australia's most recognised ad jingles, dies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/geoff-ayling-songwriter-dies-famous-ad-jingles/105817238</link><description>The man who wrote the music for many well-known advertising jingles, including Good on You Mum, Tip Top bread and Take Me Away, P&amp;O, is being remembered for his musical skill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b53a6564057672097bb047c151dca62</guid></item><item><title>Why you might consider glass food containers over plastic</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/are-glass-containers-better-for-food-storage/105814738</link><description>Compared to plastic containers, glass alternatives can reduce exposure to microplastics when used in the microwave and be easier to clean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62503c861f079a92f249f37bd31d4008</guid></item><item><title>Inquest into Mackay Base Hospital death of Hugo McGregor hears of mother's anguish</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/coronial-inquest-hugo-mcgregor-mackay-base-hospital-death/105812908</link><description>Jenna McGregor says she will forever treasure the moments she had with baby Hugo, who died in a Queensland hospital five days after his birth in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9c25ec8e37aa1d959d3ba71a50e47f8</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste scraps lifetime pensions after student-led protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/timor-leste-scraps-lifetime-pensions-student-protests/105822222</link><description>Timor-Leste votes to cancel the lifetime pension law for MPs and public officials, following student-led demonstrations against lavish perks in one of South-East Asia's poorest countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45a5c26bb186d48e726ba42169e2ac69</guid></item><item><title>Disgraced Sydney business tycoon Ron Brierley unfit for trial, lawyers say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/disgraced-sydney-business-tycoon-ron-brierley-unfit-for-trial/105821436</link><description>Ron Brierley, 88, was charged in March with three counts of the offence, about three years after an appeals court overturned a previous jail term for similar offending because of his ill-health and conditions in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51b2c90790119881c59b4d56606b97f8</guid></item><item><title>Nick Kyrgios spruiks construction of $9.9 million Gungahlin tennis facility in Canberra's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/act-9-million-tennis-facility-construction-begins/105821980</link><description>Construction on a new $9.9 million tennis facility in the Gungahlin has begun five years after the ACT government pledged funding for it ahead of the 2020 territory election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f140dc898fba699bca2f89fcd4262dab</guid></item><item><title>Hostel Reef Trips fined $60k for workplace health and safety breach after tourist's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/great-barrier-reef-tourism-operator-fined-after-passenger-death/105819840</link><description>A magistrate has sentenced a Great Barrier Reef tourism operator that pleaded guilty to a workplace health and safety breach following the death of a passenger in 2022.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16ad0e132525c9165c48a5f298c18202</guid></item><item><title>Six men jailed after police foiled 2.4 tonne cocaine importation operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/men-jailed-cocaine-importation-shambles/105822590</link><description>Six men involved in a drug importation operation described by the prosecutor as a "comedy of errors" are jailed in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8d0a510c0be4786f4dad60cf83becaa</guid></item><item><title>Jury unable to reach verdict in trial of a teenage girl charged with sexually assaulting, stalking ex-boyfriend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/act-jury-unable-verdict-teen-girl-sexual-assault-stalking-ex/105821172</link><description>The trial of a teenage girl accused of sexually assaulting and stalking her former boyfriend ends with no result, after an ACT Supreme Court jury is unable to reach a verdict.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e7b752f7f976aaad070ad61420dd21f</guid></item><item><title>RAAF serviceman jailed for international child sexual abuse offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/raaf-member-sentenced-over-online-child-abuse/105667502</link><description>The man has been sentenced over 18 child sex offences against 10 victims from Australia, the US and the UK.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43c7a67e58ce5f2bd490318ab94457d0</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur powers through at China Open, Aleksandar Vukic set for big-name quarterfinal in Japan Open</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/alex-de-minaur-powers-through-in-china/105823034</link><description>Aussie Alex de Minaur is through to the China Open round of 16 thanks to a crushing straight-sets win over a local wildcard, while in Japan Aleksandar Vukic has recorded a second win to set up a tasty quarterfinal clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">536d835a42b45245a5e4b71e9f9aff13</guid></item><item><title>Police investigating after woman's body found in the Hobart Rivulet by man walking dog</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/body-of-female-found-in-hobart-rivulet-near-molle-street/105823302</link><description>Police say they have notified the family of a woman aged in her 30s whose body was found in the Hobart Rivulet on Friday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b833cae44c2ced572ea0a27f2b63b47</guid></item><item><title>Russia helping China to prepare for potential invasion of Taiwan, defence think tank RUSI says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-26/russia-helping-china-prepare-for-taiwan-invasion-says-thinktank/105823308</link><description>Leaked Russian documents analysed by a leading UK think tank suggest Russia is selling military equipment and technology to China that could help it prepare an airborne invasion of Taiwan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8da797f22ee0851495fbdb3b01797dc</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese says Aussies are 'concerned' about far right's rise abroad, ahead of Donald Trump meeting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/anthony-albanese-says-aussies-are-concerned-about-far-right-rise/105819050</link><description>Anthony Albanese warns against the rise of populism and the far right ahead of his in-person meeting with Donald Trump next month, saying governments should "not seek to divide people".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26f76d3a7768af90f019f28385e9129a</guid></item><item><title>Gulf states reevaluate US relationship as Israel replaces Iran as a threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/gulf-states-united-nations-general-assembly-donald-trump/105801292</link><description>The Gulf, along with Israel, will be wondering just how far Donald Trump really is prepared to push Benjamin Netanyahu.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e0e64a2d1db9bd1d64b2ebafe1d2ab8</guid></item><item><title>Australia's climate target doesn't eclipse today's tough questions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/climate-announcement-targets-emissions/105801294</link><description>As a nation, it's as if we're arguing about where to have a family holiday in 2035, and whether we fly economy or business. Meanwhile, nobody can agree on dinner tonight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4146131c7945d7a9befae50175a86f11</guid></item><item><title>How Alliyah's community missed the signs of a female predator</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/female-child-abusers-hidden/105806706</link><description>Gender stereotypes "play a role" in allowing predators like Kellie Whiteside to fly under the radar, but that's not the whole story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5212f82642c02bf7652806df1582ca0</guid></item><item><title>The drug smuggling case of Japanese tourist Chika Honda and its parallels with Donna Nelson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/chika-honda-1992-drug-smuggling-case-australia-and-donna-nelson/105812710</link><description>A Japanese tourist who served 10 years in an Australian prison for drug smuggling offences sees her story reflected in the case of Australian Donna Nelson, who was sentenced to six years in a Japanese prison for smuggling 2 kilograms of methamphetamine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b06cef5818c953eb5ee9e418eeb4d004</guid></item><item><title>Soldier, Shakespeare die-hard, and the next Liberal leader? Andrew Hastie's week in the headlines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/andrew-hastie-liberal-party-leadership/105822510</link><description>The West Australian veteran has a clear vision for the future of the Liberal Party — and he's making it known.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c9cd9bedbb6ade58671fe793227f3da</guid></item><item><title>Geelong and Brisbane's AFL grand final meeting a clash of 21st-century titans 25 years in the making</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-geelong-brisbane-grand-final-21st-century-titans/105817210</link><description>When they meet at the MCG on Saturday afternoon, Geelong and Brisbane are bidding for more than just the 2025 premiership. For the two most dominant clubs of a generation, true greatness is at hand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a8fca4f4487c82e1257eae08d6d9ec0</guid></item><item><title>The majority of Queensland councils are washing their hands of fluoridation under the watch of both sides of politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/qld-fluoride-water-supply-tooth-decay-politics-washing-hands/105820504</link><description>Attacks by Queensland Opposition Leader Steven Miles against Premier David Crisafulli over fluoride this week are more than hard to swallow after another local government's decision to stop adding the mineral to its water supply, writes Janelle Miles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3f79307107db030116e62bb5f9c648d</guid></item><item><title>Crocodile industry stakeholders urge Australian government to reform outdated code of practice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/code-of-practice-wild-farmed-australian-crocodiles/105821646</link><description>Thrust back into the international spotlight by the recent trial of Outback Wrangler star Matt Wright, questions are being raised about the Top End's lucrative crocodile industry and its outdated code of practice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5f0239291a3bab11069711c4f720cb3</guid></item><item><title>Best books out in September, from Ian McEwan, Patrick Ryan and Lee Lai</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/best-books-september-ian-mcewan-patrick-ryan-lee-lai/105805520</link><description>Wondering what to read next? This month's best books include the latest from literary giant Ian McEwan and Buckeye, a multigenerational family saga set in America's Midwest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0348b42f488a06fcaa90b607ac100204</guid></item><item><title>Persistent algae bloom causing political headaches as scientists are copping the flak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/algae-bloom-political-headaches/105821302</link><description>South Australia's algal bloom continues to cause political headaches for state and federal Labor. Perhaps that's why scientists are copping some of the flak now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4eda47c6abdb95b5e7cb1558c679e6d</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump warns 'there will be others' after James Comey's indictment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/trump-says-there-will-be-others-after-comey/105823804</link><description>Donald Trump expects more indictments to be issued against political figures after the former FBI chief was charged.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52700f3b187e6e4b599041821740bea8</guid></item><item><title>AI can't teach our kids to be curious and think critically</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/ai-revolution-classrooms/105756868</link><description>The AI dystopia might already be here but there are some things only humans can teach our children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a55b864c2b25cccc3569eb1e7b2df7c5</guid></item><item><title>Detailed designs of new lyric theatre inspired by Canberra's natural landmarks revealed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/act-new-lyric-theatres-detailed-designs-revealed/105823106</link><description>Detailed designs show plans for the new 2,000-seat lyric theatre, inspired by Canberra's natural landmarks, which will host major musicals, ballets and operas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32104f4565bc9ee2f42947c31b206b9c</guid></item><item><title>Police locate 10yo boy missing in Victoria's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/missing-boy-campground-chaz-jeparit-victoria-police-appeal/105823820</link><description>A 10-year-old boy has been located safe and well, more than 15 hours after he was last seen near a campground in Victoria's north-west.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67c2852121ebcc63490fc24605d75459</guid></item><item><title>Conservation notice issued for alleged native vegetation clearing at Chittering</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/dwer-issues-notice-over-alleged-native-tree-clearing-chittering/105807210</link><description>Western Australia's environmental regulator has issued a property owner with a vegetation conservation notice for the alleged clearing of a significant amount of native trees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a73ca93c90bcc1f5bb19f601570855d0</guid></item><item><title>What time is the 2025 AFL grand final? Here's how to watch and everything you need to know as Brisbane and Geelong clash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grand-final-2025-what-time-does-the-game-start/105823862</link><description>Wondering what time the AFL grand final starts and how you can watch it live? We've got you covered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">961b6e51ce3e13209f14691157297bb3</guid></item><item><title>Police reveal link between man and woman found dead in New South Wales home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/police-investigate-after-two-bodies-found-in-coffs-harbour/105823928</link><description>Police found the bodies of a man and woman in their 60s when doing a welfare check at a Coffs Harbour property on Friday evening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47e234f9b8ecd79651a27ee1302b040c</guid></item><item><title>The banal, brutal life of traffic police in South West WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/ride-along-with-south-west-road-traffic-police/105820992</link><description>As WA experiences its worst year for road deaths in over a decade, the ABC shadows two traffic officers as they try to stop the number climbing higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">607dd8386b70fdaac1a7dbd4afc9ea3f</guid></item><item><title>For four years, Yuna and Minu Jo lay in a suitcase in a New Zealand storage unit. Now they have justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/nz-suitcase-deaths-aftermath/105811894</link><description>Minu and Yuna Jo's bodies lay in a storage unit for four years. They finally have justice after their mother was found guilty of their murders seven years after they were killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c20fa9f4daa00b724ebbc96dbed5d5c6</guid></item><item><title>Gladstone Strollers walking group creates a village for postpartum mums</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/postpartum-mum-walking-group-mental-health-benefits/105820070</link><description>A Queensland mum desperate to have a positive postpartum experience when she had her second child found that just a few small steps were enough to make a huge difference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4aabdb9b02f032a6f0dfa2b02445682e</guid></item><item><title>Trump visit to Ryder Cup not enough to inspire Americans as Europe dominates day one</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/ryder-cup-golf-trump-visit-fails-to-inspire-americans/105823802</link><description>President Donald Trump visits on the opening day of the Ryder Cup, but it's the Europeans who dominate heading into day two.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">971dd8b151a82436219cb0443b384982</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final 2025: Brisbane Lions thump Geelong Cats by 47 points, Will Ashcroft wins Norm Smith Medal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grand-final-2025-geelong-vs-brisbane-live-blog/105822258</link><description>Brisbane secures its second straight AFL premiership, taking control in the final quarter of an otherwise gripping grand final against Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14ca0c766669a84c1c64d308b07e389c</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Storm Bualoi sweeps through Philippines leaving 10 dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/tropical-storm-bulaoi-philippines-flood-corruption/105823944</link><description>The death toll from a tropical storm that swept across the central Philippines and southern Luzon has risen to 10, as the country's north continued recovering from Super Typhoon Ragasa.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2df415b803d0ecbfbe0362606b7d507</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's last flying-fox cash dispenser gains Lifeline in Gayndah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/lifeline-for-queenslands-final-flying-fox-cash-dispenser/105789280</link><description>A not-for-profit organisation has created a new era for a heritage-listed shop and its nostalgic flying-fox change dispenser, which is the last remaining in Queensland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43234991c230220980a87add3ea50db7</guid></item><item><title>Fortescue offers measles vaccine boosters after Christmas Creek outbreak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/fortescue-measles-vaccine-boosters-christmas-creek-outbreak/105820426</link><description>Iron-ore giant Fortescue says it will offer vaccine boosters after three measles cases were confirmed at its Pilbara mine earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26e09d8753cc469c42fac166c15b08d3</guid></item><item><title>Tourist dies at Tasmania's Cradle Mountain National Park after group becomes 'overwhelmed' by extreme weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/cradle-mountain-walker-dies-extreme-weather/105824188</link><description>A group of tourists who were unprepared for the extreme conditions at Cradle Mountain National Park is rescued, but one member of the group dies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c2bacc1d4008463c044ab40ec94a7ab</guid></item><item><title>Clive Palmer ordered to pay more than $13 million after foreign investor claim dismissed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/clive-palmer-foreign-investor-claim-dismissed/105823966</link><description>The decade-long dispute was related to WA government legislation, which impeded Clive Palmer's ability to extract damages over the Balmoral South Iron Ore Project in the Pilbara.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b97d0fa74d42a0e0aad8a2eb639f05fe</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous teenager teaches Paakantyi language to teachers at Menindee school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/aboriginal-paakantyi-language-teacher-outback-nsw-school/105815440</link><description>Jaz Fusi has been passionate about learning Paakantyi language for most of her life. Now, she teaches it to her local school's teachers and is eager to see other kids do the same.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffc9b2d6c78f4e662e2f96fe4e5bf8a9</guid></item><item><title>WA government facing $400m cost blowout over Peel Health Campus redevelopment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/peel-health-campus-cost-blowout/105824094</link><description>The long-awaited redevelopment of Peel Health Campus is facing a $400 million cost blowout and potential delays, a leaked document reveals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7295950907094099603d65d0a0b06af</guid></item><item><title>All Blacks edge brave Wallabies to retain Bledisloe Cup for 23rd year at Eden Park, Morgan Turinui rants at referee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/live-updates-all-blacks-vs-wallabies-bledisloe-cup-in-auckland/105816056</link><description>The All Blacks have beaten the Wallabies 33-24 at Eden Park, extending their 39-year and counting winning record against Australia at the Auckland venue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13406db2d00d984b62fdf93c8404b3c6</guid></item><item><title>Relationship experts on the signs that it may be time to call it quits</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/signs-it-might-be-time-to-end-a-relationship/105675792</link><description>If you are feeling indifferent about your relationship, have high conflict, or just don't really enjoy their company anymore, it is possible the partnership has reached its end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">499d5b97aa70d0462b93fa23afce5eb8</guid></item><item><title>Snoop Dogg, Baker Boy and Tash Sultana star in AFL grand final entertainment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/snoop-dogg-afl-grand-final-entertainment-mcg/105819406</link><description>The legendary rapper delivered a squeaky clean performance, incorporating local artists and a didgeridoo in a trip through his catalogue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">520a21469afd2968627cca416d5cdb69</guid></item><item><title>Matt Wright's lawyers reveal five grounds of appeal for Netflix star's guilty verdict, including allegation against judge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/matt-wright-five-grounds-of-appeal-revealed/105824618</link><description>Matt Wright's lawyers have revealed the five grounds they are seeking to appeal their client's guilty verdict on, including an allegation that the judge made an "impermissible comment to the jury".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45adde7e87d9110419b85a7a1e1c1ee1</guid></item><item><title>Lions star Will Ashcroft wins second consecutive Norm Smith Medal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grandfinal-norm-smith-lons-cats-will-ashcroft/105824400</link><description>Will Ashcroft claims back-to-back Norm Smith Medals after playing a starring role in the Brisbane Lions' grand final win over Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d02e668f13c6768be3d2d3f2232c0931</guid></item><item><title>Pilot dies in light plane crash after skydiving flight in Moruya</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/man-dead-after-light-plane-crash-skydiving-drop-in-moruya/105824806</link><description>The pilot of a light plane dies following a successful sky-diving drop when the aircraft crashes into bushland on the NSW south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfd74f67fd39f997c5ab04ab0783973a</guid></item><item><title>Shark victim Mercury Psillakis's twin brother leads paddle out on Sydney's Northern Beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/paddle-out-shark-victim-mercury-psillakis-sydney-long-reef-beach/105824476</link><description>The twin brother of shark victim Mercury Psillakis has led hundreds of surfers in a paddle out in his memory on Sydney's Northern Beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0130705e7e9b9976106bd6990598bf9</guid></item><item><title>Paddle out in memory of shark victim Mercury Psillakis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/paddle-out-in-memory-of-shark-victim-mercury-psillakis/105824534</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9c1a41e45ff84c4c29db5b8bb30a7ee</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane's back-to-back AFL grand final wins suggest we could be back in a 'Lions era'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/brisbane-lions-defeat-geelong-in-grand-final-in-new-era/105824588</link><description>The Lions successfully defended their premiership to go back-to-back and pose the question: Are we back in a Lions era?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7311d26402f791ca2c79be844c093f2</guid></item><item><title>AFL grand final quick hits: Lions' Lachie Neale gamble pays off, Cats' Jeremy Cameron in the wars, and it's Country Road time at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/afl-grand-final-quick-hits-geelong-cats-brisbane-lions/105821966</link><description>Brisbane's gamble on Lachie Neale's fitness pays off with a team-lifting goal, a brave Jeremy Cameron has a painful day out, and Charlie Cameron's goals provide a Country Road soundtrack at the MCG. Here are the quick hits from the 2025 AFL grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef10be159c2c5da37bc2677e999bc6a9</guid></item><item><title>White House releases photo of Donald Trump and Anthony Albanese</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/albanese-trump-photo/105824944</link><description>A photo of a smiling Donald Trump, alongside Anthony Albanese, his fiancée Jodie Haydon and US First Lady Melania Trump, has been released by the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff4eec3691a0dfeed959566549f25d32</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese meets with King Charles at Balmoral Castle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-27/anthony-albanese-meets-king-charles-balmoral-castle/105825036</link><description>King Charles III has received Prime Minister Anthony Albanese in a royal audience held at Balmoral Castle in Scotland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6937ee0e6be00561e8724ba711d45b9</guid></item><item><title>Chinese presence in the Pacific runs deep and is now reshaped by Beijing's ambitions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/china-pacific-islands-untold-story-chinese-geopolitics-influence/105818894</link><description>China's presence in the Pacific is often viewed in the context of geopolitical tension and rivalry. But Chinese people have been in the region for generations — these are their stories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6598aaeafdf808048e2ae2838622179b</guid></item><item><title>Geelong's strength-in-numbers approach fails its biggest test in AFL grand final loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/afl-grand-final-geelong-cats-brisbane-lions-analysis/105824608</link><description>It is the cruel irony of sport that what is usually the ace up Geelong's sleeve proved to be its downfall in the loss to the Brisbane Lions in the season decider.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1face944653c3d1f368bbbf10b8ded7</guid></item><item><title>As Australia's retirement savings grow into world's second biggest, government to review consumer protections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/as-australian-retirement-savings-grow-greater-regulation-needed/105820684</link><description>Compulsory super has led to higher levels of national savings but, as the pool of savings grows, many argue that stricter supervision is needed to protect Australians' retirement savings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">727169d9557e7aa1856d8b008f7d6fd7</guid></item><item><title>When it comes to love, more of us are crossing the religious divide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/more-australians-are-marrying-across-the-religious-divide/105779468</link><description>Exclusive data for 5.2 million couples shows nearly one in five marriages are between people of different religions – double the proportion recorded in 1986.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">013dc6d1c3729b713228afd937c045d6</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz Kids: Tom Gleeson's back to put Australia's pint-sized hot shots in their place</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/hard-quiz-kids-weekly-trivia/105773368</link><description>The grump's back to take on the grommets in a new series of Hard Quiz Kids. Don't let the pint-sized know-it-alls show you up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a862981fd7047144319126295a5f472</guid></item><item><title>Guy Sebastian reflects on Titus Day legal case and the lesson he's learned from fans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/guy-sebastian-the-assembly/105671828</link><description>Guy Sebastian opens up about the fan encounter that made him "burst into tears" and a court case with his former manager Titus Day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d1fceb0fd7d9b21cd61a61a6b4f7281</guid></item><item><title>Roosters on cusp of perfect NRLW season after beating Sharks 17-16</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/nrlw-preliminary-final-sydney-roosters-cronulla-sharks/105825564</link><description>Jocelyn Kelleher is relishing the chance to prove her credentials as the Sydney Roosters look to claim back-to-back premierships for the first time in their history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c98d6e82e7da5e596aaac09a0d982f4d</guid></item><item><title>Woppaburra people welcome ancestor's return but face final hurdle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/woppaburra-peoples-fight-to-get-ancestor-home/105788102</link><description>More First Nations remains are being returned to Australia from international institutions, but these Woppaburra men say laying them to rest on country can prove a fresh challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f2752aea82ec37f1fac83229df02a1</guid></item><item><title>England defeats Canada 33-13 in Women's Rugby World Cup final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/rugby-world-cup-final-england-defeats-canada/105825580</link><description>In front of a record crowd of more than 80,000 spectators, England delivers on the biggest stage with a 33-13 defeat of Canada in the tournament decider at Twickenham.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62fcacd86e45554323ddd632300502bc</guid></item><item><title>A small win for beachgoers and gardeners as washed-up sea life turned to compost</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/algal-bloom-dead-sea-life-turned-to-compost/105807488</link><description>Dead sea life washed ashore during SA's marine algal bloom has been diverted into commercial compost for farms and gardens, in what has been viewed as a small win amid the large-scale devastation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4b9a8f084b8a14c310d2e1372a86ca2</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's coal royalty regime back in the spotlight after job cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/qld-coal-mine-royalties-regime-questioned-after-job-cuts/105818488</link><description>Despite a change of government, Queensland's controversial coal royalty scheme remains in place and recent job cuts are prompting renewed discussion about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05fc998cc23e435b2b1e012ba6d8ab22</guid></item><item><title>Sydney stomping grounds of 1920s and 30s crime bosses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/1920s-razor-gang-crime-bosses-that-wreaked-havoc-on-sydney/105749468</link><description>From the 'queen of the underworld' to a razor gang slasher in control of an underworld empire, these were the bosses at the centre of an organised crime battle in the late 1920s and early 1930s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9422096e9eace91d69505b24dca8e33f</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane and Geelong fans experience the ecstasy and agony of AFL's biggest game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/afl-grand-final-lions-and-cats-fan-reactions/105824822</link><description>For the second year in a row, Brisbane Lions fans were celebrating in the streets as their team claimed the premiership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6337aba73bc17913cc11052d6f937e4</guid></item><item><title>Bowie Daly, 9, makes surfing comeback after surviving shark attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-28/bowie-daly-returns-to-surfing-weeks-after-shark-attack/105788210</link><description>Bowie Daly may be back in the surf but he says the near miss still plays on his mind.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4545e4bca232ff37c4b0fe146c7aa2dc</guid></item></channel></rss>