<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 02:31:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Survival camping isn't for everyone — so how would you go in the wilderness? Take the quiz to find out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/survival-camping-quiz-tasmanian-wilderness/105888688</link><description>For 18-year-old Rivi, knowing what gear to leave behind can be as important as knowing what to take with.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab49ce291cf03e60517a144569b2e9c7</guid></item><item><title>Rain brings relief across much of Victoria but the drought is 'certainly not over'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/victorian-drought-not-over-despite-relief-of-spring-rain/106004802</link><description>Dusty Victorian farms turn muddy as drenching rain brings much-needed relief.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87d1f24f3b4d20878cb22c831a1aa5d7</guid></item><item><title>Rose Byrne plays a mother on the edge in Mary Bronstein's If I Had Legs I'd Kick You</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/if-i-had-legs-i-kick-you-rose-byrne-movie-mary-bronstein/105977540</link><description>The Sydney-born movie star discusses how her creative partnership with If I had Legs I'd Kick You director Mary Bronstein has opened the Oscars conversation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a57ec37515d332a6074b6269009da5c4</guid></item><item><title>Inspection of Weona Park horse stud found several serious animal welfare issues, just weeks before public outcry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/weona-horse-stud/106012012</link><description>Investigators warned the "situation" at a horse stud in the state's south "is likely to [be] the next welfare issue hitting the news".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff8f2c6eb64387a9de9b3397ae1d51b1</guid></item><item><title>Horned 'devil' bee found in remote Goldfields prompts call for further research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/horned-lucifer-bee-discovery-goldfields/105997548</link><description>The discovery of a new "lucifer" bee with devil-like horns sparks concerns over land clearing regulations in WA's Goldfields region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae67dce636b1d6d9780e5a16b4b27f80</guid></item><item><title>Amid ongoing drought in South Australia, these women are redefining resilience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/women-showing-up-for-community-during-drought/105926946</link><description>Dusty paddocks, with no grain crop to harvest, and scarce feed for the few animals left, is the reality of many South Australian farmers right now. Four women are redefining resilience and showing what it means to endure tough conditions despite it all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5497b2acddf11b8b1ea3f54f23673983</guid></item><item><title>Victorian farmer to auction father's vintage tractor collection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/victorian-farmer-to-auction-fathers-vintage-tractor-collection/105990840</link><description>Tony Forrest reflects on his father's love of old tractors as he prepares them for sale.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8c2f2f7c59d020c9c17b7e189a1935c</guid></item><item><title>Indonesian school kids poisoned by free school lunches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/indonesian-school-kids-poisoned-by-free-school-lunches/106010538</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61fbcb16360c16afdcf8e5c097d19b79</guid></item><item><title>Aldo Revaldo taken to hospital with suspected poisoning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/aldo-repaldo-taken-to-hospital-with-suspected-poisoning/106010560</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb1cad64e02ae52dcb0ae19ad430e102</guid></item><item><title>Accusations of secrecy, abuse of power fly as WA Labor wades through third term</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/wa-government-accused-of-secrecy-abuse-of-power/106010294</link><description>Accusations of secrecy and abuse of process have been levelled at the Western Australian government this week on several fronts. Are they blips on the radar or signs WA Labor is under strain?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">641b8039ba4f80240938b1dff54fec01</guid></item><item><title>Wong won't put price tag on COP31 as final host decision looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/cop31-price-penny-wong/106014762</link><description>Foreign Minister Penny Wong has refused to say how much it would cost Australia to hold the COP31 climate conference, as negotiations over hosting rights enter the final stages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a300239a7111e75ab0cafa979cd434c</guid></item><item><title>Love of toys takes former retailer from Sydney's CBD to Blayney library</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/louise-sheather-hero-of-blayney-toy-library/105994988</link><description>After a career in one of Sydney's busiest department stores, a retail expert takes her tricks of the trade to a toy library in central west NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed4e3cbc45b5b1c67feede6e2529171</guid></item><item><title>More coloured sand recalls prompt ACT to close 70 schools over asbestos concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/more-coloured-sand-products-recalled-over-asbestos-fears/106014952</link><description>Kmart has recalled four coloured sand products over concerns of asbestos contamination, prompting the ACT education department to close dozens more schools.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0c60746dd4e3f1d8cbdf98f839bc448</guid></item><item><title>Government considers dramatic intervention to save Tomago smelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/government-considers-intervention-to-save-tomago-smelter/106015238</link><description>The federal government is considering a power-purchase agreement with Tomago to supply electricity at a stable price, after warnings the smelter may need to close because of rising power costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4939cc71d7e33335bf2c9f977ab8634a</guid></item><item><title>Former MP Nick Dametto declares victory in Townsville mayoral by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/townsville-mayoral-by-election-nick-dametto-declares-victory/106014032</link><description>Nick Dametto, a former Queensland MP, has won 61 per cent of the votes counted, succeeding in his campaign to become Townsville's next mayor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e93915c10ec838af548b5920da333d1b</guid></item><item><title>Coalition plans to strip climate from energy operator's objectives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/coalition-joint-net-zero-position-leaked-submission/106015290</link><description>Emissions reduction would no longer be an objective of Australia's energy operator under a Coalition plan endorsed by the Nationals and Liberals, prioritising affordability and reliability over climate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e121017def600970fa4dff5d9f2618b7</guid></item><item><title>ACT closes 70 schools as more sand products recalled amid asbestos concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/act-to-close-schools-after-coloured-sand-recall-over-asbestos/106015398</link><description>The ACT will close more schools after additional coloured sand products were recalled by Kmart and Target, while the schools that were shut on Friday will reopen on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9518404fe2157f394c68f2bfa67ac72</guid></item><item><title>From 'female Donald Trump' to 'Wacky' Marjorie — how Taylor Greene's alliance with the president crumbled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/donald-trump-marjorie-taylor-greene-alliance-erupts/106015394</link><description>Once considered one of Donald Trump's most loyal soldiers, Marjorie Taylor Greene has found herself an outcast of the MAGA firm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce47c00f288f5b76e52c94fe74013bf6</guid></item><item><title>Renegades down Stars by four wickets as Devine sends down stunner in Scorchers win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/renegades-down-stars-scorchers-defeat-strikers/106015666</link><description>The Renegades get the better of the Stars in the Melbourne derby, while Sophie Devine bowls one of the balls of the season in the Scorchers' defeat of the Strikers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ec6f32af3d9f60d49cdfd034530342e</guid></item><item><title>Zac Lomax released by Eels for 'opportunities outside NRL', fuelling speculation of R360 switch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-16/lomax-released-by-eels-fuelling-speculation-of-r360-switch/106015696</link><description>Parramatta star Zac Lomax is released from the final three years of his NRL contract, fuelling speculation of a move to breakaway rugby competition R360.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e096c75a6ce2bd66a948cea80f34803</guid></item><item><title>Energy chiefs say net zero 'irreversible' even though bills unlikely to fall 'for a decade'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/energy-ceos-say-transition-irreversible-despite-rocketing-costs/106015292</link><description>Amid swirling debate among conservative politicians over decarbonisation, energy bosses have warned against turning away from net zero despite cost pressures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30ce8fd67aeb676bb34fe21971b4fd65</guid></item><item><title>Why 'not just living for the weekend' may be a social media trend for good</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/not-living-for-the-weekend-social-media-trend/105999240</link><description>Emma Dickeson says her "school night" adventures are about devoting time and attention to the things that energise you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42759f841e6bf8bfce2e2a4594556426</guid></item><item><title>Laos methanol poisoning survivor 'turning grief into action'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/laos-methanol-poisoning-survivor-turning-grief-into-action/106007590</link><description>A survivor of last year's Laos mass methanol poisoning has started a campaign to educate travellers on the dangers of the toxic form of alcohol.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5926b3d2a458b4519574ccc128a7360</guid></item><item><title>The strange macho appeal of fossil fuels in a world struggling to reach net zero</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/macho-appeal-of-fossil-fuels-in-a-world-struggling-with-net-zero/106011600</link><description>The strange macho appeal of fossilised vegetation means that 30 years of annual United Nations meetings to stop the planet heating any more have been a bust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d07adbbaa77ec7a1ebd1bd5822d3206</guid></item><item><title>Indian counterterrorism agency arrests alleged co-conspirator in Red Fort suicide bombing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/man-arrested-over-deadly-delhi-red-fort-explosion/106016028</link><description>India's National Investigation Agency says two men behind last week's deadly car blast in Delhi were from Kashmir, a region that has been a source of tension between India and Pakistan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e53842f29d91924a30d3bdb5722563d5</guid></item><item><title>WA testing lab inundated by families' and retailers' concerns about asbestos-contaminated sand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/wa-hazard-testing-lab-overrun-with-asbestos-sand-requests/106015136</link><description>Concerned families and retailers are inundating a materials testing laboratory with enquiries, since news broke that asbestos had been detected in decorative and coloured sand for children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21052cae1747cefb9fccbf348f33cb3f</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley scrabbling to retain leadership after net zero capitulation puts one advantage at risk</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/ley-puts-one-advantage-at-risk-scrabbling-to-keep-leadership/106011602</link><description>It was only a week ago that the moderates in the Liberal Party were flexing their muscle privately (and some publicly), threatening a divorce with the Nationals and to walk the plank if net zero was dumped. Neither threat ever materialised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0db26107892679ddf443db6d1c4ef15c</guid></item><item><title>Operational dates for Northern Water project pushed out by several years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/northern-water-project-timeline-pushed-back/105995628</link><description>Completion of the South Australian government’s Northern Water desalination plant and water pipeline is now forecast to occur in 2032.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3321bf605b72948ab339039081d26fc</guid></item><item><title>Numbers suggest England's Ashes preparation does not make a difference</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/ashes-england-preparation-first-test-historical/106012450</link><description>Has England compromised its pre-Ashes preparation by playing only one three-day warm-up match against its own reserve team before the first Test in Perth? The numbers say no.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64090b0afb139b2e1d6c0f0cee876498</guid></item><item><title>Police mental health unit under the spotlight after the deaths of 10 people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/nsw-police-mental-health-responses-criticism-from-coroners/105914846</link><description>An officer who headed the NSW Police unit training the force in mental health responses once committed misconduct in a case where a mentally ill man was fatally shot by police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12f3f7fd35e360033cf2335d8bb2a05f</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr rested as Chelsea drops Women's Super League points</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/sam-kerr-rested-chelsea-drops-wsl-points-arsenal-draw/106016282</link><description>English champs Chelsea decide to rest Sam Kerr for their WSL clash against Liverpool but appear to pay the price with a 1-1 slip-up at Liverpool.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43246472ac0ff91330de097de8b29e25</guid></item><item><title>Maya Joint's fighting qualities praised in Billie Jean King Cup win over Brazil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/maya-joint-s-fighting-qualifies-praised-in-bjk-cup-win/106016324</link><description>Australia advances to the qualifying stage of the Billie Jean King Cup after Maya Joint and Kimberly Birrell dug deep to defeat Brazil and top their group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c08e333a529694f7ed6bdb93ce9ab748</guid></item><item><title>Locals brace for timber industry job losses amid creation of Great Koala National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/job-losses-in-timber-industry-to-create-koala-park/106004814</link><description>A third of Herons Creek’s population on the NSW mid north coast faces possible redundancy as the timber mill struggles to survive the logging moratorium to create the Great Koala National Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9af06d114671af8f00a4cf766aa9abe</guid></item><item><title>Jannik Sinner beats Carlos Alcaraz in ATP Finals in latest Sincaraz rivalry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/jannik-sinner-beats-carlos-alcaraz-in-atp-finals/106016348</link><description>Jannik Sinner has defeated world number one Carlos Alcaraz 7-6 (4), 7-5 in the ATP Finals title decider, defending his crown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e22513592369347affdecc29fa48dd1</guid></item><item><title>Groote Eylandt's unique rehabilitation program offers alternative to NT prison system amid record incarceration rates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/groote-eylandt-nt-rehabilitation-program-nt-prison-crisis/106007976</link><description>As the NT's prison population soars to new highs, Anindilyakwa elders on Groote Eylandt are delivering a unique rehabilitation program that provides participants with physical and psycho-educational programs, as well as new skills and employment opportunities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c264b98767b14288601b3656e660f24</guid></item><item><title>Unique rehabilitation program offers alternative to prison system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/stateline-groote-eylandt-rehab-centre-alternative-to-prison/106015402</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">039031c507c111d5767aa5572109796c</guid></item><item><title>Esperance community fights for more change, a decade on from deadly bushfires</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/deadly-esperance-fires-10-year-anniversary/106011936</link><description>A decade on from bushfires that claimed four lives, this community says not enough has been done to ensure they are safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26fef5c10f539bb8ef24c281e054fc28</guid></item><item><title>Iran begins cloud seeding to induce rain as it faces worst drought in decades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/iran-cloud-seeding-worst-drought-in-decades/106016566</link><description>Cloud seeding involves spraying particles such as silver iodide and salt into clouds from aircraft to trigger rain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2ac4d6818d3c9412a85d4a3f80ca6df</guid></item><item><title>Calls for greater education as growers in WA's south-west brace for polyphagous shot-hole borer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/growers-brace-for-impact-of-polyphagous-shot-hole-borer/106015566</link><description>Growers in this major food bowl are nervous for their future, as the state focuses its shot-hole borer efforts on outer-Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50f4a3a5e7ce5cf47c88150724bea96c</guid></item><item><title>South Africa beat India by 30 runs in low-scoring first Test boilover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/south-africa-beat-india-in-first-test-boilover/106016596</link><description>South Africa upsets India on a turning pitch at Eden Gardens, with spinner Simon Harmer taking eight wickets in a man-of-the-match performance for the World Test Champions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f15a3e3dceaa4fad6333648dc1958129</guid></item><item><title>Koala mapping near Mudgee discovers strong population and ideal habitat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/mudgee-koala-mapping-finds-critical-population/105977120</link><description>Scientists mapping koala habitat in the NSW central west find it is larger than previously thought, but concerns remain over expansion plans at a nearby coal mine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">084df53a2828bc45a1af61c81e23d553</guid></item><item><title>Ireland celebrates after Troy Parrott secures last-second World Cup qualifier victory over Hungary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/ireland-beats-hungary-in-last-second-of-world-cup-qualifiers/106016698</link><description>Ireland keeps its hopes alive of making the World Cup finals for the first time since 2002 with a stunning comeback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0fecaa98eb474ea98596755ff77fd05</guid></item><item><title>When is the 2025 AFL draft? Here's your guide to bidding, trades and the official pick order</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/afl-draft-2025-everything-you-need-to-know-guide/106017028</link><description>Another AFL draft has arrived, offering dozens of teenage footballers the chance to realise their dreams. Here is everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95c3159204fc6f2fc50d5996c5f009b6</guid></item><item><title>From Blue Poles to Gina Rinehart, the most controversial artworks in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/controversial-artworks-australia/105984714</link><description>Art can stir strong feelings in people, both good and bad. These artworks fell in the latter, provoking great controversy in Australia, and telling us a lot about who we are as a nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2c66a5a1b1ff5afbc408c2410615cc7</guid></item><item><title>Sam Konstas picked to open for Prime Minister's XI against England in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/sam-konstas-picked-to-open-for-prime-minister-xi-england/106017212</link><description>Sam Konstas will return to the scene where he made his case for Test selection last summer, with the axed opener given a chance to face England with the Prime Minister's XI.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3473b1050834fe6d4191bbba1937ae0</guid></item><item><title>Paralympic gold medal winner Paige Greco dies, aged 28</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/paralympic-gold-medal-winner-paige-greco-dies-aged-28/106017286</link><description>Australian Paralympian Paige Greco, who won Australia's first gold medal of the 2020 Tokyo Paralympic Games, has died aged 28.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39fe1f64b531a269cb3986cf717522a6</guid></item><item><title>China's seafood import rules behind a partial closure of Tasmania's rock lobster fishery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/tasmania-rock-lobster-fishery-antibiotic-florfenicol-salmon/106016448</link><description>The Tasmanian government closed two zones within the state's rock lobster fishery just hours after the commercial season opened. The closure is in response to concerns about an antibiotic being used by salmon companies and the rock lobster industry's reputation in overseas markets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b69359e0def6b5ab9dacf255531f62d1</guid></item><item><title>Why the ACT has gone further than other jurisdictions in closing schools over coloured sand asbestos concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/why-the-act-has-closed-schools-over-asbestos-sand/106016514</link><description>The ACT has closed 70 schools over the coloured sand asbestos scare. Why is it the only jurisdiction to do so?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c01cfca034233367a3ea078fd54beb00</guid></item><item><title>Mackay Base Hospital expansion paused as contractor withdraws from site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/mackay-base-hospital-expansion-paused/106016520</link><description>Brisbane contractor BESIX Watpac will leave the Mackay Base Hospital construction site in Queensland as a report finds the cost of a 128-bed expansion has more than doubled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcec71f0845df5a45558dc3a585ca88d</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump calls on Republicans to vote to release Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/trump-calls-epstein-vote/106018036</link><description>President Donald Trump has called on his fellow Republicans in Congress to vote for the release of files related to the late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df4f580cc759e73761cec529a1b9db13</guid></item><item><title>Sharing COP presidency with Türkiye 'not an option', says Albanese</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/albanese-sharing-cop-presidency-with-turkiye-not-an-option/106017904</link><description>As Chris Bowen lands in Belém with the clock ticking on a resolution, Anthony Albanese says the rules against co-presidency for the COP are clear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9794fb3c53b4519304b21822dc905b0b</guid></item><item><title>Should I kick my diet soft-drink habit? Where do I start?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/should-i-kick-my-diet-soft-drink-habit-where-do-i-start-/106007994</link><description>You don't have to give up diet soft drinks altogether. But being mindful of how much soft drink you drink, and how often, can help you make healthier choices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8ad2c096503d0bd2d35b8a08f58567a</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese writes to states, telling them to rein in public hospital spending</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/anthony-albanese-tells-states-to-rein-in-hospital-spending/106017654</link><description>Health ministers are furious with a letter from the prime minister demanding they rein in spending if they want a public hospital funding deal honoured.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84ca8710050bda5c8532914dceb9e7e4</guid></item><item><title>Child poverty, homelessness hit new highs in mining-rich WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/child-poverty-homelessness-hit-new-high-in-mining-rich-wa/106017944</link><description>Rates of child poverty in WA have doubled in a decade, but there is a severe lack of crisis accommodation, prompting experts to call on governments to do more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">511b99517b8cf3509a543bf8f9c0bc75</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government denies dingoes could be kept as pets under contentious reclassification</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/dingo-reclassification-biosecurity-regulations-queensland/106000986</link><description>Queensland is considering changes that would remove restrictions on keeping dingoes and while the government says that will not mean people can keep them as pets, experts fear it could be an unintended outcome.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4338424fa0fdeae0ef247600ca95736</guid></item><item><title>Caroline Flack: Search for the Truth raises questions about assault charges and British tabloid ethics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/caroline-flack-documentary-revelations-media-police/106018362</link><description>In a two-part series, the mother of television presenter Caroline Flack examines the final months of her daughter's life and what she believes to be the mishandling of the criminal case against her daughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a12a6552a4b1f5a4fd8d1f21aa0b176</guid></item><item><title>Late Yolŋu leader Paul Gurrumuruwuy Wunungmurra honoured with PhD for anthropology, filmmaking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/paul-gurrumuruwuy-wunungmurra-phd-for-original-research/106013740</link><description>World-renowned anthropologist, filmmaker and Arnhem Land Indigenous leader Paul Gurrumuruwuy Wunungmurra has become the first Yolŋu person to be honoured for his work with a PhD for original research.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b19ee00b267d8622be272dec4ca318ee</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos sand contamination also affecting New Zealand, after 70 Australian schools close</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/asbestos-sand-contamination-new-zealand-school-closure/106017844</link><description>After asbestos was found in a range of coloured sand, early childhood centres and schools in Australia and New Zealand are hurrying to dispose of potentially contaminated products.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfa35953b42e65748b152a39baccd75a</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian private mental health service The Hobart Clinic reopens after 17-day closure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/tasmanian-mental-health-hospital-hobart-clinic-reopens/106016912</link><description>A $2 million transitional funding injection from the Tasmanian government has allowed The Hobart Clinic to treat patients for six more months while it comes up with a sustainable business model.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fddd37d2b51ab0986ed2914f7d3cf0b</guid></item><item><title>South African man who attended Neo-Nazi rally outside NSW parliament has visa cancelled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/verify-neo-nazi-rally-participant-visa-revoked/106018130</link><description>The federal government has revoked the visa of a man who attended the far-right National Socialist Network protest at NSW's parliament house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b76921ba7f888c119b8ec7bca1ab37b</guid></item><item><title>Australian beef producers welcome end to Donald Trump's import tariffs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/beef-producers-welcome-end-of-tariffs/106018228</link><description>Shoppers at home and abroad are unlikely to see any immediate change in the price of Australian beef as tariffs that did little to curb demand in the first place are lifted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c0295fa27b30c3d32c17b6c75d5199f</guid></item><item><title>Quick and easy summer dinners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/easy-healthy-summer-dinners/105822526</link><description>The busy end of year calls for simple dinners that are ready in 35 minutes or less.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c150e5b10f059167f94843c91f1d296</guid></item><item><title>Dozens of Canberra schools to reopen, 25 remain closed over coloured sand asbestos contamination concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/dozens-canberra-schools-remain-closed-coloured-sand-asbestos/106019038</link><description>Dozens of public schools in the ACT will reopen or partially open on Tuesday, but 25 remain closed for all students.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">403edecc55dd3b941ebf562588a5450e</guid></item><item><title>Black swan 'Jandal' released in Alice Springs after recovering from suspected dog attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/alice-springs-black-swan-released-after-dog-attack/105974208</link><description>An unlikely patient in Alice Springs is returned to the water treatment ponds two weeks after being found injured from a suspected dog attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ac67925c2602e1c59871b9efe0f6a00</guid></item><item><title>Monday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106018274</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98779dd691f5cd97ed5db0d8fb719e54</guid></item><item><title>Brendan Doggett poised for Test cricket debut in first Ashes Test against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/brendan-doggett-ashes-test-selection-perth/106020038</link><description>Fast bowler Brendan Doggett says he learned he could make a Test debut while waiting to bat in South Australia's Sheffield Shield run chase last week against Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8502ae382f2de6c019d1618216d6f0e</guid></item><item><title>Mary Fowler's resilience in face of mental health struggles hailed by Matildas coach Joe Montemurro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/mary-fowler-matildas-mental-health-joe-montemurro/106019580</link><description>Mary Fowler is unlikely to be back on the pitch with the Matildas until next year at the earliest, but coach Joe Montemurro is making sure to stay in close contact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4088e4edf783bb36f9dab8b7ce4f910a</guid></item><item><title>Several Tasmanian non-government schools closed, others partially closed due to coloured sand recall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/tasmanian-catholic-schools-shut-tuesday-coloured-sand-recall/106020206</link><description>At least six non-government schools have closed, and six others partially closed on Monday due to the national recall of coloured sand products over asbestos contamination, with others slated for closure on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fbea7ca273f5cb2f2e20576efc392e4</guid></item><item><title>Bangladesh's ousted PM Sheikh Hasina sentenced to death for student crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/bangladesh-pm-sheikh-hasina-sentenced-to-death/106020478</link><description>A Bangladesh court has sentenced ousted prime minister Sheikh Hasina to death after finding her guilty of crimes against humanity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">178548480ecd805a14632813c78b7a83</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley continues the fight for her political life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/sussan-ley-continues-the-fight-for-her-political-life-/106019804</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c707d4a679097a3d3d7d6e1cfb2ce90d</guid></item><item><title>Pat Cummins completes bowling session before first Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/pat-cummins-completes-bowling-session-before-first-ashes-test/106020424</link><description>Australia captain Pat Cummins completes a full bowling session at training just four days before the start of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7efacbc1a9c820d6f1197e4a721fbc1</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump’s “Epstein Files” problem</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/donald-trump-s-epstein-files-problem-/106019888</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1985385914dc64f39c8de5cbd9bebc3d</guid></item><item><title>Rio Tinto scraps $215m research centre and BioIron product after decade of development</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/rio-tinto-scraps-wa-green-steel-bioiron-product/106019692</link><description>Mining giant Rio Tinto scraps a $215 million research centre and green steel project touted last year as a key staging ground for the world's net zero transition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51ffe8af4b14a77380de2ca43c97d8d5</guid></item><item><title>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley guarantees she will remain leader until next election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-17/opposition-leader-sussan-ley-guarantees-leadership/106020032</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley may be under siege, but says she has no doubts she will remain party leader until the next federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f004c86a7822636864959b0d1b52cdaf</guid></item><item><title>Australian man Johnson Wen jailed after grabbing Ariana Grande at Wicked: For Good premiere</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/australian-jailed-for-grabbing-ariana-grande/106020466</link><description>Johnson Wen, who is alleged to have disrupted other global sports events and concerts, has shown "a pattern of behaviour", according to a Singapore court judge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecc3872a900d455284a7f911d5c0cae4</guid></item><item><title>BBC 'determined to fight' looming Trump lawsuit over speech edit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/bbc-says-it-will-defend-against-trump-lawsuit/106020752</link><description>The US president says he could sue the British national broadcaster for as much as $US5 billion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">535a31ce8ec0759c2495b4724c9dbbed</guid></item><item><title>Japan attempts to cool tensions with China as diplomatic spat over Taiwan continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/japan-moves-to-calm-tensions-with-china-over-taiwan-comments/106020928</link><description>Tokyo has sent a senior foreign ministry official to Beijing to try and ease tensions, that have seen threats made against Japan's prime minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d213f775764726d9b8161d108b5cb60</guid></item><item><title>At least 18 people killed in Indonesian landslides as rescue efforts continue to find more than 30 others missing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/indonesia-landslides-cilacap-banjarnegara-rescue-continues/106021038</link><description>Multiple landslides have engulfed communities in Central Java, with hundreds of emergency workers involved in the rescue operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">625a097599cde81c977cf6239b709a89</guid></item><item><title>The Ashes quiz: Test your knowledge ahead of the 2025/26 Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/the-ashes-quiz/105954056</link><description>Ahead of the 2025/26 Ashes series getting underway on November 21 in Perth, test out your knowledge in our fiendish Ashes quiz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c23d2aa29854277ae713a18dc1ce0f7</guid></item><item><title>What price power? How electricity became a political weapon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/how-electricity-became-a-political-weapon-in-australia/106017144</link><description>A decade and a half after an energy company CEO outlined his greatest fears for Australia's economic future — no carbon price — the nation again appears set for a renewed battle over climate policy and power generation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4345b97848a444c0296bfbc0178c05da</guid></item><item><title>Nirvana’s MTV Unplugged: How a near-disaster became an iconic live performance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/nirvana-mtv-unplugged-in-new-york-live-album-history-kurt-cobain/106004264</link><description>It was nearly a disaster, but Nirvana going acoustic for MTV ended up being one of the most iconic live performances ever and cemented Kurt Cobain as a tortured genius.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd684fbce58f9676f21b2f33b346196a</guid></item><item><title>Lost at sea: The harrowing hours of the deadliest Sydney to Hobart race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/sydney-to-hobart-1998-tragedy/105686076</link><description>The fleet of the 1998 Sydney to Hobart yacht race set sail from the harbour city, unaware they were travelling directly into the path of a huge storm and unrelenting swell that would throw the race into disarray and claim six lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2e3bc8203f33a6235d72740fa054717</guid></item><item><title>Renewable energy generators need to cut supply to stay sustainable. Here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/why-renewable-generators-need-to-cut-production-when-sun-is-up/105981004</link><description>When there is an oversupply of solar and wind power, energy producers are paying more to deliver electricity to households than they get paid. Here's what we know about how it affects you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">107c6c268ba2af68933ea4d9201c4b51</guid></item><item><title>Inside the AFL's infamous 2020 'COVID draft' as teams and players battled impacts of lockdowns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/afl-2020-covid-draft-feature-lockdowns-struggles/105993190</link><description>It is the AFL draft that has become a cautionary tale to clubs. Five years on from the infamous 2020 draft, here is the story on the tumultuous year from those involved in it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15222eb0ee497abf146d967106d5a525</guid></item><item><title>'Aussie Cossack' Simeon Boikov says staff at Russia's Sydney consulate are trying to push him out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/simeon-boikov-complains-of-conditions-in-sydney-russia-consulate/106019604</link><description>Simeon Boikov, the pro-Putin propagandist hiding from authorities in the Russian consulate in Sydney, launches an extraordinary attack on his hosts, saying they are subjecting him to "prison-like conditions" in a bid to "push me out".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f63e5782371fbc5228021a621c4d1df2</guid></item><item><title>The long road to the House of Representatives vote on the Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/what-we-know-about-the-vote-to-release-epstein-files/106017078</link><description>The US House of Representatives is poised to take a significant step in the mammoth saga of the so-called "Epstein files". Here's how we got there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5620839042534a3657f3a6b3a927719c</guid></item><item><title>Rio Tinto pauses plans for $3.7b lithium mine but Serbians remain concerned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/rio-tinto-jadar-valley-mine-paused-amid-huge-opposition/106020944</link><description>Rio Tinto may have mothballed its proposed $3.6 billion lithium project in Serbia's Jadar Valley, but opponents have vowed to keep fighting until the mining giant leaves the area for good.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d46a4bc7d782c94f6b5239ede5e86862</guid></item><item><title>Figures show areas with high Indigenous populations have more poker machines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/data-on-pokies-in-indigenous-communities/105999308</link><description>New figures show there are 50 per cent more pokies in areas with an Indigenous population of at least 10 per cent. Gambling groups say it is "not surprising".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60a1e17c594345399bcc01e64e02698d</guid></item><item><title>Queensland parents divided on recall of decorative sand over contamination concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/qld-asbestos-sand-parents-split-stressed-unbothered/106018662</link><description>While some Queensland parents are angered by the nationwide recall of coloured sand that may have traces of asbestos, others are less concerned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2fa2ba2d633edf7b85b57c60f73eeae</guid></item><item><title>Businesses urge Labor and Coalition to 'work together' on environmental reform</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/business-groups-epbc-work-together-on-environmental-reform/106020174</link><description>The next few days are viewed as critical to landing a deal on the proposed reforms to update the EPBC Act, amid hopes the Liberals will be more motivated to bolster their environmental credentials after ditching net zero.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">784e3f72a9fa1c34bf9f70ab2c8ac3e4</guid></item><item><title>Slain paramedic Steven Tougher's wife speaks out on mental health, a year after killer was detained</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/wife-slain-paramedic-steven-tougher-speaks-out-on-mental-health/106019350</link><description>One year after Steven Tougher's killer was found not criminally responsible due to mental impairment, his wife says she has learnt to accept it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22823b1bd9aa206012027d726db2131a</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian duo Beau Webster, Jake Weatherald vie for Ashes Test spot in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/tasmanian-duo-battle-one-ashes-test-spot-webster-weatherald/106021218</link><description>Teammates for Tasmania, Beau Webster and Jake Weatherald will be locked in a battle to play for Australia in the first Test of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8845419c1784350ec40f62288341cb6</guid></item><item><title>Alex Greenwich moves to fast track medicinal cannabis driving reforms in NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/nsw-alex-greenwich-medicinal-cannabis-driving-bill-motion/106019210</link><description>Independent Sydney MP Alex Greenwich says it is time to "get the ball rolling" on medical cannabis reforms in NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a5e88c6268a2b624857a0f619017fcb</guid></item><item><title>Landowner concerned about site rehabilitation as Murray Zircon shuts operations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/murray-zircon-mine-closed-with-promise-to-rehabilitate/105973222</link><description>A mine in South Australia's Murray Mallee is ceasing operations and says it will rehabilitate the site back to its original condition. However, the site's owner says the land will never get back to what it was before mining.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d676c8d6d8249e35ac4a7caeead00ae9</guid></item><item><title>Darebin asks AFL for lifeline as club faces financial pressure to stay in VFLW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/darebin-falcons-face-financial-pressure-vflw-aflw-vfl/105818748</link><description>Darebin nurtured AFLW stars Daisy Pearce and Darcy Vescio, but financial constraints could force the independent club out of the VFLW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">700f22852a6c9f923402cc61bdee9239</guid></item><item><title>Lleyton Hewitt's Davis Cup win over Rodger Federer saw off AFL switch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/lleyton-hewitt-afl-switch-halted-by-roger-federer-win/106021256</link><description>An epic Davis Cup win over Roger Federer in 2003 convinced Australian tennis great Lleyton Hewitt to not go ahead with a stunning career change. Two-time grand slam champion Hewitt is one of seven inductees into the Sport Australia Hall of Fame.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6739ec89ad2b2b91e1e11afaa081385</guid></item><item><title>TPG Telecom says Sydney person died after outdated phone software blocked Triple Zero calls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/nsw-tpg-telecom-sydney-person-samsumg-triple-0-death/106021692</link><description>TPG Telecom says a Sydney customer died after outdated software blocked a Samsung phone from making Triple Zero calls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dea78879d3540ec8b0cbd886a458d35</guid></item><item><title>Emotional scenes at Moss Vale site hearing over proposed plastics factory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/moss-vale-site-hearing-over-proposed-plastics-factory/106019648</link><description>Normally confined to four walls, the Land and Environment Court holds a site hearing in the NSW Southern Highlands to hear residents' concerns about a proposed recycling plant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abec674d125082e6230833490d7485b7</guid></item><item><title>When is the ARIAs awards ceremony? Where can I watch it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/arias-australian-music-awards-where-to-watch/105995312</link><description>The Australian music industry awards will be celebrating some of the best acts in the country this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07890810d76bc99b56d9f7bcd6df57e4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says he will sign bill to release Epstein files if it passes Congress</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/donald-trump-would-sign-jeffrey-epstein-files-bill/106021282</link><description>The bill — to direct the US Justice Department to release its documents about late sex offender Jeffrey Epstein — now looks set to sail through the House of Representatives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64ce961156f1d882a2423edba210e6b1</guid></item><item><title>Coloured sand is being disposed of across the country due to asbestos contamination concerns. How much risk does it actually pose?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/type-asbestos-found-coloured-sand-schools-closed-act-sa-tasmania/106021238</link><description>Dozens of schools remain closed in the ACT, Tasmania and South Australia today as the clean-up and disposal of potentially asbestos-laced coloured sand continues. What risk does it actually pose?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f754e246024da0a3576ac2c3c64e511</guid></item><item><title>Jake Paul and Anthony Joshua's boxing match is a dangerous betrayal of the sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/jake-paul-vs-anthony-joshua-boxing-match-netflix/106021412</link><description>Nobody plays at boxing. But Jake Paul's upcoming contest against a bona fide, former two-time unified heavyweight champion of the world smacks of a game about to go seriously wrong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">236aee0df8d9b848b87e56b1ef80d128</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos scare widens as more than 350 SA schools detect recalled sand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/hundreds-of-sa-schools-detect-sand-linked-to-asbestos-scare/106021664</link><description>The number of public education sites in South Australia that have reported coloured sand linked to an asbestos contamination scare rises above 350, but authorities say there is no plan for closures at this stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ec8f43cdaf64676c821b8f00d82ea1d</guid></item><item><title>More schools reopen in Canberra on Wednesday as coloured sand clean-up continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/schools-still-closed-in-canberra-as-coloured-sand-clean-up/106022660</link><description>More schools have reopened in Canberra, with a list of current closures to be updated today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22858175e2a35e1652224ec2c9370bd6</guid></item><item><title>AFL draft 2025 club by club preview: Your team's picks and potential targets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/afl-draft-2025-club-by-club-preview/105992174</link><description>With the AFL draft just around the corner, see which picks each club has to work with and the players they could select.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dd86e4ed42dd2930cabb8c36b4aff59</guid></item><item><title>Cyclists, pedestrians diverted to Causeway amid closure of Boorloo Bridge in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/boorloo-bridge-closed-after-lightning-cable-incident/106022532</link><description>The Boorloo Bridge, which connects Perth's inner southern suburbs with the CBD, will remain closed until Thursday after lighting fell from the structure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33afea7dbfe9de316a0fe32f604c2748</guid></item><item><title>Category two cyclone predicted off NT coast by Thursday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/tropical-low-cyclone-nt-bureau-of-meteorology-/106023036</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology has issued its first forecast track map for a tropical low over the NT, showing the system is expected to strengthen into a category two cyclone by Thursday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a6c322a2a62ea9ae943397610bd552c</guid></item><item><title>Health expert, football pioneer, historian, and mental health advocate honoured as ACT Australians of the Year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/act-australian-of-year-awards-rose-mcgready-doctor/106021788</link><description>This year's ACT Australian of the Year honours go to a refugee health expert, football pioneer, historical guide and mental health advocate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df23b23feb221b8508b77f67e9640fad</guid></item><item><title>Sikh communities celebrate Gurmesh Singh's election as NSW Nationals leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/gurmesh-singh-elected-nsw-nationals-leader/106021864</link><description>Gurmesh Singh's election as the new leader of the NSW Nationals is being hailed as great news for Indian Sikh communities across the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c453b829f562c9122b477bb188597ca8</guid></item><item><title>The Australian music groups celebrating major milestone anniversaries in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/australian-music-groups-major-milestones-2025/105999894</link><description>Improvising with headlights, a sold-out debut and championing new music are some of the impacts these Australian music groups have made in their decades-long existence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">645e25ee987fda0c6bf4553d7cd6f8f6</guid></item><item><title>Gippsland's Willem Duursma set to become fourth family member to join AFL/AFLW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/willem-duursma-tipped-for-top-afl-national-draft-pick-west-coast/105999938</link><description>Willem Duursma's dancing feet could carry him all the way to the number-one pick at tomorrow night's AFL National Draft.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc905c920ae77b121913d5fcd4067338</guid></item><item><title>Eli Katoa to miss 2026 NRL season after Melbourne Storm star's brain surgery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/eli-katoa-to-miss-2026-nrl-season/106024440</link><description>Melbourne Storm star Eli Katoa will miss the 2026 NRL season as he continues his recovery from head knocks that forced him to have brain surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5232341e3582eed41e32b4e562d739c</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu council repeals law banning menstruating women from selling food</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/vanuatu-menstruating-women-ban-selling-food-markets/106017328</link><description>A Vanuatu provincial government says it will repeal parts of its new bylaw banning menstruating women from preparing and selling food at markets and roadside stalls after the decision sparked a public outcry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">034f538d5d412c8217577c70505f422b</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos contamination of children's sand was a fluke discovery in an Australian lab</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/asbestos-sand-contamination-chance-discovery-in-australian-lab/106022486</link><description>An Australian lab discovered asbestos in children's play sand by chance and regulators only found out about it because of a podcast interview, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62364137d29d39242b79167919e508a9</guid></item><item><title>Inside The Hood Contender, Australia's controversial amateur fighting competition trying to save men's lives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/inside-the-hood-contender-controversial-amateur-fighting/106006086</link><description>The organiser of this fight club says it saves lives. But critics say it is putting young men at serious risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72aefa26eb296ef6083bcca281a4094a</guid></item><item><title>CSIRO to cut up to 350 research jobs in major overhaul</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/csiro-cuts-350-research-jobs/106024498</link><description>After 440 positions were slashed last year, the CSIRO has announced more staff cuts across the country in a bid to remain financially viable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0416ad87616bb5deb09ddba2a6777aae</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Lions recruit Neasa Dooley wanting to add more Irish success in AFLW preliminary final against Carlton Blues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/neasa-dooley-brisbane-lions-aflw-preliminary-final-carlton/106024288</link><description>No stranger to the big stage, Brisbane's Neasa Dooley wants a piece of what her fellow Irish imports have been selling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b39d76b6c1f3e81e97d4b65690c26dad</guid></item><item><title>What it's like being a male early childhood educator amid the childcare crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/what-it-is-like-being-a-male-educator-amid-the-childcare-crisis/105995392</link><description>While the childcare crisis has left me concerned about my own child's safety, as a male early childhood educator, I'm also worried about the future of men in the sector, writes Ben.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a62aba2abcb529305bf54887ade96ce5</guid></item><item><title>Parents in 'childcare desert' left scrambling as Playtime Preschool enters voluntary administration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/playtime-preschool-broken-hill-enters-voluntary-administration/106021714</link><description>One of the few childcare operators in Broken Hill has closed its doors indefinitely with 24 hours warning after entering voluntary administration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">645912bd0d8354ef6ba596b69e3361b2</guid></item><item><title>Defence inspector inadvertently omitted 10 consultations held with NACC chief Paul Brereton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/defence-inspector-omitted-consultations-with-nacc-chief/106023634</link><description>A previous disclosure that the head of the federal corruption watchdog had been consulted 11 times has been corrected to 21.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1781d5607362739f541e7ff802db05f6</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Liberals' first female leader Jess Wilson must prove the party is worth fighting for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/jess-wilson-victorian-liberal-leadership-spill-analysis/106024016</link><description>Victoria's first female Liberal Party leader is facing a gargantuan task to unite her party and prove the opposition is worth voting for, Richard Willingham writes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4938f4f27a6b73a13b48845792efb884</guid></item><item><title>BlueScope AGM held in shadow of Port Kembla steelworks fatality, minute’s silence held</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/bluescope-agm-fatality-whyalla-gas/106023286</link><description>Shareholders and executives observe a minute's silence at BlueScope's AGM for the young worker killed at Port Kembla steelworks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">145511701e866a9689d26c9f84090755</guid></item><item><title>Sydney waste water likely origin of debris on Central Coast beaches</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/beach-greaseballs-likely-from-sydney-waste-water-system/106022634</link><description>Sydney Water is working to determine the source of high levels of grease and oil that caused debris balls to wash up on beaches across Sydney and the Central Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c33b5671c318dc726c5b28ea01fd417</guid></item><item><title>COP30 decision by South Korea to shut down coal a reckoning for Australian exports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/south-korea-coal-plant-closure-warning-on-australian-exports/106021660</link><description>In a move that has been welcomed by climate campaigners, South Korea has vowed to phase out coal, sparking a warning for Australian exporters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a1e49f91f32ca80234fe2254283c60c</guid></item><item><title>Numerous Tasmanian public, Catholic and independent schools to close from Wednesday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/catholic-public-independent-tasmanian-schools-closed-asbestos/106022702</link><description>More than 50 Tasmanian schools will either close or be partially closed from Wednesday in response to ongoing public health concerns relating to asbestos in coloured sand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f7a4638311fad228f17b1ee6e4650f</guid></item><item><title>Remote Aboriginal community of Tjuntjuntjara challenges local government election result</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/tjuntjuntjara-election-dispute/106019700</link><description>A remote Aboriginal corporation lodges a formal dispute over the outcome of a local government election decided by just one vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9ca57d6c316de3bf92b08f85b9f4912</guid></item><item><title>Senator Fatima Payman calls on prime minister to denounce online trolls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/senator-fatima-payman-calls-on-pm-to-denounce-online-trolls/106024908</link><description>After the man who threatened her life via email was sentenced in court earlier this week, Senator Fatima Payman is being targeted by online abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2ebeb36f39a44d81191de3588d46754</guid></item><item><title>Most restrictive abortion bill in the US being considered</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/most-restrictive-abortion-bill-in-the-us-being-considered/106024856</link><description>Restrictions on IUDs and IVF and decades of imprisonment for having an abortion could become the reality for some women living in South Carolina if the legislation passes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ef3cb80551fe490d0f6301954d7ffb7</guid></item><item><title>Coalition leadership turmoil in Australia’s two most populous states</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/coalition-leadership-turnmoil/106025098</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79ec9dc482d3a096f642b6313bd088fd</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos contamination identified in imported coloured sand products</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/asbestos-contamination-identified-/106025112</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45782c7e825f6e9ae891619789b5b041</guid></item><item><title>Are tiger prawns labelled as being Australian, really from Australia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/are-your-australian-tiger-prawns-really-from-australia-/106025136</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b04250e60ba47b3ca2f1c4c23e21254</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese heralds WA gallium project as 'game changing'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/anthony-albanese-hails-wa-role-in-us-critical-minerals-deal/106024178</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese visits the future West Australian gallium processing plant site, central to the United States critical minerals deal, heralding it as a "game changing" project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c597633a766fbe2ac505dfff6094f877</guid></item><item><title>Public hospitals wasting $1.2b a year and hindered by 'bogus budgets', Grattan Institute says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-18/public-hospital-wastage-grattan-institute-report/106019006</link><description>A new report recommends Australia’s public hospitals stop wasting money and adopt efficiency measures seen in other countries amid governmental tensions over a new funding deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fb764f3d78d4b1ae4ff6ec601222e32</guid></item><item><title>Poland says Russian intelligence likely behind railway sabotage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/poland-says-russian-intelligence-likely-behind-railway-sabotage/106025554</link><description>Polish authorities say "everything indicates" Russian involvement in a blast along a railway line used to transport goods to Ukraine, as they identify two people believed to be responsible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa547069580b98e715786b936d0c32b1</guid></item><item><title>Britain's MI5 spy service issues alert to MPs over Chinese espionage threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/britain-s-mi5-spy-service-warns-lawmakers-of-chinese-spy-risk/106025666</link><description>MI5 has warned that Chinese agents attempt to collect information and influence activity, posing the latest spy threat to the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbfe6d820186bd439b3183c99fa6d171</guid></item><item><title>Japan warns citizens in China to be careful as diplomatic spat continues over Taiwan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/japan-warns-citizens-in-china-as-diplomatic-spat-continues/106025668</link><description>Authorities have told Japanese people in China to avoid large crowds, as tensions between Tokyo and Beijing continue to simmer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56948e21a448507e1c8128eabd1d690a</guid></item><item><title>Roblox promises age checks as Australia's under-16 social media ban looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/roblox-brings-in-age-checks-ahead-of-australian-ban/106025742</link><description>The company says age verification checks will start in early December, around the same time Australia's social media ban for under-16s is set to come into effect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddb9f39ecaa26e3689373df8bfc33f0a</guid></item><item><title>Jess Wilson is the Victorian Liberals’ survival strategy. Are federal Liberals listening?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/victoria-liberal-party-gamble-jess-wilson-survival-federal/106024478</link><description>The Liberals in two big Australian states are realigning themselves — shifting to what Sussan Ley once described as the sensible centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b848213f89e676a20bde80e4634f44e</guid></item><item><title>How the Nintendo Wii's remote control changed gaming — one strike at a time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/nintendo-wii-release-anniversary/105971384</link><description>Innovative motion controls and accessible design made the Nintendo Wii one of the most popular consoles of all time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed1b3832f564dd508a1196eea55005ce</guid></item><item><title>Booker Prize quiz: Test your knowledge of the prestigious book award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/booker-prize-2025-quiz/105950622</link><description>The prestigious Booker Prize, worth $100,000, announced its 2025 winner last week. Do you remember who won? Test your knowledge of the world's favourite book awards with our quiz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">744594b38b052e94f8b8562ab648c256</guid></item><item><title>Dud superannuation options could cost retirees up to $205,000, Super Consumers warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/super-consumers-performance-warning-retirees-after-retirement/106021954</link><description>Superannuation products that fail the federal government's performance test are still offered to those already retired at a potentially huge cost, according to the consumer advocate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">734cd2c9adc2e984c8b09e16b7bc5f50</guid></item><item><title>Australia's weapons programs exposed in defence industry cyber attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/defence-cyber-attacks-adf-military-projects-redback-hackers/105999222</link><description>Information relating to Australian military programs has been compromised in cyber attacks on defence industry contractors, exposing security vulnerabilities along supply chains.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c4323b865cb7b2f9705f053f1dd1693</guid></item><item><title>Industry experts say TPG Telecom should have done more to address Triple Zero issue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/tpg-telecom-contact-customers-triple-zero-death/106022250</link><description>There are growing questions about whether one of Australia's largest telcos could have done more to ensure customers would be able to call Triple Zero.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c43bd54bc8b0f41677f4d307b5e3cc5b</guid></item><item><title>As Donald Trump's plan for Gaza gets UN approval, development proposals are circulating</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/rebuilding-gaza-donald-trump-plan-investment-potential/106006900</link><description>As Donald Trump's plan for Gaza gets UN approval, the proposals for how the territory might be developed are circulating and advocates are worried about who they ultimately benefit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebb4457531a367904752bce1bd7c9a88</guid></item><item><title>How often should you pay your mortgage to save?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/mortgage-repayments-frequency-fortnightly-or-monthly/105996588</link><description>Switching to fortnightly repayments from monthly — if you can afford it — can help you pay down your mortgage faster. Here’s why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6f78dfdd43c67b57f8f07db843eb41b</guid></item><item><title>Trainers of Melbourne and Caulfield Cup winner, Half Yours, welcomed home to Streaky Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/streaky-bay-mcevoy-melbourne-cup-half-yours-horse-racing-sa/106018384</link><description>Horse trainer Tony McEvoy returned to his hometown of Streaky Bay, on South Australia's west coast, with trophies in tow after his horse Half Yours' recent wins at the Caulfield and Melbourne cups.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c15e256c04df4da3fe3d8663c7da3931</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of power poles wrapped in protective mesh ahead of 'what could be a dangerous bushfire summer'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/power-poles-wrapped-fire-resistant-mesh-bushfires/106015438</link><description>A fire-resistant mesh is being used to protect thousands of wooden power poles from bushfires across the NSW Central Coast and Hunter regions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20ee7810140cad6a6c4dbd4849a91ace</guid></item><item><title>ACCC traces some coloured asbestos sand to 'a particular quarry in China'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/coloured-sand-with-asbestos-traced-to-china-quarry/106024514</link><description>Some of the coloured sand found to contain asbestos has been traced to a quarry in China, according to the ACCC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bd4812eb24af1cb61c507559c41dc9d</guid></item><item><title>US politics: Congress agrees to force release of Epstein files and paves way for Trump sign-off — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/blog-congress-to-vote-on-release-of-epstein-files/106017700</link><description>Both houses of the US Congress have agreed to force Justice officials to release documents relating to the investigation into convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein. Look back on the day's events here.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be2ca4287ee5d7258f85d4005953a1ae</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files have 'ripped MAGA apart', says Marjorie Taylor Greene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/epstein-files-have-ripped-maga-apart-marjorie-taylor-greene/106025808</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a4e24a33b857d44e1295b1b7e99425</guid></item><item><title>Family of missing schoolboy Terry Floyd accuse government of breaking promise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/family-of-terry-floyd-accuses-government-of-breaking-promise/106024176</link><description>The brother of schoolboy Terry Floyd, who disappeared 50 years ago, has accused the Victorian government of breaking its public promise to fund the search for his remains.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edc7716e2290375f31b58757b011a642</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos sand contamination leaves families seeking clearer house cleaning, disposal guidance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/safely-clean-homes-sand-recall-australia/106022792</link><description>One Queensland grandmother says her daughter had vacuumed, and even replaced her vacuum cleaner, after removing the asbestos-contaminated sand following "confusing" advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf0f5c8480339c7e164cc723d6544c74</guid></item><item><title>Financial crimes regulator refers 45 suspected paedophiles following payment industry crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/child-sexual-exploitation-crackdown-online-payments-austrac/106018652</link><description>A crackdown on online payment services reveals "multiple examples of high-risk customers", as the Australian regulator orders a global company to appoint an external auditor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4e020847c50eb9b9475e112e1438ab1</guid></item><item><title>US Senate passes bill to release Epstein files in win for defiant Republicans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/epstein-files-bill-passes-us-congress/106023130</link><description>The bill's passage marks a major win for a small group of Republicans who defied pressure from the Trump White House to drop their crusade for the release of the Epstein files..</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d8a9ed2bd40d382bfe0031c7709ed40</guid></item><item><title>England's Joe Root backed to make first Ashes Test century in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/ashes-cricket-england-australia-joe-root-first-test-perth/106025838</link><description>With the first Ashes clash only two days away, Joe Root's England teammates are unfazed by the fact he has not scored a Test century in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a56c37032f0d2b050fb2a8565664b59</guid></item><item><title>The AFL draft might be broken for the league's biggest strugglers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/the-afl-draft-might-be-broken-for-leagues-strugglers/106011254</link><description>The AFL draft is more complicated and compromised than ever before, meaning clubs rebuilding from the bottom of the ladder are doing so with one arm tied behind their backs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b049c7cc8c0729242481a853525bc9b3</guid></item><item><title>Moment: US House of Representatives passes bill to release Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/passes-bill-to-release-epstein-files/106025874</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6a6bc0dcf9fd188a4e9d0ca9f60237d</guid></item><item><title>Understanding ADHD symptoms such as RSD, hyper-focus, task paralysis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/adhd-symptoms-signs-rsd-task-paralysis-hyper-focus-mental-health/104803078</link><description>Some people refer to attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder as "a superpower" while others describe their ADHD symptoms as debilitating. Can both be true?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f5dc0dc0e577bb893421a05d4dcc8d9</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: ABC MD delivers first speech at press club outlining vision for the broadcaster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/federal-politics-live-blog-nov-19/106024456</link><description>The ABC's managing director Hugh Marks is outlining his vision for the public broadcaster in his first address to the National Press Club. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca2aa89e48adac5073acce14b5a3d2a0</guid></item><item><title>Is Victoria about to run out of gas and what does that mean for your hip pocket?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/victorias-gas-supply-and-shortage-explained/105999652</link><description>Victoria produces more gas than it uses, so how is the state on the verge of a gas shortfall?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d6f2f7cab6b49b5eb1ecb87007305e6</guid></item><item><title>David Pocock says CSIRO's proposal to cut 350 jobs is 'incredibly disappointing'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/david-pocock-says-csiro-s-proposal-to-cut-350-jobs-is-/106025902</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73e7b697cb0c827cf07569ead72dad73</guid></item><item><title>ABC host Sharnelle Vella expecting a baby after fertility struggle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/abc-presenter-sharnelle-vella-pregnant-ivf-struggles/106023456</link><description>The ABC Radio Melbourne breakfast co-host and her husband say they are overjoyed but terrified as they prepare for the birth of their baby girl in March.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd8fbc9127dd022b28d103cbdade634e</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies star Joseph-Aukuso Suaalii in contention for prestigious World Rugby award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/wallabies-joseph-aukuso-suaalii-nominated-for-world-rugby-award/106025892</link><description>Wallabies outside centre Joseph-Aukuso Suaalii is recognised for his performances since switching codes from rugby league late last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75eb964d2b6306bc3f841f2b522ed648</guid></item><item><title>Workers made redundant at Gippsland sawmill weeks from Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/yarram-sawmill-to-close-timber-shutdown-gippsland/105904140</link><description>A Gippsland sawmill owned by Australia's largest softwood producer is set to shut immediately, with more than 70 jobs lost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20e608a0e0a4e0e34719c3a581e47730</guid></item><item><title>Markets live: 'Little prospect of rate relief' following wages data release</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/asx-markets-business-live-news/106025882</link><description>ABS figures show workers received an average base pay increase of 3.4 per cent over the year to September, in line with the previous quarter and economist forecasts. Webjet shares soar after a takeover offer from rival Helloworld. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83fdeab36f891d1ab8b747278d6317f7</guid></item><item><title>As autism diagnoses rise, experts caution against 'non-evidenced treatments'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/caution-over-oxygen-therapy-as-autism-treatment/106019362</link><description>Experts warn against signing up for autism therapies that are not evidence-based, as diagnoses rise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d6fcccbaf2f52bbf378787f7c54bf00</guid></item><item><title>NSW government to bring in tougher laws to combat public displays of Nazi ideology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/nsw-government-nazi-laws-amendment-parliament-rally/106025436</link><description>Police and courts will be given greater powers to combat public displays of Nazi ideology in NSW following a rally outside state parliament earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47706493835ce08f5a7f9523a999135f</guid></item><item><title>Mechelle Turvey leads calls for more Indigenous community liaison officers in WA Police Force</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/call-for-more-indigenous-community-liaison-officers-in-wa/106010684</link><description>Cassius Turvey's mother Mechelle is leading the call for WA Police to hire more Indigenous community liaison officers, saying just 20 officers to serve the entire state was nowhere near enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd1c8df65d5719800a3d0daad43de243</guid></item><item><title>Stephanie Gilmore announces World Surf League Championship Tour comeback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/surfing-australia-stephanie-gilmore-announces-wsl-comeback/106025994</link><description>Two years after stepping away from the tour, Australian surfing legend Stephanie Gilmore will make her return in 2026 after being awarded a season wildcard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">191d6532923bf7bc7499f3b4cb9f69bf</guid></item><item><title>Watch alert issued for NT communities as Tropical Cyclone Fina intensifies east of Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/cyclone-fina-forms-off-darwin-coast-landfall-expected-saturday/106025980</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology has issued a cyclone watch alert for communities in north-west Arnhem Land and the Tiwi Islands as Tropical Cyclone Fina intensifies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d355cfd1efe70b08c2bffb8b96cd0f87</guid></item><item><title>West Coast's rebuild is at a critical juncture. This draft could make or break it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/west-coast-eagles-2025-afl-draft-preview/105866808</link><description>The worst performing team in the AFL has a bumper hand in this year's national draft. How it uses it will shape the club's fortunes for the next decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da644df515da05cd845c47dbe806b5f4</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump insists visiting Saudi crown prince knew nothing about Jamal Khashoggi killing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/donald-trump-defends-mohammed-bin-salman-jamal-khashoggi-killing/106025864</link><description>US President Donald Trump warmly welcomes the Saudi crown prince to the White House where he deflects journalists' questions about Mohammed bin Salman's role in the killing of reporter Jamal Khashoggi, saying: "Things happened, but he knew nothing about it."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2635a8708158f7659bb93c0b10e90738</guid></item><item><title>Legislation to stop councils rating some mining land passes lower house of parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/miscellaneous-rate-local-government-reform-bankrupt-mount-magnet/106019936</link><description>The Mount Magnet shire says its reserves would shrink from $3 million to $300,000 if a bill to block shires from rating certain mining land is passed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">215fea21433337ed7027887199ccecf3</guid></item><item><title>What are the chances of a cyclone hitting Darwin and the NT coast this week?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/what-are-the-chances-of-cyclone-hitting-darwin-nt/106022656</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says Tropical Cyclone Fina has formed off the NT coast. Here's what you need to know to prepare.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f11991b1f7acff3196057908837034f5</guid></item><item><title>How to watch the 2025 AFL draft and what time does the coverage begin?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/afl-draft-2025-how-to-watch-and-what-time-does-it-start/106026096</link><description>Another AFL draft has arrived, offering dozens of teenage footballers the chance to realise their dreams. Here is everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16bb0a1d8942d9c358894ebf311bd860</guid></item><item><title>Trump defends Saudi crown prince at Washington talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/trump-defends-saudi-crown-prince-at-washington-talks/106026110</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d05262cc217e7f8b3724d79edd5c2ce8</guid></item><item><title>Carlos Alcaraz withdraws from Spain's Davis Cup Finals campaign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/davis-cup-finals-carlos-alcaraz-pulls-out-of-spain-campaign/106026144</link><description>Just days after going down to Jannik Sinner in the ATP Finals decider, world number one Carlos Alcaraz is forced to pull out of Spain's Davis Cup campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58bfba26ee9d97cc72b3617f6853d27e</guid></item><item><title>Game designed to save dying Aboriginal language wins global awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/aboriginal-language-game-wins-global-award/105975448</link><description>With only eight fluent Nyiyaparli speakers remaining, an Aboriginal group is racing against time to save their 41,000-year-old language.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ae26c1d700be95bac9b13ea5fb11781</guid></item><item><title>Jess Wilson faces climate change grilling on first day as Victorian Liberal leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/victoria-liberals-jess-wilson-first-day/106025500</link><description>Jess Wilson has faced questions over whether her party will embrace different policies on net zero emissions from the federal Liberal Party, which dumped its commitment last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56b8a015402daf726597c2a731b0f7fe</guid></item><item><title>US Senate approves Epstein file release unanimously</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/us-senate-approves-epstein-file-release-unanimously-/106026758</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcca0c46442e2bbbd9cbede7af07d0d6</guid></item><item><title>Tongans are heading to the polls for just the fifth time. Is their young democracy on the line?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/tonga-election-king-democracy-noble-votes/106022830</link><description>Tongans are heading to the polls this week amid concerns that democratic reforms in the country could be short-lived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90d8fec4a58c871d7b2f35edf9dfb0a4</guid></item><item><title>Scotland defeats Denmark 4-2 to qualify for World Cup finals after stunning goal by Scott McTominay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/fifa-world-cup-scotland-beat-denmark-scott-mctominay/106026514</link><description>A breathtaking goal from Scott McTominay paves the way for Scotland to qualify for the World Cup finals after a 28-year absence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3d2b6eb3ace5d406a2886b25849f494</guid></item><item><title>Israeli air strike on a Palestinian refugee camp in Lebanon has killed 13 people, Lebanese ministry says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/israel-strike-palestinian-refugee-camp/106026280</link><description>It was the deadliest strike on Lebanon since a ceasefire in the Israel-Hezbollah war a year ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69b213869d4ad1126549bd9e9b5b98e4</guid></item><item><title>Queensland men's shed still without a home after being evicted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/queensland-men-s-shed-still-without-a-home-after-being-evicted/106023830</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3f9f734879d268bdc1fc324227a3d2d</guid></item><item><title>Gympie Men's Shed in desperate search for a new home after being shown the door</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/gympie-mens-shed-in-desperate-search-for-new-home/106009024</link><description>The future of the Gympie Men's Shed is in doubt as the search for a new home continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e3605246f5235460c0080ef04ffda59</guid></item><item><title>How should you safely dispose of coloured sand products?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/how-to-dispose-coloured-sand/106027052</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29cd55b452be0821473be4088cd73a8c</guid></item><item><title>Epstein survivor pays tribute to Virginia Roberts Giuffre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/epstein-survivor-pays-tribute-to-virginia-giuffre-/106027126</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2716cc7f14ed07dacf134e77da051f52</guid></item><item><title>Wage growth remains steady at 3.4 per cent, just ahead of inflation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/abs-wage-price-index-figures-released-september-quarter/106026360</link><description>ABS figures show workers received a real pay increase over the past year, but economists warn that is likely to flip over coming months as inflation increases and wages growth slows further.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa8b6d1a5ef5c8da2d52578e7c5b0421</guid></item><item><title>US agrees to $US1bn loan to restart Three Mile Island nuclear power plant</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/three-mile-island-nuclear-power-plant-constellation-energy/106026820</link><description>Once the site of the worst commercial nuclear power accident in the US, Pennsylvania's Three Mile Island will again start producing electricity after the Department of Energy agreed to a $US1 billion ($1.5 billion) loan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a964b9e2fd0db5973449b1a5c84d0133</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos continue World Cup preparation with friendly against Colombia in New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/socceroos-vs-colombia-new-york-live-blog/106026972</link><description>After falling to a meek 1-0 loss to Venezuela on Saturday, the Socceroos will be looking for an improved performance against Colombia in New York. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7d3fc982270b2839d0e5643620424f0</guid></item><item><title>Now that US Congress has voted to release the 'Jeffrey Epstein files', here's what happens next</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/where-does-the-jeffrey-epstein-files-bill-go-from-here/106023134</link><description>The Epstein Files Transparency Act sailed through both the US House of Representatives and the Senate in a single Washington afternoon. Here is how we got here, and what could happen next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">983bc3fe7484c4765b07d5ee8bbedb7b</guid></item><item><title>Boy charged over fatal Sunshine Coast e-bike crash that killed 8yo child</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/boy-charged-over-fatal-sunshine-coast-ebike-crash/106027202</link><description>The boy has been charged with dangerous operation of a vehicle causing death, unlicensed driving, and driving an unregistered and uninsured vehicle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9cbf98e4fb7542d15def9a11daa4140</guid></item><item><title>Through dust and drought, these women are redefining resilience</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/through-dust-and-drought-these-women-are-redefining-resilience/106024268</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15ec73793bc09515a28939cf16fbf8df</guid></item><item><title>CSIRO chief defends job cuts amid fears for growth of scientific research in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/fears-for-science-as-csiro-chief-defends-job-cuts/106026314</link><description>The chief executive of the CSIRO has defended the decision to cut hundreds of jobs, arguing the organisation needs to alter its priorities to remain relevant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82d9f1d97e9e5256286575cb1f965897</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the Cloudflare outage that impacted X and ChatGPT</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/cloudflare-outage-x-chatgpt/106026070</link><description>Cloudflare says it has fully restored services after a "latent bug" sent major platforms including X and ChatGPT into a tailspin. Here's what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bff3b726989176d00d9c34ae93799137</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide University co-vice chancellors share complexities of uni merger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/sa-adelaide-university-co-vice-chancellors-on-uni-merger/106022624</link><description>The co-vice chancellors of the new Adelaide University says the mammoth task of merging two universities has its own complexities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb603c46b9a5c5d629e8740bb5354491</guid></item><item><title>SA education minister calls for urgent national inquiry as asbestos sand sites climb to more than 450</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/sa-minister-calls-for-urgent-national-inquiry-into-asbestos-sand/106026188</link><description>South Australia's education chief has called for a national inquiry into how coloured play sand contaminated with asbestos was imported into the country, with more than 450 Department for Education sites now impacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">325123170c9d15d9ae9fab868a3931a8</guid></item><item><title>'Dignifying of an ordinary life': Joel Edgerton on his new film Train Dreams</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/the-cast-of-train-dreams-on-their-new-neo-western-movie/106027360</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee330bd692f804b4eb4af401ac9bb821</guid></item><item><title>John Laws funeral live: Radio titan farewelled by friends and family at Sydney cathedral</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/nsw-john-laws-state-funeral-sydney-live/106026460</link><description>Family, friends and long-time listeners of the late radio broadcaster John Laws are gathering at Sydney's St Andrew's Cathedral for his state funeral.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75d558fd3e4921be161f000304eedb52</guid></item><item><title>Cristiano Ronaldo attends White House with Donald Trump and Saudi crown prince</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-19/cristiano-ronaldo-attends-white-house-dinner-with-trump/106026916</link><description>The US president says he introduced his youngest son, Barron, to the soccer player, adding that his son was impressed with the meeting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61950b0a73edf998391be27650fdcefb</guid></item></channel></rss>