<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 16:16:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Police investigate alleged sexual assault of boy in Adelaide park toilet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/police-investigate-sexual-assault-of-boy-at-flagstaff-hill/106294376</link><description>Police say a teenage boy was sexually assaulted at a toilet block in Adelaide's south on Saturday by another young male who had asked for help to "look for his lost mobile phone".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">abbcd6c5b67780d0e36db7a2cd29e70a</guid></item><item><title>Bad Bunny makes Grammys history with Album of the Year win — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/68th-grammy-awards-live-updates-winners/106288902</link><description>Debí Tirar Más Fotos is the first Spanish-language record to win Album of the Year at the Grammy awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a88755bbc9bfeab625c4992dd0387c0</guid></item><item><title>2026 Grammy Awards red carpet: Sabrina Carpenter, Olivia Dean arrive in style for the ceremony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/grammys-2026-red-carpet-fashion/106294278</link><description>The best and most memorable red carpet looks at the 68th Annual Grammy Awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">daeb2fcb28fae6863657b83025630e93</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, February 2: Balto and the dogs of 1925's Great Serum Run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/today-in-history-february-2-balto-nome-serum-run-of-1925/106200774</link><description>Children of an icebound Alaskan town were dying. The journey to save them would be treacherous, freezing, and in these dogs' paws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee0becf2af32bee92f962dde0284bfce</guid></item><item><title>From Sabalenka to Djokovic and 'animals in the zoo', here are the best quotes from the Australian Open 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australian-open-2026-best-quotes/106291648</link><description>From tennis stars pushing for more privacy, to Djokovic saying he feels like an old man and a Kyrgios F-bomb, there have been some funny and weird quotes at this year's Australian Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">092b0db1619ef3d506d5e88441d9fb8c</guid></item><item><title>Liam Conejo Ramos returns to Minnesota after being detained by ICE on way home from preschool</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/liam-conejo-ramos-and-father-released-return-to-minnesota/106294570</link><description>Five-year-old Liam Conejo Ramos, whose detention by federal agents as he returned from preschool sparked outrage across the United States, has been released from immigration detention, according to a US congressman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">519a373b59f667b2f02344c2344e5d02</guid></item><item><title>Australian monobob star Bree Walker welcomes pressure at 2026 Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/australian-monobob-star-bree-walker-2026-winter-olympic-games/106294878</link><description>The g-force felt hurtling down the bobsleigh track is the only pressure Bree Walker is feeling despite the Australian speed demon entering the Winter Olympics as one of the gold-medal favourites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">802275741ac10d99b8f9a2bd75d0123e</guid></item><item><title>Grammy winners 2026: Bad Bunny takes home Album of The Year, Olivia Dean Best New Artist</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/2026-grammys-winners-list-kendrick-lamar-olivia-dean/106294398</link><description>The 68th Grammy Awards main ceremony has happened in Lose Angeles. See who won what here.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f57b87937c11bb8b07ffe60a4bcb7e5e</guid></item><item><title>Norwegian rape trial rocks the royal family and grips the public</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/norways-monarchy-braces-as-princess-son-rape-trial-begins/106290156</link><description>This week, Marius Borg Høiby, the stepson of Norway's future king, will face trial on a string of rape, drug and abuse charges, and it has the whole country talking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9ca20ad3386ff60069b66e182bbc9d0</guid></item><item><title>Cleveland man charged over death of three-week-old baby south of Brisbane in 2024</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/man-charged-murder-newborn-death-south-brisbane/106295760</link><description>Police have charged a man with murder over the death of a newborn baby south of Brisbane more than 18 months ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f72549d4460eaddc34bca2ceb6ab2f1</guid></item><item><title>Former Queensland Origin player Joshua McGuire's child assault case before Brisbane court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/queensland-joshua-mcguire-court-alleged-child-assault/106295560</link><description>The case against a former Queensland State of Origin player accused of assaulting a child has come before a court for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">470f049fe337a9354f1961c7db347987</guid></item><item><title>Corporate Travel Management founder Jamie Pherous resigns amid overcharging scandal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/corporate-travel-jamie-pherous-resignation/106294550</link><description>Corporate Travel Management boss Jamie Pherous has exited from all his executive and board roles as he moves to a "strategic advisory role."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c02e7d1dc69ed80588946088c0865378</guid></item><item><title>Shaun Michael Dunk mental competence murder trial begins in SA Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/shaun-michael-dunk-mental-competence-murder-trial-begins/106294382</link><description>A trial to determine if a man was mentally competent at the time he killed a woman in Adelaide hears that he "always wanted to know what it was like to kill someone". Warning: This story contains content some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff1e8f2db98af9c926cfe7ed557dfe3b</guid></item><item><title>Found a PCOS 'cure' on social media? It might not be for you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/pcos-cures-myths-and-other-mistruths-to-be-wary-of/106286496</link><description>Advice on how to "manage", "treat" and "heal" PCOS is easy to come by online, but experts say a more personalised approach is usually what's needed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38340fdb3fa30f7c96f4dea3e5531ef0</guid></item><item><title>'Lucky' fishermen rescued after boat fire near Binalong Bay, Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/tasmanian-boaties-set-fire-to-items-on-board-to-raise-alarm/106294694</link><description>Two boaties stranded at sea for eight hours after their tinnie caught fire chose a survival plan police described as "highly unrecommended" — to set it on fire again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6902805b042b374f2d868a23640d1c6</guid></item><item><title>Grammys 2026: Bad Bunny, Billie Eilish slam ICE at music's biggest awards</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/grammys-2026-bad-bunny-billie-eilish-ice-speech/106295626</link><description>The 2026 Grammys blended protest, celebration and cultural change as artists confronted powers that be, embraced diversity and reshaped the night's biggest awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdcdf266663abf7ab5a05d2412ba7808</guid></item><item><title>TasWater's proposed 8.8 per cent bill increase knocked back by regulator</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/taswater-bill-increase-knocked-back-by-regulator/106295926</link><description>Tasmanian households have dodged a bullet, with the state's economic regulator refusing TasWater's proposed annual fee hikes of 8.8 per cent for the next four years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bbd39bdf9d1991991530e75ea729a06</guid></item><item><title>Boy, 13, makes 'superhuman' swim to save family swept out to sea in Geographe Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/geographe-bay-rescue-boy-superhuman-swim/106296100</link><description>A 13-year-old boy has been hailed a hero after swimming four hours through rough seas to get help for his mother and two siblings, who were swept out to sea on an inflatable paddleboard in WA's South West.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09b506eaaea53e3da37f0b9e9e7f28a7</guid></item><item><title>Wadeye traditional owners worry community violence is escalating</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/wadeye-violence-nt-police-government-urged-more-action/106295814</link><description>Traditional owners from the NT's second largest Indigenous community Wadeye are appealing for more support to end a month of attacks on houses, and fights involving up to 100 armed people in the streets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e94226762117e101426da041280d6e3d</guid></item><item><title>Mosman Park suspected double murder-suicide prompts calls for greater support for families with high-needs children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/mosman-park-murder-suicide-reaction-disability-support/106291002</link><description>A suspected murder-suicide in Perth has put the spotlight on families with high needs children, with speculation that the Clune family were not getting the support they needed in the lead up to their deaths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd4f898364abe030c24f15ba48adef3b</guid></item><item><title>Woman who fatally hit and drove away from Alexx Wright, 19, sentenced to three years' jail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/woman-jailed-over-jurien-bay-fatal-hit-and-run/106287472</link><description>A 45-year-old woman is sentenced after fatally striking a 19-year-old with her car in WA's Midwest and failing to stop and offer assistance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">740115aa9a0cbd1853da5a6219277e6f</guid></item><item><title>Slain police officer Neal Thompson's sister says death would be 'too good' for Dezi Freeman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/alleged-porepunkah-shooter-dezi-freeman-neal-thompson-sister/106296848</link><description>The sister of one of the police officers shot dead in Victoria's high country last year tells the ABC that death would be "too good" an outcome for the accused gunman Dezi Freeman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bf9a2ad0154f949ee0124ab79e76b60</guid></item><item><title>Police granted Julian Ingram bail despite safety concerns, court documents reveal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/julian-ingram-triple-murder-suspect-released-before-shooting/106294472</link><description>Accused triple-murderer Julian Ingram was granted bail by police despite concerns being raised over the safety of potential victims and the community. The 37-year-old remains on the run from police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6dca2ae340889564ebe0789a23ab161</guid></item><item><title>Ley and Littleproud hold 'civil' talks but yet to agree terms for Coalition reunion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/ley-and-littleproud-hold-coalition-crisis-talks/106297282</link><description>The federal Liberal and National leaders held eleventh-hour crisis talks after David Littleproud survived an unlikely challenge from as disgruntled backbencher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb521b68bf1b98170a5f6585eac6792e</guid></item><item><title>Is Dezi Freeman dead?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/is-dezi-freeman-dead-/106296922</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adc9e1be81959eedd26088662fec9717</guid></item><item><title>WA man to serve at least 21 years in jail for 'brutal' murder of father</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/john-matthew-gallagher-sentenced-murder-father/106296134</link><description>A man who committed a "horrific" attack on his father in regional WA, recording some of it and posting it online, will have to serve at least 21 years for murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0313e11d9859a7118e3e4acbb4103f27</guid></item><item><title>Cory Bernardi to contest SA state election for One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/cory-bernardi-to-lead-one-nation-sa-state-election/106297448</link><description>Former federal Liberal senator Cory Bernardi will lead One Nation's Legislative Council ticket at the upcoming state election in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82327f03ddfe8f054bc1364e0c41712e</guid></item><item><title>Katherine River peaks just below flood levels, with more rain on the way</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/katherine-river-flood-preparation-as-more-rain-forecast/106297438</link><description>The Katherine River peaked just below the minor flood level on Monday, but the Bureau of Meteorology says the situation could change with more rain expected in coming days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">548fd1d9c6f55a683fe4c6890b0976e2</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Court to be first female head of ASIC, Treasurer Jim Chalmers announces</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-02/sarah-court-appointed-asic-chair/106297512</link><description>This position will give Ms Court significant influence over Australian corporate culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">896634fa2fd826de486ac299ad09a264</guid></item><item><title>Dalai Lama's Grammy win slammed as 'anti-China' by Chinese government</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/china-says-dalai-lama-grammy-win-anti-china/106297758</link><description>The 90-year-old, who lives in exile from his Tibetan homeland, says he accepts the award with "gratitude and humility" but it has sparked a furious response from China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e426129bd0771d848581ce4d4df41338</guid></item><item><title>Slow movement at Gaza border after Israel reopens Rafah crossing to Egypt in key step for truce</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/gaza-s-border-crossing-to-egypt-reopens-in-a-key-step-for-truce-/106297578</link><description>Gaza's key Rafah border crossing with Egypt has been reopened. However, Israeli authorities have allowed fewer than 30 Palestinians to enter or exit the territory on the first day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3a2935cad2a7efdca4abc00e400c76b</guid></item><item><title>Trump administration to unveil rare-earths mineral stockpile to counter China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/trump-to-launch-rare-earth-minerals-stockpile/106297862</link><description>A $US12 billion ($17.2 billion) investment from the US Export-Import Bank is attracting attention from major American car companies, and comes as Washington seeks to break China's dominance of resources key for military and computing applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50a65bd5efb49ce8caca71a7d4661053</guid></item><item><title>Keir Starmer orders investigation into Peter Mandelson's ties to Jeffrey Epstein</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/starmer-orders-investigation-into-mandelson-ties-to-epstein/106297984</link><description>Documents released reportedly show Peter Mandelson sent Jeffrey Epstein briefing notes meant for then-British prime minister Gordon Brown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7404eab633f20ee2010991632232846</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Ferguson called Epstein a 'legend', told him to 'just marry me', new emails show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/fergie-emails-epstein-files-legend/106297980</link><description>The former Duchess of York's friendship with the late sex offender is back in the spotlight after the latest release of documents about the Epstein case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e97603600426faf0b2647f43f40bee8</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump announces trade deal between US and India with tariffs slashed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/trump-says-us-india-trade-deal-agreed-to-with-modi/106298034</link><description>The US president says his social media platform that a deal had been struck, which includes a reduction of tariffs on Indian products in exchange for New Delhi no longer buying oil from Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f94a01b98bae6193dbbfae37ee176e55</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane baby coffee assault tests Australia-China relations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/brisbane-baby-coffee-assault-australia-china-relations-beijing/106294458</link><description>Sixteen months after a stranger poured scalding coffee over a baby in a Brisbane park, China's decision to send a working group to Australia marks the first tangible shift in a complicated case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e117a579109e547bee7eb4bc5d3fff4</guid></item><item><title>In Antarctica's hostile environment, survival experts keep people safe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/the-dangers-of-working-and-living-in-antarctica/106295598</link><description>Antarctica can be a dangerous place to live and work, but to mitigate the risks, a team of survival specialists is contracted to keep Australia's expeditioners safe on the ice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5499b2f21580cf9255e2bf4dc9a230c</guid></item><item><title>How decluttering your digital streaming subscriptions can save you money this year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/how-decluttering-your-digital-subscriptions-can-save-you-money/106294296</link><description>With Australian households now holding an average of 3.7 digital entertainment subscriptions each, doing an audit on what you're using and whether it's providing value can be a good place to start when looking to cut costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c13fa3915e6c9c3a59644cc8b377541</guid></item><item><title>If the Reserve Bank starts the year with a rate hike, you can't say it didn't warn us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/if-rba-hikes-interest-rates-you-cant-say-it-didnt-warn-us/106295546</link><description>Could RBA economists conceivably see inflation returning to target without a rate hike? We'll know this afternoon, and while it's not the dominant view, it's not a fringe one, either.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d881ee61aa57aa94f39c3577ccc7cbb</guid></item><item><title>Should I take a fish oil supplement for my heart, joints or mood?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/should-take-fish-oil-supplement-heart-joints-mood/106281540</link><description>Fish oil is one of the most popular dietary supplements. It's often promoted for protecting the heart, boosting mood, reducing inflammation, and supporting overall health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65db459e18e709e4acbdb0e1c9cf9b19</guid></item><item><title>Amber Wraith's parents say medical professionals dismissed her suicidal thoughts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/amber-wraiths-parents-say-suicidal-thoughts-downplayed-dismissed/106213582</link><description>A hospital has apologised to the parents of 19-year-old Amber Wraith, who took her own life in 2022. Her family hopes her death will prompt changes in the way mental health patients are treated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2a360c9e244c2fecc308c79af403c7b</guid></item><item><title>Dezi Freeman search continues as Victoria Police vow hunt 'will not stop'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/dezi-freeman-five-day-search-mount-buffalo-national-park/106294902</link><description>Victoria Police is continuing to search bushland in the Mount Buffalo National Park for traces of alleged gunman Dezi Freeman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b107d824efc5c91b447ad06397cce400</guid></item><item><title>Panic selling hits gold as analysts warn of potential 'regime change' in financial markets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/panic-selling-hits-gold-as-analysts-warn-of-market-regime-change/106296154</link><description>The precious metals market collapses following the appointment of new US Federal Reserve chair Kevin Warsh, and some analysts say it signals a significant shift in the world's financial markets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3d569257b28f20ad7ac4eeb4d9ccf63</guid></item><item><title>Where do you spend your money? Tell us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/audience-callout-cost-of-living/106295774</link><description>We are keen to understand how the cost of living is being felt across Australia. What are your biggest expenses? Are you making cutbacks? Do you afford yourself luxuries?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93c007436aad1470a52310d87ce96a29</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroo Island's sea lions.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/kangaroo-island-s-sea-lions/106152240</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6da9b03c3506f606888829ac56721a3</guid></item><item><title>Citizen scientists look for hope as the algal bloom persists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/kangaroo-island-citizen-scientists-algal-bloom-fight-sa/106131388</link><description>On Kangaroo Island – where the bloom has washed death ashore for almost a year – a group of citizen scientists are focusing their efforts on "what’s still out there".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86498380fc9493692055ee20a3b6a5ed</guid></item><item><title>Australian Climate and Homelessness Alliance to help rough sleepers through extreme weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/australian-climate-change-homelessness-alliance/106226294</link><description>Tim knows firsthand the struggles of being homeless and navigating the weather, but it's experiences like his which will be the focus of a newly formed Australian Climate and Homelessness Alliance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ee4b360629767c864633ca83a3fa33b</guid></item><item><title>Victorian GPs to be trained to diagnose and treat ADHD in adults and children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/victorians-with-adhd-gps-diagnose-treat/106297198</link><description>General practitioners in Victoria will soon be able to diagnose and treat ADHD in adults and children in a move the state government says will cut lengthy wait times and save thousands of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">626bf10fde7d1333d29aa19d33772b5b</guid></item><item><title>Josh Hazlewood to miss start of T20 World Cup, Mitch Marsh shrugs off Pakistan loss</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/josh-hazlewood-to-miss-start-of-t20-world-cup-for-australia/106298116</link><description>Speedster Josh Hazlewood will miss the early stages of the T20 World Cup as captain Mitch Marsh shrugs off Australia's lamentable capitulations in their warm-up series in Pakistan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b56ebcc0ef744c39d942e4f6467aeb6f</guid></item><item><title>Children with brain cancer given hope in trial of personalised vaccines across eight Australian hospitals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/brain-cancer-vaccine-trial-for-children/106294532</link><description>The four-year trial of about 70 children with "dismal prognoses" in eight hospitals across Australia will test the safety and effectiveness of the experimental treatment designed to harness the immune system to attack a child's tumour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd9820b0bf9253cde4f11cb68c42b639</guid></item><item><title>ACT election data suggests neither Liberal nor Greens voters would want a coalition between the parties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/act-election-voter-data-greens-liberals-coalition/106294870</link><description>Greens voters overwhelmingly preference Labor over the Liberal Party across the country — and a look at the data from the 2024 ACT election suggests there's no reason to think that would be different in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53db3562aaf24beff1f311b356101d70</guid></item><item><title>High Court to consider if Victoria's strict cap on individual political donations is discriminatory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/high-court-consider-victoria-individual-political-donations-cap/106297046</link><description>Two independent Victorian political candidates will ask the High Court to overturn a state law capping political donations to just under $5,000 but allowing an exception for the major parties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a432293ac4cfa7a887e76b721678ae23</guid></item><item><title>Sita Walker's debut novel, In a Common Hour, takes place across a single hour at a state high school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/sita-walker-author-in-a-common-hour/106272552</link><description>Sita Walker, an English teacher from Brisbane, explains how she tackled her first work of fiction, set in a single hour at a state high school.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04fa39d46b8cdc0621342a7ae8b5a249</guid></item><item><title>Spanish figure skater Tomas-Llorenc Guarino Sabate says Minions music barred due to copyright issue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/tomas-llorenc-guarino-sabate-olympic-minions-copyright-issue/106298168</link><description>Spanish figure skater Tomas-Llorenc Guarino Sabate says he will not be allowed to use the music from the Minions film franchise that he has skated to throughout the season at the Milano Cortina Games due to a copyright clearance issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd82cc6e98ea73dad0ceec84b42cffa1</guid></item><item><title>Seaspray beach residents push back on wind farm turbines 10km from shore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/seaspray-against-offshore-wind-blue-mackerel-turbines/106123752</link><description>A tiny coastal community in Victoria's east is battling an international wind energy giant that wants to build 60 to 70 turbines in the ocean 10 kilometres from shore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31b11189f57ab299838aee739a3fa3db</guid></item><item><title>Aussie dollar climbs as RBA raises rates and leaves door open to more hikes — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/asx-markets-business-live-news-03feb-2026/106298200</link><description>The Reserve Bank has hiked the cash rate 0.25 percentage points to 3.85 per cent, in its first rate rise in more than two years. The Aussie dollar rose back above 70 US cents after the decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b42f830cea274bb82911f5597fb674b0</guid></item><item><title>Behind the music of hit Australian indie game Hollow Knight: Silksong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/christopher-larkin-hollow-knight-silksong-music-at-acmi/106127840</link><description>The video game soundtrack will be performed live for the first time by Orchestra Victoria at ACMI in February.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56a776d3a39c7522f7d9a4501e65808a</guid></item><item><title>Townsville health authorities report rise in pregnant women drinking</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/pregnant-women-drinking-in-townsville-report/106289078</link><description>A sharp rise in pregnant women drinking alcohol in Australia's largest northern city might be linked to the impact of last year's floods, health authorities say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eae5e5d2bd19515e8636e51dbb982756</guid></item><item><title>Tributes flow for long-time ABC host James Valentine after cancer forces retirement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/james-valentine-tribute-long-time-abc-radio-cancer-retirement/106296950</link><description>Listeners and former colleagues share treasured memories of a veteran broadcaster who has announced his retirement due to cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0d468fec3b5614e674d134292a20d31</guid></item><item><title>Belinda Bencic and Elina Svitolina make history as two mothers sit in WTA top 10 for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/belinda-bencic-elina-svitolina-wta-top-10-ranking-mothers/106298230</link><description>For the first time in women's tennis, two mothers are ranked inside the world's top 10 simultaneously.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e8a5c61f4dab9ec33ffdbe9458a4894</guid></item><item><title>Denmark volunteers unite for coastal rehabilitation in wake of destructive tourist season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/denmark-volunteers-unite-for-coastal-rehabilitation/106292930</link><description>Volunteers have completed phase one of their plan to restore the dunes at a beloved beach in regional WA where four-wheel drives have destroyed parts of the unique habitat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbeea4a0fe66b3b831e30a05c1bae24a</guid></item><item><title>Rare photo captures Christmas Island flying fox ferrying pup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/rare-photo-captures-christmas-island-flying-fox-ferrying-pup/106284950</link><description>Often compared to a "teddy bear", advocates hope the special snap of an endangered flying fox carrying its pup will shine a light on the Christmas Island animal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c88e0ee70cafc37e3aa2c4c11c901e9</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Island Flying Fox</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/christmas-island-flying-fox/106289522</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e397d549949703d7d5ef7213a34e0406</guid></item><item><title>Takeaways from the many mentions of Donald Trump in newly released Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/donald-trump-mentioned-in-epstein-files-thousands-of-times/106297878</link><description>Donald Trump's name appears many times in the Epstein files — including on an FBI list of men who are named as subjects of "salacious information". So what have we learned about the US president?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c6fdfd17bf7e45e891cef6bc9effcb7</guid></item><item><title>Bright light blazing across Victorian skies believed to be Starlink satellite debris</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/bright-light-seen-in-victorian-skies-not-meteor-but-space-debris/106298226</link><description>Keen observers reported a "massive, bright orange meteor" streaking across the sky, but one astronomer says it was likely to be space debris from a Starlink satellite.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf496c8b7acbbc3bb9ba4bb62a74099d</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr is back for the Asian Cup, half a lifetime after winning it as a teenager</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/matildas-captain-sam-kerr-is-back-for-the-womens-asian-cup/106291550</link><description>Matildas captain Sam Kerr was just 16 when she helped the team win the Women's Asian Cup — their first, and to date only major trophy. Now she's leading the side at home, ready for another shot at glory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4773abd5659955aee0a061ec54f6d43</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies Rugby World Cup matches revealed against All Blacks, Hong Kong China and Chile</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/wallabies-rugby-world-cup-games-all-blacks-hong-kong-china-chile/106298576</link><description>Australia's home Rugby World Cup campaign will kick off against debutants Hong Kong China rather than bitter rivals New Zealand, who also feature in the same pool.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18bc99a334146dcdad380878f346971e</guid></item><item><title>Nusantara Beat to bring 'psychedelic' take on Indonesian folk music to WOMADelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/nusantara-beat-psychedelic-take-on-indonesian-music-womadelaide/106295532</link><description>All members of Amsterdam-based band Nusantara Beat have Indonesian heritage, so what better way to connect with those roots than through a very different take on the archipelago's traditional music?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3790e5030aee437d9cf14b7b9b3dc9a9</guid></item><item><title>NT to introduce strongest penalty for domestic violence murder in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/nt-government-increases-non-parole-dv-murder-life-sentence-jail/106298466</link><description>Domestic violence killers in the Northern Territory are set to serve longer prison sentences without parole than others charged with murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">125be98a2433ae5ef325c08b7627540a</guid></item><item><title>Model revealed for Thriving Kids, the NDIS alternative for some children with developmental delay or autism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/thriving-kids-model-released-autism-developmental-delay/106287786</link><description>The federal government has released the model for its Thriving Kids program, aimed at setting up services and supports run by states and territories outside the NDIS.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84c3588ab95c5d928665807132dd1d9f</guid></item><item><title>Greg Roser to serve life sentence as woodchipper murder appeal rejected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/gympie-woodchipper-murder-appeal-greg-roser/106298968</link><description>In 2022, Gregory Lee Roser was found guilty of murder after beating a man with a metal bar and then placing his body in a woodchipper.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f2d843cf45488490446ca5fe32d825d</guid></item><item><title>Major potato company Zerella plans NT expansion with proposed Katherine seed farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/potato-company-zerella-plans-nt-katherine-expansion/106296502</link><description>Potatoes have not been grown in the Northern Territory at commercial scale for many years but could change if a planned seed potato venture goes ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7f85bf9c4ee325502a9239ed174836a</guid></item><item><title>Cadia goldmine faces Supreme Court class action over contamination claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/rural-community-launches-class-action-against-major-goldmine/106295724</link><description>Landowners in central west NSW are behind an environmental class action against one of the world's biggest goldmines, alleging contamination of more than 2,000 properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">726e02a66a85295017adc0738a39598c</guid></item><item><title>NSW protest restrictions extended ahead of Israel president's visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/nsw-police-protest-laws-israel-president-isaac-herzog-sydney/106298050</link><description>The NSW Police commissioner announces restrictions on protests will be extended, ahead of planned demonstrations against the upcoming Sydney visit of Israel's president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">463559519f7a8d9aa80aa9c06ff0a848</guid></item><item><title>Parents of Brooke Day, 22, preparing to bring daughter home after Japan ski lift death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/brooke-day-mourned-japan-ski-lift-death/106298942</link><description>The parents of a Queensland woman who died in a horror ski lift accident in Japan say she was an advanced snowboarder who had completed safety training.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72d53878eac64487e6a8f0188e6ed02d</guid></item><item><title>One Nation SA candidate Cory Bernardi says party will be the 'strongest voice of opposition'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/cory-bernardi-criticises-two-party-duopoly-in-sa/106298630</link><description>One Nation's lead candidate for South Australia Cory Bernardi has taken aim at the "two-party duopoly" in the state, with Pauline Hanson issuing a warning to Labor that her party would be "coming for your seats".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9af4b39e7c80b0b90f6edb40c7e34d27</guid></item><item><title>Former Hobart Matriculation College student sues department, teacher over child sexual abuse allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/child-sexual-abuse-hobart-matriculation-college/106299166</link><description>A woman is suing a former accounting teacher at the then-Hobart Matriculation College, alleging he raped her when she was a 16-year-old student in the 1980s and offered her cash to terminate a pregnancy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25e86a600c067e6cce4df8fe9bac1e79</guid></item><item><title>VicHealth given a lifeline as opposition vows to block health promotion agency's axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/vichealth-political-battle-opposition-blocks-health-agency-axing/106299646</link><description>The Allan Government's plan to merge VicHealth with the health department hits a major political roadblock, with the state opposition vowing to vote against the move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e1d46db59eda6fd1473a741b04abd78</guid></item><item><title>Mortgage repayment calculator: How much extra you could be paying now the cash rate is 3.85 per cent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/mortgage-repayment-calculator-rba-feb-2026/106298746</link><description>Tell us your loan size, term and interest rate, and our mortgage repayment calculator will work out how much extra you may have to pay on your loan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">520e983395db574fe59bb4ebb1d0c810</guid></item><item><title>RBA lifts interest rates by 0.25pc as inflation rises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/reserve-bank-lifts-interest-rates-february-2026/106298696</link><description>RBA lifts interest rates by 0.25 per cent, to 3.85 per cent, after inflation rose "materially" in the second half of 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42f190caa823d3fb1803e159ff505609</guid></item><item><title>South Sydney recruit David Fifita will lean on Wayne Bennett in an effort to rebuild his NRL career</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/david-fifita-south-sydney-rabbitohs-wayne-bennett/106300192</link><description>After a season lost to injury, newly minted South Sydney backrower David Fifita will lean on Rabbitohs coach Wayne Bennett in an effort to reclaim his status as one of the NRL's most dangerous players.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e598bd46e833e1c28273dbde317f83d</guid></item><item><title>Who is Deni Avdija? Israel's first NBA All-Star, who received a personal message from Benjamin Netanyahu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/deni-avdija-explainer-benjamin-netanyahu-nba-all-star/106299002</link><description>Deni Avdija's breakout season with the Portland Trail Blazers earns him an NBA All-Star nod as well as a message from Israel's president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6738933db0b47fd47e5149e9fe3f629</guid></item><item><title>Treasurer asks ASIC to restrict public access to company directors' home addresses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/company-director-addresses-restricted-asic-jim-chalmers/106299932</link><description>The Australian Securities and Investments Commission moves to dramatically restrict public access to the residential addresses of company directors at the request of Treasurer Jim Chalmers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60107a43f86082b98a4b37261658c873</guid></item><item><title>Child safety officers took no action over 16-month-old’s worsening scabies, inquiry hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/child-safety-inquiry-queensland-toddler-undiagnosed-for-months/106299804</link><description>A 16-month-old child with "persistent" scabies did not receive a medical diagnosis for up to eight months due to inaction by Queensland's child safety department, an inquiry has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4d8d256118cab78d6faddca9d3c5daa</guid></item><item><title>Perth man accused of backing Bondi attackers facing more firearms charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/perth-man-accused-of-backing-bondi-attackers-faces-more-charges/106299954</link><description>A Perth man who allegedly stated support for the Bondi shooters appears in court to face new firearms charges, with his lawyer flagging a bail application.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">173892de45dae16b058f9c7fc901fae1</guid></item><item><title>Piper James's family arrives in Australia to farewell 19yo who died on K'gari</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/piper-james-parents-arrive-at-kgari-fraser-island/106295146</link><description>The parents and close friends of Piper James, 19, who died on K'gari (Fraser Island) last month, arrive in Australia to say their final farewells.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">346c6b703b2e9541c37736d64cd99c7a</guid></item><item><title>Federal parliament condemns attempted bombing at Perth/Boorloo Invasion Day rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/lidia-thorpe-motion-invasion-day-alleged-bomb-attack-parliament/106298440</link><description>Federal parliament officially condemns the attempted bomb attack at Perth's Invasion Day rally on its first sitting day, acknowledging the harm caused to the First Nations community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0103b72fa857b451dd3fc06e27901fd9</guid></item><item><title>Australian Nurse working in Gaza for MSF says looming ban on aid organisation 'abandons' vulnerable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/wa-nurse-in-gaza-says-msf-ban-abandons-vulnerable/106300002</link><description>Broome nurse Rebecca Smith says a looming ban on Doctors Without Borders due to registration issues will harm the most needy patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20f121a9c3bb78edbfd306a9bafd6fb1</guid></item><item><title>SA Parole Board says commissioner made 'error' in overturning Snowtown killer's release</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/commissioner-error-snowtown-killer-release-parole-board/106299260</link><description>New documents accuse the Parole Administrative Review Commissioner of making a mistake by not allowing the SA Parole Board to participate in a review of a decision to release Snowtown serial killer James Vlassakis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d814fb5bba5684e70e7e7dab1658125e</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Mardi Gras pulls plug on party weeks out from parade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/nsw-sydney-mardis-gras-party-axed-financial-loss/106301046</link><description>Chief executive of the Sydney Gay and Lesbian Mardi Gras, Jesse Matheson, announced the post-parade celebration will not go ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0da779dd70ea8a433ef837cd0fafc67e</guid></item><item><title>Austin Appelbee speaks after 'superhuman' swim off Quindalup to save family in Geographe Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/teen-speaks-after-saving-family-in-geographe-bay/106298798</link><description>A WA mother says asking her teenage son to swim 4 kilometres through rough seas to get help after their family was swept out to sea, was "one of the hardest decisions" she has ever made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">498dc56b9b0ded2fcee4d47f8ec5eafd</guid></item><item><title>'Mass exodus' from Cambodian scam compounds a 'humanitarian crisis'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/mass-exodus-from-cambodian-scam-compounds/106282530</link><description>Cambodia has witnessed a "mass exodus" from the country's online scam operations in recent weeks amid growing international pressure and the extradition to China of an alleged kingpin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acfa4a7d9b13b747a8a1bb4f5be6460b</guid></item><item><title>'Spas' and 'saunas' used to reintroduce green and golden bell frogs to the ACT in world-first trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/green-golden-bell-frog-reintroduced-canberra-sauna-spa/106300276</link><description>Scientists are reintroducing hundreds of green and golden bell frogs into the ACT, nearly 50 years after they became locally extinct.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d4a48e5fa72c011a8c8764346c89302</guid></item><item><title>Water Corporation makes 'error' in early publication of new desalination plant location in Albany</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/nanarup-chosen-as-site-for-desalination-plant/106297216</link><description>The long-anticipated decision on a site for a desalination plant near Albany has been shared on the Water Corporation's webpage in an "administrative error" ahead of the official announcement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06455ee2bbbab3d9fbe2d078ffaa1dea</guid></item><item><title>Nightmare on Martin Place as RBA outlines horror interest rates scenario</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/rba-decision-to-raise-interest-rates-horror-scenario-outlined/106300520</link><description>The good news is the economy ended 2025 in relatively good shape — with growth starting to pick up, the economy transitioning away from government-led spending, and a historically strong jobs market. Unfortunately, that's where it ends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">079ab8a94c5849a572eae7be29c3f6dc</guid></item><item><title>13-year-old Austin Appelbee recounts his heroic four-hour swim through rough seas to help his family.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/13yo-boy-recounts-swim-through-rough-seas/106301382</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1612708736c8b1bc1031a984088bb8e</guid></item><item><title>Two alleged Brothers 4 Life gang members charged with firearms offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/sydney-brothers-for-life-gang-arrest-gun-charges-alleged-members/106301166</link><description>More than a decade after the gang wreaked havoc on Sydney's streets, two of its alleged members have been charged with firearms offences by the Raptor Squad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9b78baafd1d746b8d51a4167d3aa80e</guid></item><item><title>Commonwealth, Westpac, NAB, ANZ respond to RBA's interest rate hike</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/banks-respond-to-rba-interest-rate-hike/106300676</link><description>The Commonwealth Bank responds to the Reserve Bank of Australia's decision to increase the cash rate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c66b92954470fe787e0746b783d8cae</guid></item><item><title>Central Coast Mariners star Annalise Rasmussen signs with Italian powerhouse Juventus</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/annalise-rasmussen-central-coast-mariners-signs-with-juventus/106300846</link><description>A-League leading goal scorer Annalise Rasmussen leaves the competition immediately to join Italian powerhouse Juventus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5824f89d8ddce116ae033a1edcb9862</guid></item><item><title>Commissioner slams attempts to use complex needs as 'justification' for Mosman Park murder-suicides</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/disability-commissioner-comments-mosman-park-murder-suicide/106301532</link><description>Australia's disability discrimination commissioner condemns "dangerous narratives" surrounding the deaths of teenage brothers Leon and Otis Clune, saying the burden of disability should never be a justification for family violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">136a95000792af616c7187752b307f5a</guid></item><item><title>To stop the rate hikes, Chalmers might have to ditch the 'I didn't do it' game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/chalmers-must-move-beyond-denying-blame-for-rate-hikes/106301560</link><description>When the news broke that rates would increase, the treasurer's main priority was to prove it wasn't his fault. That won't satisfy voters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">674fede48d6785b58808b56edd9ee6b9</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106301786</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">634e1d6cb3e7070dc32fa57f4e0714bb</guid></item><item><title>Aerial crews were able to spot the family.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/aerial-crews-were-able-to-spot-the-family-/106301828</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">647a1b1bfea6d0ba41302b67aef24a29</guid></item><item><title>Russia resumes strikes on Ukraine, leaving hundreds of thousands without heating in freezing temperatures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/russia-strikes-ukraine-on-eve-of-peace-talks/106301878</link><description>The 71 missiles and 450 drones came a day before Ukrainian and Russian negotiators were due to meet for a second round of talks in Abu Dhabi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26befb821cfbd762f37e27169ad35d8f</guid></item><item><title>French police raid X offices in Paris as Elon Musk ordered to face questions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/french-police-raid-x-offices-in-paris/106301984</link><description>A widening probe into the social media platform is investigating alleged abuse of algorithms and fraudulent data extraction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">658f37f0a51f01a933896ed86cd157bf</guid></item><item><title>Luxury Gnarabup Development granted approval by WA Environment Minister Matthew Swinbourn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-03/gnarabup-development-approved-wa-environment-minister/106302028</link><description>A controversial $138 million luxury resort slated for construction in WA's South West is given a long-anticipated green light by the state's environment minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">318352032ebe8695184f63153a2a55b4</guid></item><item><title>Battery demand 'straps on a rocket' as rooftop solar passes its peak</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/subsidies-the-fuel-as-battery-demand-straps-on-a-rocket/106300776</link><description>Even as Australia appears to have passed the peak of solar uptake, demand for batteries is seemingly headed into orbit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5b4517944a3b5dad2acef06d44b0f99</guid></item><item><title>Australian freestyle skier Laura Peel hurts knee in Winter Olympics training camp</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/injury-casts-doubt-over-aussie-star-s-winter-olympics/106302148</link><description>Australian freestyle skier Laura Peel hurt her knee in a training camp ahead of the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics, raising doubts about her participation in a fourth Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef36ed4831fc792821a677ffdbe7f021</guid></item><item><title>Poland to probe links between Epstein and Russian intelligence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/epstein-russian-intelligence-links-poland-investigation/106302296</link><description>Polish Prime Minister Donald Tusk says the step has been taken amid growing speculation that "this unprecedented paedophilia scandal was co-organised by Russian intelligence services".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdd0f87274da12ba99c3905e7742791f</guid></item><item><title>Son of Norway's crown princess tells rape trial sex was consensual</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/son-norway-crown-princess/106302292</link><description>Marius Borg Høiby pleads not guilty to four counts of rape and one of domestic violence but guilty to a count of offensive sexual behaviour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">402ea0fa721a64c5ff0edc7185b3003e</guid></item><item><title>UK police open criminal investigation into politician Peter Mandelson over links to Jeffrey Epstein</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/peter-mandelson-epstein-files-links-force-resignation-from-lords/106302398</link><description>The former UK ambassador to the US will retire from Britain's parliament as police open a criminal investigation over his ties to the late paedophile.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">461392404fe32dcdd93c4f2d54507f4c</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of parents seek support as children cannot go to school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/school-cant-parents-seek-support/106298400</link><description>Thousands of Australian parents are struggling with children who cannot go to school. A new podcast and e-book have been released to help support them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb507a88382b90baa4d0ff18ae33cd3e</guid></item><item><title>RBA rate hike highlights plight of borrowers versus boomers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/rba-hikes-cash-rate-0-25-percentage-points-in-february/106299582</link><description>A third of Australians could benefit if banks raise deposit rates on savings, while mortgage holders are having to decide what to cut back on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3484042aaac301fba77e9aa6b157da86</guid></item><item><title>What could the government do to help battle inflation?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/what-could-the-government-do-to-help-battle-inflation/106301894</link><description>The federal government has a variety of options available if it wants to do more to stave off inflation, but none are popular.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39726803731460e09844b959e8b4513c</guid></item><item><title>Elite women athletes finding ways to work smarter, to help sporting and professional careers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/elite-women-athletes-work-careers-performance-chloe-dalton/106284886</link><description>The sport-work-life balance is a struggle faced by many female athletes, but many are finding meaningful ways to diversify their income to secure their future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6fe2599cc430201f4c2313ceeb5ba38</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberals face three major threats in One Nation, a popular premier and independents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/three-major-threats-facing-sa-liberals-in-state-election/106283356</link><description>While South Australia is considered a more moderate state than Queensland or New South Wales, March's state election will still be a chance to gauge the seriousness of One Nation's polling surge and the impact of the Coalition split on the Liberal Party's brand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">296bac91364bf71c5c4e21124339099e</guid></item><item><title>US forces shoot down Iranian drone near American warship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/us-forces-shoot-down-iranian-drone/106302478</link><description>The US military has shot down an Iranian drone that was flying towards an American aircraft carrier in waters near Iran, US authorities say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8cb54f3192e7cbb03f1c19412106f13</guid></item><item><title>More than 1.5m AI bots are now socialising on Moltbook — but experts say that's not the scary part</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/what-is-moltbook-the-new-social-media-platform-for-ai-bots/106298768</link><description>A social network run entirely by AI bots has attracted more than a million users — but experts warn it is not what the bots are saying that poses the true risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86187441164dc46707927b0ed0eeba4b</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane 2032 looking to learn from Milano Cortina Olympics as costs of dispersed Games start to bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/brisbane-2032-learn-from-milano-cortina-2026-dispersed-games/106301998</link><description>Brisbane 2032 president Andrew Liveris says the bid budget "bears no resemblance to reality" as the financial impact of a dispersed Olympics hits home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dbc94cdf2750ba1c646f9e6054c412c</guid></item><item><title>How to know if you're experiencing PTSD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/how-to-know-if-you-are-experiencing-ptsd-symptoms/106287082</link><description>Louise was experiencing nightmares for five years before being diagnosed with post-traumatic stress disorder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93d1325bb199373e4f1bf9b01b5f6fff</guid></item><item><title>LIV Golf members to start receiving Official World Golf Ranking points</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/liv-golf-official-world-golf-ranking-points/106302498</link><description>Members of the LIV Golf league will receive points toward the Official World Golf Ranking system on a limited basis, the OWGR governing body has announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">206655f98048faffe96ae079eded52f2</guid></item><item><title>Sydney students tackle climate change livability as world records hottest three years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/students-innovate-to-address-climate-change-livability/106200782</link><description>The designs include cooling devices for street lights, air-purifying pods for train stations and re-imagined bus shelters to improve livability, after the world records its hottest three years ever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54d846ea2fea4df10fa74c85fa452202</guid></item><item><title>Boost for development of low-emissions alternatives to glass wine bottles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/low-emission-alternatives-to-wine-glass-bottles-australia/106272524</link><description>The federal government provides $2 million towards developing low-emissions alternatives to glass wine bottles using materials like seaweed and plant sugar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf150fa9f741923d5e2f222d98ce87cf</guid></item><item><title>What the Epstein files tell us about Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor's 'car crash' 2019 interview</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/epstein-files-shed-more-light-on-mountbatten-windsor-interview/106302294</link><description>Documents released last week have shed more light on what the former prince might have been lying about in that fateful sit-down with the BBC's flagship current affairs program, Newsnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6779dc32f34e97d931db509a2116209a</guid></item><item><title>Formula 1 driver Jack Doohan signs with Haas as reserve driver after leaving Alpine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/australian-f1-driver-jack-doohan-joins-haas-after-leaving-alpine/106302540</link><description>Former Alpine racer Jack Doohan signed with Haas as a reserve driver for the 2026 Formula 1 season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c6e6f34f5a9d7dddf2670f39f8be255</guid></item><item><title>Police search for two men who slashed teen and ran him over in St Kilda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/teenager-slashed-run-over-in-st-kilda-incident/106302480</link><description>Several men described by police as acting like "rabid dogs" are on the run after allegedly slashing a teenager with a knife and running him over in an incident in Melbourne on Tuesday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ebd84548f9c501025f20c6c6eac583f</guid></item><item><title>Otways residents burnt out of their 'paradise' determined to rebuild home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/gellibrand-residents-plan-rebuild-after-otways-bushfire/106298822</link><description>The Cochrane family has called the Otways home for more than four decades. Even after fires destroyed their property, they do not plan to move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ac632500ce00dd1d79fb0abb32dfde6</guid></item><item><title>Sydney property manager with alleged ties to 'satanic' paedophile ring denied bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/sixth-man-charged-in-sydney-over-alleged-satanic-sex-abuse-ring/106302516</link><description>Sydney man Colin Milne has been denied bail after "extremely graphic, violent and depraved" material was found on his devices, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">216bdc4a7539de8c34c2357078f51b6b</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says Republicans should 'nationalise' US elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/donald-trump-says-republicans-should-nationalise-us-elections/106302586</link><description>Donald Trump says he wants Republicans to "nationalise" US elections and has encouraged his party to "take over the voting" in at least some parts of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfa59fb39f30d2f19264ded5dd67ca3a</guid></item><item><title>Extreme heat will make Northern Territory unlivable within 40 years, activists warn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/climate-change-will-make-nt-unlivable/106301158</link><description>The Climate Justice Alliance says rising temperatures and increasingly severe heatwaves present a direct and immediate threat to people across the Territory, particularly in the Top End.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b1d3866b5c2d147df28a5050c3daff3</guid></item><item><title>Jill Biden's first husband charged with killing wife in domestic dispute at Delaware home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/jill-bidens-first-husband-charged-with-killing-wife/106302634</link><description>William Stevenson is charged with the murder of his wife, Linda Stevenson, at their Delaware home on December 28.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fbd0a09ad35d744e2ce30dfd800bc6d</guid></item><item><title>Dr Karl's How Things Work quiz: How much do you really know about guitars?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/dr-karl-how-things-works-guitar-quiz/106087196</link><description>From shaping to tuning — how much do you know about how an acoustic guitar is made?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fb9bed30875263bd1cde77dae2ff4de</guid></item><item><title>'Rogue' tour guides threaten Gold Coast glow-worm population</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/illegal-tour-guides-threaten-gold-coast-glow-worms/106299890</link><description>Last year two operators were fined for running glow-worm cave tours in the Springbrook and Tamborine national parks without the required permits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f2cfeee4d953e332e303330f7a82147</guid></item><item><title>ASX climbs after Wall Street's tech sell-off as bitcoin trades around $US76,000 — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/asx-markets-business-live-news/106302610</link><description>The Australian share market edges up after a brutal session on Wall Street, weighed down by massive losses in tech and AI stocks like Nvidia and Microsoft, while bitcoin trades around $76,000 after dropping to a 16-month low.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa44dbbdca7084896acd908a86fb0bb9</guid></item><item><title>Australia knocked out of under-19 Cricket World Cup by England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/australia-knocked-out-of-under-19-cricket-world-cup-by-england/106302650</link><description>Ollie Peake's hobbling and defiant captain's knock of 100 has proved too little too late to rescue Australia as their reign as under-19 World Cup champions was ended by England in a compelling semifinal in Zimbabwe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80e061901ed74c831535e7098735692e</guid></item><item><title>Deep Creek blaze destroys three structures as CFS concerned about northern flank</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/deep-creek-bushfire-destroys-structure-cfs-says/106302518</link><description>A bushfire on South Australia's Fleurieu Peninsula has now burnt an estimated 3,200 hectares, with the CFS saying it believes three structures has been lost in the blaze. It is now concerned about the northern flank of the fire as crews come to help from interstate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b3ddcd18354b40f5ea18472a7b54736</guid></item><item><title>Forestry industry sounds alarm over 'cheap' timber imports landing in Australia and threatening jobs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/cheap-timber-imports-into-australia-threatening-jobs-forestry-sa/106277274</link><description>Imported timber is coming into Australia at nearly half the price of domestically manufactured products and is increasingly being used in local homes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a52aa70cb7c741f4282a0f544e25a26</guid></item><item><title>Survival expert praises WA family's calm decision-making during miracle Geographe Bay rescue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/survival-expert-praises-teen-family-geographe-bay-rescue/106301816</link><description>"Outback Mike" Atkinson says the Appelbee family's ability to stay calm and make smart decisions was critical to their survival after they were swept out to sea off Geographe Bay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f435077eb20063df3172c768b75873f3</guid></item><item><title>Greens link Hospitality Tasmania's donations to Liberals to pokies card demise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/tasmanian-greens-question-hospitality-bodys-donations/106301766</link><description>The Tasmanian Greens have accused the state's peak hospitality group and the Liberal Party of a "political stitch-up" to kill off the proposed mandatory pokies card, after hundreds of thousands of dollars in donations were revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">838eaf69d7c4524d7958123e9e02f240</guid></item><item><title>Randa Abdel-Fattah to appear at one-off Adelaide literary festival Constellations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/randa-abdel-fattah-to-attend-adelaide-writers-event/106302864</link><description>Palestinian Australian author, lawyer and activist Randa Abdel-Fattah will be appearing at the one-off literary event created to fill the void left by the cancellation of this year's Adelaide Writers' Week, organisers have announced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4904fed8fc7c1243585bf6ff6358a34</guid></item><item><title>Travel blogger called out for visit to asbestos-ridden former Wittenoom town site with young daughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/wittenoom-trespass-pilbara-townsite-filled-with-asbestos/106242016</link><description>Asbestos disease advocates criticise a Queensland blogger for taking her daughter to one of Australia's most contaminated sites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49f7bb4223225c4f96be57f7cf5d6448</guid></item><item><title>Western Australia's oldest lighthouse at risk from rising sea levels in Geraldton</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/calls-for-plan-to-protect-point-moore-lighthouse-from-erosion/106278568</link><description>The Point Moore lighthouse has kept seafarers safe along the unforgiving Batavia Coast since 1878, but a maritime historian says there needs to be a firm plan to protect it from future erosion and rising sea levels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0cca86a9ea926318ff9175fe54ccdec</guid></item><item><title>Man to stand trial for allegedly killing Yarrawonga woman Kylie Sanders with car</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/kristopher-castle-trial-over-death-of-kylie-sanderson/106300504</link><description>Two neighbours of Yarrawonga woman Kylie Sanders tell a court of the night she was allegedly struck by a car driven by Kristopher Castle, who will face trial over her death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf60bd0b4def28dd81fb1bb8b670f980</guid></item><item><title>Ley and Littleproud stand firm ahead of fresh round of Coalition reunion talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/ley-littleproud-stand-firm-coalition-reunion-talks/106302662</link><description>The Nationals leader has refused to disclose whether he will reject an offering for the Coalition to reunite with a list of conditions, including a six-month suspension from the frontbench for three Nationals senators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">060f9aa250142afb9d4c023dc5bf4283</guid></item><item><title>Eddie Obeid, son Moses and Ian Macdonald lose High Court appeal against conviction for conspiring over coal mine licence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/act-high-court-dismisses-appeal-obeids-macdonald/106303012</link><description>The High Court throws out an appeal by former New South Wales Labor ministers Ian MacDonald and Eddie Obeid, and Mr Obeid's son Moses, after they were convicted for conspiring over a coal mine licence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e75eb5544a86cd0fea526fd883f9d62b</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Police appeal for information as search continues for missing 70-year-old Dawn Wells</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/queensland-police-appeal-search-dawn-wells/106302820</link><description>A large-scale search operation is underway south of Brisbane as police intensify efforts to locate a "beloved community member" who went missing late last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cb8a842a996a0b308883afdca283fe2</guid></item><item><title>Government eyes off fire sale of historic defence properties around Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/government-eyes-off-fire-sale-of-historic-defence-properties/106303044</link><description>The Albanese government has identified 67 defence sites for potential sale, aiming to unlock up to $1.8 billion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a25672e0dc02248844e31c801347f23e</guid></item><item><title>Four new rule changes announced for the 2026 NRL season, kick-off tweak to be trialled</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/nrl-rule-changes-announced-kick-off-trial/106303402</link><description>A proposed rule change to the rugby league kick-off will not be enforced at the start of the 2026 NRL season and will instead be trialled during matches later in the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d9d00eb3975f5c050c7b0d39427e65f</guid></item><item><title>Drought-affected SA farmers able to access low-interest loans of up to $250,000</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/south-australia-government-low-interest-loans-farmers-drought/105129392</link><description>The SA government has stepped in with an "unprecedented" offer of direct low-interest loans to farmers hit hard by years of drought.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55741a05a8befe715a8b0655de10e0cc</guid></item><item><title>Up to 100,000 dead fish found on bank of Lake Menindee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/fish-kill-on-sunset-strip-shores-near-menindee/106302904</link><description>Residents of a far west New South Wales community found tens of thousands of dead fish on the banks of Lake Menindee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cb838985300290e2945ea85c41c9eb9</guid></item><item><title>Child abuse survivors want compensation loophole tightened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/paedophile-compensation-payment-loophole/106300310</link><description>While they welcome proposed law changes, advocates say more can be done to help victim-survivors of child sexual abuse in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d77ab79dc0340ace5b6447c7b795925b</guid></item><item><title>Defence Department announces plans to sell off Leeuwin and Irwin Barracks in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/defence-to-sell-leeuwin-irwin-barracks-in-perth-aukus/106304108</link><description>The Department of Defence announces plans to sell off both Leeuwin and Irwin barracks, freeing up dozens of hectares of residential land in prime Perth suburbs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7cb905c1e535e04c71949d55a017c42</guid></item><item><title>Demons defender Steven May misses AFL pre-season training</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/demons-defender-may-misses-afl-pre-season-training/106304280</link><description>Melbourne Demons veteran Steven May was not at training for his club on Wednesday, just six weeks out from the start of the 2026 AFL season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59f8902d785b99ba4c5c2cd0b16a3148</guid></item><item><title>Art exhibitions to see this summer, from Ron Mueck to Hobart Current and Olafur Eliasson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/art-exhibitions-ron-mueck-hobart-current-olafur-eliasson/106295866</link><description>From Aussie expat Ron Mueck's hyper-realistic sculptures and Icelandic Danish artist Olafur Eliasson's thought-provoking installations to the best contemporary artists in Tasmania, here are three exhibitions to see.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">298caa8ff84eba3f4959fca7878c20aa</guid></item><item><title>Ban on sand flathead fishing in south-eastern Tasmania amid severe decline in numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/fishing-ban-for-southern-tasmania-on-depleted-sand-flathead/106302974</link><description>Populations of sand flathead have "severely declined" in Tasmanian waters, prompting the government to close a fishery in the state's south-east to recreational anglers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edf2da94922d88069d46b2a4b63def7b</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds eye timely glimpse of Jamaica in Test series ahead of Commonwealth Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/diamonds-eye-timely-glimpse-of-jamaica-in-test-series/106304506</link><description>Australia's netballers expect to gain precious intelligence ahead of a showpiece tournament when they host Jamaica in a three-Test series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">535538818f21f4d078ae5407fa58b3bd</guid></item><item><title>Teen charged with rape and taking a person by force after Flagstaff Hill park incident</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/teenager-arrested-and-charged-with-rape-and-other-offences/106304306</link><description>A 16-year-old boy is facing charges of rape and taking a person by force after the alleged sexual assault of another teenager in Adelaide's south on Saturday night, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c3757897955665ac55e3fa90ac30299</guid></item><item><title>Ski racing event planned for SA's Lake Bonney cancelled amid permit requirement issues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/ski-racing-event-lake-bonney-riverland-cancelled-south-australia/106299936</link><description>A ski racing event which was advertised to go ahead this weekend in South Australia's Riverland has been cancelled by organisers at the 11th hour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c44b894be0dea3861ce04aea29b8fd9</guid></item><item><title>Australian man Michael 'Micky' Hurst dies in Japan while skiing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/second-australian-dies-skiing-in-japan/106304484</link><description>Michael Hurst had a medical episode and died on the slopes in Hokkaido, making it three Australians in total that have died in Japan this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59bf4fadabbac5f06ebeb80894f1c005</guid></item><item><title>Report finds NT residents feel less safe and less satisfied with police despite crime crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/nt-residents-feel-less-safe-productivity-commission-2026-report/106294508</link><description>A new report reveals NT residents felt less safe over the past year, despite a government crackdown on crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64ab151784949347c8881a5f06033311</guid></item><item><title>$15b National Reconstruction Fund allowed to back 'losers' in push to cut emissions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/national-reconstruction-fund-loss-inflation/106303788</link><description>The $15 billion fund will be allowed to back riskier green projects under new rules announced today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0a1f4b2852c62dc23b446075a270c39</guid></item><item><title>P-plater intercepted at high speed on Sunshine Motorway, Mountain Creek</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/p-plater-intercepted-at-high-speed-on-sunshine-motorway/106304756</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06ef768ef9f3e607189b7ae602e96b1e</guid></item><item><title>Police lecture teen caught driving 189km/h on Sunshine Motorway at midnight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/police-teen-midnight-189kmh-sunshine-motorway-mountain-creek/106304564</link><description>The teenager on his P-plates was pulled over by police along a Sunshine Coast motorway driving at almost 200km/h.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">472c3c0a3258dde9fc72c9927268faec</guid></item><item><title>Former deputy Liberal leader Sam Groth quits Victorian parliament, triggering Nepean by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/sam-groth-quits-victorian-parliament-nepean-by-election/106304976</link><description>Retired tennis star and former deputy Liberal leader Sam Groth will quit Victorian parliament next week, about a month after announcing he would not contest November's state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d29850448a7da913aecd9ebf4c2c8f66</guid></item><item><title>Queensland to expand to adult crime, adult time laws for a second time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/qld-adult-crime-adult-time-laws-victim-numbers/106304110</link><description>Queensland's tough youth crime laws will be expanded for a second time, but the government won't reveal which new offences will be included.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c005cbc94883125f667effeefe9c3b5</guid></item><item><title>Melinda French Gates responds to Bill Gates allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/melinda-french-gates-responds-to-bill-gates-allegations/106303380</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">307f254012e2ccce08874c63d1cbadf9</guid></item><item><title>Melinda Gates reacts to allegations against ex-husband Bill Gates in new Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/melinda-gates-breaks-silence-on-allegations-in-new-epstein-files/106303172</link><description>Melinda French Gates says her ex-husband, Bill Gates, needs to answer for his behaviour alleged in the latest batch of Epstein files.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8978eeb8f5341b7fe13d13f786c91e95</guid></item><item><title>Desperate need for medical evacuations in Gaza as Rafah crossing reopens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/desperate-need-for-medical-evacuations-in-gaza/106298622</link><description>Only five patients, along with their family members, exited through Rafah on the first day of its reopening, according to ABC staff inside Gaza. Doctors say it does not scratch the surface of the thousands of Palestinians who desperately need medical evacuation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7570dabbdc9cde9cdb8e64347ab63ed</guid></item><item><title>Malaysian PM Anwar Ibrahim and India's Narendra Modi named in Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/leaders-of-malaysia-india-named-in-epstein-files/106298458</link><description>The prime ministers of Malaysia and India deny having links with disgraced financier Jeffrey Epstein after their names appeared in a tranche of files released by the US Department of Justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd0e95ffeef84b3d540e276ce3f64581</guid></item><item><title>Inquest to be held into baby girl's mysterious death in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/inquest-to-be-held-into-babys-mysterious-death/106304312</link><description>The baby's family says it's "distressing" that the inquest comes several years after the baby's death, but hopes it helps other families.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">557a57e5869ffebfc251bf245c3a99a0</guid></item><item><title>Trump's failure to extend nuclear treaty leaves door 'wide open' to arms race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/start-treaty-russia-america-donald-trump-nuclear-arms-race/106303426</link><description>The last remaining nuclear arms pact between the United States and Russia has come to an end at a time of global instability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc3f69c281ddb28c7f975bb1833daccc</guid></item><item><title>NSW parliamentary inquiry to investigate mould and maggot issues at Newcastle's Mater Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/newcastle-mater-inquiry-parliament-mould-maggots/106304626</link><description>Shadow Minister for Health Sarah Mitchell has successfully moved a motion in parliament for an inquiry at the Calvary Mater Hospital, after the discovery of mould and maggots.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4602943345d81d975cafa1dc4164dc08</guid></item><item><title>Police condemn dozens of e-bike riders for Sydney Harbour Bridge stunt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/sydney-harbour-bridge-e-bikes-investigation/106305318</link><description>Police are combing over CCTV of Tuesday's stunt where officers believe several offences were committed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8873dd91855d3699a07adf2425fe75f</guid></item><item><title>Humpty Doo locals help relocate crocodile from side of highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/humpty-doo-locals-help-relocate-crocodile-from-side-of-highway/106304366</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3e0a3ff3c023e3ab1ba031de41c6426</guid></item><item><title>Northern Territory mum wrangles Humpty Doo crocodile near Arnhem Highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/nt-mum-helps-wrangle-crocodile-humpty-doo-bottle-shop-arnhem-hwy/106303792</link><description>Melody Wehipeihana was dropping her kids off at school when she pulled over to see what a crowd had gathered to look at in a puddle outside a Northern Territory pub.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3391dee89a5e7c013bfaf9e4aeb786b7</guid></item><item><title>Banned tennis player Thomas Fancutt makes comeback after IV vitamin breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/banned-tennis-player-thomas-fancutt-makes-comeback/106303088</link><description>Thomas Fancutt has made his return to professional tennis after receiving a 10-month ban for a vitamin and magnesium infusion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42fc7b5264f3284f619a1da6e7afddf2</guid></item><item><title>Scammers staged a fake AFP set in a Cambodian compound. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/fake-afp-office-scam-centre-cambodia/106303328</link><description>A fake AFP office staged by scammers who operated from a Cambodian scam centre reveals much about their tactics, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23bc847ad2e5565c35a14e7b47e8d707</guid></item><item><title>Olympic sports face 'difficult conversations' before Brisbane 2032 as IOC president confirms reforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/fit-for-the-future-olympic-games-brisbane-2032-sports-difficult/106302676</link><description>Brisbane Olympic organisers say they do not know what events will be at the 2032 Games, as IOC president Kirsty Coventry says her reforms will result in "difficult conversations" with established sports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6c1204787ebdd74db7210cdf5703b95</guid></item><item><title>Doberman pinscher named Penny wins top prize at Westminster Dog Show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/doberman-pinscher-named-penny-wins-westminster-dog-show/106305290</link><description>Penny bested six other finalists at New York's Madison Square Garden to win the show dog world's most coveted prize, after more than 2,500 dogs strutted their stuff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4a3d25eeeb60efc4bee30ff36c4861f</guid></item><item><title>More than 8,000 SA properties left without power from ongoing dust pollution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/yorke-peninsula-power-outage-dust-pollution-south-australia/106303486</link><description>Some parts of the state were still without power this afternoon, as SA Power Networks says outages are likely to persist this summer because of long-term wear and tear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd6303fd94e9c8ea44e85fe6d12770c6</guid></item><item><title>World's fastest falcon spotted in Central Australian outback for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/fastest-falcon-in-the-world-spotted-in-nt-outback-for-first-time/106302874</link><description>The world's fastest falcon has been spotted in Central Australia for the first time, surprising even the seasoned birdwatcher who caught the rare sight on camera.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ea8c83e1e51e04c99e35192847ac587</guid></item><item><title>Daly River residents being evacuated to Darwin ahead of predicted major flooding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/emergency-evacuation-for-daly-river-ahead-of-major-flooding/106305594</link><description>About 450 people are being evacuated from the remote Northern Territory town of Daly River, ahead of expected flood levels of more than 14 metres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">752a5659cbfe3bb88bfb57771236b4cc</guid></item><item><title>Living costs rise for all but some hit harder, new ABS data finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/living-costs-hit-some-harder-new-abs-data/106303060</link><description>Cost-of-living pressures are being felt by all households, but some have been hit harder than others as annual costs increased between 2.3 and 4.2 per cent in 2025, according to the Australian Bureau of Statistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">369e16b106575391e97cd3adea8dbc2e</guid></item><item><title>FOI documents reveal how Anika Wells' New York trip costs escalated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/foi-docs-show-details-of-anika-wells-new-york-trip/106305526</link><description>The final New York travel bill for Communications Minister Anika Wells and her staffer rose $7,000 from an initial booking due to last-minute changes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96ba52c6d67a0db4813ff41da47a6fa5</guid></item><item><title>K'gari traditional owners hold smoking ceremony for Piper James on beach where she died</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/kgari-traditional-owners-hold-smoking-ceremony-for-piper-james/106283182</link><description>K'gari traditional owners have held a smoking ceremony for Piper James, who died on the island last month, to give her spirit a safe passage home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5195525635f75c9bb6c42ce2a24571ea</guid></item><item><title>Raymond Reddington's trial told wife Sharon Fulton was murdered for insurance money</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/sharon-fulton-murder-raymond-reddington-trial/106305196</link><description>Raymond Reddington failed to report his wife missing for several days, changed his story multiple times and wrote a fake confession letter to the state coroner, a Perth court hears.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c73e0387be31319c0a408c07b2cc2f2</guid></item><item><title>Second inquest wraps up into the disappearance of escort Revelle Balmain at Kingsford in 1994</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/revelle-balmain-inquest-wraps-escort-disappearance/106295582</link><description>An inquest has wrapped up into the disappearance of Sydney escort Revelle Balmain, 31 years after she was reported missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0115d1f603e0b73cf43f85d5e4045ace</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106306354</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f41a8bd0e12792fbc4bd949240e88c6a</guid></item><item><title>Labor MP Ed Husic 'uncomfortable' with Israeli President Isaac Herzog's visit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/labor-mp-uncomfortable-with-israeli-president-visit/106306522</link><description>Labor's Ed Husic says it is "hard to reconcile" a visit by Israeli President Isaac Herzog with comments he has made in relation to the war in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60ffa360cbfd037bf13220c549d2a3f2</guid></item><item><title>How Austin Appelbee saved his family in miracle ocean rescue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/how-austin-appelbee-saved-his-family-in-miracle-ocean-rescue/106306586</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">baab61234b82fdfaa9cde0461208a54c</guid></item><item><title>What is India’s Nipah virus and should Australians be worried?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/what-is-india-s-nipah-virus-and-should-australians-be-worried-/106306542</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2df3f880fe00808e693d3e9adcc2d761</guid></item><item><title>Ex-prince Andrew leaves Windsor home as British police investigate latest Epstein revelations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-moves-out-of-windsor/106306600</link><description>British police are investigating Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor after new files suggest Jeffrey Epstein arranged for a woman to have sex with the former prince at his home at the Royal Lodge in 2010.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96c031baea93110fb38b3d9532c422c4</guid></item><item><title>Bill Gates denies allegations in new Epstein files release</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/bill-gates-responds-to-alleged-behaviour-in-new-epstein-files/106305816</link><description>Microsoft co-founder Bill Gates denies ever visiting Jeffrey Epstein's private island after new claims surfaced following the release of files from a US government investigation into the late sex offender.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">857168fab81ca4ae41d2e29829855f72</guid></item><item><title>Australia announces Jakara Anthony, Matt Graham as 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics flag bearers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/australia-announces-2026-winter-olympics-flag-bearers/106306688</link><description>Jakara Anthony and Matt Graham have been named as flag bearers for the 2026 Winter Olympic Games in Milano Cortina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dd17f2d42429c1b56d68a37e9849f4c</guid></item><item><title>Capital gains tax reform among options as Labor weighs housing pitch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/capital-gains-tax-changes-among-options-as-labor-weighs-housing/106306738</link><description>After Jim Chalmers repeatedly refused to rule out changing the capital gains tax discount, a government source told the ABC that changes related to housing were being considered, with capital gains not ruled out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f269829be055760893cb914da47e749c</guid></item><item><title>Greek rescuers search for potential missing people after deadly migrant boat collision</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/greek-rescuers-search-for-potential-missing-people-after-deadly-/106306780</link><description>A Greek coastguard vessel and a speed boat carrying migrants collided in the Aegean Sea, on Tuesday, killing 15 people off the island of Chios.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da450be3d2476dc8c5764be9b5d1b99c</guid></item><item><title>At least 162 dead, local king missing after gunmen storm Nigerian village</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/gunmen-kill-162-people-in-nigeria/106306892</link><description>Government authorities are blaming "terrorist cells" for the violence in Africa's most populous country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a077d5ec7193a775f961198149cc5a1d</guid></item><item><title>At least seven killed after Russian cluster munitions attacks in Ukraine-controlled Donetsk, governor says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/russia-cluster-munitions-attack-on-donestk/106306910</link><description>Another round of US-brokered talks on ending the almost four-year war began as Russian cluster munitions killed seven people at a market in Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c7d96bc82173f2c90d2872336b14859</guid></item><item><title>Xi Jinping speaks with Vladimir Putin and Donald Trump on eve of Ukraine war anniversary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/xi-speaks-to-putin-and-trump-on-eve-of-ukraine-war-anniversary/106306896</link><description>The Chinese leader and his Russian counterpart hailed the success of the relationship between the two countries and pledged to further ties in a call broadcast on state television.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9239808dcd283fdc633d7d087db41a5</guid></item><item><title>Marius Borg Høiby, son of Norwegian crown princess, denies rape charges in testimony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/hoiby-norwegian-prince-testimony-cries-rape-trial/106306936</link><description>Marius Borg Høiby is pleading not guilty to the most serious charges of rape and domestic violence but admitted some lesser charges, including driving too fast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4ce7b016f8b79d715372aa5e208ab27</guid></item></channel></rss>