<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 14:57:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>After being run over by a car while sunbaking, Sam reunites with paramedics who saved her</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/sunbaker-survives-car-accident-mica-paramedics-cardiac-arrest/106145824</link><description>Melbourne woman Samantha Hind was sunbaking on her lawn when her husband ran over her. After recovering from the brink of death, she is reunited with the paramedics who saved her life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c831b5ea961a7d56dd0fa761d4d7971e</guid></item><item><title>It's author Jane Austen's 250th birthday, and her books still have lessons for us today</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/this-day-in-history-jane-austen-250th-birthday/106143026</link><description>Her books like Pride and Prejudice and Emma were written hundreds of years ago, but have themes that still resonate in today's society.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">686588500f4cdb12d6f2ef95bb7c415d</guid></item><item><title>What Australia can learn from the great Kiwi interest rate hike experiment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/rba-interest-rates-what-australia-can-learn-from-new-zealand/106143194</link><description>The RBA's interest rate-cutting cycle is at an end, and now a hardcore handful of critics say they shouldn't have cut rates in the first place. Conveniently, you only need to look across the ditch to see what could've happened if we'd followed that path.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1b2084b9bc67e4d71a38d1f785d89e5</guid></item><item><title>Bondi attack caused by 'cascading hate' left unchecked, say critics urging antisemitism plan be adopted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-unchecked-hate-antisemitism-plan-adoption/106143840</link><description>A report that has sat on Prime Minister Anthony Albanese's desk for months is being raised by critics as key evidence that the federal government has done too little, too late to respond to the rising tide of antisemitism since the October 7 terror attack in Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c19e0c4318584a39ff92f0045d5dbe37</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting: Community pays tribute to terror victims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-beach-shooting-victims-tributes/106144588</link><description>An act of terror took the lives of 15 people at Bondi. Their names, stories and legacies are held close by a shaken, grieving community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6444854282aecb8338066ba6efb222ab</guid></item><item><title>NSW Premier Chris Minns defends police response to Bondi Beach terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nsw-sydney-bondi-beach-mass-shooting-inquiry-update/106145160</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns has defended the police response to Sunday's Bondi Beach terror attack, saying officers acted with "bravery and integrity".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6a75769e600bdbe0ef597e6f7ee7566</guid></item><item><title>Magic mushroom warning as Nimbin farmer fed up with trespassing foragers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nimbin-farmer-warns-magic-mushrooms-sprayed-with-herbicide/106136770</link><description>A farmer is concerned for the safety of people foraging for magic mushrooms, which he has sprayed with herbicide, as a toxicologist warns about the dangers of fungi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">235afd5ea704c22d47cdfdea7d76344f</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Day weather forecast points to heatwave, tropical storms and festive sunshine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/christmas-day-weather-australia-heatwave-storms-sunshine/106144926</link><description>With only nine more sleeps until Christmas, we have now entered the meteorological window of predictability — in other words, forecasts are more accurate than just guessing the weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c35555d46a80393c36a4ca258163f838</guid></item><item><title>Inquest into Sonya Dutton's death in outback NSW hears of 'many unanswered questions'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/coronial-inquest-into-sonya-dutton-death-in-outback-nsw/106144034</link><description>Barkindji mother-of-two Sonya Dutton, 31, was found in her family's Wilcannia residence on March 29, 2022 — four days after she was reportedly last seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0798f908bc137573034726977e2d0c2d</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting gunman Naveed Akram was follower of pro-Islamic State preacher Wisam Haddad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/video-shows-bondi-beach-shooting-gunman-preaching-islam-to-teens/106145626</link><description>At least one of the gunmen who killed 15 people in Sunday's Bondi Beach terrorist attack was known to authorities as a follower of a notorious Sydney pro-Islamic State cleric, the ABC can reveal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b52ae302a33646b87014607b9cbabe0e</guid></item><item><title>Richmond takes Olivia Wolmarans with top pick in the 2025 AFLW draft, Suns complete raid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/aflw-draft-2025-richmond-takes-olivia-wolmarans-at-number-one/106147828</link><description>Richmond takes Olivia Wolmarans with the top pick in the AFLW draft, as the Suns complete a stunning raid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f25b2ae36c9f9ebbabab0d92fd7d4e5</guid></item><item><title>Advocates express concerns over ACT government wombat management plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/act-government-considers-wombat-management-plan/106146098</link><description>The ACT government is considering how to better manage the territory's wombat population, in response to challenges being experienced by farmers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b410c4eebc046f7d2b49c70d1bfa647</guid></item><item><title>Noosa region hit with minor flooding, with isolated storms, rain and cooler temperatures forecast for Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/qld-weather-rain-storms-summer-bom-forecast-brisbane/106146608</link><description>Storms and heavy rain are forecast to again hit large parts of Queensland today, with temperatures dropping across much of the sunshine state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a6e5c1436b140651eb92fbb95969cde</guid></item><item><title>London plane trees to be removed in Hamilton following infrastructure concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/hamilton-london-plane-trees-to-be-removed/106143002</link><description>Twenty-five London plane trees are set to be removed from Hamilton after they were found to be causing problems with local infrastructure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">650a4458c8203323dc2f86e1bcacfc46</guid></item><item><title>The best board games to play (and gift) this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/the-best-board-games-to-play-and-gift-this-summer/106139214</link><description>Over the holiday period, the right game can make all the difference while spending time with friends and family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afc9ef668c6e91a92a25b0f8351ea204</guid></item><item><title>John Howard calls push to tighten gun laws in wake of Bondi attack an 'attempted diversion'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/john-howard-gun-laws-attempted-diversion/106148416</link><description>Former prime minister John Howard, whose gun reforms fundamentally reshaped Australia, says he would support further tightening, but it cannot be made into a distraction or an "excuse" not to tackle antisemitism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1ec6f3fc1f7f27d32e49292924e37f0</guid></item><item><title>What time does the Adelaide Test start? How to watch the Ashes, and Adelaide weather forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/ashes-2025-how-to-watch-and-follow-the-adelaide-test/106148302</link><description>The third Ashes Test is upon us and the series is on the line. Here's everything you need to know about the clash in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e92c26a7c6ff558c6b311e874066f635</guid></item><item><title>Former taekwondo instructor Kwang Kyung Yoo jailed for murdering three people</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/former-taekwondo-instructor-jailed-for-murdering-three-people/106148710</link><description>Kwang Kyung Yoo murdered a woman and child at a Sydney taekwondo studio before killing the woman's husband at their home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a4caa5637009f4c590c06120b5e109e</guid></item><item><title>Nick Reiner, son of Hollywood director Rob Reiner, 'responsible' for parents' deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/nick-reiner-responsible-death-parents-rob-rainer-michele-singer/106148280</link><description>As Nick Reiner, son of film director Rob Reiner and Michele Singer Reiner, is arrested on suspicion of their murder, US President Donald Trump's response sparks a bipartisan backlash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2db985e8722039bee131e170b54d9019</guid></item><item><title>Bondi terrorists travelled to Philippines for 'military-style training', security sources say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-gunmen-went-to-philippines-for-military-style-training/106148662</link><description>Father-son gunmen Sajid and Naveed Akram travelled to the Philippines to receive "military-style training" in the month before they killed 15 people at a Hanukkah celebration at Bondi Beach, security sources have confirmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52edb6122488935f51e540d7c1ade39e</guid></item><item><title>Usman Khawaja left out of Adelaide Test as Pat Cummins and Nathan Lyon return to Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/ashes-2025-usman-khawaja-left-out-of-adelaide-test/106149056</link><description>Australian selectors stick with Josh Inglis as Usman Khawaja misses out on selection for the third Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cb08134c57fd6032acedb421aedb22c</guid></item><item><title>Farmers' Facebook group racks up 100,000 followers as they seek support across seasons</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/australian-farmers-harvesting-the-crop-facebook-group/106143522</link><description>A group dedicated to Australian grain farming created more than a decade ago has just cracked 100,000 followers with about 20,000 people following from overseas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45bd01ef5eb6e271490a8f818c46382c</guid></item><item><title>Bendigo Writers Festival debacle continues as La Trobe University is asked to apologise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bendigo-writers-festival-la-trobe-apology-call/106142986</link><description>The debate around the failed Bendigo Writers Festival, which will not run next year, again embroils sponsor La Trobe University in controversy amid calls for more transparency and accountability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a562f742d6a8cdb21c5809d7bdab97b0</guid></item><item><title>Flu prompts postponement of A-League Women's match between Reds and City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/a-league-women-match-postponed-because-of-flu-outbreak/106148360</link><description>An outbreak of the flu has delayed an upcoming A-League Women's match between Adelaide United and Melbourne City, as South Australia grapples with a record number of cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ebdff9d08294f39e4ad9d4a19bde8db</guid></item><item><title>WA's gun laws in national spotlight with national reforms flagged after Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/wa-gun-laws-in-spotlight-as-national-reform-flagged/106147144</link><description>As Australia looks to strengthen its firearms laws in the wake of the Bondi terror attack, recent changes to Western Australia's gun rules could provide a blueprint for the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44045f403addf2db81fcab01e301a654</guid></item><item><title>The boom or bust rehab plan that saved Pat Cummins's Ashes series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/pat-cummins-ashes-adelaide-england-injury-return/106149958</link><description>It normally takes four months to come back from the injury that has sidelined Pat Cummins thus far during the Ashes, but the Australian skipper is set to return after just seven weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e12cb953845d1c23b62436bea61374bf</guid></item><item><title>Rob Reiner's classic films and the lines that have endured</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/rob-reiner-classic-films-and-the-lines-that-have-endured/106149700</link><description>Rob Reiner directed some classic films, many of which contained quotable lines that stuck around long after he yelled "cut!"</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a96b0aa6f1fcd784200c8c5411b6fe97</guid></item><item><title>Crisis hotline Lifeline records more than 4,300 calls after Bondi shooting in busiest day of year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/lifeline-busiest-day-after-bondi-shooting-tragedy/106149344</link><description>Crisis hotline Lifeline has experienced its busiest day of the year in the wake of the Bondi mass shooting, with more than 4,300 calls made in 24 hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">883779dc698385d4b0a9ac8d5a876dfb</guid></item><item><title>Residents urged action to restrict burn-offs for years before Dolphin Sands bushfire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/dolphin-sands-residents-warned-authorities-fire-ban-bushfire/106139290</link><description>Locals of an east coast Tasmanian community say they urged authorities to tighten rules around burn-offs in the years before yet another bushfire tore through the area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ae1fddabb7ee0fff3c5684577a4eecf</guid></item><item><title>Deciding to get a pet when I didn't think I could</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/deciding-to-get-a-pet-when-i-did-not-think-i-could/105985508</link><description>It took me a long time to decide to get a cat, and just as long to adopt after I had decided. When I saw Giles, any lingering uncertainties I had disappeared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c571e4ddcb865455d328f73d7438687</guid></item><item><title>Premier Roger Cook handed extra powers as pro-development laws pass WA parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/wa-state-development-act-passes-parliament/106146908</link><description>The powers allow WA Premier Roger Cook and a bureaucrat to sign off on projects with "strategic or economic significance", sparking concerns about the wide-ranging powers and potential environmental impact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dec3386a50ab9f81090620dc6cafe1e6</guid></item><item><title>Man, 18, charged over allegedly displaying Nazi symbol near mosque in Perth suburb</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/man-18-charged-over-allegedly-displaying-nazi-symbol-near-mosque/106150612</link><description>A man is charged after allegedly wearing a necklace displaying a Nazi symbol, caught by increased police patrols in WA after the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">391a82107f91735e13025f94f3e224ef</guid></item><item><title>Sir Cliff Richard urges awareness following cancer treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/sir-cliff-richard-urges-awareness-following-cancer-treatment/106150232</link><description>The 85-year-old singer says the disease has been successfully treated, and he is urging people to get checked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e0ddc216ff4df93386c483143bc4689</guid></item><item><title>Out-of-control bushfire damages historic Mogumber Mission, WA Wheatbelt crops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bushfire-damage-mogumber-mission-eneabba-crops/106148826</link><description>As firefighters continue to battle bushfires across WA's south-west land division, a century-old mission, which was part of the Stolen Generations history, has reportedly been badly damaged in the fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49b10e7c50767dedd5784abc231a029d</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday Finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/tuesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106151016</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba4c14b2dca2b65d3fe96067cc89605c</guid></item><item><title>Peri the koala released into the wild</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/peri-the-koala-released-into-the-wild/106150644</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf90a6d6cca60b11e3b5fb0195540481</guid></item><item><title>Koala rescued from Brisbane city bus after death-defying dash across busy Camp Hill street</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/koala-rescued-brisbane-city-bus-camp-hill-city-glider-schrinner/106150364</link><description>A rescue group says the quick-thinking of a Brisbane bus driver could have saved the koala — named Peri — from being hit by traffic on a busy road.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70afd410865b1442d9d643b73ee8cd66</guid></item><item><title>Queensland coroner investigates 'extremely unusual' deaths of premature twin boys</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/baby-boy-twins-death-inquest-queensland-extremely-unusual/106150808</link><description>The Coroners Court in Brisbane hears details about the twins' short lives before their "cold, blue and lifeless" bodies were discovered in separate cots one morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8880cb91ed6f73ceeef0783f0684311</guid></item><item><title>Conservationists slam 'pointless' federal regulator's long-awaited draft to crack down on rat bait poisoning of wildlife</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/rodenticide-decision-apvma-slammed/106143876</link><description>After a five-year wait, conservationists say draft regulations on second-generation rat baits do not go far enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11f6c007bd18c434ad67b23fb247aa69</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach terrorism survivor Jessica Chapnik Kahn threw herself and daughter to shelter as people around them were killed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/bondi-beach-terrorism-survivor-tells-of-15-minutes-of-terror/106150322</link><description>A mother throws herself and her daughter into a pit to avoid bullets as her husband goes searching for her among the bodies of the dead at Bondi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74f6bbcf501b5b52d668fc77771f7d06</guid></item><item><title>Coalition launches antisemitism taskforce after Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/coalition-launches-antisemitism-taskforce-after-bondi-terror-att/106151212</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley will head the internal group aiming to intensify scrutiny of the federal government's response to antisemitism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">154d4d3a302eba3a7e957b33b878e008</guid></item><item><title>Mid-year budget update to show $8.4b improvement to bottom line</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-16/myefo-budget-update-show-deficit-improvement/106150778</link><description>A combination of savings and higher tax takes have delivered an $8.4 billion improvement to the federal budget's bottom line, the mid-year update is expected to show when it is released on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2522fb5ff1f2ae144f04edc9bc349cae</guid></item><item><title>Driver in Liverpool soccer parade ramming handed 21-year prison sentence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/liverpool-car-attack-driver-sentenced-paul-doyle/106151538</link><description>Paul Doyle rammed his minivan into a crowd celebrating Liverpool's Premier League championship win, injuring more than 130 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64c5fdefc5761849d8a23106bb459b9a</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine peace deal could be presented to Russia within days: Zelenskyy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/ukraine-war-wrap-deal-could-be-presented-to-russia-in-days/106151590</link><description>Marathon talks between the US and Ukraine led to "not perfect" but "very workable" framework that could bring to an end Russia's near four-year-old invasion, the Ukrainian president says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67e5109aa32a118bbbfd67804a4affec</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach shooting updates: Gunman charged with 59 offences, including 15 counts of murder — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/bondi-beach-shooting-terrorist-attack-islamic-state-live-blog/106151426</link><description>Bondi shooter Naveed Akram has been charged with 59 offences over the mass shooting on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afddd661a5a897e8db6446a7392d0483</guid></item><item><title>Racist and antisemitic false information spreads online following Bondi Beach terrorism attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/abc-news-verify-misinformation-bondi-terrorist-attack/106150286</link><description>ABC NEWS Verify finds social media posts spreading misinformation about the Bondi attack are receiving millions of views, as a deepfake image depicting one of the victims circulates online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">768653d079cfb0b1e9879c0687c161a9</guid></item><item><title>As the BOM's Christmas outlook nears, here is the truth about forecast accuracy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/bom-christmas-forecast-accuracy/106135952</link><description>Some forecasts will tell you the weather 28 days from now. But is it accurate?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1c1e331b53722c210a16aca3f1ec5bc</guid></item><item><title>De-escalation skills, not guards, needed in Tasmanian hospitals, nurses' union says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/security-guards-tasmania-public-hospitals-emergency-department/106136802</link><description>The nurses' union in Tasmania wants to see private security guards in public hospitals replaced with support officers trained in de-escalation, after a review found "overwhelming dissatisfaction" among staff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2065c23d952786ecca31a4197c78b796</guid></item><item><title>'Significant' jump in sea lion pup deaths on South Australian island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/significant-jump-in-sea-lion-pup-deaths-on-sa-island/106000790</link><description>Australia's sea lion population has had a tough winter with rising pup mortalities amid the algal bloom, but dedicated researchers are doing everything they can to help their survival as a species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91b1d14c3da3130c0085c3b25cfa240b</guid></item><item><title>Medical and charity groups back free period product vending machines in NSW hospitals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/groups-call-for-free-period-products-in-nsw-hospitals/106148444</link><description>Share the Dignity and the Australian Society of Psychological Medicine back calls for vending machines providing pads, tampons and underwear in NSW hospitals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cdda50e37f457c94b32eace77f622c2</guid></item><item><title>Mary River cod thriving in Brisbane River catchment, century after relative went extinct</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/mary-river-cod-brisbane-river-cod-catchment-apex-predator-bremer/106146520</link><description>An important apex predator died out 100 years ago due to overfishing and land clearing. Now, a close relative is bringing balance back to the habitat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">102512458cf9eca07cbb7dfdab770941</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder over the death of man in Melbourne's south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/vic-police-investigate-cheltenham-death/106151724</link><description>A man will face court on Thursday following the fatal assault of a man in Cheltenham on Tuesday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c643a6d8028b62412ad9281b1acc9fc5</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Chalmers flags difficult decisions to come in next year's budget — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/federal-politics-live-blog-dec-17/106151730</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers hands down the Mid-Year Economic and Fiscal Outlook showing an $8.4 billion improvement to the budget bottom line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a7e01f90ad3f50e53451cca124d08ad</guid></item><item><title>Lung Foundation calls for urgent action on underdiagnosis and undertreatment of COPD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/drop-in-testing-behind-underdiagnosis-of-copd-lung-foundation/106115100</link><description>Experts call for urgent action to turn around an "unacceptable" decline in testing for a disease that kills 20 people every day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">272ce8b47bb8d502180121ee61c09156</guid></item><item><title>WA Jewish MP Simon Ehrenfeld feared terror attack before Bondi shooting, says antisemitism 'part of life' in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/simon-ehrenfeld-details-wa-jewish-community-grief-after-bondi/106151184</link><description>State Liberal MP Simon Ehrenfeld says he has felt a greater sense of risk when attending events recently, fearing an increase in antisemitism and the possibility of a terror attack on Australia's Jewish community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0728da40797c909810da147dd24511e1</guid></item><item><title>FIFA cuts World Cup tickets prices following global backlash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/fifa-cuts-world-cup-ticket-prices-for-2026-tournament/106151914</link><description>FIFA backtracks on high-priced World Cup tickets, with a limited amount of seats to be made available for less than $100.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6ccc497b76281a23502e841482e4847</guid></item><item><title>Hugh Jackman says he is 'heartbroken' for communities affected by Bondi Beach attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/hugh-jackman-says-he-is-heart-broken-for-communities-affected/106152016</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7f6802876a5e5b88e0a0af34e76b84a</guid></item><item><title>WA teenager escapes jail time over petrol station caravan-car theft that left tourist in coma</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/teenager-halls-creek-service-station-car-theft/106144328</link><description>A 15-year-old boy who left an elderly tourist in a coma after a Kimberley car theft has escaped immediate jail time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">453ef77b6606cc368fed1608b35862ba</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Alex Carey century carries Australia on day one of third Test against England at Adelaide Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/ashes-live-adelaide-oval-third-test-australia-england/106151318</link><description>Australia's Alex Carey scores his maiden Ashes century to carry his team to a solid total of 8-326 on day one of the third Test at the Adelaide Oval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">819f3d45b272204d8e59b997b481e2f4</guid></item><item><title>Rabbi brother of man shot at Bondi urges Jewish Australians not to 'cower'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/injured-bondi-volunteer-yaakov-super-identitified/106151280</link><description>The rabbi brother of a healthcare volunteer shot in the Bondi Beach terror attack, damaging his lungs, urges Jewish Australians not to "cower".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4cf187882931b646be90b4aaa04434f</guid></item><item><title>Taskforce Falcon charges alleged 'onshore leader' of Alameddine crime family</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/taskforce-falcon-charges-alameddine-alleged-onshore-leader/106151918</link><description>The alleged "onshore leader" of Sydney's fracturing Alameddine crime family has been charged with conspiring to murder two underworld adversaries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">897048ebb3213affa96712c42cf76417</guid></item><item><title>Tom Silvagni, son of AFL star, sentenced to more than six years' jail for rape</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/tom-silvagni-rape-court-sentencing/106149996</link><description>Tom Silvagni, son of former AFL star Stephen Silvagni, will have to serve at least three years and three months of his sentence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f31aa30d69dd5d7991c7745f913ddd4</guid></item><item><title>Celine Cremer search in Tasmanian bushland uncovers water bottle, garbage bag</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/celine-cremer-tourist-search-in-tasmania-water-bottle-found/106151898</link><description>Searchers find a water bottle and a garbage bag that may have been used as a poncho in the Tasmanian bushland where Belgian tourist Celine Cremer went missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d506ed73cdc22035e7c10eb8a17b54e2</guid></item><item><title>Search resumes for second man missing off Cape Jaffa in South Australia's south-east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/search-for-second-man-missing-off-cape-jaffa/106152324</link><description>A 67-year-old Victorian man has been found dead, and a 74-year-old Victorian man is still missing in waters off Cape Jaffa after they failed to return from fishing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6df66156a890a4379ec3a377718f993</guid></item><item><title>High Court overturns ruling that NSW government was not liable for light rail delays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/high-court-appeal-light-rail-class-action-result/106152520</link><description>The move clears the way for businesses to seek compensation from the NSW government after the project hampered traders in the city's CBD for four years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0043d65c5f88e0e57b54230cc585af3c</guid></item><item><title>Steve Smith ruled out of third Ashes Test in Adelaide due to nausea and dizziness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/ashes-2025-steve-smith-unwell-as-usman-khawaja-comes-into-team/106152450</link><description>Pat Cummins says Steve Smith is a "little bit unwell" as Usman Khawaja makes a shock return to Australia's Test team.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3602037b5fbe504f5474e0c58c580aa1</guid></item><item><title>Why photos are not the most harmful thing we share about our kids online</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/photos-not-most-harmful-thing-we-share-about-our-kids-online/106074142</link><description>Many parents are aware posting photos of their children online comes with risk. But it's not only images that can be harmful for your child.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f06b6f0af87f0a4c7f5751a28757e008</guid></item><item><title>Call for action on homelessness as WA government falls short of target to end rough sleeping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/call-for-action-on-homelessness-as-rough-sleeping-target-missed/106151378</link><description>Social services want the WA government to use its significant budget surplus to invest in breaking people out of the cycle of homelessness, after it failed to achieve its goal of ending rough sleeping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88ca5d2f55c6502293c0bdf39d0bbdcf</guid></item><item><title>Gippsland vegetable farm accused of underpaying migrant workers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/bulmers-vegetable-farm-charges/106022616</link><description>The Fair Work Ombudsman has accused Bulmer Farms in Victoria's East Gippsland region of underpaying migrant workers more than $645,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06c24ddc050b6be2cafb6c5df9b2768e</guid></item><item><title>Man who drove getaway car from fatal Canberra crash will spend at least 21 months in jail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/act-getaway-driver-jailed-fatal-crash-parliament-house/106152518</link><description>A getaway driver who helped two teenagers flee the scene of a fatal crash near Parliament House is jailed in the ACT Supreme Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3f89b14d11f071139db45228d71feb2</guid></item><item><title>World's tallest spotted gum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/world-s-tallest-spotted-gum/106136966</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d3e11b4570a9c937e20f4ee7feae191</guid></item><item><title>Call for North Brooman nature reserve to protect 70-metre-tall 'Big Spotty'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/big-spotty-spotted-gum-north-brooman-state-forest/106135758</link><description>Thought to be 500 years old, a 70-metre-tall spotted gum is almost hidden in the middle of a South Coast state forest. Conservationists want the "world champion" tree and the forest it lives in recognised and celebrated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ff6d0b6b816341b1c9cd9953cfbf863</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate two alleged sexual assaults at the Winnindoo B&amp;S Ball</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/police-investigate-two-sexual-assaults-at-winnindoo-b-and-s-ball/106152056</link><description>Officers are working through a list of people who bought tickets to the Bachelor and Spinster Ball at Winnindoo last month as they investigate two alleged sexual assaults, including one in a portable toilet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25fbe029d48953db92dc4174d7728d7f</guid></item><item><title>Short-term spending rises despite overall budget improvement as Treasury upgrades inflation forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/short-term-spending-rises-despite-overall-budget-improvement/106152498</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers and Finance Minister Katy Gallagher hand down their first budget update since the 2025 federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cca1dc7dffc05df6f14c303b00844651</guid></item><item><title>Bondi attack came after huge increase in online antisemitism, early research finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/bondi-attack-came-after-huge-increase-in-antisemitism/106153148</link><description>Research, which is in the early stages and yet to be peer reviewed, records a significant and worrying increase in antisemitic sentiment since October 7.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4aee4562ea378579144863503d5386ad</guid></item><item><title>Increased police powers begin at Adelaide Oval Ashes Test following Bondi attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/increased-police-powers-begin-at-adelaide-oval-following-bondi/106152410</link><description>South Australian Police will be carrying rifles and exercising additional weapon and drug search powers at Adelaide Oval during the Third Ashes Test, following the Bondi terror attack on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bdfe322d0fc11117ff95fb3815d52c3</guid></item><item><title>CSIRO to receive $233 million in mid-year budget but up to 350 jobs still to be cut</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/csiro-funding-233-million-mid-year-budget-long-term-solution/106152446</link><description>Just a month after announcing 350 job cuts, the CSIRO has received a funding boost, but proposed job cuts will still happen, the national science agency says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">116d2d494313030b9b86e39c61cb9d69</guid></item><item><title>Police officer shot in Bondi Beach terror attack named as Jack Hibbert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/bondi-beach-attack-injured-officer-jack-hibbert/106153520</link><description>The second police officer injured in Sunday's terrorist attack at Bondi Beach has been identified as 22-year-old Probationary Constable Jack Hibbert.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">730f74a83bd1efe37aa5b82216d91bf8</guid></item><item><title>Bondi hero Ahmed Al Ahmed a 'source of pride' for family and friends in Syria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/bondi-beach-attack-hero-ahmed-hometown-in-syria-proud/106152374</link><description>The village of Al Nayrab, in north-west Syria, is the hometown of Bondi hero Ahmed Al Ahmed — and its residents are filled with pride.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7615ddca5036b8e0d311e00d04942785</guid></item><item><title>NSW parliament recalled to discuss gun reforms after Bondi Beach shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/nsw-parliament-recalled-for-gun-reform-over-bondi-beach-shooting/106154014</link><description>Premier Chris Minns said among the reforms to be discussed were proposed limits on the number of firearms a licensed shooter could own.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14af22be07c59ec6087f816ac2ef74c7</guid></item><item><title>Falling tree kills farmer tackling blaze in Mindarabin, in WA's Great Southern</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/volunteer-firefighter-farmer-killed-in-mindarabin/106154044</link><description>A 34-year-old farmer dies helping fight a fire in Mindarabin, in WA's Great Southern region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">634525a829a1a63f04c1966f631cc7e6</guid></item><item><title>Former Beauty and the Geek contestant's murder case adjourned as SA court awaits more evidence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/former-beauty-and-the-geek-contestant-murder-case-adjourned-sa/106152380</link><description>Police are still waiting to examine a large volume of evidence, including a a post-mortem report in the "complex" alleged murder case involving Tamika Chesser, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb9db6b05e5fc08d0a56729066826346</guid></item><item><title>Shakira Adams gets maximum time behind bars for crash that killed Matthew McLuckie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/shakira-adams-jailed-over-matthew-mcluckie-canberra-road-death/106153876</link><description>Shakira Adams had no licence and methamphetamine in her system when she drove a stolen car at least 177 kilometres per hour into Matthew McLuckie's car.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2b208b9427e6081b758247813cd6f7f</guid></item><item><title>Rays and sharks washed up on Kangaroo Island linked to algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/rays-and-sharks-washed-up-on-sa-kangaroo-island/106153566</link><description>Dead rays and sharks found along a regional South Australia beach have been linked to the algal bloom, the government confirms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05739e15ce3e7048e1ca460c5f1d0537</guid></item><item><title>Former AFL footballer Marlion Pickett handed suspended prison term</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/ex-afl-tigers-star-marlion-pickett-given-suspended-prison-term/106152720</link><description>Dual Richmond premiership player Marlion Pickett receives a suspended prison term for possessing and dealing with proceeds of crime, in what a judge calls a "line-ball decision".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7e4ebf01d24b153bc9ab0ce85ca953b</guid></item><item><title>Police lay murder charge against Jamesie Rankin, three years after woman's death in Katherine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/police-charge-man-with-murder-over-death-of-woman-in-katherine/106152656</link><description>Police have charged 47-year-old Jamesie Rankin with murder three years after the death of a woman who was found unconscious on a street corner in Katherine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42c0a97b78b59e0221488307fe11c96e</guid></item><item><title>Frydenberg calls for antisemitism royal commission after Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/frydenberg-s-fury-at-bondi-attack-royal-commission-calls/106154546</link><description>Former treasurer Josh Frydenberg has called for bans on radical "hate preachers," protests, stronger immigration laws and a royal commission into antisemitism in an emotional speech at the site of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fa5dd9cd4cf4be1f32efc021bb8eb42</guid></item><item><title>Bondi shooter Naveed Akram charged by NSW Police over terrorist attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/nsw-bondi-shooting-naveed-akram-charged-police-terrorist-attack/106144420</link><description>Naveed Akram has been charged over the terrorist attack that killed 15 people at Bondi Beach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6569b2c06614349d9fe2db5225701c8</guid></item><item><title>North Queensland's small Jewish community celebrates Hanukkah in Townsville</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/strong-turn-out-at-private-north-queensland-hanukkah-event/106154056</link><description>North Queensland's only rabbi did not let a nine-hour traffic delay stop him from spreading light during Hanukkah to a Jewish community grappling with the Bondi tragedy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af71850fa42fbe1e495c51164dc623db</guid></item><item><title>Australians are rushed and time-poor with most working unpaid hours</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/how-australians-are-spending-time/106153236</link><description>Most people spent time doing unpaid work in 2024, according to new data from the Australian Bureau of Statistics. It found women spent on average an hour more doing unpaid work than men.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6f641840e295793eba7e38b6528aee9</guid></item><item><title>Queensland records worst flu season in a decade, with cases 18 per cent up on last year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/queensland-flu-statistics-worst-season-in-over-decade/106152596</link><description>Official data shows more than 90,000 lab-confirmed cases of influenza in 2025, which is more than an 18 per cent jump on the number of cases reported last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a20def121db0a0cbe627dcfdc9ca93e0</guid></item><item><title>Tom McLuckie outside court after Shakira Adams is sentenced over his son Matthew's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/tom-mcluckie-outside-court-after-shakira-adams-sentence/106155130</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21aa00fd8dab2a872ab9d399d149c891</guid></item><item><title>Noosa Council blames 'human error' for $2.3 million AI scam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/noosa-council-backflip-scam-human-error/106152030</link><description>The Noosa Council is now blaming human error for a major fraud incident that cost ratepayers millions of dollars — while not acknowledging earlier supplier scam warnings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4110601b030ead0375c8dfe9bac56ff5</guid></item><item><title>Loved ones seek support to repatriate minivan crash victims to Papua New Guinea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/muckatah-crash-victims-papua-new-guinea-repatriation/106154584</link><description>A teenage boy and a 51-year-old woman from Papua New Guinea have been identified as victims of a fatal crash in Northern Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4828fad546ec111665a7bb108b486c41</guid></item><item><title>Day-night Tests locked in for Australian summer until 2031</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/day-night-tests-cricket-australia-future/106155236</link><description>Cricket Australia CEO Todd Greenberg opens up on the future of day-night Tests in the future summer schedule.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">972090bdd7440acf1461a2b76ff872da</guid></item><item><title>Talison Lithium will not reopen historic rail line from world's biggest lithium mine after finding it economically unviable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/lithium-train-not-viable-company-says/106154826</link><description>Talison Lithium rules out reopening a century-old rail line from the world's biggest lithium mine, despite ongoing complaints about truck traffic and dust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac27301025a5bad1cc22c64372711f0a</guid></item><item><title>Ashes drama for Steve Smith, Alex Carey and DRS — quick hits from day one of the third Test at Adelaide Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/ashes-adelaide-oval-day-one-quick-hits-alex-carey-snicko/106152316</link><description>Australia's first-innings topscorers get some help from England's sloppy fielders and the DRS technology on a tightly contested day in Adelaide. Here are the quick hits from day one of the third Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">168d5a951ad1597d526d5d5c906e799b</guid></item><item><title>Teenager jailed after stabbing doctor at Tasmanian hospital in 2023</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/teenager-sentenced-stabbing-north-west-regional-hospital-tas/106153638</link><description>A doctor went through a "lengthy, risky and complicated" surgery and continues to experience nightmares and flashbacks after being stabbed by a teenager he was treating in 2023, a court is told.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72c2e48d63b3e2eccd869cb1bf1d0ec2</guid></item><item><title>Tim Tszyu dominates Anthony Velazquez, wins on boxing return in Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/live-updates-tim-tszyu-vs-anthony-velazquez-boxing/106154982</link><description>Tim Tszyu has dominated against unbeaten American Anthony Velazquez, winning by unanimous decision at the Sydney Entertainment Centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d550e41b0a45fbec1292c1a76116d98</guid></item><item><title>Alex Carey's maiden Ashes ton rescues Australia, delights Adelaide and elevates his status</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/carey-rescues-australia-in-adelaide-third-test-day-one/106153158</link><description>Alex Carey looked to the heavens as his name rang out from the Adelaide Oval stands, his emotional century saving Australia's day one and furthering his push to one day stand among the great wicketkeeper-bats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0317b7d746872f59f5a90670e1d2994</guid></item><item><title>Cyril Mark Yeeda faces court over alleged $170k sale of alcohol in WA dry communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/cyril-mark-yeeda-alcohol-sly-grogging-court/106149408</link><description>Police allege Cyril Mark Yeeda sold $45,000 worth of alcohol in dry communities for $170,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a25e665f036e38c92f0afddd7a2d1fe</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106155170</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b27f0578a1a3d0b8152250148316f669</guid></item><item><title>Man refused bail charged with depicting Adolf Hitler and Nazi symbols on boat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/man-refused-bail-charged-with-depicting-hitler-and-nazi-symbols/106155230</link><description>Lake Macquarie man Jake Dearie has been refused bail after being charged with depicting Adolf Hitler and Nazi symbols on his boat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df2520c3ae6b970e249131c4d998b94c</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach gunmen's movements in Philippines under investigation by local police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/philippines-officials-investigating-bondi-gunmen-travel/106153264</link><description>Philippines National Police say they are investigating whether the father-son Bondi gunmen travelled to a region known as a hotbed for violent Islamist militants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cfdebf849791ab6273271f58a4cbc16</guid></item><item><title>Two men charged with murder after man shot in SA's wine region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/man-fatally-shot-at-mclaren-flat/106155906</link><description>Two people have been charged with murder after a 62-year-old man was shot dead near South Australia's wine region of McLaren Vale on Wednesday evening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13da29001cdb280510a40ad770aa2de4</guid></item><item><title>UK's Duke of Marlborough charged with intentional strangulation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-17/duke-of-marlborough-charged/106155930</link><description>Charles James Spencer-Churchill, 70, who is known as Jamie Blandford, is the 12th Duke of Marlborough, one of Britain's most senior aristocratic families.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cb8793bf68c1b94a68e587165a1594a</guid></item><item><title>Warner Bros Discovery board rejects rival $163bn bid from Paramount</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/warner-bros/106155922</link><description>In a letter to shareholders, the board wrote that Paramount had "consistently misled" Warner Bros shareholders that its $US30-per-share cash offer was fully guaranteed, or "backstopped," by the Ellison family,</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf0f68320b76ae52c38e1b58baa3cfd</guid></item><item><title>Labor faces green 'Grinch' hospital funding accusations with a budget in the red</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/labor-hospitals-medical-funding-states-health-grinch/106148814</link><description>Labor has two options when it comes to straddling a budget in the red and accusations it has become a green Grinch on health funding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">403a7e02a516464585f97fbd71863c4e</guid></item><item><title>How Tom Silvagni kept his name out of headlines before his rape conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/tom-silvagni-rape-court-suppression-order/106155458</link><description>Silvagni employed a legal team exclusively to fight for a suppression order, preventing his name from being reported by the media for more than a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18e4bf0a23e855ccdfbdf3194b4c6ccc</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, December 18: The lessons from Donald Trump's first impeachment trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/the-lessons-from-donald-trump-s-first-impeachment-trial/106137900</link><description>When Trump was elected president in 2016, he joined the world's most exclusive and revered club. But three years later, the president added his name to a smaller list of US leaders who'd been impeached.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25ec2f0f53fe2e0cbac512328c364226</guid></item><item><title>How well do you know 2025 arts award winners?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/award-winners-2025-quiz/106107628</link><description>The 2026 Oscars are just around the corner but let's give this year's arts award winners just a couple more moments in the sun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fcfc399cdfb0eb083de3f7eecb138f4</guid></item><item><title>Pregnant mum who shielded stranger's daughter in Bondi terror attack says she is 'not a hero'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/nsw-holder-mum-who-shielded-girl-rejects-hero-status/106154580</link><description>When Jessica Rozen saw a little girl crying as gunshots rang out, instinct kicked in.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd09409d5d087e25d9f9d18730009665</guid></item><item><title>AI-generated images of Bondi gunman used to spread false information</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/verify-disinformation-and-deepfakes-after-bondi-attack/106154250</link><description>AI-generated images of Bondi gunman Naveed Akram in the Philippines and a fabricated Facebook page are spreading online. And an image of police officers taken out of context is debunked by ABC NEWS Verify.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15ab0c067a6ffbe3272f2fd6c08c77f7</guid></item><item><title>The election is over, but inflation is still dominating the economic story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/the-election-is-over-but-inflation-anxiety-remains/106155140</link><description>Jim Chalmers has started his second term as treasurer just like the first one ended: trying to frame the budget on his terms, but with one eye on inflation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4757ea4c3eebd15be91f442d24385147</guid></item><item><title>Government issues warning as mandatory registration for some NDIS providers confirmed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/ndis-regisistration-sil-digital-platform-providers/105996290</link><description>The government confirms two categories of NDIS providers will be subject to mandatory registration, more than a year after it was handed recommendations for how to implement a new system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e15a876018add669215906bca7ecbbad</guid></item><item><title>Why Trump's low-profile chief of staff Susie Wiles is making headlines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/susie-wiles-vanity-fair-white-house-trump/106155936</link><description>The long-time political operator is unusually candid during a series of interviews with magazine Vanity Fair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">809ee6779de44683800762b5f5539bd8</guid></item><item><title>England fume as Snicko operator admits error in Alex Carey reprieve in third Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/snicko-operator-admits-error-in-alex-carey-reprieve/106155864</link><description>Snicko's boss admits an operator error dudded England out of the wicket of Alex Carey on day one of the third Ashes Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cc2bd2871b2a987e190427ac01ccce3</guid></item><item><title>Bodyline bowler Harold Larwood pummeled Australia — but was pipped by pomegranates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/bodyline-ashes-cricketer-harold-larwood-and-the-quorn-incident/106119290</link><description>Flying fruit pips are less menacing than the cork and leather cricket balls that Harold Larwood hurled at Australian batsmen during the infamous Bodyline series, but a showdown between the English fast bowler and a disgruntled crowd that was allegedly armed with pomegranate seeds is part of the rich story of Ashes acrimony.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6aeea52ec8ae35eda2f9b43d08bddea</guid></item><item><title>Prostate cancer survivor with incontinence speaks out about lack of men's sanitary bins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/cancer-survivor-calls-for-sanitary-bins-in-mens-bathrooms/106143134</link><description>Prostate cancer survivor Mick Barrett is calling on businesses to consider installing rubbish bins inside men's bathrooms to help those with incontinence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b447055899a4ddac8d3514898c400a00</guid></item><item><title>Don't rush to change gun laws after Bondi, farmers and shooters group in Tasmania says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/gun-laws-debate-pressure-in-tasmania-builds-post-bondi/106153894</link><description>As state and territory leaders consider tougher gun laws, the Tasmanian government is under pressure from interest groups and advocates on all sides of the debate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c39865a2ca0e09a2731fac2cefe72ca</guid></item><item><title>Outback town has 'zero' rental stock as new copper mine is set to increase housing pressure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/cloncurry-housing-rental-market-crisis-eva-copper-mine/106152176</link><description>When Leylanie moved her family back to her home town a year ago, she did not expect to be spending this Christmas still living out of a motel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33491fa3e20cc48910a7121840b44366</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's gold boom continues as two big exploration tunnels approved</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/gold-renaissance-as-two-exploration-tunnels-approved-victoria/106137082</link><description>The Victorian government approves two companies to drill deep underground exploration tunnels amid a gold "renaissance" driven by high gold prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f60712965ae25c95a3cd364a334df6e4</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley calls on Albanese to recall parliament to address antisemitism — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/bondi-beach-shooting-terrorist-attack-live-blog-dec-18/106155938</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley calls on Prime Minister Anthony Albanese to recall parliament to address the issue of antisemitism in the community, in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96b79195d02d17c6016ee60792adf459</guid></item><item><title>Gun control debate heats up over proposed NSW firearm cap in wake of Bondi Beach shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/reaction-mixed-to-gun-reform-proposal-after-bondi-beach-shooting/106148350</link><description>Firearm restrictions proposed by the New South Wales government in the wake of the Bondi Beach terror attack would go far to reduce the growing number of guns across the state and prevent further harm, a gun control researcher says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4585fdfcdceac0866896e6558a84f234</guid></item><item><title>Aged care centres urged to budget for live entertainment to provide human connection</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/aged-care-centres-live-entertainment/105702206</link><description>A performer and an advocate for older Australians are worried that live entertainment for aged care residents is on the decline as other leisure activities, such as virtual reality, gain popularity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2351fcd079f80544a7bbcb1a8e83182b</guid></item><item><title>ASX ends flat as Boss Energy leads uranium rout — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/asx-markets-business-live-news-dec-18-2025/106156268</link><description>The uranium sector weighed on the ASX after Boss Energy warned of lower expected output from its Honeymoon project, while the big iron ore miners gained ground. See how the trading day unfolded on the business blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bb104e43a1cf84f9a74cb444503097b</guid></item><item><title>Celine Cremer searchers 'take a breath', as they wait for forensic tests on phone, plastic bag and bottle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/celine-cremer-search-wait-for-forensic-testing-on-items/106153540</link><description>After new breakthroughs in the search for missing tourist Celine Cremer in the dense Tasmanian bush, the wait begins for the results of forensic tests on items discovered in the forest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3f9906da3d8be18049ece1ed54563e1</guid></item><item><title>Oscars to stream exclusively on YouTube from 2029, academy says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/oscars-to-stream-exclusively-on-youtube-from-2029/106156210</link><description>In a seismic shift for one of television's marquee events, the Academy Awards will depart US broadcaster ABC and begin streaming on YouTube, beginning in 2029.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b2a3bea8d3ea1606da38930c85634bc</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide Strikers down Sydney Sixers in BBL as Daniel Hughes makes sensational catch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/bbl-adelaide-strikers-beat-sydney-sixers-in-final-over/106156360</link><description>The Strikers consign the Sixers to 0-2 despite Daniel Hughes taking a one-handed ripper late in the match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f35890cd109e91585a64dcd5908dbd9</guid></item><item><title>Leroy Johnson talks and sings about his travels through the far west.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/leroy-johnson-talks-and-sings-about-his-travels-through-west/106137142</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb73689f3332096ed0adac74df3e6baf</guid></item><item><title>Broken Hill arts community left in the lurch following funding cuts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/broken-hill-arts-community-left-in-lurch-following-arts-cuts/106126872</link><description>Malyangapa Baaka Wiimpatja artist Leroy Johnson says the axing of an arts grant, which he is the last recipient of, has left the Broken Hill arts community feeling unsupported.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b3a6fee31b695634ba5cca51ecf993a</guid></item><item><title>Nick Reiner appears in court charged over the stabbing murder of his parents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/nick-reiner-appears-in-court-rob-michele-reiner-murder/106156240</link><description>Nick Reiner briefly faces court three days after he was arrested over the stabbing murders of his Hollywood director father, Rob Reiner, and mother, Michele Singer Reiner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe8b388740540ee90a4af6115b3067c6</guid></item><item><title>Outback Farm stars finish first barley harvest at Central Australian farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/outback-farm-stars-barley-harvesting-at-athelle/105910900</link><description>Amid the red dirt, termite mounds and buffel grass, the first barley harvest is finished at Central Australia's Athelle Outback Hideaway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4efdcac86120cd9033a291516f7e54b</guid></item><item><title>Crime in Victoria continues to rise, driven by an increase in thefts and family violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/vic-crime-stats-victoria-machete-ban/106156470</link><description>The latest statistics show crime in Victoria is at its highest level since the Crime Statistics Agency started keeping records 20 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b90625f57a38f252951ec3fadc26a80</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Ben Stokes cramps, DRS woes continue as Pat Cummins, Nathan Lyon claim wickets on dominant day two at Adelaide Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/adelaide-ashes-test-day-two-live-updates/106156540</link><description>Ben Stokes has dragged his battered, cramping body to the close on day two of the third Ashes Test, with the tourists chances of victory hanging by a thread.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a7a17505140fd3d4d2be613d8f7ef43</guid></item><item><title>NT Police doubles reward for information on missing mother-of-two Angie Fuller to $500k</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/nt-police-angie-fuller-missing-person-reward-increase/106155860</link><description>NT Police has doubled its reward for information related to the disappearance of Angie Fuller, almost three years after her suspected murder in outback Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94a3c02c77d24d73932b9d0604eaac42</guid></item><item><title>Woodside chief executive Meg O'Neill resigns in move to BP</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/meg-oneill-resigns-as-woodside-ceo-to-join-bp/106156568</link><description>The chief executive of Perth-based oil and gas producer Woodside, Meg O'Neill, resigns from the company effective immediately in order to take up the same role at BP.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db976d0815d4331ccd3cfeda4efde02d</guid></item><item><title>Coalition 'flabbergasted' by Labor's response to calls for Bondi royal commission into antisemitism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/labor-brushes-aside-calls-for-antisemitism-inquiry/106156446</link><description>The opposition criticises the government for brushing aside calls for a royal commission into antisemitism as pressure mounts on Prime Minister Anthony Albanese to act in the wake of the deadly terror attack on Sydney's Jewish community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8428a4bb199dae7c9f208b323a41741f</guid></item><item><title>Albanese announces tougher hate speech laws in wake of Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/albanese-announces-tougher-hate-speech-laws-after-bondi-terror/106157020</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has announced sweeping reforms to crack down on antisemitism in the wake of the deadly terror attack on Sydney's Jewish community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb1481dd3d507d8f207dcaf53fabf32a</guid></item><item><title>Two years out from FIFA's equal prize goal, the men's tournament's pool will be six times that of the women's</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/fifa-world-cup-prizemoney-six-times-more-for-men-tournament/106156952</link><description>FIFA has announced a record prize money pool for the 2026 men's World Cup, but the figures are dwarfed by the riches on offer for the biggest club competitions, and fly in the face of the deadline for parity with the women's tournament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f61b5b4739119d707026638fb1a5d04</guid></item><item><title>Optus flags possible terminations after report into Triple Zero failures released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/optus-releases-triple-zero-report/106157268</link><description>Optus has released a much-anticipated review into September's network failure that left hundreds of people unable to reach Triple Zero (000) and was linked to two deaths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6da0c511121216a8b92d05b4d9d9a172</guid></item><item><title>Netwealth strikes ASIC deal to compensate First Guardian investors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/netwealth-strikes-asic-deal-to-compensate-first-guardian-losses/106156744</link><description>Financial services company Netwealth has agreed to pay more than $100 million to more than 1,000 clients who invested in the failed First Guardian super fund through its platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ead504871a8071956e3651af1208fbd1</guid></item><item><title>The best films of 2025: From gory horror to sugar-rush animation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/best-films-of-2025/106143092</link><description>From Australian-made gore to sugar-rush animation, here are the films that had our critics seated and watching this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad1b57ad13abb1e0cf26196589f6c8d2</guid></item><item><title>Amazon ordered to allow delivery driver to return to work after 'unlawful' dismissal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/amazon-sydney-worker-unlawful-dismissal/106154060</link><description>After 22,0000 successful deliveries, Gopal Bandameeda was blocked from the Amazon app. Now a Fair Work Commission finding will let him get back to work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef44dbc3e8cccc73ef7b7ab789f83e4d</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: Alex Carey's DRS controversy leaves experts questioning use of 'Snicko' technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/ashes-drs-real-time-snicko-alex-carey-adelaide-test/106156654</link><description>The use of "Snicko" in the Ashes is questioned after yet another DRS controversy in the third Ashes Test frustrates England and helps Alex Carey to a Test century.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b03ebceb2f178654fa59208f1e08226</guid></item><item><title>Local organiser calls on Albanese to attend every Bondi funeral</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/local-organiser-calls-on-albanese-to-attend-every-bondi-funeral/106158020</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a6cd0012b70b9fcf85704506b20d205</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr scores the winner as Chelsea makes it through to Women's Champions League quarterfinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/sam-kerr-scores-the-winner-for-chelsea-in-womens-cl/106158026</link><description>Sam Kerr heads in the winner as Chelsea secures a spot in the Women's Champions League quarterfinals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a30653c9718b291a83ae7e7ee3b67482</guid></item><item><title>Tens of thousands of Queensland year 12 students receive ATARs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/queensland-year-12-students-receive-atar-thursday/106156444</link><description>It marks the end of a tumultuous schooling period — marked by extreme weather and a pandemic along the way — and many are celebrating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a08789e458ba3614135658e1b3fa253</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese announces additional actions and powers to combat antisemitism.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/albanese-recommendations-antisemitism/106157450</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7bb0172ccf8d810584557d609277601</guid></item><item><title>X payments incentivised misinformation in wake of Bondi shooting, expert says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/expert-says-x-incentivising-misinformation-bondi-shooting/106152144</link><description>US social media platform X incentivised the spread of inflammatory misinformation in the wake of the Bondi Beach shootings, a digital media expert has said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8751dbc55d2a8c36b53eedab5e615bb7</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach terror attack survivor Arsen Ostrovsky recalls bullet grazing his head</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/bondi-beach-terror-attack-survivor-arsen-ostrovsky/106157968</link><description>Arsen Ostrovsky's bloodied selfie went viral and he is calling on social media companies to step up after doctored versions were widely spread online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3a3bb446fd64d847a0f7d7d2c3fc864</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government appoints Tracy Beaton to head Commission for Children and Young People</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/victoria-commission-children-young-people-tracy-beaton/106155854</link><description>The Allan Labor government has appointed Tracy Beaton to head the Commission for Children and Young People, as Victoria continues to grapple with its childcare crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e229f97077149c33c7820ce122b0f5e5</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Eriksen sentenced to 26 years' jail for Lisa Fenwick's murder at south Sydney home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/anthony-eriksen-sentenced-for-lisa-fenwick-murder-in-sydney-unit/106157760</link><description>A man who showed no remorse after a stabbing attack on his partner in their south Sydney home is sentenced to more than 26 years in jail for the woman's murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73dfb898a7b60771943024b6377c856e</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Beach gunmen spent November holed up in tiny hotel room in Philippines, local staff say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/bondi-beach-terror-suspects-gunmen-hotel-in-philippines/106158000</link><description>Alleged terrorists Naveed and Sajid Akram spent almost a month holed up in a small hotel room in a city in the southern Philippines in the lead-up to the attack, local staff have said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5453c2b12b1a504ffed880138716b68f</guid></item><item><title>New large-scale battery approval laws in Queensland draw mixed reaction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/what-new-large-scale-battery-approval-laws-mean-for-queensland/106156666</link><description>There have been big changes in the way battery energy storage systems are assessed in Queensland. Some rural communities applaud the shift, while industry groups say it risks investment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d3dfb5f04d211200e82d3945eb0d400</guid></item><item><title>Humbled Albanese shifts gear as Jewish community's anger builds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/anthony-albanese-antisemitism-press-conference-bondi/106158612</link><description>This was a humbled prime minister. Showing contrition, some regret, and an acknowledgement more could have been done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a35623b9f1fa29f6533d76df8584ecf</guid></item><item><title>Australian National University stabber Alex Ophel 'may never be safe to be released into community'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/anu-stabber-alex-ophel-sentenced-life-mental-health-facility/106157722</link><description>The man who stabbed two Australian National University students in 2023 is given a nominated sentence of life to be carried out in a secure mental health facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b01c5c6e8366f0a1e8abf0df3115ed10</guid></item><item><title>Optus slapped with 21 recommendations following Triple Zero outage linked to two deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/optus-releases-triple-zero-report-david-taylor-analysis/106158108</link><description>Kerry Schott's report into the Triple Zero outage debacle increases pressure on Optus to implement 21 recommendations, some of them "urgent", and highlights numerous errors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd3859e8c3a83ab01d4c2b17790f44cc</guid></item><item><title>South Coast WA towns brace for booming angler numbers as West Coast fishery closes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/south-coast-angler-surge-ahead-of-fishery-closure/106152490</link><description>South Coast towns are calling for more funding to cope with a surge of recreational fishers as the region prepares to shut down recreational and commercial fishing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28e4f25d18ee7f34d1982808059f3a94</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous community mourns Stolen Generation mission site destroyed by fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/mogumber-mission-stolen-generation-site-damaged-fire/106150974</link><description>Parts of WA's Indigenous community are in mourning, while others have mixed feelings, after a former mission where members of the Stolen Generation were institutionalised was partly destroyed in a bushfire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8a6abceac33c462c6755e73bde195cb</guid></item><item><title>NSW paramedics reunite with baby they unexpectedly delivered at Queanbeyan home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/paramedics-reunite-with-baby-they-unexpectedly-delivered/106152700</link><description>Rachel Szigeti was preparing to leave for the hospital to give birth to her second baby when she realised the moment had suddenly arrived. That was when her husband Cedric sprang into action and called paramedics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">493e1cd6d664f240945c616358208e7b</guid></item><item><title>FBI deputy to step down from role less than 12 months after appointment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/dan-bongino-resigns-as-fbi-deputy-director/106158644</link><description>FBI deputy director Dan Bongino will step down from his post next month, ending a short but tumultuous tenure as the bureau's second-highest-ranking official.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdb044dd4783a11e9ec1bd28be355174</guid></item><item><title>Public officers facing corruption charges over alleged secret payments for medical devices in public hospitals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/queensland-health-criminal-charges-corruption-ombudsmen-probe/106158696</link><description>Crime and Corruption Commission (CCC) Queensland alleges five public officers accepted secret payments from sales representatives from a medical device company to place its equipment in the state's public hospitals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da224ae46c2298c6f2f994ab6ba89093</guid></item><item><title>10yo Bondi terror attack victim Matilda farewelled at Sydney funeral</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/matilda-and-holocaust-survivor-bondi-victims-sydney-funerals/106156492</link><description>Mourners wore bee stickers and brought bee-shaped balloons to farewell 10-year-old Bondi victim Matilda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4beed518a909437466d5d2247cfda9a9</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters put out 'ferocious' 30m tall blaze at Forster oyster business</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/police-investigate-fire-at-forster-oyster-business-christmas/106157276</link><description>A NSW oyster grower is left reeling after tens of thousands of dollars' worth of equipment went up in flames just a week away from Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e2d415f3e52b07daeafcbf18770471b</guid></item><item><title>Safety report released into power bank fire on Virgin flight to Hobart amid rule changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/the-powerbank-plane-fire-that-led-to-airline-rule-changes-/106158520</link><description>The national transport safety regulator's report into a fire, which broke out on a flight to Tasmania earlier this year, has found the blaze was caused by a lithium-ion battery experiencing "thermal runaway".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">570906c0eb82c2714cf9efc36e76f2e0</guid></item><item><title>NT government's tourism permit for Lorella Springs Wilderness Park 'in excess of its powers', federal court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/nt-lorella-springs-tourism-permit-under-review-federal-court/106158346</link><description>The future of an isolated tourism hotspot home to stunning waterfalls and ancient rock art is uncertain following a Federal Court hearing in Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6b5cf83771d56ecc607988f963b9ceb</guid></item><item><title>US approves largest ever multi-billion-dollar arms package for Taiwan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/us-approves-largest-ever-weapons-spending-for-taiwan/106158962</link><description>The United States has approved its largest ever weapons package for Taiwan which is under increasing military pressure from China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0afaf9f65ad62333010998a4d0e9d52e</guid></item><item><title>'Children aren't born antisemitic': Education review aims to make Jewish students safer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/antisemitism-education-taskforce-review-david-gonski/106158642</link><description>The focus will turn from the threats outside the gate to those some critics say are embedded within education from a lack of Holocaust education to the harassment of Jewish students at universities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c28629c71488122314f4634803c7887</guid></item><item><title>FOGO avoids scrap heap as WA government commits to truck it away</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/fogo-avoids-scrap-heap-government-funding-councils-/106157354</link><description>The WA environment minister has thrown a $3 million lifeline to councils to help revive the failing 'FOGO' bin system in the South West — and says the controversial three-bin system is here to stay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11eac707c34729d870609e0d32cad3bc</guid></item><item><title>Victorian Government details 'value capture' mechanisms to fund Suburban Rail Loop east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/victorian-government-suburban-rail-loop-value-capture/106158982</link><description>The Victorian government turns to developer contributions and car park levies as it tries to raise more than $10 billion in funding for the first stage of the Suburban Rail Loop.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42bd9034870f97187799cd6e0f36c8e0</guid></item><item><title>Ashes 2025: DRS madness in Adelaide Test as Jamie Smith survives, then gets out after shambolic reviews</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/drs-madness-jamie-smith-adelaide-ashes-test/106159504</link><description>A series of strange decisions by umpires further erodes any trust in the DRS process as day two at the Adelaide Oval devolves into "shambles" and "chaos".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e5c2a27ce8a53f03b7f1460dfb9e536</guid></item><item><title>Christmas Day predicted to be scorcher in Perth with top of 39 degrees predicted</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/christmas-day-perth-weather-city-to-swelter/106159466</link><description>With only seven more sleeps until the big day, Western Australia looks like being the hottest capital city in the nation this Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdfe5017133ef9d9e011c289172be07c</guid></item><item><title>Australian Jews speak out about antisemitism after Bondi Beach shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/australian-jews-feel-anger-and-despair-after-bondi-beach-attack/106156790</link><description>Jewish Australians say the terror attack at Bondi Beach has left the community feeling angry, devastated and scared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12a3bb570ecae5c152bc96044a41b876</guid></item><item><title>How to handle awkward comments and conversations this Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/handling-awkward-comments-and-conversations-this-christmas/106089872</link><description>While your Instagram feed says the holidays are about joy and love, for many people Christmas is a time of managing tricky family members, inappropriate comments and probing questions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bc0df96a730c250545430b3882f82d8</guid></item><item><title>Former Dobell MP Craig Thomson jailed over multi-million-dollar migration fraud</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/former-dobell-mp-craig-thomson-jailed-for-migration-fraud/106153350</link><description>The former member for Dobell, Craig Thomson, has been sentenced to a maximum of four years jail over a migration scheme that netted him $2 million and for fraudulently receiving the JobKeeper payment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba27174ac648f8c57104a292036866b0</guid></item><item><title>Former Australian National University academic jailed for six years for raping two people in separate incidents</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/former-canberra-academic-sentenced-over-two-rapes/106152066</link><description>Chief Justice Lucy McCallum says Rick McGary has not accepted blame for the rapes, which occurred in Canberra in 2020 and 2016.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">380b2c6fbda75013e48d4f93bf36af05</guid></item><item><title>Craig Freeman bailed after being charged with 1991 murder of wife Melinda</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/craig-melinda-freeman-murder-court-bail-granted/106159804</link><description>Craig Freeman was charged last month with murder over the death of his wife Melinda in October 1991.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d7de245118e28dbeffb9fc030a21929</guid></item><item><title>Lucky few Zone RV customers rejoice after receiving caravans from collapsed manufacturer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/some-zone-rv-customers-collect-caravans-despite-collapse/106151986</link><description>People who fully paid before the company collapsed can receive their vans if they pay an extra fee, while the majority of customers remain in limbo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d252b499c53d44089413bc79dd642917</guid></item><item><title>Snicko's issues, Archer argues with Stokes and catching controversy — quick hits from day two of the third Ashes Test at Adelaide Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/ashes-adelaide-oval-quick-hits-day-two-archer-stokes-snicko/106156806</link><description>Ben Stokes and Jofra Archer share a robust conversation, Snicko is decried as "the worst ever" and another catching controversy. Here are the quick hits from day two of the third Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcb3884c4d515195fd8c242745419262</guid></item><item><title>Snicko circus distracts in Adelaide as Australia sends England sliding towards Ashes oblivion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/snicko-circus-distracts-england-slides-ashes-adelaide-day-two/106158348</link><description>The circus comes to town in Adelaide with technological madness marring a second day which, more importantly, saw England wilt again and Australia tighten its grip on the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc1ead655fe8dfe21518a7f410576c3b</guid></item><item><title>Bondi gunman Naveed Akram trained in firearm safety and hunting, Sydney shooting club president reveals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/bondi-naveed-akram-firearm-hunting-training/106159540</link><description>Bondi gunman Naveed Akram trained at a Sydney shooting club in "firearms safety" and "how to hunt", the club's president has revealed in an interview with a Serbian newspaper.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3fb435e2a5bcd35eb3ef0c8f5758ac6</guid></item><item><title>Tropical disease melioidosis rebranded 'melio' after record-breaking year for soil-borne bacteria</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/tropical-disease-melioidosis-rebranded-melio-/106157064</link><description>Cases of melioidosis in Cairns have set records this year, and authorities are uncertain why. But one survivor has joined a campaign to start a conversation about safety as the rains return in the north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">955ddfc1328853d6e419c39ac0beb7a2</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106159216</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b41ae5d6f0b8341cc9c3d373f494549</guid></item><item><title>PALM farm worker sentenced to eight years' jail for raping teenager near Arrawarra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/samoan-palm-farm-worker-jailed-for-rape-at-beach-near-arrawarra/106156802</link><description>Samoan national Agaalofa Agaalofa, 27, is jailed for raping a 17-year-old girl on a beach on the NSW mid north coast in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfafdbe916b0b7f27094d8775de88e4c</guid></item><item><title>Nearly 600 trees to be lost for North Adelaide's public course redevelopment for LIV Golf event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/north-adelaide-golf-course-trees/106157472</link><description>The South Australian government has released plans for North Adelaide's public golf course redevelopment confirming that nearly 600 trees will be cut down, not the thousands previously claimed by the Liberals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8b42f76b4e3a8eecb245c24fce8adc2</guid></item><item><title>Former senior police officers detail why Bondi Beach terror incident was so difficult to defend</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/bondi-beach-terrorism-hard-to-defend-former-police-say/106158866</link><description>The investigation into how and why the Bondi terror attack unfolded has only just begun, but the question of whether there were enough police and security there that day will be central.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">865eceb51e5d227e7d0903eeefb56b2a</guid></item><item><title>Queensland mother accused of staging drowning death of four-year-old son committed to stand trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/tara-maree-richardson-committed-for-trial-son-found-in-pool/106160022</link><description>Tara Maree Richardson is charged with the 2021 murder of Tarrin O'Sullivan, with prosecutors alleging the boy was killed before being placed into the water at Munbura, south of Mackay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63f73f18022f7712ab91d97a46c19be3</guid></item><item><title>Inquest hears nothing could have been done in 'rare, tragic' baby's death at Atherton Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/inquest-into-death-of-newborn-at-atherton-hospital/106159620</link><description>An inquest has been examining the death of a newborn at Atherton Hospital and whether the care the mother and baby received were in any way responsible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05ad532b556233f4f62ffa25201f4db8</guid></item><item><title>Australian man Lamar Ahchee sentenced to 12 years in prison for role in Bali cocaine-smuggling plot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/lamar-achchee-sentenced-12-years-in-jail-cocaine-smuggling/106160268</link><description>An Australian man is sentenced to 12 years in a Bali prison for his role in trafficking cocaine into the country in Lindt chocolate wrappers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a17afa13de67b8c5f7cad4c9dc04de23</guid></item><item><title>Why defending Bondi Beach was a difficult scenario for police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/why-defending-bondi-beach-was-a-difficult-scenario-for-police/106159424</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cfccf956a639bec3bdb51dac9818be9</guid></item><item><title>Security experts say hate speech crackdown may 'constrict' preachers promoting violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/hate-speech-crackdown-welcome-as-labor-warned-laws-must-be-used/106155900</link><description>Experts say the federal government must actually use new laws being finalised this summer to crack down on hate speech and so-called "hate preachers" in the wake of the Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34fb8c1b3b2094c7d69a7a13a1c1ae7c</guid></item><item><title>Signs the algal bloom that's devastated our beaches could be diminishing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/is-the-worst-of-the-algal-bloom-over/106159452</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1b419093c29c764b432dd2523f021ad</guid></item><item><title>ICAC report clears NT Police of improper conduct in arresting Zachary Rolfe over fatal shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/nt-police-conduct-arrest-charge-zachary-rolfe-icac-investigation/106157432</link><description>A Northern Territory corruption watchdog investigation has cleared senior police officers of misconduct in their decision to arrest and charge Zachary Rolfe, following the fatal shooting of Kumanjayi Walker.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d09401f08775a53ab4c018d98d4ec166</guid></item><item><title>Prime minister should resign after failing to attend Bondi funerals, survivor's brother says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/call-for-pm-to-resign-for-not-attending-bondi-terrorism-funerals/106160278</link><description>The brother of a survivor shot during the weekend terrorist attack in Sydney says it is "utterly shameful" the Australian prime minister has not attended funerals of the victims and has called on him to resign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f978e4405e70dc7d0eb158535c6d8c2</guid></item><item><title>Yoshua Bengio explains why AI could become a threat to humanity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/yoshua-bengio-explains-why-ai-could-become-a-threat-to-humanity-/106159442</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">111e26eb49a84be3db245ba5adfc2025</guid></item><item><title>Police called to Mordialloc again after reports of assaults near pier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/victoria-police-mordialloc-pier-assault-young-people/106160536</link><description>Police have again been called to the Melbourne bayside suburb of Mordialloc, a day after reports of a brawl involving more than 100 teenagers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">391289b209db692692dc509e8c89a1ff</guid></item><item><title>Seven men assisting police after operation at Liverpool in Sydney's south-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/nsw-tactical-operations-officers-descend-on-liverpool-seven-men/106160544</link><description>Officers from the Tactical Operations Unit conducted an operation on George Street in the south-west Sydney suburb of Liverpool late on Thursday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0257a047fb39c8ca03cc7dae5700111c</guid></item><item><title>Extra $42.6 million for mental health support after Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-18/extra-funds-for-mental-health-support-after-bondi-terror-attack/106160596</link><description>A temporary mental health centre will be set up in Bondi offering free walk-in services to help Australians grieving and traumatised by the deadly terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40e9bb859fa1f6720f1100846a5ca6b3</guid></item><item><title>French doctor jailed for poisoning 30 patients, including children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-12-19/french-court-jails-dr-death-30-patients-poisoned/106160720</link><description>Frederic Pechier's youngest victim, a four-year-old, survived two cardiac arrests during routine tonsil surgery in 2016.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b83fabf3e6844b123c26ef92e0adb2cd</guid></item></channel></rss>