<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 16:15:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Drought-affected SA farmers able to access low-interest loans of up to $250,000</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/south-australia-government-low-interest-loans-farmers-drought/105129392</link><description>The SA government has stepped in with an "unprecedented" offer of direct low-interest loans to farmers hit hard by years of drought.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55741a05a8befe715a8b0655de10e0cc</guid></item><item><title>Up to 100,000 dead fish found on bank of Lake Menindee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/fish-kill-on-sunset-strip-shores-near-menindee/106302904</link><description>Residents of a far west New South Wales community found tens of thousands of dead fish on the banks of Lake Menindee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cb838985300290e2945ea85c41c9eb9</guid></item><item><title>Demons defender Steven May misses AFL pre-season training</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/demons-defender-may-misses-afl-pre-season-training/106304280</link><description>Melbourne Demons veteran Steven May was not at training for his club on Wednesday, just six weeks out from the start of the 2026 AFL season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59f8902d785b99ba4c5c2cd0b16a3148</guid></item><item><title>Art exhibitions to see this summer, from Ron Mueck to Hobart Current and Olafur Eliasson</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/art-exhibitions-ron-mueck-hobart-current-olafur-eliasson/106295866</link><description>From Aussie expat Ron Mueck's hyper-realistic sculptures and Icelandic Danish artist Olafur Eliasson's thought-provoking installations to the best contemporary artists in Tasmania, here are three exhibitions to see.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">298caa8ff84eba3f4959fca7878c20aa</guid></item><item><title>Ban on sand flathead fishing in south-eastern Tasmania amid severe decline in numbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/fishing-ban-for-southern-tasmania-on-depleted-sand-flathead/106302974</link><description>Populations of sand flathead have "severely declined" in Tasmanian waters, prompting the government to close a fishery in the state's south-east to recreational anglers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edf2da94922d88069d46b2a4b63def7b</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds eye timely glimpse of Jamaica in Test series ahead of Commonwealth Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/diamonds-eye-timely-glimpse-of-jamaica-in-test-series/106304506</link><description>Australia's netballers expect to gain precious intelligence ahead of a showpiece tournament when they host Jamaica in a three-Test series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">535538818f21f4d078ae5407fa58b3bd</guid></item><item><title>Report finds NT residents feel less safe and less satisfied with police despite crime crackdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/nt-residents-feel-less-safe-productivity-commission-2026-report/106294508</link><description>A new report reveals NT residents felt less safe over the past year, despite a government crackdown on crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64ab151784949347c8881a5f06033311</guid></item><item><title>$15b National Reconstruction Fund allowed to back 'losers' in push to cut emissions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/national-reconstruction-fund-loss-inflation/106303788</link><description>The $15 billion fund will be allowed to back riskier green projects under new rules announced today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0a1f4b2852c62dc23b446075a270c39</guid></item><item><title>Desperate need for medical evacuations in Gaza as Rafah crossing reopens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/desperate-need-for-medical-evacuations-in-gaza/106298622</link><description>Only five patients, along with their family members, exited through Rafah on the first day of its reopening, according to ABC staff inside Gaza. Doctors say it does not scratch the surface of the thousands of Palestinians who desperately need medical evacuation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7570dabbdc9cde9cdb8e64347ab63ed</guid></item><item><title>Malaysian PM Anwar Ibrahim and India's Narendra Modi named in Epstein files</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/leaders-of-malaysia-india-named-in-epstein-files/106298458</link><description>The prime ministers of Malaysia and India deny having links with disgraced financier Jeffrey Epstein after their names appeared in a tranche of files released by the US Department of Justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd0e95ffeef84b3d540e276ce3f64581</guid></item><item><title>Trump's failure to extend nuclear treaty leaves door 'wide open' to arms race</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/start-treaty-russia-america-donald-trump-nuclear-arms-race/106303426</link><description>The last remaining nuclear arms pact between the United States and Russia has come to an end at a time of global instability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc3f69c281ddb28c7f975bb1833daccc</guid></item><item><title>NSW parliamentary inquiry to investigate mould and maggot issues at Newcastle's Mater Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/newcastle-mater-inquiry-parliament-mould-maggots/106304626</link><description>Shadow Minister for Health Sarah Mitchell has successfully moved a motion in parliament for an inquiry at the Calvary Mater Hospital, after the discovery of mould and maggots.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4602943345d81d975cafa1dc4164dc08</guid></item><item><title>Humpty Doo locals help relocate crocodile from side of highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/humpty-doo-locals-help-relocate-crocodile-from-side-of-highway/106304366</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3e0a3ff3c023e3ab1ba031de41c6426</guid></item><item><title>Northern Territory mum wrangles Humpty Doo crocodile near Arnhem Highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/nt-mum-helps-wrangle-crocodile-humpty-doo-bottle-shop-arnhem-hwy/106303792</link><description>Melody Wehipeihana was dropping her kids off at school when she pulled over to see what a crowd had gathered to look at in a puddle outside a Northern Territory pub.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3391dee89a5e7c013bfaf9e4aeb786b7</guid></item><item><title>Banned tennis player Thomas Fancutt makes comeback after IV vitamin breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/banned-tennis-player-thomas-fancutt-makes-comeback/106303088</link><description>Thomas Fancutt has made his return to professional tennis after receiving a 10-month ban for a vitamin and magnesium infusion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42fc7b5264f3284f619a1da6e7afddf2</guid></item><item><title>Scammers staged a fake AFP set in a Cambodian compound. Here's what we know</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/fake-afp-office-scam-centre-cambodia/106303328</link><description>A fake AFP office staged by scammers who operated from a Cambodian scam centre reveals much about their tactics, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23bc847ad2e5565c35a14e7b47e8d707</guid></item><item><title>Why these women took marriage sabbaticals — and how it went</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/women-on-taking-a-break-from-their-marriage/106281918</link><description>Do you ever feel like taking a break from your marriage? Three women share how a marriage sabbatical changed their relationship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a22d596cb89a89bdce7261b2f8056448</guid></item><item><title>Olympic sports face 'difficult conversations' before Brisbane 2032 as IOC president confirms reforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/fit-for-the-future-olympic-games-brisbane-2032-sports-difficult/106302676</link><description>Brisbane Olympic organisers say they do not know what events will be at the 2032 Games, as IOC president Kirsty Coventry says her reforms will result in "difficult conversations" with established sports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6c1204787ebdd74db7210cdf5703b95</guid></item><item><title>Doberman pinscher named Penny wins top prize at Westminster Dog Show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/doberman-pinscher-named-penny-wins-westminster-dog-show/106305290</link><description>Penny bested six other finalists at New York's Madison Square Garden to win the show dog world's most coveted prize, after more than 2,500 dogs strutted their stuff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4a3d25eeeb60efc4bee30ff36c4861f</guid></item><item><title>World's fastest falcon spotted in Central Australian outback for the first time</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/fastest-falcon-in-the-world-spotted-in-nt-outback-for-first-time/106302874</link><description>The world's fastest falcon has been spotted in Central Australia for the first time, surprising even the seasoned birdwatcher who caught the rare sight on camera.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ea8c83e1e51e04c99e35192847ac587</guid></item><item><title>Living costs rise for all but some hit harder, new ABS data finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/living-costs-hit-some-harder-new-abs-data/106303060</link><description>Cost-of-living pressures are being felt by all households, but some have been hit harder than others as annual costs increased between 2.3 and 4.2 per cent in 2025, according to the Australian Bureau of Statistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">369e16b106575391e97cd3adea8dbc2e</guid></item><item><title>K'gari traditional owners hold smoking ceremony for Piper James on beach where she died</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/kgari-traditional-owners-hold-smoking-ceremony-for-piper-james/106283182</link><description>K'gari traditional owners have held a smoking ceremony for Piper James, who died on the island last month, to give her spirit a safe passage home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5195525635f75c9bb6c42ce2a24571ea</guid></item><item><title>Austin Appelbee's incredible tale of survival has made international headlines. How did the 13yo do it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/austin-appelbee-13yo-boy-swims-to-shore-to-save-family-australia/106301468</link><description>Austin Appelbee, 13, has made international headlines after swimming for four hours in rough seas to save his mum, sister and brother stranded in the ocean. How did he do it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">178c976d4aeb49f1fcb20f8290878d75</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/106306354</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f41a8bd0e12792fbc4bd949240e88c6a</guid></item><item><title>What is India’s Nipah virus and should Australians be worried?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/what-is-india-s-nipah-virus-and-should-australians-be-worried-/106306542</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2df3f880fe00808e693d3e9adcc2d761</guid></item><item><title>Australia announces Jakara Anthony, Matt Graham as 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympics flag bearers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-04/australia-announces-2026-winter-olympics-flag-bearers/106306688</link><description>Jakara Anthony and Matt Graham have been named as flag bearers for the 2026 Winter Olympic Games in Milano Cortina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dd17f2d42429c1b56d68a37e9849f4c</guid></item><item><title>At least 162 dead, local king missing after gunmen storm Nigerian village</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/gunmen-kill-162-people-in-nigeria/106306892</link><description>Government authorities are blaming "terrorist cells" for the violence in Africa's most populous country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a077d5ec7193a775f961198149cc5a1d</guid></item><item><title>At least seven killed by Russian cluster munitions attacks in Ukraine-controlled Donetsk, governor says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/russia-cluster-munitions-attack-on-donestk/106306910</link><description>Another round of US-brokered talks on ending the almost four-year war began as Russian cluster munitions killed seven people at a market in Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c7d96bc82173f2c90d2872336b14859</guid></item><item><title>Xi Jinping speaks with Vladimir Putin and Donald Trump on eve of Ukraine war anniversary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/xi-speaks-to-putin-and-trump-on-eve-of-ukraine-war-anniversary/106306896</link><description>The Chinese leader and his Russian counterpart hail the success of the relationship between the two countries and pledge to further ties in a call broadcast on state television.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9239808dcd283fdc633d7d087db41a5</guid></item><item><title>Marius Borg Høiby, son of Norwegian crown princess, denies rape charges in testimony</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/hoiby-norwegian-prince-testimony-cries-rape-trial/106306936</link><description>Marius Borg Høiby is pleading not guilty to the most serious charges of rape and domestic violence but admits some lesser charges, including driving too fast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4ce7b016f8b79d715372aa5e208ab27</guid></item><item><title>Trump administration pulls 700 immigration officers out of Minnesota</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/ice-to-pull-700-officers-out-of-minnesota/106306958</link><description>The administration's border tsar says the decision came after local and state authorities agreed to cooperate more closely with its immigration crackdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a4e08db35f2fac1abab8e4ccffd4424</guid></item><item><title>Ryan Routh sentenced to life in prison for attempted assassination of Donald Trump on Florida golf course</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/ryan-routh-given-life-sentence-for-attempted-trump-assassination/106307006</link><description>Ryan Routh will spend the rest of his life behind bars for his 2024 assassination attempt on the then US presidential hopeful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75ae6551ab5fe840df0155638e8254e7</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics quiz: How well are you prepared for the Games?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/winter-olympics-quiz/106289820</link><description>The Winter Olympics gets underway in Milan Cortina this week — but how much do you know about the Winter Olympics? Test yourself in our fiendish quiz.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f80031d3dc4b6049fe0ed85b109e119b</guid></item><item><title>'Bloodbath' at Washington Post as massive layoffs announced</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/washington-post-layoffs/106307024</link><description>The Jeff Bezos-owned paper, which famously brought down US President Richard Nixon, will drastically cut back in size and lay off workers in all its departments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8394731a7449ead8a495e63eba201e42</guid></item><item><title>A 'ghost airport' and sinkhole highway as Timor-Leste gambles on oil and gas with Greater Sunrise project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/timor-leste-greater-sunrise-project-ghost-airport-and-sinkholes/106303186</link><description>The Greater Sunrise gas project was meant to transform Timor-Leste and bring billions in revenue, but locals are still waiting for the jobs and opportunities that were promised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">603ba36a5b4f815803e7ca0f07a4648c</guid></item><item><title>Attorney-General asked anti-corruption chief to explain himself after Defence ties emerged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/attorney-general-asked-nacc-chief-to-explain-defence-ties/106305764</link><description>Attorney-General Michelle Rowland asked Paul Brereton to explain why his ongoing ties to Defence had not been "adequately" disclosed in a letter sent last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3360d83b4fc62fe0f11eb67adf53c94d</guid></item><item><title>Online safety watchdog says tech giants failing to detect child abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/online-safety-watchdog-says-tech-giants-failing-on-child-abuse/106306564</link><description>Major tech companies including Apple, Google, Meta and Microsoft are still failing to do enough to detect and stop child sexual abuse, eSafety has claimed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ece1344204c760ec445b497d6251da3</guid></item><item><title>Report points to exploitation, Medicare and visa concerns in Pacific islander jobs scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/palm-scheme-report-calls-for-change/106298514</link><description>Changing jobs is a basic right for most people, but it is not so simple for Pacific Australia Labour Mobility workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f21909b4c4949bb2d5b3a261ebd665c</guid></item><item><title>Psychiatrist of Westfield Bondi Junction attacker referred for review by coroner</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/bondi-junction-westfield-stabbing-coronial-inquest-findings/106294950</link><description>Findings from the coronial inquest into the Westfield Bondi Junction stabbing have been handed down, almost two years on from the attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">babc262080a5894c153088a2849da980</guid></item><item><title>In Zak Hilditch's horror movie We Bury the Dead, the zombie apocalypse devastates Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/we-bury-the-dead-movie-interview-zak-hilditch/106298866</link><description>These Final Hours writer and director Zak Hilditch drew on personal tragedy to produce We Bury the Dead, his biggest cinematic epic yet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f08c892351946b5092876fe0022699c</guid></item><item><title>Report calls for Australia to grow security, trade and diplomatic ties with Taiwan because of China's influence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/australia-taiwan-security-trade-ties-should-expand-experts-say/106306736</link><description>Experts say Australia needs to do more to grow its relationship with Taiwan as China works to diplomatically isolate Taipei in the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1330754f2b1cb129cf14b6557beb0af6</guid></item><item><title>Fears SA's endangered glossy black-cockatoo eggs will 'cook' in nesting boxes during heatwave</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/kangaroo-island-glossy-black-cockatoos-heatwaves/106273812</link><description>South Australia's population of a unique subspecies of glossy black-cockatoos is heavily dependent on artificial nesting boxes. That could pose a problem during extreme heat conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92c894ea4f73cd62977ed5ac13ed4426</guid></item><item><title>Mother shares concerns about treatment at Toowoomba Hospital amid culture review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/mothers-raise-concerns-about-treatment-at-toowoomba-hospital/106049878</link><description>A confrontation caught on body-worn security footage in the halls of the Toowoomba Hospital maternity unit highlights concerns raised by local mothers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a112f801e8fcf10c351770673c3ebca7</guid></item><item><title>Grandmother removed from Toowoomba birth suite by security</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/grandmother-removed-from-toowoomba-birth-suite-by-security/106301414</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82f83e6cb6359c2e1b990d90449f47f9</guid></item><item><title>Man allegedly pretended to fire on people near bridge where Bondi terror attack occurred</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/man-charged-over-alleged-offensive-acts-at-bondi-beach-bridge/106307032</link><description>A man accused of mimicking firing on people near the pedestrian bridge where the Bondi terror attack occurred has been denied bail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc69ac43a7239cdacca1fd936c6894a1</guid></item><item><title>Parramatta Eels veteran Josh Addo-Carr urges young teammates to step up after Zac Lomax depature</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/eels-josh-addo-carr-urges-backs-to-step-up-post-zac-lomax/106307096</link><description>Parramatta's next generation of outside backs must step up if they are to fill the void left by Zac Lomax, his ex-teammate Josh Addo-Carr has said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea4e92a9e372c42cef9125691653f930</guid></item><item><title>'Ironic' and 'lazy' AI-generated images shared on Queensland government department social media accounts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/fisheries-queensland-ai-images-social-media/106287728</link><description>A Queensland government department has urged social media users not to trust AI through the use of an AI-generated image.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efa4fbc893136c3c4c2bcc42e263c7db</guid></item><item><title>High Court to consider limiting CSL Australia's liability for accident that sank two tugboats in Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/high-court-challenge-limit-liability-goliath-sunk-tugboat/106300958</link><description>A convention on laws of the high seas will be front and centre in the High Court in Canberra today as the owners of the MV Goliath take on the Tasmanian Ports Corporation over an incident where the ship hit and sank two tugboats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e68db1bb135d243b9616603eaed97ac1</guid></item><item><title>Pauline Hanson returns to Senate seat after seven-day suspension — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/federal-politics-live/106305974</link><description>One Nation Leader Pauline Hanson has returned to her seat in the Senate after she was suspended for seven sitting days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3c0cae8506b4df580cead12886e3518</guid></item><item><title>What are data centres and what do they mean for regional Victoria?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/inside-data-centre-computers-ai-information-storage-servers/105904128</link><description>With the announcement of two new facilities outside of Melbourne, could regional Victoria become a hotspot for data centres?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f298636a4109a23d53086ea1d6b5745</guid></item><item><title>Authorities say Appelbee family's rescue highlights unexpected dangers in WA's South West</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/geographe-bay-water-safety-austin-appelbee/106306336</link><description>Marine Rescue workers tasked with monitoring WA's Geographe Bay say last week's astonishing rescue of a Perth family highlights the dangers facing tourists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13e4bb920220ee89906831f1827453fb</guid></item><item><title>Silver plunges over 14 per cent as ACTU pushes above-inflation wages — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/asx-markets-business-live-news-feb-5-2025/106307192</link><description>Spot silver has hit a new low, crashing to $US75 an ounce, down over 14 per cent, while the ACTU is pushing for "above-inflation" wage increases in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8f184e00425aec1a279ace0f8df7dac</guid></item><item><title>Police launch investigation into sudden death in Toowoomba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/police-launch-investigation-into-sudden-death-in-toowoomba/106307100</link><description>Police have closed part of Bell Street and the Toowoomba bus terminal car park on Chronicle Lane in Toowoomba's CBD as part of the investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b8806170d7bec631fc6c26704d033eb</guid></item><item><title>Mildura residents desperate for investment in train, bus transport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/bus-public-transport-adelaide-mildura-renmark-community-advocacy/106285990</link><description>The Victorian city of Mildura has a population of 54,000 people, yet travelling to the nearest capital city for work or medical appointments can be quite a headache.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80bfab1a48742e289ba8959cafdbd605</guid></item><item><title>What is the difference between a tropical low and cyclone in northern Australia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/meteorologist-explains-tropical-low-cyclone-difference-australia/106299336</link><description>Tropical lows are weaker than tropical cyclones, but a meteorologist explains they can still cause significant damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03da663f1e95f8663d18a36c3196f2a2</guid></item><item><title>Central Queensland conservation group wants to see more transparency on coal mine water releases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/call-for-more-information-on-coal-mine-water-release/106288312</link><description>There were 55 water releases from the region's coal mines in the month of January into the largest catchment draining to the Great Barrier Reef.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ff8693894a0a260e74954e81d5136b2</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine and Russia wrap 'productive' first day of US-backed peace talks in Abu Dhabi, as war rages on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/ukraine-war-negotiations-kyiv-moscow-meet-in-uae/106307234</link><description>The two-day trilateral meeting began after Volodymyr Zelenskyy said Russia had exploited a US-backed energy truce last week to stockpile munitions before attacking Ukraine with a record number of ballistic missiles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">811291e02c4e4915f44141734b103d14</guid></item><item><title>Homeless Whitsunday boaties begin long rebuild after Tropical Cyclone Koji carnage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/homeless-sailors-tropical-cyclone-koji-aftermath/106304140</link><description>Around a dozen boats recovered by Marine Safety Queensland were part-time or permanent liveaboard boats, with boaties in the Whitsundays facing a long journey to find a new permanent home on or off the water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbed372baa692d7226e9b5fc59f9157c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump, gold, interest rates and AI data centres to dominate company reporting season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/donald-trump-gold-interest-rates-ai-reporting-season/106306266</link><description>Australia's mining sector is expected to lead the earnings charge for this reporting season, boosted by signs of a stabilisation in the Chinese economy and a turbo-charged commodities market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56354f78af37bcda67f3e92d68cb1d7b</guid></item><item><title>NRL rookie Sebastian Su'a poised for breakout year after injury-plagued 2025 season with Dolphins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/nrl-rookie-sebastian-su-a-poised-for-breakout-year/106307552</link><description>The work ethic of a former Test fast bowler and the mentoring of an elite prop are inspiring Dolphins rookie Sebastian Su'a's NRL quest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5c998e776a7dca4626b0951980d5bc8</guid></item><item><title>Sydney man, 19, charged over alleged threats to kill Israeli president</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/sydney-teen-charged-threats-to-israel-president-isaac-herzog/106307538</link><description>Darcy Tinning was arrested by AFP officers on Wednesday and charged with making a threat to kill an "internationally protected person".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">710d51ed300bc62b14c2402ac4cb7ddd</guid></item><item><title>Worker's death at Tanami gold mine in Central Australia under investigation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/nt-tanami-mine-newmont-confirms-worker-death-tragic-incident/106307980</link><description>A 47-year-old worker has died following an incident at the Tanami gold mine in remote Central Australia, with police and NT WorkSafe investigating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1662970481b3a89b3a77c8d22c4b591</guid></item><item><title>New resource connects people with organisations on front lines of bushfire relief effort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/resource-connecting-people-with-frontline-bushfire-relief-orgs/106273490</link><description>A new online resource aims to make it easier for people to contribute to bushfire relief efforts across Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd36f19dbab5f9df4c883c9b96a27f9f</guid></item><item><title>Police executing drug raid find deadly snakes, crocodile in alleged makeshift zoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/police-discover-snakes-crocodile-during-kempsey-drug-raid/106307800</link><description>More than 50 reptiles, including a 1.3-metre crocodile, have been seized after police discovered an alleged makeshift zoo during a drug raid on the NSW Mid North Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">192a2b9248295d31e2166b2cd7d961e9</guid></item><item><title>CIA says it will cease publishing the World Factbook, a free online resource used by millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/cia-closes-world-factbook-online-resource/106307724</link><description>A statement on the CIA's website gives no reason for the decision, simply stating that the Factbook has been "sunset" while encouraging readers to "stay curious about the world and find ways to explore it".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4877c5364c33bc1d2ec58b25d642a0a2</guid></item><item><title>Australians in Japan say ski fields are safe after spate of deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/australians-in-japan-say-ski-fields-are-safe/106307558</link><description>Australians working in Japan's ski fields say while the sport has unpredictable risks, there are ways to be prepared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39a03324b4a4d2e1f6d635af5d43a345</guid></item><item><title>Owner of Arnie the German shepherd sentenced over death of dog and misleading police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/arnie-the-dog-owner-nathan-mckeown-sentenced/106307612</link><description>A Queensland man who claimed his dog Arnie had been stolen, despite having left the German shepherd in his car, where it was later found dead, has pleaded guilty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e7e6b683be7e8bfde1224620f0cd213</guid></item><item><title>Two people in custody after alleged Huon Valley home invasion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/two-people-in-custody-after-alleged-huon-valley-home-invasion/106308590</link><description>Police take two people into custody in relation to an alleged early morning home invasion and firearms theft in the Huon Valley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa75d62edb1dff75376f7c6b0aa63ac6</guid></item><item><title>State of Origin 2027 in New Zealand hailed as a boost for rugby league by Kiwi great</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/state-of-origin-2027-in-new-zealand-boost-says-kiwi/106308612</link><description>The NRL's reported landmark move to host a State of Origin match in New Zealand is hailed as "sensational" by Kiwi legend Gary Freeman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">159d849e4617ffdb86ae3e8b97588b9a</guid></item><item><title>Invasion Day bomb declared terror act, as accused's 'pro-white ideology' probed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/perth-invasion-day-rally-attempted-bombing-terrorist-act/106303806</link><description>The attempted bombing of an Invasion Day rally in Perth's CBD last week is declared a terrorist attack by authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bc486c32a0f3eb6459afa4f7641f5a9</guid></item><item><title>Union calls for urgent response after Ashley Youth Detention Centre staff hospitalised</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/incident-at-ashley-youth-prompts-calls-for-urgent-response/106305736</link><description>A union claims management at Tasmania's youth prison did not follow its own short-staffing policy, despite an incident occurring only a day after workers took strike action due to safety concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4482b91e3519213c47b7d439cadcda51</guid></item><item><title>Strict caps on bottled water extraction urged for World Heritage-listed Springbrook</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/water-extraction-caps-at-world-heritage-springbrook/106304388</link><description>A long-awaited study warns that the extraction of bottled water from the World Heritage-listed Springbrook area poses a potential risk to the ancient Gondwana rainforests and should be strictly limited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19d076e599ae81db17a9effaa24af962</guid></item><item><title>Private health insurers take aim at rising specialists fees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/private-health-insurers-take-aim-at-rising-specialists-fees/106308202</link><description>A survey of 4,000 patients finds more than half had an unexpected cost when under a specialist's care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3b29ee24b3af0599b1188251d3a6096</guid></item><item><title>AFL integrity unit looking into why police visited Melbourne Demons player Steven May</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/afl-integrity-unit-looking-into-why-police-visited-steven-may/106309028</link><description>Melbourne veteran Steven May is being investigated by the AFL integrity unit, as the premiership defender stays away from Demons training.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c42c8d49e23a155f085f14d82937f7e5</guid></item><item><title>ACTU pushing 'above-inflation' wage increase in 2026 as real paypackets decline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/actu-pushing-above-inflation-wage-increase-in-2026/106308042</link><description>Australia's biggest employers are under pressure to give their workers pay increases above 4 per cent this year, as real wages go backwards and the union movement ramps up pressure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1561858751d3b34e812d34954a75a67f</guid></item><item><title>Families respond after Westfield Bondi Junction stabbing inquest findings released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/families-react-westfield-bondi-junction-stabbing-inquest/106308886</link><description>Loved ones of victims Ashlee Good and Jade Young have fought back tears responding to findings from the high-profile inquest into the Westfield Bondi Junction stabbing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">971eff173ebca3c3a31f9914d604ef48</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie reads Art of War, Pauline Hanson returns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/andrew-hastie-pauline-hanson-clive-palmer-art-of-war/106294690</link><description>The calamity unfolding in the dissolved Coalition provided a convenient distraction for the government, which should have had a worse week amid an interest rate hike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f8f4cd69aef50acb18d65e06bf186c0</guid></item><item><title>Mother of autistic children shares experience in wake of suspected double murder-suicide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/kalgoorlie-mother-with-two-autistic-children-jo-russell/106306344</link><description>A mother of two autistic children living in regional Western Australia has shared her experience of navigating bureaucracy while caring for children with complex needs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2466f5262b39215d9077d95960b80a1</guid></item><item><title>Lockhart River Mayor Wayne William Butcher pleads guilty to Cairns bail breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/lockhart-river-mayor-wayne-william-butcher-bail-breach/106309858</link><description>A Far North Queensland mayor has pleaded guilty to two counts of breaching his bail conditions after he was found drinking tea in a casino with a person he must avoid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d25d211015b67c4f5a1d5efb7ea9fda9</guid></item><item><title>Old Spirit ferries up sale with new berth 'on track' for October launch, TT-Line says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/spirit-of-tasmania-oct-launch-date-on-track-tt-line/106307332</link><description>Ferry operator TT-Line is confident its two new Spirit of Tasmania vessels will begin operating by October — but it says there is a "risk" its existing ships might not be sold by then.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96626d61393ecd333e4ca7e74aa0b968</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne public housing tower residents win injunction against eviction notices ahead of High Court bid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/melbourne-housing-tower-injunction-against-eviction/106309622</link><description>Homes Victoria will be temporarily halted from evicting remaining residents at three Melbourne public housing towers in Flemington and North Melbourne, after an injunction was issued in Victoria's Court of Appeal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac97e2ca66d531e0cd8f886fcab92deb</guid></item><item><title>Bunnings wins fight to use AI facial recognition tech to combat store crime, opening door for other retailers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/bunnings-wins-ai-facial-recognition-tech-fight/106309308</link><description>Bunnings was reasonably entitled to use AI facial recognition technology to combat crime and staff abuse in its stores, the Administrative Review Tribunal finds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11a50582c492ed335c2d3ebadc4e8d41</guid></item><item><title>Murray-Darling Basin Authority hands down discussion paper ahead of first review in 14 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/murray-darling-basin-authority-plan-review-under-way/106307966</link><description>The Murray-Darling Basin Authority says the basin plan has delivered real benefits, but climate change, disconnected floodplains and poor water quality mean things still need to change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40ca47d8c527baec96da95cd77b458be</guid></item><item><title>NSW government contacts Newcastle Writers Festival about author Randa Abdel-Fattah's inclusion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/nsw-government-newcastle-writers-festival-randa-abdel-fattah/106310270</link><description>The NSW government makes contact with the board of next month's Newcastle Writers Festival about the inclusion of Palestinian-Australian author Randa Abdel-Fattah, the ABC understands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f89720cdcf51ab246cbcc55ed24f0196</guid></item><item><title>Albanese, Ley condemn alleged act of terror targeting Indigenous protesters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/albanese-ley-condemn-alleged-invasion-rally-terror-act/106309170</link><description>The prime minister and opposition leader have both condemned the alleged attempted bombing of an Invasion Day rally more than a week ago, after police revealed it was being prosecuted as a terror incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5627852046870a17972ecd39ceb5004e</guid></item><item><title>Today show host Savannah Guthrie asks for proof her mother is alive in social media video</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/savannah-guthrie-asks-kidnappers-for-proof-of-life-of-mother/106309080</link><description>The Today show host releases a video on Instagram asking for proof her mother is still alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06da074f52fc1bfbf749ec01b7810db8</guid></item><item><title>Democrat victory in Republican stronghold could spell trouble for Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/texas-special-runoff-election-results/106308914</link><description>The US has been gripped by cold weather in recent weeks, but pundits say it is in Texas where hell has truly frozen over. A blue wave just swept a GOP stronghold, and Republicans are very worried.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e651758ff0d99631704edb4c046d58f8</guid></item><item><title>Gus Lamont disappearance from Oak Park Station near Yunta: What has happened so far</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/timeline-of-gus-lamont-oak-park-disappearance/106309554</link><description>It is now more than four months since Gus Lamont went missing from his family's home in South Australia's outback, with the case being declared a major crime on Thursday. Here's what has happened so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c458d64bdef26badd7b278d4e3d5058</guid></item><item><title>How capital gains tax changes could impact you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/how-capital-gains-tax-changes-could-impact-you/106309066</link><description>According to a well-sourced leak, changes to capital gains tax discounts could form the centrepiece of the next federal budget in May. And while the government has downplayed the idea, it has not been ruled out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">566800855cbc95596fa22fe075eeef0e</guid></item><item><title>Union urges Sanjeev Gupta to sell Tahmoor mine as $350m offer revealed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/union-pressure-on-gupta-tahmoor-mine-sale/106309462</link><description>The Mining and Energy Union says a firm $350 million offer is on the table to restart Tahmoor Colliery, warning delays risk the mine's future and hundreds of jobs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc17aa194e049037a72616045ef64b12</guid></item><item><title>Man convicted of grooming one girl and raping another at Canberra Reptile Zoo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/man-convicted-sexual-assault-girls-canberra-reptile-zoo/106310784</link><description>A 26-year-old man has been convicted in the ACT Supreme Court of sexually assaulting two girls at Canberra Reptile Zoo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33ab35ad4d2b0b48e7630e638b33075e</guid></item><item><title>Coroner recommends Ambulance Victoria guideline review following nut allergy death of Max McKenzie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/anaphylaxis-death-nut-allergy-max-mckenzie-box-hill-hospital/106307284</link><description>The coroner could not definitively rule that the anaphylaxis death of 15-year-old Max McKenzie was preventable, despite identifying delays in the teen's medical treatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7fb96224de8dfd3ac5b2522e7071ec1</guid></item><item><title>Thursday Finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/thursday-finance-with-david-chau/106309854</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ac2a52ba0b6ad6ce9ccec04590edbb7</guid></item><item><title>Alleged attempted murder victim gives evidence in Shaun Michael Dunk trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/alleged-attempted-murder-victim-gives-evidence-shaun-dunk-trial/106307666</link><description>A woman who was stabbed multiple times in an alleged attack which killed her colleague at an Adelaide real estate office tells a court of her “fight for life”. Warning: This story contains content some readers may find distressing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">833bc109e15f857ad157f430abc773b2</guid></item><item><title>Nationals issue Ley with reunion counteroffer as deadline looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/nationals-issue-ley-with-reunion-counteroffer/106311354</link><description>The minor party has given the opposition leader terms that one Nationals MP said they did "not expect" would be acceptable in what has been described as a bid to push out her self-imposed deadline.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ad11d81c208265b1abb07a42b719062</guid></item><item><title>Victoria and Queensland lose 17 wickets on day one of MCG Sheffield Shield game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/mcg-sheffield-shield-queensland-victoria-17-wickets-day-one/106311360</link><description>After the two-day Ashes Test raised eyebrows over the MCG pitch, Queensland and Victoria are on track for another swift finish after 17 wickets on day one of their Sheffield Shield clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ed4a66d2d73a61e60062f1dd0187e85</guid></item><item><title>Bondi Junction inquest saw recommendation for supported housing for homeless, some are already benefitting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/bondi-junction-stabbing-inquest-habilis-mental-health-housing/106309484</link><description>An inquest into the Bondi Junction stabbing has recommended that the NSW government support long-term accommodation for homeless people experiencing mental health issues. It's a model that is already finding success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a81fc4ebb5907745acfeae2e974efbeb</guid></item><item><title>Porsches, Maserati allegedly stolen from Melbourne homes during overnight crime spree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/luxury-cars-stolen-melbourne-victoria-police/106311510</link><description>Four young men are charged after allegedly stealing three luxury vehicles from homes across Melbourne on Thursday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e9e07691648c70fb20f7e7cf67d7a2</guid></item><item><title>Germany’s Foreign Minister, Dr Johann Wadephul speaks to 7.30</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/germany-s-foreign-minister-dr-johann-wadephul-speaks-to-7-30/106310976</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e63a25ad087da8d5c90905bad60d5203</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds defeat Jamaica in first netball Test match in Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/diamonds-defeat-jamaica-in-adelaide/106311692</link><description>The Diamonds made a flying start with the initial six goals in a comprehensive 72-41 victory at the Adelaide Entertainment Centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be741f4d1fb677fd340efe1016d77511</guid></item><item><title>Keir Starmer apologises to Epstein's victims for appointing Lord Mandelson as ambassador to US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-05/starmer-apologises-epstein-vicitims-lord-mandelson/106311694</link><description>British Prime Minister Keir Starmer says former ambassador to the US Peter Mandelson lied when asked about the nature of his relationship with convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dd4c3f72b9b1905e38debc10f5639d7</guid></item><item><title>Russian captain of cargo ship Solong jailed over fatal North Sea collision</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/north-sea-collision-captain-jailed/106311942</link><description>A judge describes Vladimir Motin as "an accident waiting to happen" as he hands the Russian national a six-year jail term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87a1a23caacdafe5b4045a3c3b2ae840</guid></item><item><title>New study reveals how stressful footy fandom can be</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/study-reveals-how-stressful-footy-fandom-is/106310960</link><description>A new study reveals how much high-stakes sporting events can get the heart pumping by strapping trackers to over 200 German football fans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c31f01f9ec961ff01d3df42c41faafef</guid></item><item><title>Russia and Ukraine conduct POW swap after latest US-led peace talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/ukraine-russia-talks-united-states-trump/106312078</link><description>The Kremlin says it sees progress and positive movement in the talks, brokered by the United States, as Donald Trump urges both sides to reach a peace deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0de94a61b88dd48205673f167c316711</guid></item><item><title>Valentino Guseli gets snowboard big air wildcard, leaps into final at Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/val-guseli-snowboard-big-air-milano-cortina-winter-olympics/106312046</link><description>Valentino Guseli only found out he had been added to the big air field a couple of hours before the competition start after a rival's injury, but still found a way to make it to the final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84ec8404886766b47120ef6c552e418d</guid></item><item><title>Epstein files reveal the men who looked away after women had spoken up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/jeffrey-epstein-files-allegations-melinda-gates/106308164</link><description>The millions of pages of documents related to the late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein have shone a light on how many influential men were ready to disregard the experiences of countless women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40d57aedebb5b5169d68dfe86d5517cc</guid></item><item><title>Country Fire Authority volunteers speak out about aging firefighting fleets, volunteer shortages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/victoria-country-fire-authority-facing-uncertain-future/106306632</link><description>Volunteer firefighters battling blazes that razed homes and destroyed livestock in Victoria last month say they contended with failing radios and broken down trucks, as questions mount over the viability of the Country Fire Authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1939e2b9e0384eb4bf0efffe062d9060</guid></item><item><title>Positive spin from Liberal leader as retiring MP Sam Groth forces Nepean by-election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/member-for-nepean-sam-groth-resignation-analysis/106309684</link><description>When retiring first-term Liberal Sam Groth told his leader he was quitting politics, forcing a by-election, Jess Wilson didn't try to talk him out of it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d064ed909c98a4fe8b1620483b07061</guid></item><item><title>Today in history, February 6: The Manchester United team that perished in the Munich air disaster of 1958</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/manchester-united-munich-air-disaster-1958/106183032</link><description>On a snowy February afternoon in 1958, the football team that many were calling the greatest that Britain had ever produced stopped to refuel at Munich Airport. The plane would never take off, and the Flowers of Manchester would take years to bloom again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd269141d3e84cd66d24a4d4ebf71ed8</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese signs security treaty with Indonesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/pm-to-sign-security-treaty-with-indonesia/106311374</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has travelled to Jakarta to sign the treaty, which the Australian government calls the "biggest step" the countries have taken together in 30 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">542b9e5f54b180e31559e9247cbd743e</guid></item><item><title>Former attorney-general Mark Dreyfus warned anti-corruption chief to 'manage' or 'avoid' conflicts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/mark-dreyfus-warned-anti-corruption-chief-to-avoid-conflicts/106311478</link><description>A letter from Mark Dreyfus to Paul Brereton provides new insight into the expectations set for the inaugural chief of the anti-corruption watchdog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e67d41ae94005c162be09aa4254b2e2</guid></item><item><title>Effect of capital gains tax changes on housing affordability likely depends on design</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/would-higher-property-taxes-mean-lower-house-prices/106311582</link><description>Labor has not ruled out changes to the capital gains tax discount but wants any tax changes to improve housing affordability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8837e3812457a3afcc82335b9e69139a</guid></item><item><title>Jim Chalmers's appetite for economic reform is about to be tested</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/jim-chalmers-inflation-interest-rates-economy-federal-budget/106294832</link><description>Jim Chalmers could face his biggest test yet as treasurer over the next few months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a3a90492a5e83271ed0e7dfbd2089e3</guid></item><item><title>Winter Olympics 2026: When does it start, how to watch and who is competing in which sports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/winter-olympics-milano-cortina-2026-when-where/106188146</link><description>Australia is tipped for enormous success over the next couple of weeks so now might be a good time to clue yourself up. Here's everything you need to know about the 2026 Winter Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a93b24614f2e1ae879ffc8503e731c6</guid></item><item><title>The questions dogging the search for Gus Lamont after latest police update</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/gus-lamont-update-leaves-more-questions-than-answers/106311214</link><description>Police declared the disappearance of Gus Lamont a major crime due to "a number of inconsistencies and discrepancies" emerging during the four-month investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1798830495f9ff4dfc031d74279bc716</guid></item><item><title>Satellite images reveal build-up of US fighter jets and missile defences ahead of US-Iran nuclear talks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/us-military-escalation-iran-middle-east-nuclear-talks-satellite/106309628</link><description>Ahead of planned nuclear talks between the United States and Iran, satellite imagery reveals how the US is positioning itself for potential military escalation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed602ad892f5d9ee098d6c3222a26202</guid></item><item><title>World Anti-Doping Agency bosses 'will look at' claims of penis enlargement in ski jumping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/wada-will-investigate-ski-jumper-penis-enlargement-allegations/106311706</link><description>The World Anti-Doping Agency will investigate bizarre claims in German newspaper Bild that ski jumpers are injecting substances into their penises to aid aerodynamics — and other stories from the Winter Olympics a day out from the opening ceremony.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84586ef0f66b1f30261a833dd26efe85</guid></item><item><title>US hopes to challenge China's critical minerals dominance with new trading bloc</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/us-pitches-new-critical-minerals-trading-bloc/106309202</link><description>The US is urging dozens of countries to follow Australia's lead and sign on to a plan to stop relying on China for the critical minerals used in modern technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4c34d4de059770202fdc288ddc3883b</guid></item><item><title>Alice Springs powerlifter Jessica Coombe encourages more women to take up the sport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/alice-springs-powerlifter-jessica-coombe/106298346</link><description>What started as a weight loss journey has turned into competitive powerlifting for this Alice Springs mum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b080a9b7129ede9d2a4ab7620e963b5</guid></item><item><title>After the ICE shooting of Renee Nicole Good in Minneapolis, a week of chaos unfolds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/renee-nicole-good-minneapolis-ice-shooting-timeline/106283054</link><description>Renee Good and her wife moved to Minneapolis "to make a better life" with their six-year-old son. But just over two minutes into an encounter with ICE agents she was fatally shot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e825dd4bb27569e03b8e78c060ecdeb</guid></item><item><title>What Israel's President Isaac Herzog has said about Gaza, and why he won't be arrested in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/herzog-will-be-aware-controversy-wont-be-arrested-in-australia/106311734</link><description>When Israel's president lands in Australia this weekend, he can expect an official red carpet treatment. But he will be all too aware of the controversy his visit is generating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ffdecd9e59cf515e239536238754ac7</guid></item><item><title>ATO debt continues to drive record level of calls to small business financial helpline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/debts-to-ato-drive-record-level-of-financial-helpline-calls/106308516</link><description>Financial counsellors say small businesses struggling to pay debts owed to the tax office are driving calls to Australia's Small Business Debt Helpline higher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5e7106c0d32cd232b4538e4271760e1</guid></item><item><title>Mark Parton admits negotiations for a Greens and Liberals coalition were 'very serious'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/parton-admit-negotiations-greens-liberals-coalition-very-serious/106311088</link><description>The leader of the Canberra Liberals has confirmed for the first time that talks with the ACT Greens about forming a coalition to unseat the ACT Labor government were "very serious".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ea0c53bae867582b596c309e271e137</guid></item><item><title>Karnivool's new album In Verses was worth the 13-year wait, bagpipes and all</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/karnivool-unpacks-album-in-verses-bagpipes-mental-health/106307988</link><description>They're one of Australia's most revered heavy acts. And arguably the most patient. Karnivool unpack the 13-year journey to their new album, In Verses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6bdc3938421e42eb84f1f18d410adb7</guid></item><item><title>Savannah Guthrie's missing mother is 'still out there', police say, but no suspects</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/samantha-guthrie-today-mother-still-out-there-police-say/106312206</link><description>US investigators believe the missing mother of Today show host Savannah Guthrie is "still out there" despite having no proof she is still alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3f661ed6f3ea9b584959ea3221e64d7</guid></item><item><title>Late NSW tradie Brett Mckay connected with thousands by sharing cancer battle online</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/brett-mckay-legacy-after-sharing-cancer-battle-via-social-media/106295230</link><description>When NSW tradie Brett Mckay started sharing videos of his cancer journey with his mates on social media, he did not expect thousands of strangers to come along for the ride.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b28afc999a5809b20a0a7c420ae28ce2</guid></item><item><title>NFL confirms Los Angeles Rams vs San Francisco 49ers in Australia at the MCG</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/los-angeles-rams-vs-san-francisco-49ers-nfl-mcg/106312200</link><description>The first regular-season NFL match played on Australian shores has been confirmed as a clash between division rivals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dab234e878786b324a91286b25c958c0</guid></item><item><title>ASX suffers worst day in almost a year in 'panic' sell-off — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/asx-markets-business-news-friday-6-february-live-updates/106312232</link><description>Nearly $70 billion has been wiped off the Australian share market in its worst trading session since the "Liberation Day" sell-off in April 2025. See how the day unfolded and read insights from our business reporters on the ABC News markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95d2e163f643de9fc3d6f43e274be5d4</guid></item><item><title>Nationals counter Ley's offer with two-week frontbench exile — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/federal-politics-live/106310298</link><description>The Nationals have proposed spending another two weeks in exile from the frontbench rather than address the Liberals' non-negotiable conditions for a Coalition reunion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6336bed62f747957f082b887d6fdb45f</guid></item><item><title>Georgia Voll helps Royal Challengers Bengaluru win Indian Women's Premier League</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/royal-challengers-bengaluru-win-indian-women-premier-league/106312236</link><description>Royal Challengers Bengaluru pulled off the biggest successful chase in the Women's Premier League to win their second title in the Indian franchise-based T20 league.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e308434821166760b39b511e513be5cf</guid></item><item><title>Man flown to hospital with burns after assault at Bacchus Marsh property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/man-burnt-in-assault-at-bacchus-marsh/106312170</link><description>Detectives from the Arson and Explosives Squad are investigating an assault that left a man critically injured with burns at Bacchus Marsh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37f1a471c808b219764bff2d38c7bb36</guid></item><item><title>NT treasurer Bill Yan says ballooning $11.7bn debt worries him</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/nt-paying-millions-a-day-to-keep-afloat-bill-yan-stateline/106309650</link><description>The NT Treasurer Bill Yan outlines his plans for the NT's financial future, saying private investment will be key to turning the debt around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">053e01f868ba1a3e41ebb5d1c7728840</guid></item><item><title>Fisheries Minister Jackie Jarvis defends controversial Perth and WA demersal fishing ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/wa-fisheries-minister-jackie-jarvis-defends-demersal-fish-ban/106306094</link><description>A "judgement call" about a permanent commercial fishing ban for demersal species went further than the advice handed to her, WA's Fisheries Minister Jackie Jarvis says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df7ef0deccac81a9af72a209aa445804</guid></item><item><title>WA Premier Roger Cook writes letter to 13yo hero swimmer Austin Appelbee</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/wa-premier-writes-letter-to-13yo-hero-swimmer-austin-appelbee/106311516</link><description>Premier Roger Cook writes to the 13-year-old, who made international headlines after swimming 4 kilometres in rough seas to raise the alarm and save his family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f53f88274bd50f3bd2024fb2f1e946fb</guid></item><item><title>When is the Super Bowl 2026? Here's what to know about American football's biggest game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/super-bowl-how-to-watch-australia-2026/106272636</link><description>Here's everything you need to know about the Super Bowl, including when it will start, how to watch, and who you'll see on the stage at half-time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbcbeb645bbc7b6ddc8463474dbb5762</guid></item><item><title>Pharmacy apologises after customers given wrong medicines, scripts in Broome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/pharmacy-customers-detail-wrong-medicines-and-scripts-in-broome/106308810</link><description>More than a dozen customers have come forward over concerns two Broome chemists have handed out the wrong medications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f538e97e2b860296b05ed825dc97371</guid></item><item><title>NSW chief justice criticises Tony Abbott's comments on Sydney Harbour Bridge protest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/judge-andrew-bell-criticises-tony-abbott-gaza-protest-comments/106308690</link><description>The former prime minister said it should not be for judges to decide when a political protest was justified, which are remarks NSW's top judge called "regrettable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98ab6cec7508f3de2ac09cc3f44222b3</guid></item><item><title>Tristan Peter Ryan faces court after allegedly threatening Prime Minister Anthony Albanese on social media</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/qld-man-beenleigh-court-allegedly-threatening-politicians/106312368</link><description>The court heard the posts included phrases such as "I want your head on a block Albo" and "I want permission to claim your head".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5e2767dac1662f2799f1039aa304fe9</guid></item><item><title>Magnetic fields, psychedelics and ketamine helping to treat the brain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/mental-health-facility-offers-ketamine-psilocybin-treatments/106090572</link><description>A Queensland not-for-profit mental health clinic that delivers novel therapies such as ketamine and psilocybin is expanding its services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">777a273bd12425d8facfba3249d6e2a9</guid></item><item><title>Prosecutors abandon drug trafficking case against Tony Mokbel</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/tony-mokbel-drug-trafficking-charges-abandoned/106312416</link><description>Prosecutors have abandoned a drug trafficking case against underworld figure Tony Mokbel following his release from prison last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba15edf1879c688d4930ef676d0b552f</guid></item><item><title>Skiers rescued from gondola at Gore Mountain in New York</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/skiers-rescued-from-gondola-at-gore-mountain-in-new-york/106312468</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87db8994f172ec26750b369e09ff50c0</guid></item><item><title>Oscar Piastri defends McLaren and says he expects 'fair shot' at F1 title in 2026</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/oscar-piastri-defends-mclaren-expects-fair-shot-at-f1-title/106312458</link><description>Oscar Piastri insists the painful ending to his F1 title bid last season has only strengthened his resolve to be the "nice person" who brings the Formula 1 world drivers' crown back to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f69e6d4d4fe6ae4def48a780606469e8</guid></item><item><title>US-Russia nuclear weapons treaty expires as Trump rejects Moscow's one-year extension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/us-russia-nuclear-weapons-treaty-expires/106312346</link><description>The last remaining nuclear arms pact between Russia and the United States has expired after Donald Trump rejected an offer from his Russian counterpart.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d429e07a7e5037ed4a467628e59a2d3b</guid></item><item><title>Demersal fishing reforms drive fish and chip price rise on WA's south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/fish-and-chip-prices-increase-wa-demersal-fishing-ban/106296470</link><description>The two-time winner of Australia's Best Takeaway Fish and Chips says it has been forced to increase prices considerably following Western Australia's demersal fishing reforms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd1a023e56ad7e334fe96734f82e30a1</guid></item><item><title>Two people charged over domestic violence murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/two-people-charged-over-domestic-violence-murder/106312740</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eef7ad5d95f899d2d1b8a5232869bb52</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Jewish leader wants stronger crackdown on symbols, flags, and slogans in wake of Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/qld-jewish-board-of-deputies-bondi-attack-antisemitism/106310388</link><description>Queensland Jewish Board of Deputies president Jason Steinberg has called on the state government to ramp up anti-hate laws in the wake of last year's Bondi terror attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">657fe1e021667e15565d5bcf8e958757</guid></item><item><title>Louvre releases photos of squashed crown abandoned by jewel heist gang</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/louvre-heist-empress-eugenie-crown-to-be-restored/106312526</link><description>The thieves who robbed the famed Paris museum last October dropped the diamond and emerald-studded crown as they escaped, leaving it crushed and broken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80c91de186b4aa4f509ce7c72582cf12</guid></item><item><title>Beyond the Songs Inside: After the applause</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/beyond-the-songs-inside-documentary/106032528</link><description>Creative prison programs are celebrated for their ability to heal and transform incarcerated people. But are they enough to break the cycle?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">522012622427958b8365731ca8a4abfe</guid></item><item><title>Questions raised over $93 million investment in WA school with 30 per cent attendance rate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/roebourne-school-low-attendance-lands-93-million-rebuild/106232702</link><description>By the end of 2026 the WA government and Woodside will have spent over $93 million on Roebourne District High School and its 141 enrolled students. But last year only one in four upper school students attended.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cdd919ebf3696cf88d426b1371b09e7</guid></item><item><title>Man shot dead by police after suspected domestic-related stabbing on NSW Mid North Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/forster-fatal-shooting-stabbing-critical-incident/106313028</link><description>Police say a man shot dead by an officer was armed with a knife and chainsaw when he stabbed a woman during an earlier assault in Tuncurry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dc46f966645a6620d1b34cd8edf7b8e</guid></item><item><title>Grandmother removed from Toowoomba birth suite by security</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/grandmother-removed-from-toowoomba-birth-suite-by-security/106312824</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7707483e20eab63b8f53e40475883021</guid></item><item><title>Plenty of barramundi expected to be caught this year after Queensland's wild weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/fishers-hopeful-wild-weather-will-mean-plenty-of-barramundi/106299924</link><description>Commercial fishers are hopeful for an abundance of barramundi after heavy rainfall from ex-Tropical Cyclone Koji on the east coast and ongoing flooding in the Gulf of Carpentaria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9e1f3269c5f4e9ebc2e6800496974a1</guid></item><item><title>NSW Liberal leader Kellie Sloane talks Chris Minns, polls, slogan bans and Bondi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/nsw-liberals-kellie-sloane-talks-minns-polls-slogans-and-bondi/106310818</link><description>The leader of the NSW opposition says the trait behind Premier Chris Minns's popularity is also his greatest weakness, declaring the Coalition is "absolutely in the game" to win next year's state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">799edd3b53920580ddc28a03d66a91d5</guid></item><item><title>French authorities sink tonnes of cocaine bound for Australia, then release suspects</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/french-authorities-sink-five-tonnes-of-cocaine/106307438</link><description>French authorities intercept a ship carrying five tonnes of cocaine bound for Australia, before releasing the vessel and its crew.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9429ea7a44b7fd6eb152b561ab54a17</guid></item><item><title>No sign of Dezi Freeman as latest search ends in Mount Buffalo National Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/latest-dezi-freeman-manhunt-ends-at-mount-buffalo/106312280</link><description>Detectives say they will not give up on finding Victorian fugitive Dezi Freeman, accused of killing two police officers and injuring a third.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">160ebf8795092502f79fbbe808695189</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police wrap up five-day search for Dezi Freeman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/victoria-police-wrap-up-five-day-search-for-dezi-freeman/106312492</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">980e52b8e755e4714aea6a625fb5f178</guid></item><item><title>Terrorist act declaration for Invasion Day attempted bombing shows WA has changed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/wa-will-never-be-the-same-after-invasion-day-terror-act-charged/106311080</link><description>It will take time and significant effort to repair relationships with the Indigenous community amid the fallout from last week's attempted bombing in the Perth CBD — but other growing rifts in society will be even harder to mend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23f6e3d28b465ad95a9a20c73b8a09a8</guid></item><item><title>How sport was both healing and isolating in the aftermath of a violent sexual assault</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/blathnaid-raleigh-sports-role-in-sexual-assault-aftermath/106308960</link><description>Sport was both healing and isolating in the aftermath of a violent sexual assault for Irishwoman Bláthnaid Raleigh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb52898cf37b9984cba0ea4038941668</guid></item><item><title>Parton confirms serious Greens–Liberals talks to bring down ACT Labor</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/act-parton-confirms-serious-greens-liberals-coalition-talks/106313852</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5865694e87535cb6ad47b28036117399</guid></item><item><title>Gus Lamont's grandparents 'absolutely devastated' by major crime declaration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/gus-lamont-grandparents-release-statement/106314122</link><description>The grandparents of missing four-year-old boy Gus Lamont say the family has "cooperated fully with the investigation and want nothing more than to find Gus and reunite him with his mum and dad".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61b66feeae95a94497e72683ac842ff0</guid></item><item><title>Australia's surging expectations at the Winter Olympics come thanks to Geoff Henke's strident advocacy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/winter-olympics-success-for-australia-geoff-henke-revolution/106302018</link><description>Australia is hoping Milano Cortina 2026 will be its most successful Winter Olympics in history. The reason for Australia's winter sports surge has its roots in a 70-year-old snubbing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">864e05b9f59b0989d860aae75009df3d</guid></item><item><title>The easiest way to clean your microwave and a common mistake to avoid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/what-is-the-best-way-to-clean-a-microwave/106307346</link><description>When was the last time you cleaned your microwave? According to experts, it's actually a lot simpler than cleaning other appliances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b708e459302ab8131d3d781a896a62ad</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Mitchell expected to form into category two system in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/tropical-cyclone-mitchell-forecast-pilbara-kimberley/106310802</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says Tropical Cyclone Mitchell has a high chance of forming into a category two system, bringing destructive winds and heavy rain to northern WA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee400f88b198bb7c1d1db47c86f20493</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia's government directs education funds to meals program as teachers struggle on low wages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/indonesia-government-directs-education-funds-to-free-meals/106307002</link><description>Temporary teachers in Indonesia paid low wages criticise a government decision to direct one third of yearly education funding to the president's flagship free meals program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06d0ac084c483586e077bca8379edf61</guid></item><item><title>Minneapolis man Kyle Wagner charged with threatening and cyberstalking ICE officers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/minneapolis-man-charged-cyberstalking-ice/106313730</link><description>A 37-year-old activist has been arrested for what the US Justice Department says is cyberstalking and threatening to kill or assault ICE officers involved in the crackdown in Minnesota.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00ae038dfa79533647ce610afffb023f</guid></item><item><title>Police investigating after unique Pokemon cards stolen from Canberra store</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/act-pokemon-cards-stolen-from-collectors-colloseum-anu/106313262</link><description>The owner of Collectors Colloseum in Canberra says he believes about $150,000 worth of trading cards was stolen overnight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">675dd4c5d354ae6a5a29aee2f809d0ad</guid></item><item><title>Brodie Jake Dewar faces upgraded charge of manslaughter after Labor identity Tim Picton's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/charge-upgraded-to-manslaughter-for-tim-picton-alleged-attacker/106313060</link><description>The man accused of a one-punch attack on former Labor strategist Tim Picton, who died in hospital last month, has his charge upgraded to manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61de2fdf6803039343685d247b1ee662</guid></item><item><title>Premier Chris Minns says Newcastle Writers Festival 'crazy' to invite author Randa Abdel-Fattah</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/randa-abdel-fattah-author-to-attend-newcastle-writers-festival/106312828</link><description>The festival's director said Dr Abdel-Fattah was invited in August last year and denied the state government pressured her to remove the writer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6e1886c2439b2a6c3591dab671487e5</guid></item><item><title>WA author Craig Silvey has child exploitation bail conditions altered after complaining of media attention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/craig-silvey-court-appearance-bail-conditions-altered/106312848</link><description>WA children's author Craig Silvey gets his bail conditions altered by a Perth court after complaining of "significant media attention" since being charged with child exploitation offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">863da9d2b143ceee4249717f0ee1f2da</guid></item><item><title>Nancy Guthrie and siblings' video response to mother's abduction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/nancy-guthrie-and-siblings-video-response-to-mother-s-abduction/106315054</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9f4584533969cd8851a2298379933d3</guid></item><item><title>Jacinta Allan backs Kyneton footballers to find new league amid appeal controversy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/kyneton-women-football-controversy-footy-premier-jacinta-allan/106300624</link><description>A former football administrator has criticised AFL Victoria's decision not to allow a club to join a women-only league in Central Victoria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b10161a418fadda2eadec065ef94304</guid></item><item><title>Police to resume searching for Celine Cremer items at Waratah after bones discovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/police-to-resume-searching-celine-cremer-waratah-tasmania/106314944</link><description>Tasmania Police will again head into thick bushland to continue searching for more items in the area where Belgian tourist Celine Cremer vanished in 2023 — after the shock discovery of bones last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc62a6cfa45051ba56cce33aab397cae</guid></item><item><title>Handful of residents remain in Daly River amid impending major flooding, as hundreds evacuated to Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/nt-daly-river-flood-handful-of-residents-stay-after-evacuation/106313380</link><description>Some long-term residents have decided to stay behind in Daly River to help amid impending major flooding, after more than 200 people were evacuated to Darwin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2206b76eb8bd7df0127affd68712616</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's free influenza vaccine program to return this year with nasal spray for children aged two to five</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/free-flu-vaccine-program-with-nasal-spray-for-children/106314974</link><description>The program — which will run from March to September — will provide free flu vaccinations, including a nasal spray option for children aged two to five years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6535ffc1b447b733a2730a130f983211</guid></item><item><title>Japan's cherry blossom festival cancelled due to fear of overtourism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/japan-cherry-blossom-festival-cancelled-due-to-overtourism/106314678</link><description>The blossom festival, which brings about 200,000 people each year, has been cancelled because "the quiet lives of local residents are threatened".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50b57a281f778f4bb1092e857d61ed91</guid></item><item><title>Inside Ryan Wesley Routh's plan to kill Donald Trump and 'up-end American democracy'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/ryan-wesley-routh-life-sentence-assassination-attempt/106310824</link><description>As Donald Trump arrived at a golf course in September 2024, a would-be assassin had already been lying in wait for almost 12 hours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bc1b1d712ae3a0abb9c8f4d6d4fe3d7</guid></item><item><title>RecipeTin Eats' Nagi Maehashi is normalising taking time off for pets. Here's why that matters.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/recipetineats-nagi-maehashi-time-off-work-care-for-dog-dozer/106313752</link><description>Experts say our pets have become such an important part of our lives that it's important to take a step back from responsibilities, if possible, when they are sick or dying.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9cbd7b56d7377cd2c066ce8db744bca</guid></item><item><title>The 25-year-old man was arrested at a home in Morayfield on Thursday.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/extremist-material-arrest/106315742</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff3bc33253c8d99bb64722d865b2e57d</guid></item><item><title>Man faces court charged with possessing extremist material after phone search at Brisbane Airport</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/extremist-material-charge-after-phone-search-brisbane-airport/106315576</link><description>Police allege a 25-year-old man intercepted at Brisbane International Airport had violent extremist material on his phone, after an investigation into an alleged Nazi flag delivery to the man.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">507bf1b576bc371496a5d69577c3b4b6</guid></item><item><title>Bullock says government spending not sole factor pushing inflation higher as political fight heats up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/rba-governor-refuses-to-blame-government-for-rising-inflation/106313266</link><description>RBA governor Michele Bullock has refused to blame the Albanese government for rising inflation, as a political fight breaks out in the wake of the bank's rate hike.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c98b12981d05c59ed145353062642772</guid></item><item><title>Josh Hazlewood out of T20 World Cup with injury in another blow to Australia's hopes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/josh-hazlewood-out-of-t20-world-cup-injury-australia/106315684</link><description>Josh Hazlewood is ruled out of Australia's T20 World Cup campaign as he continues to recover from the injuries which kept him from playing in the summer's Ashes series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc2eaa2ecdfd92d77e913bc4aef7b367</guid></item><item><title>Perth council in 'respectful' disagreement over spending choices on meals and rent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/serpentine-jarrahdale-council-spending-questioned/106315816</link><description>A newly elected councillor in the Shire of Serpentine-Jarrahdale, in Perth's outer-eastern fringe, accuses the shire of making poor spending choices with ratepayers' money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9179207dbb2aaf3a119581498699ea39</guid></item><item><title>Patrol boats out of action in Cairns shipyards as foreign fishers reach Australian shores</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/patrol-boats-out-of-water-amid-illegal-foreign-fishing-influx/106309428</link><description>A "continuous" influx of illegal foreign fishing boats in Queensland waters coincides with at least two of the nation's fleet of patrol boats being out of commission.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4161f0b872e22c9609c84a3991e94649</guid></item><item><title>Light plane crashes into ocean at Goolwa South on South Australia's south coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/light-plane-crash-at-goolwa-south/106316008</link><description>The Australian Transport Safety Bureau says it has begun an investigation into a crash involving a single-engine Cessna aeroplane which has "collided with water".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9d6ef2428367d98d4d26641250d7829</guid></item><item><title>Why it took police nine days to declare the Invasion Day attempted bomb attack in Perth terrorism</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/process-to-declare-invasion-day-alleged-attack-terrorism-/106314916</link><description>When a homemade fragment bomb was allegedly thrown into a crowd on January 26, it took nine days for it to be declared an act of terrorism. The WA police commissioner explains why, as Indigenous leaders raise concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3aa7ffedfadafcc72701809222cd8964</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Snook, The Newsreader and Bring Her Back triumph at AACTA Awards — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/aacta-awards-2026-live-blog-winners-sarah-snook-celeste-barber/106295178</link><description>Australia's answer to the Oscars — the AACTAs — lit up the Gold Coast tonight, with horror Bring Her Back and The Narrow Road to the Deep North dominating.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">473742d5b25ca33648f2c7c0647748d5</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire warning downgraded for blaze in Darlington, Helena Valley in Perth's eastern suburbs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/emergency-warning-issued-for-bushfire-in-perth-hills/106315940</link><description>Fire authorities downgrade a bushfire in Darlington and Helena Valley as it becomes stationary but not controlled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1099bec1413e09a0f9f36833cf4aed4</guid></item><item><title>Student allegedly raped by Hobart teacher in 1980s disclosed concerns, court told</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/hobart-matriculation-college-student-alleged-rape-trial/106314120</link><description>A student who was allegedly raped by a Hobart teacher in the 1980s was told to focus on her studies after raising concerns with the teacher's behaviour, a court has heard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">699c796ee3d839d6dceb2b50fb9f7c92</guid></item><item><title>Senior Russian military official in hospital after being shot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/russian-lieutenant-general-vladimir-alexeyev-shot/106316214</link><description>Lieutenant General Vladimir Alexeyev, a senior Russian military official, has been rushed to hospital after being shot in Moscow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe110178526afd790180e28c5610e97b</guid></item><item><title>Accused murderer Shaun Michael Dunk told police he wanted to kill 'a few people', court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/shaun-michael-dunk-murder-trial-police-interview/106315738</link><description>A recorded police interview reveals that a man accused of killing a woman at a real estate business in Adelaide was not satisfied with his alleged murder.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51f8e90094cc16ff3b586f8adca7dbbc</guid></item><item><title>Friday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/friday-finance-with-david-chau/106316284</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">442d545004b23100d0c522b6883e3f48</guid></item><item><title>Pentagon reportedly asked to probe SpaceX for potential Chinese ownership seen as a 'national security threat'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/pentagon-asked-to-probe-spacex-chinese-ownership/106311868</link><description>Chinese investment in Elon Musk's company SpaceX has been cited as a "national security threat", according to senators Elizabeth Warren and Andy Kim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a14c66ba0a91388f5002547f0fc8165b</guid></item><item><title>Firefighters battle the blaze in Darlington and Helena Valley, east of Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/firefighters-battle-the-blaze-in-darlington-east-of-perth/106316272</link><description>Follow the latest headlines from ABC News, Australia's most trusted media source, with live events, audio and on-demand video from the national broadcaster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b3c5bc8650cdb374e76ee79b6ee13bb</guid></item><item><title>Suicide bombing at Islamabad mosque kills at least 31 people and wounds 169 others</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/explosion-muslim-mosque-in-islamabad/106316320</link><description>The explosion rocked the mosque on the outskirts of Pakistan's capital during Friday prayer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ec0cdbd411b3d935607bc74648fd1f4</guid></item><item><title>Evidence concludes in inquest into psychiatric patient's death at Alice Springs Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/kumanjayi-brogus-inquest-nt-alice-springs-hospital-death/106309452</link><description>A coronial inquest has heard that the death of a 34-year-old mother who was repeatedly sedated during a schizophrenic episode was "entirely preventable".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e37e11908baa219401597f522da46fe7</guid></item><item><title>AACTA 2026 winners list: Gory horror wins best film, Jacob Elordi drama dominates TV</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-06/aactas-winners-list-jacob-elordi-key-moments/106315590</link><description>Directors Danny and Michael Philippou clean up at the 2026 AACTA awards, taking home 10 statues for their chilling horror film Bring Her Back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">180771fbc8035cfdbeeb3540d53fab91</guid></item><item><title>Tropical Cyclone Mitchell forms off Western Australia's Pilbara coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/wa-pilbara-warnings-cyclone-mitchell/106314534</link><description>Residents along WA's Pilbara coast have been warned to expect gale force winds and heavy rain over the next 48 hours as Cyclone Mitchell drifts down the coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b97a227aadadcc4688c45e3310259768</guid></item><item><title>Small plane crashes in Normanton, north-west Queensland, starting grass fire and knocking out power</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/plane-crash-normanton-gulf-of-carpentaria/106316536</link><description>Only the pilot was on board, police said, adding that his injuries remain unknown and that the response to the incident is ongoing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">176d16328e32da70f02c6ad0f7168c27</guid></item><item><title>Daisy Thomas, competing without an ACL, suffers heavy crash at Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/daisy-thomas-acl-milano-cortina-2026-winter-olympics/106316542</link><description>Australian freestyle skier Daisy Thomas, who is competing at the 2026 Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games without an ACL, suffers a heavy fall in slopestyle training.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f025e657abeae9134b373e8a2e58473</guid></item><item><title>Indirect talks between US and Iran finish in Oman with indication they will continue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-07/iran-us-nuclear-talks-in-oman-finish/106316594</link><description>The two countries held talks mediated by Oman in Muscat after weeks of tensions between Washington and Tehran.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9579e92f07d53c571622ec4a32ba20d5</guid></item></channel></rss>