<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 07:46:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>First Guardian, Shield superannuation disasters expose deep flaws in Australia's $4.3 trillion retirement system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/first-guardian-shield-collapse-asic-and-superannuation-flaws/105783328</link><description>The failed First Guardian and Shield schemes have cost about 12,000 Australians more than $1 billion in retirement savings and exposed deep flaws in how Australia's $4.3 trillion superannuation sector is regulated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b80687a0c984dcbca73fbbe0b5a3dbb7</guid></item><item><title>Carnival of Flowers visitors brace for wet weather while smelling the roses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/storms-set-to-dampen-toowoomba-carnival-of-flowers/105790282</link><description>Visitors flocking to Queensland's Darling Downs for the annual Carnival of Flowers in Toowoomba are advised to take an umbrella, with thunderstorms forecast for the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb4dfb7296770565076ab2a1302356b1</guid></item><item><title>Surprise La Niña hints at another wet and stormy Australian summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/la-nina-hints-at-wet-stormy-australian-summer/105790134</link><description>Australia's key drivers of weather variability are stacking up to produce another wet, severe-weather season, with an increased risk of flooding, thunderstorms and cyclones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a42ca16638c1124b410a58f0cccc3ecf</guid></item><item><title>Mount Isa waits for '11th-hour' decision on financial support for copper smelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/mount-isa-copper-smelter-glencore-negotiations/105787756</link><description>Copper production is on the chopping block in outback Queensland, with mining giant Glencore about to decide on its future. What is the cost of losing a legacy industry?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6389a1b1230c562f480fd57d5cbe967b</guid></item><item><title>Miranda Tapsell and Gwilym Lee show it 'takes a village' to raise a child in Top End Bub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/top-end-bub-miranda-tapsell-gwilym-lee/105775286</link><description>Miranda Tapsell and Gwilym Lee return to their characters from the hit movie, Top End Wedding, to take on parenthood in the TV series, Top End Bub.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6b3a94883d6882b00c7e6f5904787b6</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Albanese seizes on Ley's climate slip up — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/federal-politics-live-sept-19/105790890</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has seized on remarks made by Opposition Leader Sussan Ley about Australia's climate targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d8c53f5355ddd10031e0a3f823e1972</guid></item><item><title>AFL finals fever takes hold as fans line up to buy tickets offline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/fans-line-up-for-afl-grand-final-tickets/105783152</link><description>AFL fans fed up with the online ticketing system have opted to line up in person days in advance to secure their finals tickets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae67e6d9e7b54c457bfa6e91a30fd4f7</guid></item><item><title>Young members bring new life to the Rural Fire Service</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/rural-fire-service-brigades-seek-new-members/105778996</link><description>Nearly a quarter of all western NSW Rural Fire Service volunteers are older than 70, but some younger recruits are urging others to follow in their footsteps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a9645dec99c6b79501e9b7ecffcd0c1</guid></item><item><title>No live export ships coming for WA sheep amid high prices, looming ban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/no-live-sheep-export-ships-wa-ban-looming/105789752</link><description>Market dynamics are stopping live export ships from coming to WA for the rest of the year, raising the prospect of an official end to the trade years before a legislated ban is enforced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24596fcbd14ee045fa2b692080145ca9</guid></item><item><title>Queensland government commits $4.5 million for locust control as swarms intensify</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/outback-locust-control-funding-queensland-graziers/105787162</link><description>As the native pest destroys crops and pasture across outback Queensland, graziers say authorities must move swiftly to tackle them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2e44afff23dbf4b7b4c4a66888af068</guid></item><item><title>Missing sailor Hartwell Champagne's siblings refuse to give up hope after boat found</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/hartwell-champagne-missing-sailor-siblings-speak/105789904</link><description>Hartwell Champagne's sister and brother are desperate to know what happened to the experienced US mariner whose sailboat was found stuck on a remote Queensland beach without him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2382d064f7190f6929c723d0e027ea55</guid></item><item><title>Water Corporation says it got advice wrong on Port Hedland water supply</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/port-hedland-water-supply-at-capacity/105789308</link><description>The state-owned utility says advice that Port Hedland does not have enough water available to support major development was given in error.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48f23c509f4c2d1738afdb51e51b8e70</guid></item><item><title>Gippsland farmer blocks AusNet maintenance workers from entering property</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gippsland-farmer-ausnet-transmission-line-dispute/105767192</link><description>A Victorian farmer who has hosted transmission lines on his property for decades says he is sick of maintenance workers damaging his property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">567d67427b571a1d541a4aceb24ac48b</guid></item><item><title>Australian Submarine Agency lobbies Fremantle locals amid protest over AUKUS defence hub</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/submarine-agency-lobbies-fremantle-locals-amid-aukus-protest/105791174</link><description>A push to earn the public's trust over a defence hub south of Perth by the Australian Submarine Agency draws protesters and sceptical residents in Fremantle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8095393b39a51688425e02f38c8b989</guid></item><item><title>Erin Patterson trial doctor Chris Webster stands by 'sociopath' comments despite AHPRA sanction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/ahpra-sanctions-chris-webster-calling-erin-patterson-sociopath/105790942</link><description>The doctor who called triple murderer Erin Patterson a "crazy bitch" and a "sociopath" has been sanctioned by AHPRA, but says he does not regret making the comments about the mushroom murderer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a747bc2c91804b7477f5a7d7cec6d86a</guid></item><item><title>Warm currents bring tens of thousands of giant yellowfin tuna to NSW South Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/unprecedented-yellowfin-tuna-season-south-coast/105784426</link><description>Fishers are reporting an unprecedented number of yellowfin tuna travelling from the tropics to the NSW South Coast, causing "mayhem" and excitement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d71fe5d9066c0d4471f7c22b0f966ba4</guid></item><item><title>Gardens of Stone State Conservation Area walks open path to incredible vistas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/gardens-of-stone-state-conservation-area-walks-open/105788604</link><description>New South Wales National Parks and Wildlife staff have spent 18 months transforming eroded vehicle trails into rehabilitated walks, opening previously inaccessible viewpoints.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0da6f8f660e8929fd1ce6563b317648c</guid></item><item><title>QCOAL's Cook Colliery coal mine in central Queensland to close half of operation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/cook-colliery-coal-mine-to-close-half-of-operation/105792906</link><description>A third Queensland coal miner has confirmed job cuts as it prepares to close one of its underground mine sites, with the company also putting the blame on rising costs and state government royalties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adae0677efe1894effb74c23021af5ba</guid></item><item><title>Rabbits cause 'devastating' damage to Junee cemetery in southern NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/rabbits-cause-devastating-damage-to-junee-cemetery-southern-nsw/105792784</link><description>The Junee Shire Council says it is battling a rabbit problem, which forced a recent closure of the town's main cemetery for a week, including on Father's Day, for a baiting program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6e24632645222977003b4a6af3561fc</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos discovery further delays Willyama High School demolition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/demolition-of-mouldy-willyama-high-school-delayed-by-asbestos/105733678</link><description>Nearly two years after a mould-infested high school was closed indefinitely, high-risk friable asbestos has caused further delays to its demolition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a23e41ae074ff173d5db5c3d17aa081</guid></item><item><title>RONA. weaves together country, colonialism and club music on new EP It's All Here</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/rona-its-all-here-ep-bush-beats-country-colonialism-club-music/105758094</link><description>This Kaytetye producer has a fresh take on the space race that draws from First Nations knowledge and culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f63cbfd798f6826103c82f171f571494</guid></item><item><title>Russell Vale Mine Shaft 4 to trial Green Gravity renewable energy technology</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/russell-vale-mine-shaft-4-to-trial-green-gravity/105780830</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89d1b1e00372ede47986a5b7fb9f02ce</guid></item><item><title>Green Gravity secures old coal mine shaft to test gravitational energy storage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/green-gravity-deal-old-mine-shaft-gravitational-energy-storage/105782756</link><description>A disused coal mine in Wollongong will be the first test site for a renewable energy company that lowers weights down old mine shafts to spin turbines and create electricity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">624bc063af2f9be2f1ecc1717cd562e3</guid></item><item><title>China urges Papua New Guinea not to exclude other countries after it signed 'Pukpuk' communique with Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/china-warns-papua-new-guinea-against-bilateral-deal-australia/105794018</link><description>China has urged Papua New Guinea not to sign any deal that might exclude or restrict third parties from cooperating with the Pacific nation, as Australia scrambles to clinch a landmark defence treaty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad04d0391ea73681a5f0351d55692b32</guid></item><item><title>Weekly news quiz: A royal visit, a glitzy award show and a new city plays host to Laneway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/september-19-friday-news-quiz/105788054</link><description>A lot happened this week. Have you been paying attention?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62ecd5fbe8b87d12bdb2cd9e003b1e8d</guid></item><item><title>Cowboys prepare to make NRLW finals debut against Sharks in Townsville</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/nrlw-north-queensland-cowboys-play-sharks-in-first-finals-match/105790490</link><description>As the Cowboys eye the path to premiership glory ahead of their sudden-death semifinal against the Sharks, they are also creating pathways off field for the next generation of NRLW stars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45bc33d0af030a85b06c99d0ea5dc2f8</guid></item><item><title>Bus driver pleads not guilty to dangerous driving over triple-fatal collision in Gumlu</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bus-driver-in-gumlu-fatal-pleads-not-guilty-to-dangerous-driving/105792662</link><description>A Townsville bus driver involved in a crash that killed three women in north Queensland last year pleads not guilty to dangerous driving causing death or grievous bodily harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">970c592c33595cd809efea0f4925bf86</guid></item><item><title>Former police officer sentenced over perjury in NRL star Jack de Belin's rape case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/ex-police-officer-avoids-jail-for-perjury-in-de-belin-rape-case/105789796</link><description>A former police officer received a 12-month intensive community correction order after he lied about accessing privileged text messages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21518a52dfd7cac5d30c94281cb36bdb</guid></item><item><title>Late-night hosts call out 'unitary intimidation' in aftermath of Jimmy Kimmel's axing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/stephen-colbert-seth-meyers-jon-stewart-back-jimmy-kimmel/105794466</link><description>Jimmy Kimmel's fellow late-night stars accuse the Trump administration of overriding free speech with the indefinite axing of the ABC America host, as parent company, Walt Disney, faces growing protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2f64fab37da9ee4ace2388f587b1eab</guid></item><item><title>Hakyung Lee, mother accused of killing children, had a 'disease of the mind', defence expert tells court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/hakyung-lee-suitcase-murders-auckland-new-zealand/105781562</link><description>Hakyung Lee has been charged with murdering her children and has pleaded not guilty by reason of insanity after leaving their bodies in an Auckland storage facility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">690cb00a0c2ca94e57c34909bfc58001</guid></item><item><title>Driver, bus company added as cross-defendants in wedding bus crash class action</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/class-action-seeks-damages-after-fatal-greta-bus-crash/105793458</link><description>Jailed bus driver Brett Button and the bus company that employed him have been added as defendants in a class action stemming from a crash that killed 10 people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">65dfe5148085e247e6293ae5a2790844</guid></item><item><title>What to know about the Macrons' legal bid to prove the French first lady was not born a man</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/what-to-know-about-macrons-defamation-suit-against-candace-owens/105794900</link><description>Emmanuel Macron and his wife, Brigitte Macron, have said they intend to provide evidence in court to disprove a right-wing influencer's claims the French first lady is transgender.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4503c882debdf66e431a20c149a3de3b</guid></item><item><title>Bruce Lehrmann applies for Toowoomba rape complainant's phone download as court hears some evidence may be missing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/bruce-lehrmann-toowoomba-rape-complainant-mobile-phone/105792890</link><description>Mr Lehrmann is facing two charges of rape, alleged to have occurred in Toowoomba in 2021. He's indicated he intends to plead not guilty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74c1ad5180bcd48cd8a70cf3751c0111</guid></item><item><title>Sharks vow not to taunt Raiders in sudden-death NRL semifinal as minor premiers look to bounce back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/nrl-cronulla-sharks-canberra-raiders-semi-final/105795410</link><description>Cronulla suggests it will not niggle Canberra in Saturday night's semifinal, despite the Brisbane Broncos successfully getting under the Raiders' skin in their thrilling one-point win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de811a022c87a3d1a6baef74c8c54ce6</guid></item><item><title>How to build a flourishing garden in a courtyard or smaller space</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/how-to-create-a-garden-with-not-much-space-or-sun/105763316</link><description>Living in a smaller space doesn't mean you can't have a lush garden. Here's how to rejuvenate your garden with some easy tips.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10fca8a72dcf1eb2dd616158042c2c3b</guid></item><item><title>Varroa mite could still be in SA despite removal of infected hives, PIRSA says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/varroa-mite-threat-south-australia-pirsa/105787606</link><description>PIRSA says there is a chance the deadly parasite remains in the state where it was detected for the first time earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">199d5d292dcbe93495cf2534c11fa8a2</guid></item><item><title>Justin Holbrook arrives at Newcastle Knights after club's wooden spoon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/newcastle-knights-coach-justin-holbrook-arrives-club/105787242</link><description>Justin Holbrook has started his tenure as Newcastle head coach, tasked with turning the struggling NRL side around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da5ef0727b375ae392cde4c88789e5ee</guid></item><item><title>AFLW great Daisy Pearce aiming to take down former club Demons with Eagles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/aflw-daisy-pearce-west-coast-eaglers-melbourne-demons/105795842</link><description>With a West Coast Eagles squad intent of reaching the finals, coach Daisy Pearce has the club she captained to a premiership in her sights this weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4489526b70edc342d88d5fdd23730376</guid></item><item><title>NT attorney-general accused of hiding potential conflict of interest in link to hit-and-run driver</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/nt-attorney-general-related-to-hit-run-driver-jake-danby/105793244</link><description>The Northern Territory's attorney-general is facing backlash after failing to publicly declare a potential conflict of interest regarding a fatal hit-and-run driver before court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">595c64791f195e8a4086a0b80f352e3a</guid></item><item><title>Coronial inquiry into death of newborn Thea Flaskett concludes with family impact statement read</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/qld-thea-flaskett-inquest-concludes-final-day/105795202</link><description>The mother of the "miracle baby" who died hours after her birth read out a family impact statement to the court, on the final day of a coronial inquiry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c9dab527e8a094111904e4c9a6774fd</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man charged with murder after assault victim dies of injuries in hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/act-man-charged-with-murder-assault-victim-dies-in-hospital/105795262</link><description>A 49-year-old Canberra man is charged with murder after a man he fought at the caravan park where they both lived died of his injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">833c0e140bea35199fdb507fae544a4b</guid></item><item><title>InterPrac boss says 'maybe we could have done more' to prevent First Guardian and Shield losses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/interprac%E2%80%99s-under-investigation-by-asic-but-its/105796044</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ac6a09728d88f3a8e841310c1dbfa2a</guid></item><item><title>Patrick Dangerfield stars to send Geelong into the AFL grand final as concussion rules Tom Stewart out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/afl-preliminary-final-geelong-vs-hawthorn-live-blog/105779366</link><description>Geelong utility Tom Stewart will miss the AFL grand final, but coach Chris Scott feels his Cats are in a great position to win the premiership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dd33f956ae78d4a6741605fb30417b7</guid></item><item><title>DV support services say more women are seeking help for coercive control since new state laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/slow-but-consistent-uptake-of-new-coercive-control-laws-nsw/105795204</link><description>A snapshot of the state's recent coercive control laws suggests there has been a "slow but consistent" uptake of the new offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f6288202d81a123e07877a555f48d8</guid></item><item><title>Potato mop-top virus impossible to eradicate, Biosecurity Tasmania says as ninth incursion detected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/potato-mop-top-virus-tasmania-eradication-impossible/105794756</link><description>Potato mop-top virus is here to stay and its source is unlikely to ever be discovered, Biosecurity Tasmania has said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c268afe33690f3e84ce03a889a9681b2</guid></item><item><title>All the latest financial news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/all-the-latest-financial-news/105796416</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6301e2bdeedf208ea5d5c5a791f35a27</guid></item><item><title>Optus CEO apologises to customers impacted by major network outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/optus-ceo-apologises-to-customers-impacted-by/105796546</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76fd1e56e640c3fcc4ec93132683da1d</guid></item><item><title>Optus CEO confirms three deaths during network outage affecting emergency calls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/optus-ceo-confirms-three-deaths-during-network/105796530</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2616d41c37b08dbe3f6b1464bddea5b</guid></item><item><title>Perth childcare worker Robert David Reti found not guilty of indecently touching two young girls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-19/perth-childcare-worker-robert-reti-indecent-dealing-verdict-/105796570</link><description>A Perth childcare worker is found not guilty of indecently touching two girls, aged four and six, at two separate centres in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">627fdd70f61b4fc5965665dfc1a9ff66</guid></item><item><title>A secret lived in plain sight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/a-secret-lived-in-plain-sight/105708692</link><description>Alliyah is reckoning with a decade of grooming and abuse at the hands of a trusted teacher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e77cd7303996f6436a98d30e0bbc14ed</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the Optus outage which disrupted triple-zero calls, linked to three deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/what-we-know-about-optus-network-outage/105796618</link><description>It's been two days since three people died after a devastating Optus outage caused hundreds of emergency calls to fail, but information about the incident remains scarce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81d841cfe097dc82a144e78eb4423953</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley and the Coalition face a ticking time bomb</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/sussan-ley-coalition-climate-donor-laws/105778688</link><description>The opposition leader survived a bruising post-election fight that left conservatives seething and has been left with no natural allies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40ee9b3f20f82e0c58514ac8c3e2b667</guid></item><item><title>Climate risks report paints grim picture, but expert on societal collapse explains giving up is not the answer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/climate-fatalism-in-wake-of-climate-risk-report/105780598</link><description>Lethal heat, mosquito-borne viruses, mass displacement and conflict — we got a glimpse into a grim climate future. Can imagining the end of the world be good for us, or is it a path to apathy?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8893cee718d8e9b52a9ba6f66c57ef49</guid></item><item><title>The inside story of an ABC report that helped scuttle Australia's biggest foreign takeover</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/abc-report-helped-scuttle-abu-dhabi-santos-takeover/105792998</link><description>Secrecy around a major methane leak helped Santos avoid public scrutiny for years. It backfired after a prospective bidder reportedly found out via an ABC News report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1a48ea533343bfad555aa06ec237be7</guid></item><item><title>Afghan refugees in Pakistan facing deportation amid local crackdown and Australian visa delays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/afghan-refugees-forced-back-from-pakistan/105697460</link><description>After fleeing Afghanistan, many refugees in Pakistan are at risk of being deported back amid a crackdown on temporary cardholders as they wait for humanitarian visas from Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18f5de78f692ffa221aeec3ce52a2172</guid></item><item><title>Technology is driving a quiet revolution in the way players relate to golf</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/rise-of-virtual-golf/105774244</link><description>Virtual golf venues are popping up en masse, as the sport adapts to suit the players of a new era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3559da2726e2650b689729488aaf246</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's historic second state visit to the UK was filled with risks for Keir Starmer. Did it pay off?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/donald-trump-uk-state-visit-keir-starmer-special-relationship/105796972</link><description>Britain rolled the dice on an historic second state visit for the US president in a year of domestic and international political turmoil. It found out where its relationship with Washington was at.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd5ca36baa0fcc9dba0912b19652f0a9</guid></item><item><title>Woman's snake bite death in Katherine sparks warnings against complacency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/katherine-nt-snake-bite-death-warning/105796156</link><description>Experts say snake bite victims may not even be aware their lives are in imminent danger after a woman was killed by a snake in Katherine earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">066248bbb54d3234414fbd1c1bdacc03</guid></item><item><title>Federal government's agriculture emissions reductions 'ambitious' but 'achievable'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/agriculture-industry-responds-toemissions-reduction-expectations/105792968</link><description>A professor of carbon farming says the agriculture industry will "naturally" contribute to a 28 per cent emissions reduction projected by 2050, but is unlikely to hit its own net-zero targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be4c701559d4d36210ea847a9fa9b087</guid></item><item><title>Pink Floyd's album and ode to Syd Barrett Wish You Were Here turns 50</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/pink-floyd-wish-you-were-here-turns-50/105782374</link><description>Pink Floyd looked to the past to find a way forward after the massive success of Dark Side Of The Moon in 1973. The result was Wish You Were Here, released 50 years ago this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78a552157b44e92ce3d5f5773e471f3d</guid></item><item><title>Labor reshuffles its furniture as the Liberals try to save what’s left</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/sa-labor-cabinet-reshuffle/105796022</link><description>Two resigning ministers, two major broken promises and an unfolding ecological crisis confront SA Labor six months out from a state election. Yet it's the Liberal Party staring down electoral punishment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80db0e8b704c5090677143ef7dd0b1e3</guid></item><item><title>Judge throws out Donald Trump's multi-billion-dollar New York Times lawsuit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/judge-throws-out-trump-ny-times-lawsuit/105797222</link><description>The US president's $US15 billion defamation lawsuit against The New York Times has been labelled "improper" by a federal judge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ca8cb4b4a1a6f182f11bd67499c7050</guid></item><item><title>Freezing rain or 12,000km away, these green Vikings will do anything for their beloved Canberra Raiders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/raiders-nrl-superfans-still-have-a-spring-in-their-step/105790848</link><description>Simon Tayoun's been a devout member of the Green Army since he watched his first-ever game of rugby league in 1987, and now he's become an unofficial mascot by bringing his custom drum to every game he can to lead the Viking Clap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f466609b2333997a9641d35394e062b7</guid></item><item><title>Perth family endure cold, wet winter in bus amid worsening housing crisis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/perth-man-living-in-bus-as-housing-crisis-worsens/105745228</link><description>A Perth man who has been sleeping rough in a bus with his family for the past three years wonders if he would be better off with a roof over his head and regular meals in jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e0a5450599eb2f6d62faabef19aae84</guid></item><item><title>Storm damage sees shark net installation delay at Sydney's Shark Beach in Nielsen Park</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/shark-net-installation-delay-at-sydney-shark-beach-neilsen-park/105794772</link><description>Shark Beach in Sydney's east is seasonally netted with an enclosure to protect swimmers from sharks during Sydney's warmer months — but for the upcoming school holidays, it is unlikely the nets will be installed in time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fb506200ed1eacf664848d3c53c5964</guid></item><item><title>Remote NSW council holds election after 12 years in administration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/central-darling-shire-council-election-nsw-votes-after-12-years/105757794</link><description>The 700 voters living in the remote Central Darling Shire Council area of New South Wales will finally head to the polls to vote again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2af8d61243c1a142aa5a6b000bb6dea5</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's tree fern trade accused of 'greenwashing' over native forest logging links, but others say it is sustainable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/tasmanias-tree-ferns-for-sale/105686750</link><description>Thousands of native tree ferns are harvested from Tasmania's forests for export each year. Some say the trade saves ferns from destruction, while others accuse the industry of greenwashing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a230cf7b613ce9f9908a403f525eaa2</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk’s murder sparks calls for revenge | If You're Listening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/charlie-kirk%E2%80%99s-murder-sparks-calls-for-revenge-if/105796612</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e5ca74218a7fb1258d28dbd24b3cf0f</guid></item><item><title>Victor Caulfield moved to Florence in his 70s and became an artists' model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/victor-caulfield-moved-to-florence-and-became-an-artists-model/105762988</link><description>Victor Caulfield packed up his Australian home and moved to Italy, where he fell into the art scene as an accidental model.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf11c6e1cc2bef7d1c59c017a7b1915d</guid></item><item><title>British couple freed from Afghanistan's Taliban</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/uk-couple-released-by-taliban/105797262</link><description>The couple, who ran a charity in Afghanistan where they had lived for 18 years, were freed after months of negotiations with the Taliban by Qatar in coordination with Britain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c3a221396bea8b5f6b5593e7f36bf7b</guid></item><item><title>South Australians reflect on life, 50 years after homosexuality was decriminalised</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/sa-50-year-anniversary-decriminalisation/105749058</link><description>Since homosexuality was decriminalised in South Australia half a century ago, LGBTIQA+ people say the state has made strides, but there is still some way to go towards equality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7eaea53257eef0f6a9ab9627e79de7ac</guid></item><item><title>One-tray honey chicken wings are an easy family dinner - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/one-tray-sticky-chicken-wings/105658174</link><description>It’s easy to make these irresistibly sticky wings that will have you licking your fingers and reaching for more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b49e38fcb0cc57c3220c789ba5301301</guid></item><item><title>Eucalypt trail named after botanist Dean Nicolle opens in SA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/rail-trail-forest-blyth-dean-nicolle-eucalypt-walk-sa/105779316</link><description>A unique partnership between an artist and a botanist has resulted in an old rail corridor in South Australia becoming an eucalypt forest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a634367098f7c56af4d4f383b07c47fd</guid></item><item><title>'America is not happy': ABC under fire for pulling Jimmy Kimmel Live!</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/complaints-about-kimmel-axing-meant-for-us-abc-sent-to-australia/105793428</link><description>The ABC has received hundreds of complaints about US talk show Jimmy Kimmel Live! being pulled off air and threats to boycott sponsors ... but that's the problem when two broadcasters from different countries share a name!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">058463060dc5663ada42854e5496b80c</guid></item><item><title>Wide Bay affordable housing estate scrapped due to 'unfeasible' costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/green-space-saved-as-bundaberg-housing-estate-scrapped/105792456</link><description>A controversial housing estate that would have been built on 26 hectares of Bundaberg's green space has been scrapped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">265b915b78077a19eec8da45dffd2c79</guid></item><item><title>Victorian apiarists finding it harder to access public land 'vital' for bees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/victorian-beekeeper-concerns-about-reduced-access-to-public-land/105788666</link><description>Apiarists are concerned they are losing access to public land in Victoria that provides a critical food source for their hives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc97f3abc783cc7a3d5c36c88876bac1</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says three 'narcoterrorists' killed in US strike on alleged drug boat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/us-military-carries-out-another-strike-on-alleged-drug-boat/105797450</link><description>This is the third fatal strike the US military has carried out this month on a vessel allegedly carrying drugs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf472bdd8248b7f4868d93c2f0b2c4f1</guid></item><item><title>Turtling tracking in Broome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/turtling-tracking-in-broome/105794988</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10cb5e530edb2253e9361a5ada40925c</guid></item><item><title>World-first turtle tracking reveals secrets of flatback turtles in WA's Roebuck Bay</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/world-first-tracking-of-flatback-turtles-in-roebuck-bay-broome/105794534</link><description>GPS tracking, motion sensors and video cameras reveal where flatback turtles in Broome's Roebuck Bay feed and travel, contributing to a richer understanding of the vulnerable species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6abd49307f41fd71e6160fa5f1479b4d</guid></item><item><title>Freezing rain or 12,000km away, these green Vikings will do anything for their beloved Canberra Raiders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/freezing-rain-or-12,000km-away,-these-green/105797680</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff39865f3b0a61caa40366eb6bb508cd</guid></item><item><title>Canberra Raiders receive NRL semifinal blow, losing five-eighth Ethan Strange to illness</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/raiders-star-ethan-strange-ruled-out-of-nrl-semifinal/105797628</link><description>Canberra Raiders are forced to reshuffle their team on the morning of the semifinal against Cronulla after illness struck wunderkind Ethan Strange.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f5873d0c087b62f90bf15bc27f5fcab</guid></item><item><title>Teenager pleads guilty to manslaughter over Hobart waterfront drowning</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/youth-pleads-guilty-to-drowning-death-man-hobart-waterfront/105794682</link><description>Deepinderjeet Singh was sitting with a woman near Franklin Wharf in Hobart in late January 2024 when a 17-year-old boy pushed the pair into the water and stole the woman's handbag.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80c316b498383625f4162e7c1e66ea7c</guid></item><item><title>UN says there's evidence organised crime scam centres are moving from South-East Asia into new frontier of the Pacific</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/organised-crime-scam-centres-move-into-pacific-united-nations/105775972</link><description>As scam centres run by organised crime find it harder to operate in South-East Asia, evidence emerges of them moving into the Pacific and setting up lucrative operations estimated to net billions each year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb89464594316563fc34dc56a716880e</guid></item><item><title>Kamala Harris's frustration with Joe Biden, and other takeaways from her election trail memoir</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/kamala-harris-election-campaign-memoir-key-takeaways/105797598</link><description>Kamala Harris has kept a low profile since losing the US election, but she has plenty to say in her upcoming book — a diary from her doomed campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">889a1be8632644b869e3a832fcf2a96a</guid></item><item><title>Transition from sheep to cropping in WA's Avon Valley leaving limited balloon landing sites</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/crops-to-sheep-hot-air-balloon-landing-sites/105794124</link><description>The move out of sheep by an increasing number of WA farmers is having an unexpected impact on the state's hot air balloon pilots.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c79d7f50ce8880f2a74edb7c05cab83</guid></item><item><title>Yolŋu people celebrate 50 years of the homelands movement in East Arnhem Land</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/nt-laynhapuy-homelands-movement-anniversary-indigenous-yolngu/105796404</link><description>Yolŋu children from nine Laynhapuy communities are screaming the Yothu Yindi anthem, Homeland Movement, in a ceremony celebrating the Indigenous elders who claimed back life on their country 50 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3184235034372056a06780912d5fe26e</guid></item><item><title>Super Netball celebrates bumper year as Sunshine Coast Lightning drives registration surge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/super-netball-sunshine-coast-lightning-registration-increase/105784044</link><description>A Queensland community is reaping the rewards of establishing the first regional professional netball team in the national league.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">266127730ccdcd9a64908f83b47107da</guid></item><item><title>From Jennifer Lopez to K-pop, meet the Australian backing artists helping superstars shine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/jlo-kpop-paul-kelly-backing-artists/105765732</link><description>Backup dancers and backing singers spend years perfecting their craft. But who are these artists and how does it feel performing in the shadows of superstars?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0b91ab8cfee821d0f58d79f05cf3da5</guid></item><item><title>Minister slams 'extremist' candidates nominating for WA council elections</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/wa-minister-condemns-extremist-council-candidates/105739550</link><description>Local Government Minister Hannah Beazely condemns the emergence of "extremist" candidates nominating for the state's forthcoming council elections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bcdc6a1da26fcdf49227a137e3eb1f7</guid></item><item><title>Trump will impose a $150,000 annual fee for H-1B visas. Here's what it means</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/trump-will-impose-a-150-000-annual-fee-for-h-1b-visas/105797648</link><description>Some hope this visa price hike will see the US tech industry prioritise American workers. Others argue it'll dissuade the "world's smartest talent" from choosing to work in the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b413fb37b55f8bb78078d6ea8144b98</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos beat Blues for 18th straight AFLW win as Cats, Hawks and Dockers triumph</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/aflw-hawks-magpies-cats-power-blues-kangaroos/105797358</link><description>Reigning premiers North Melbourne thrashes Carlton by 53 points, while Port Adelaide is stunned by an umpiring decision in its narrow loss to Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9fbf9ee09174863b8df7c1d000baca0</guid></item><item><title>Crowds flock to Toowoomba Carnival of Flowers despite wet weather</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/toowoomba-carnival-of-flowers-draws-crowds-despite-weather/105794286</link><description>Cold and damp conditions have not been enough to keep people away from Toowoomba's annual floral extravaganza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0670d318c12fc7fd9d19e3d22856487c</guid></item><item><title>Sharks and Knights reach NRLW preliminary finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/nrlw-knights-titans-cowboys-sharks/105798044</link><description>Cronulla keeps its season alive by defeating North Queensland, as Newcastle advances to a fourth NRLW preliminary final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7645684df002fee75327e38b809ba19c</guid></item><item><title>Queensland's measles outbreak growing after case confirmed in rural town Middlemount</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-20/measles-outbreak-queensland-growing-middlemount-case/105798134</link><description>A rural town in central Queensland is the latest community affected, after a case was recorded in Middlemount.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85ce8d1b5f911925dc41badfdac6d776</guid></item><item><title>F1 Azerbaijan qualifying: Oscar Piastri crashes out in Baku, Max Verstappen secures pole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/f1-azerbaijan-grand-prix-qualifying-oscar-piastri-crashes/105798072</link><description>Formula 1 drivers' championship leader Oscar Piastri crashed out of qualifying in Azerbaijan, but his teammate and championship rival Lando Norris was unable to make the Australian pay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16c3e647b407abef8304c1675bef09ab</guid></item><item><title>Republicans seize on Charlie Kirk's death to crack down on liberal dissent that puts freedom of speech 'in peril'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/republicans-trump-seize-on-charlie-kirk-death-to-target-liberals/105785372</link><description>The Trump administration saw an opportunity to crack down on liberal groups in the wake of the death of conservative activist Charlie Kirk. But not all conservatives are onboard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e9d2990ada472892c8d338b81a74b82</guid></item><item><title>Asia's protests grew from social media where misinformation also spread</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/nepal-indonesia-gen-z-social-media-misinformation/105779038</link><description>These movements may be separated by time, distance and language, but they were all born on social media, led by a new generation of activists fed up with the old systems of corruption and nepotism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">553dda439e393b87eb7b6bc4eff754a9</guid></item><item><title>Antinatalists say human suffering, and climate change, makes having children unethical. Are they right?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/antinatalism-child-free-climate-change-human-suffering-baby/105695328</link><description>Elon Musk believes the collapsing birth rate is humanity's biggest danger. But antinatalists argue having kids is little more than a procreational Ponzi scheme, and the risks are real.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28999cb939ddfbe63b4a8339d72f435e</guid></item><item><title>What makes China confident enough to ban microchips made by US firm Nvidia?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/what-makes-china-confident-to-ban-nvdia-microchips/105795486</link><description>Beijing's decision this week to ban Chinese companies from using microchips made by US firm Nvidia indicates the country is increasingly confident about replacing them with domestically produced chips, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c451e4e0710bc1516100c22ae7e23289</guid></item><item><title>Pirate attacks and sea robberies surge in key South-East Asian shipping lane</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/piracy-sea-robberies-rise-malacca-strait-asia/105736740</link><description>Piracy and sea robberies are increasing in the strategic straits of Malacca and Singapore, which could have implications for Australian imports and exports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2b3b37fb5cc2fee69c406b2aa0ccdc5</guid></item><item><title>Volodymyr Zelenskyy says he will meet Donald Trump next week as Russia intensifies attacks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/zelenskyy-to-meet-trump-at-un-general-assembly/105798222</link><description>The Ukrainian president says he will hold "a meeting with the President of the United States" to discuss security guarantees for Ukraine and sanctions on Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27f2a7b23010a2519d63afe0bdaa2f12</guid></item><item><title>When is Jess Hull's 800m final? When do Nicola Olyslagers, Eleanor Patterson and Matt Denny compete?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/sunday-2025-world-athletics-championships-tokyo-hull/105796966</link><description>Australia is looking at a veritable super Sunday on the final day of the 2025 World Athletics Championships, with four medals up for grabs. Here's when the Aussie contenders are in action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b90865f628cba21e9cb67af643b01ca4</guid></item><item><title>Former nurse shares devastating experience of attempts to get urgent cancer surgery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/hospital-logjam-blamed-for-delays-to-cancer-surgeries/105724218</link><description>Karenne Mosley was diagnosed with aggressive uterine cancer in March. She was booked in for surgery twice but is now in palliative care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">322dfad9007ac7be6793c351ff5df832</guid></item><item><title>'We should kill him': AI chatbot encourages Australian man to murder his father</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/ai-chatbot-encourages-australian-man-to-murder-his-father/105793930</link><description>Experts are calling for new regulations on artificial intelligence chatbots, after a triple j hack investigation uncovered a disturbing example of a chatbot encouraging a man to murder his father while engaging in paedophilic role-play.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">046595a368ebd4097697482ef340ab85</guid></item><item><title>The Duchess of Kent renounced her title in 2002 and never looked back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/duchess-of-kent-future-talent-music/105792856</link><description>Away from the public eye, Katharine, the Duchess of Kent, was a trailblazer quietly changing lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9687b291b6917fd21961664f6d1b8db2</guid></item><item><title>When is Charlie Kirk's memorial service? How to watch it in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/charile-kirk-memorial-service-live-stream/105787236</link><description>A public memorial service will be held for the late political commentator at a stadium in the US state of Arizona.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfae182b1b4361df304588c976ecb59c</guid></item><item><title>For Dr Mackenzie Little, javelin bronze at the World Athletics Championships is 'icing on the cake'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/dr-mackenzie-little-javelin-bronze-medal-world-champs/105798484</link><description>Mackenzie Little's second-successive World Athletics Championships bronze medal is an amazing achievement, all the more so considering she's a full-time surgical resident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9e9cf632aadd0f46716889b6c0fea24</guid></item><item><title>Scrubs is getting a reboot just in time for the hospital procedural revival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/scrubs-reboot-the-pitt-cheat-sheet/105793612</link><description>In a sea of hospital-based TV, long-running sitcoms Scrubs is often highlighted as one of the most realistic options. Now the reboot has been confirmed, and off the back of The Pitt’s big Emmy wins, we look back at the beloved show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f7cc2efbfa7b3a4841ebb5cb0fb4b85</guid></item><item><title>Jacinta Allan charts her own path with China in five-day tour of networking, photo ops and pandas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/jacinta-allan-victorian-premier-china-trade-talks-rail-tunnel/105795186</link><description>Premier Jacinta Allan has completed a tour of five Chinese cities where she has attempted to set the tone for future trade, boost Chinese international student numbers and promote her Suburban Rail Loop project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">413058ef77458bf91e819f55287f3109</guid></item><item><title>Street artist Rone's new 90-metre mural a visual love letter to Geelong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/tyrone-rone-wright-new-mural-captures-geelong-faces/105762354</link><description>The faces of 14 people will be immortalised in an enormous mural on the side of a new building in Geelong by locally born, globally renowned artist Rone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28ac13e735d6c51ed4a4df9593e87271</guid></item><item><title>How skateboarding became a family affair for Townsville single dad Jay MacAskill</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/qld-skateboarding-becomes-family-single-dad/105774582</link><description>For almost eight years, Jay MacAskill's skateboard was collecting dust at home — until his daughter found the skate park around the corner.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ab26eabc2acb19d8f736401a36cb5d2</guid></item><item><title>Canadian teenage golfer Anna Huang leads the La Sella Open by three shots after 54 holes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/golf-prodigy-anna-huang-eyes-historic-win-with-three-shot-lead/105798862</link><description>Canadian golf sensation Anna Huang, 16, is on the brink of making history, holding a three-shot lead going into the final round of a Ladies European Tour event in Spain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32b25913f0921eb04f02c6904a2adef3</guid></item><item><title>Addressing Australia's housing crisis is a mammoth task. Is making housing a human right the answer?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/housing-human-right-law-act-analysis-what-does-that-mean/105797726</link><description>The ACT government has passed legislation enshrining housing as a human right. What does that mean, and should other states follow?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ddf114810459395b3a99bce81b68b05</guid></item><item><title>Republicans warn Anthony Albanese of 'punitive measures' over Palestinian recognition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/republicans-warn-australia-over-palestinian-statehood/105798830</link><description>As Anthony Albanese touches down in New York ahead of the UN General Assembly, Republicans issue a warning against formally recognising Palestinian statehood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebe5c9ff00ace1a2ffdeee5ad7a40913</guid></item><item><title>SA Liberals' star candidate in spotlight after AI algal bloom 'admin error'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/ai-liv-golf-algal-bloom-comments-put-frank-pangallo-in-spotlight/105787864</link><description>When Frank Pangallo announced he was joining the Liberal party, he vowed to put the blowtorch on a first-term government riding high in the polls. But barely four weeks later, the blowtorch is firmly on Pangallo instead, writes Leah MacLennan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bd3524d93d528173e52862abfbcd325</guid></item><item><title>The Adelaide Crows have been the powerhouse of the AFLW. Now they are being challenged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/aflws-rapid-evolution-has-been-a-double-edged-sword-for-crows/105798110</link><description>The AFLW's rapid evolution has been a double-edged sword for Adelaide, which is the most successful club in competition history, having won three of the eight premierships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fca7baecebf0b1b986bd2de9e15eea87</guid></item><item><title>Man formally charged with murdering TikTok influencer Sana Yousaf in Pakistan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/sana-yousaf-murder-pakistan-man-indicted/105798922</link><description>A Pakistani court charges a 22-year-old man with murder for shooting a teenage social media influencer, Sana Yousaf, after refusing his offer of friendship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1eb11b4917ab879362f102711a80d0c5</guid></item><item><title>Inside Ninga Mia, a forgotten community in the shadow of Kalgoorlie the city of gold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/ninga-mia-kalgoorlie-mining-aboriginal-reserve-homelessness-gold/105774862</link><description>There's an eerie silence in Ninga Mia, a once thriving community on the edge of Kalgoorlie. The Aboriginal reserve is a microcosm of the cycle of displacement endured by many First Nations people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eafa5daeccecbae05c7c9ef093e72c5</guid></item><item><title>Cockchafer worm wreaking havoc on West Australian grain crops</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/cockchafer-pest-costing-wa-grain-farmers-thousands/105783068</link><description>Growers and scientists have teamed up in a bid to combat the rapidly increasing population of the voracious pest, which is devastating crops in WA's south-east.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a33788626f5c22861ceddd417b44c658</guid></item><item><title>Government has not set 2035 renewables target, downplays 90 per cent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/government-yet-to-set-2035-renewables-target/105798906</link><description>In New York for the UN summit, Energy Minister Chris Bowen declines to offer a renewable energy target for 2035 after the Climate Change Authority projected more than 90 per cent would be needed to hit its recommended emissions target.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4880a6213f11733719ca49464957e58</guid></item><item><title>Symbio Wildlife Park emu chicks being raised by hens after father walks out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/symbio-wildlife-park-abandoned-emus-raised-by-chickens/105795380</link><description>Birds of a different feather are flocking together at a wildlife park in New South Wales, where the chickens have been given the responsibility of being foster parents to a pair of abandoned emu chicks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6846407eac281053e23e77b5a99c248</guid></item><item><title>White House says the new $100k H-1B visa fee won't apply to existing holders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/h-1b-visa-100k-fee-existing-holder-gold-platinum-card/105798972</link><description>The massive fee hike prompted a panicked reaction from big tech companies, but the US government says workers already on the visa won't be affected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e18dc67ea13b6fbf6bef5002b0237098</guid></item><item><title>Koori Court marks 20 years in Mildura as Victoria approaches treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/twenty-years-of-koori-justice-in-mildura-victorias-north-west/105784288</link><description>Mildura marks two decades since its Koori Court opened, as Victoria sees mixed results in the push to reduce Indigenous incarceration and offending rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d57275cbeb1abf5d81f15d9fb2c32b08</guid></item><item><title>UK fighter jets begin NATO air defence mission over Poland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/uk-fighter-jets-begin-nato-air-defence-mission-over-poland/105798964</link><description>British fighter jets fly their first NATO air defence unit over Poland as part of a mission to bolster the Western alliance's defences following a Russian drone incursion this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c68471ff237392537d4d015d338c7ef</guid></item><item><title>Crocodiles on the move in northern Australia as breeding season arrives</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/crocodiles-on-the-move-breeding-season-arrives-north-australia/105766898</link><description>It's crocodile breeding season and at one central Queensland farm, the drama is on par with a reality television dating show as keepers try to work out the best pairings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab50329a1039618670babc23784c4980</guid></item><item><title>Life on Aboriginal reserve remembered by Carnarvon traditional owners</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/aboriginal-reserve-memories-carnarvon-traditional-owners/105510728</link><description>In 1975, an anthropologist wrote his thesis on Carnarvon's rich Aboriginal reserve. Decades later, traditional owners revisit the work to contribute to "big truth-telling" documentary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf8bb607751e84f71648e4dfa5cd44a</guid></item><item><title>Australian-born singer drops out of Russian-hosted Intervision song contest after 'political pressure'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australian-born-singer-drops-out-of-russian-hosted-song-contest/105799020</link><description>Vassy dropped out of the contest at the last minute after coming under what Russian organisers said was "unprecedented political pressure from the government of Australia".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6f53824a2ed40b9ae66bd7ebdb25e1a</guid></item><item><title>How Brisbane, Hawthorn, Geelong and Collingwood stay on top of the AFL world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/afl-analysis-geelong-brisbane-collingwood-hawthorn/105797710</link><description>The 21st century has been dominated by four AFL clubs — Geelong, Hawthorn, Collingwood and Brisbane — but there's no single secret to their success.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0de8258f95182f2d73692053694b3fa</guid></item><item><title>Penola High School's agriculture program revives community and enrolments</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/penola-high-school-ag-program-revives-falling-enrolments/105787042</link><description>Cory O'Connor's three-week teaching placement turned around his hometown high school. Now he's receiving an award for the agriculture program he started there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">800678cadea15a18ec482186c893d046</guid></item><item><title>Pistachios are the latest food trend and a lot of work goes into predicting what's next</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/pistachios-are-everywhere-but-how-was-that-decided/105680106</link><description>Pistachios have become the food flavour of the season, and a lot of work goes into predicting what the next big thing will be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5eba132db24b42ad0a82c8f2ec02621</guid></item><item><title>Demons defeat Eagles as Crows, Giants, Lions and Saints score AFLW wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/aflw-demons-eagles-giants-swans-bulldogs-lions-saints-tigers/105799148</link><description>The Demons' Eden Zanker enjoys a day out with five goals to help defeat Daisy Pearce's young Eagles squad by 51 points, while the Crows launch a final-quarter fightback to get past the Suns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da04417bb1dcf00ff78c602f53360a77</guid></item><item><title>How to clean out your wardrobe as the seasons change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/how-to-spring-clean-wardobe-clean-out/105780140</link><description>It's the kind of task that can seem overwhelming, but the change of season is the perfect opportunity to review what's in your wardrobe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf9c7f0a36323b3457588962f5d0b0b0</guid></item><item><title>F1 Azerbaijan Grand Prix: Oscar Piastri crashes on lap one, Max Verstappen wins in Baku</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/f1-live-azerbaijan-grand-prix-oscar-piastri-lando-norris/105775138</link><description>Oscar Piastri's worst weekend of 2025 ended with a false start, then a lap one crash, but he retains a healthy championship lead after his teammate failed to capitalise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b5c02bd1e41bfd4c73291bff536dac1</guid></item><item><title>Penrith's win over Canterbury was a reminder there is no team like them</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/panthers-bulldogs-nrl-finals-cleary-galvin-too/105799368</link><description>Canterbury is a team built in Penrith's image, but the Panthers served Canterbury a stark reminder that there can be only one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43391fdd3b75eadfd140d1ee7f293931</guid></item><item><title>Nicola Olyslagers wins high jump gold, Ky Robinson comes fourth in 5,000m on rain-hit final day of World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/live-updates-world-athletics-championships-2025-in-tokyo-day-9/105799230</link><description>Nicola Olyslagers won a superb gold medal in a women's high jump that was twice suspended for torrential rain on the final day of the World Athletics Championships in Tokyo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">793485d5d71e56e9efd0376681667aa8</guid></item><item><title>Australia formally recognises state of Palestine as Anthony Albanese arrives in US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australia-formally-recognises-state-of-palestine/105799238</link><description>The historic decision foreshadowed last month has now become a reality, as Australia moves with Canada and the United Kingdom to join the growing list of countries to recognise Palestinian sovereignty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f7f36cbe6b5b1fbaaf3e78efd2951a2</guid></item><item><title>Can recognising the state of Palestine achieve a two-state solution as Israel continues bombing Gaza?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-21/australia-recognises-state-of-palestine-two-state-solution/105799276</link><description>While the Israel Defense Forces bomb Gaza and bulldoze the West Bank for settlements, moves to recognise Palestine in pursuit of a two-state solution may appear like something of a sick joke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfa3467335da07f9ce07cf8e87421ac9</guid></item><item><title>Is artificial intelligence overhyped or is AI the 'fourth industrial revolution'?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/is-ai-the-fourth-industrial-revolution/105790912</link><description>It's estimated 30,000 people are working in the AI industry in Australia, and fanfare is growing with start-ups tapping into billions of dollars of venture capital. Yet there are concerns about hype and a lack of regulation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26daac2bce5f986abcbf545a3ec82df2</guid></item><item><title>Older Australians to pay up to $50/hour for basic care at home under aged care changes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/older-australians-to-pay-for-showers-under-home-care-changes/105796118</link><description>Older Australians entering the aged care system will have to pay for "non-clinical" services such as showers and help with medication under wide-ranging changes taking effect in November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fad2ebda86259a9a52aff0b346c39071</guid></item><item><title>Brownlow Medal 2025 — when is it, how to watch and who are the favourites for AFL's best-and-fairest award</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/brownlow-medal-2025-explainer-how-to-watch-who-might-win/105799236</link><description>The AFL's big night is here, as the league's best and fairest player is honoured with the Brownlow Medal. Here is everything you need to know about the big event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a533b478e86cba0a5d23c3da7fd118e4</guid></item><item><title>The government says its 2035 climate targets are achievable but mathematics suggests a different story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/climate-target-2035-2050-carbon-emissions-global-warming/105799080</link><description>The problem with an emissions reduction target is that its mere existence implies it is achievable and that if we do achieve it, we will be fine. The truth is more complex.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55dd3a3450e5da05cd2e7e786ef836f8</guid></item><item><title>Sarah Kopp's teacher Paul Grealy groomed her at 15. As an adult, she held him to account</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/sarah-kopps-teacher-paul-grealy-groomed-her-from-15/105775958</link><description>Sarah Kopp's life was up-ended when a charismatic teacher twice her age started grooming her. Then they married and had children. When she sought justice 20 years on, she faced an impossible choice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">329e0e5fdb603a2e16d3f7e31513666e</guid></item><item><title>In an Australian first, chip company recycles leftover cooking oil into packaging to reduce emissions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/chip-packet-oil-recycling-snackbrands-australia-viva-energy/105788230</link><description>Hundreds of litres of used cooking oil is disposed of every year as a by-product of making some of Australia's favourite snacks, like chips — but one company is trialling a method to reduce waste.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ff59f9aa179f301bfc7d9f1c6d8480c</guid></item><item><title>Lachlan Murdoch involved in possible TikTok deal, Donald Trump says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/tiktok-deal-involves-murdoch-trump-says/105800256</link><description>The deal would see TikTok's American assets transferred from China's ByteDance to American owners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da7908cffd99b9ae76881cabbe2df158</guid></item><item><title>Eleanor Patterson's 'bittersweet' moment of support for young rival at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/eleanor-patterson-world-championships-support-heartwarming/105762048</link><description>Eleanor Patterson did not come away with a medal at the 2025 World Athletics Championships. But by supporting Angelina Topić through a tough moment, she gained so much more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">826692bb635f6dcf2b35199ab6113385</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump calls Charlie Kirk a 'martyr' at memorial service, widow Erika Kirk forgives alleged assassin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/thousand-gather-charlie-kirk-memorial-service-donald-trump/105800038</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Charlie Kirk was a "martyr to American freedom", while his widow says she forgives his alleged assassin during a memorial to the right-wing activist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a195c5eaab3b46f9f8c92705e3433bbb</guid></item><item><title>Pensioners left 'waiting to die' in regional Victoria as specialist healthcare costs rise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/pensioners-cant-afford-specialist-health-care-costs-victoria/105713416</link><description>Victorian pensioner Eddie Rushforth says he does not know whether his bowel cancer has returned because he cannot afford the cost of the scans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2bc72941774215310fee9627fe967a3</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk memorial at Arizona stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/charlie-kirk-memorial-at-arizona-stadium/105800378</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31c9f43e6ca8858e9667817c44a6c650</guid></item><item><title>BOM forecasts sunny skies ahead for Queensland school holidays</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/sunny-skies-ahead-for-queensland-school-holidays/105799388</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says the weather will be as good as people in the Sunshine State can hope for at this time of year, with another wet summer on the horizon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de4b1e56c2c94f0650974a071e492fdb</guid></item><item><title>Murray River flood may not be to blame for SA algal bloom, Senate inquiry hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/murray-river-flood-link-to-algal-bloom-questioned-senate-inquiry/105733848</link><description>Scientists have questioned the link between the 2022-23 floods and South Australia's ongoing harmful algal bloom, despite the state government listing it as one of the three primary causes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e88db31a70e241e8774222579aebebdc</guid></item><item><title>Tinder, Hinge ban for man convicted of possessing child abuse material welcomed by child safety advocate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/dating-app-ban-upheld-welcomed-by-child-safety-advocate/105799280</link><description>A child safety advocate welcomes a recent decision to uphold a ban on a convicted child sex offender from two dating apps, which comes after the man tried to have the ban overturned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef1189b7a8f414f0db4332dac0eaf728</guid></item><item><title>Storm-damaged turbine at NSW Central West wind farm raises safety concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/storm-damaged-turbine-at-nsw-central-west-wind-farm-concerns/105782400</link><description>After a wind turbine blade snapped in half during a storm, the NSW National Party has called for a safety audit into the renewable technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">020cbe7c7b785e21c8f3c2fd850c4be9</guid></item><item><title>Short-term stays are swallowing up housing stock in these WA coastal havens</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/wa-coastal-towns-for-rent/105628728</link><description>With one of the nation's highest proportions of Airbnbs, some of WA's most popular tourist towns face a dilemma. Tourism is their biggest breadwinner — but with a housing crisis in full swing, short-term stays are pushing more and more locals away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42e3387b3cda80c2ffd9d9842d5c1c42</guid></item><item><title>Live updates: RBA says the economy is in a cyclical upturn, ASX gains after a record close on Wall Street</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/105799724</link><description>RBA delivers upbeat economic assessment to Parliament, but warns about the risks of a Chinese slowdown. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3094f05703291a277172c746b1d52b0</guid></item><item><title>Ben Graetz is amplifying voices through drag and music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/stateline-ben-graetz-is-amplifying-voices-through-drag-and-music/105800476</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">630db041a99b34f065b43cfd99120d2d</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr earns a standing ovation in home game return as Chelsea defeats Leicester 1-0 in WSL</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/wsl-sam-kerr-returns-home-to-standing-ovation-in-chelsea/105800446</link><description>Chelsea fans stand and applaud Australian superstar Sam Kerr in her long-awaited return to Kingsmeadow in the WSL.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da70332495135e59ba3b6176d03d566d</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese on Australia formally recognising state of Palestine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/anthony-albanese-on-australia-formally-recognising/105800598</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be089f767d04edd270d79c6fc8eb57e7</guid></item><item><title>This program could be the blueprint for helping kids fleeing domestic violence stay off the streets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/homeless-kids-domestic-violence-solution-politics/105793902</link><description>Every night, thousands of Australian kids are homeless without an adult to look after them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e17c22bd4e0bdb7ea0d6cd380a87fbf</guid></item><item><title>NT police data shows violent crime increasing, property crime decreasing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/is-nt-crime-decreasing-since-clp-government-elected-police-data/105797920</link><description>NT police data show crime rates in the NT are moving in two directions, with violent crime increasing and property crime decreasing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdbfb4dc342090b5ac73b9b9188a7325</guid></item><item><title>Protesters in Philippines clash with police in rallies against corruption</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/protesters-in-philippines-rally-against-corruption/105800512</link><description>Thousands of Filipinos marched in the capital to vent their anger over a ballooning scandal involving bogus flood-control projects believed to have cost taxpayers billions of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffa83e3c2e5be80abb8e2dcb772951a9</guid></item><item><title>Police charge woman with allegedly defrauding four elderly residents at aged care facility where she worked</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/queensland-police-fraud-charges-rothwell-aged-care-residents/105800700</link><description>Police allege the woman defrauded four elderly residents at an aged care facility where she worked and used their bank details to make personal purchases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2725d37a3ace6ec371c99b16fc7b5d20</guid></item><item><title>World leaders are meeting at the UN General Assembly this week. Here are four things to watch for</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/united-nations-general-assembly-what-to-watch-for-in-new-york/105800440</link><description>World leaders are arriving in New York for the UN General Assembly — and for the first time, Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is among them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">761958b8abcd8c47c96a8d78d674b211</guid></item><item><title>Optus triple-0 outage investigation underway as minister warns of 'consequences'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/optus-investigation-triple-0-outage/105800556</link><description>The Australian Media and Communications Authority begins its investigation into the Optus triple-0 outage that has been linked to multiple deaths in South Australia and Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64e8d943c326b70c38e9b095d514da19</guid></item><item><title>Germany sends planes to track Russian military aircraft as Trump vows to defend Baltic states</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/german-sends-planes-over-poland-as-trump-vows-to-defend-baltic/105800452</link><description>President Donald Trump says he will defend the Baltic states if Russia intensifies hostilities following Moscow's incursion into Estonia's airspace in recent days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5204fff459f01296ee960b38ecc71bf0</guid></item><item><title>Lack of communication from Optus 'inexcusable': SA premier</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/lack-of-communication-from-optus-inexcusable:-sa/105800796</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cf54ba9a1dda378310a827bfa243a6e</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk's wife says she forgives alleged assassin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/charlie-kirks-wife-says-she-forgives-alleged/105800824</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c83a813d9064777f6dabf3f01ba84ba</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with murder of Queensland mother Crystal Beale, whose body was found in the Brisbane River</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/qld-man-charged-murder-domestic-violence-crystal-beale/105801310</link><description>Ms Beale's body was found in the Brisbane River by a member of the public in the early hours of February 22.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b57a9a5abde994d1da426ed287896e9d</guid></item><item><title>Optus customer details failed triple-0 call after mother was trapped by mobility scooter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/sa-optus-victim-speaks-out/105800730</link><description>A former triple-0 operator has detailed the distressing moment she could not reach emergency services when her mother became trapped under her mobility scooter during the company's 13-hour outage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17fcf874f0c650c193d3577e9ebbb23e</guid></item><item><title>Estranged bandmates reunite for a new gig in Spinal Tap II: The End Continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/estranged-bandmates-reunite-for-a-new-gig-in/105801544</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2ef3b9fda1eb0ec36bd802a5c87c362</guid></item><item><title>Jacqui Lambie calls on independent MLCs to 'block' the proposed Macquarie Point stadium</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/jacqui-lambie-calls-on-independent-mlcs-to-block-hobart-stadium/105797716</link><description>Senator Jacqui Lambie tells the independents in Tasmania's upper house — who hold the fate of the Macquarie Point stadium in their hands — to "find the courage the premier can't" and stop the project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b78160dbac88202c3169fcc945ea29c</guid></item><item><title>Aussie brothers Jett and Hunter Lawrence win at SuperMotocross World Championship</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/jett-and-hunter-lawrence-win-supermotocross-world-championship/105800412</link><description>Two brothers from the Sunshine Coast finish first and second in the SuperMotocross World Championship, taking home an eye-watering cash reward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec083ecb530c8893ea5dfef096ffdb6d</guid></item><item><title>Australians can't trust the triple-0 network after 13-hour Optus outage results in deaths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/optus-triple-0-failure-analysis/105800592</link><description>The Optus failure is shocking and no doubt a massive fine and other sanctions could be on the way, but experts say it raises further questions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2edd7465f8b9851c69c1b7efadb1f5f1</guid></item><item><title>'Turning it up to eleven': Spinal Tap returns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/turning-it-up-to-eleven-spinal-tap-returns/105792970</link><description>The new film follows the fictional heavy metal band reuniting for one final gig with cameos from Elton John and Paul McCartney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4608648fffc66e4e36ba98d635f1990</guid></item><item><title>Easy and healthy dinner recipes for spring</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/easy-healthy-recipes-for-spring-dinners/105660408</link><description>If you're looking for light dinner ideas as the weather warms up, we have plenty of easy options. Think veggie-filled frittatas and beef taco bowls with a few healthy swaps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c28e2a7be5345c5402fc685acca89162</guid></item><item><title>Shalom House drug rehab centre CEO Peter Lyndon-James to step down over immigration views</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/peter-lyndon-james-steps-down-shalom-house-ceo/105801198</link><description>The head of a controversial WA drug rehabilitation service says he will resign so he can speak out against "mass migration".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f37d78dd839c3af15e6c8564d4e771f2</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's exam authority leadership to be 'reset' following VCE failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/government-accepts-vce-exam-blunder-vcaa-report-recommendations/105801398</link><description>The Victorian Curriculum and Assessment Authority's leadership team is set to be overhauled after a 2024 exam blunder allowed some students access to exam questions ahead of time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53a0474709ea661f4a9e0f75d1e2c06c</guid></item><item><title>Two men charged after alleged assault of referees following junior rugby grand final in Canberra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/junior-rugby-referee-in-hospital-after-alleged-coward-punch/105801788</link><description>Two men have been charged with assault after an alleged coward punch attack during a junior rugby sevens grand final on Sunday in which a referee was knocked unconscious.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87fdb730cde332a506fd7ccf1b011e9e</guid></item><item><title>NT Police complete Kumanjayi White death in custody autopsy, with brief of evidence handed to prosecutors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/kumanjayi-white-death-in-custody-alice-springs-autopsy-completed/105801756</link><description>The autopsy into the Aboriginal man's death in custody in Alice Springs has been completed, with the police brief of evidence handed to prosecutors to determine whether any charges should be laid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b34f78ebd2e7994895d35c509e3ce63</guid></item><item><title>Australian pair Holly Harris and Jason Chan qualify for ice dance at 2026 Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/ice-dance-at-2026-winter-olympics-australia-qualifies-in-beijing/105802160</link><description>Australian pair Holly Harris and Jason Chan finish second at the Skate to Milano event in Beijing to book their spot at the Milan-Cortina Olympic Games in February next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbfee981ea89ca45bca4d6f89ad7983b</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast man sentenced over former partner's traumatic brain injury</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/man-sentenced-over-former-partners-traumatic-brain-injury/105801732</link><description>A man is sentenced over a 2023 incident in which his former partner jumped from a moving car to escape him, leaving her with a traumatic brain injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e9c37ba116765f615c221f6c4108a07</guid></item><item><title>Corrie Feehan's family, friends search for evidence after disappearance</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/corrie-feehan-family-friends-search-for-missing-bushman/105799586</link><description>Corrie Feehan was last seen on his kayak along WA's Midwest coast in April this year. His family and friends want to find evidence to change the investigation from missing persons to criminal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4bfccd11c50288473e8ff00ddfaf3de</guid></item><item><title>Is AI impacting your career or life plans? Has its rapid rise got you rethinking your future? The ABC wants to hear from you</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/ai-artificial-intelligence-future-job-career-impact/105762606</link><description>Whether you’re a student halfway through a degree or a mid-career manager planning the next five years, artificial intelligence (AI) is reshaping lives across the country. If you've been feeling its effects, the ABC want to hear from you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc9fb0b057b73e053ee1ce795957b20a</guid></item><item><title>West Swan's Pow Street residents demand water pipes be replaced after 'massive' leaks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/west-swan-residents-tire-of-ongoing-water-main-leaks/105802606</link><description>Residents of a street in the Perth's outskirts say they are desperate after six water main bursts in the past 20 years, but the Water Corp says the pipes are only 52 years old and well within their life span.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">659c10fa7f2b80ca122f698fa1a8926e</guid></item><item><title>Vital shipping route plagued by pirates and sea robbers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/vital-shipping-route-plagued-by-pirates-and-sea/105802894</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51ae5c28dd52b64419536143c6ef1f57</guid></item><item><title>Masood Zakaria asks court to permanently stay his murder trial over 'unlawful' deportation from Türkiye</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/masood-zakaria-trial-vacated-re-alleged-illegal-deportation/105802494</link><description>A major Sydney murder trial is at risk of falling over as a Supreme Court judge ruled there was evidence the man charged was deported back to Australia unlawfully.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50b9900e4915898991b85033dca86795</guid></item><item><title>'It is do-able': How interim vice-chancellor Rebekah Brown plans to balance ANU's expenditure and revenue</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/interim-vice-chancellor-rebekah-brown-interview-plan-reputation/105800874</link><description>Eight days into her new role as interim vice-chancellor at the Australian National University, Rebekah Brown sat down for an exclusive ABC interview to share her plan for getting the institution back on track.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94bab8bb94646b877de5b418d1b0614e</guid></item><item><title>Court hears details of final hours of murdered children as Hakyung Lee murder trial nears end</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/hakyung-lee-trial-week-three/105801212</link><description>Hakyung Lee admits killing her children but claims she is not guilty by reason of insanity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8bb6b299ff32e2539915e7831b1952d</guid></item><item><title>Nasal spray flu vaccine becomes available for young SA children next year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/nasal-pray-flue-vaccine-for-children-in-south-australia/105801696</link><description>Three-year-old Clive has a brain injury after contracting influenza B. His mother is urging others to be immunised as SA announces it will make a nasal spray vaccination available to young children next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0f7955c6ec3304e91a066b683f38206</guid></item><item><title>Geelong star Max Holmes admits missing 2022 grand final hurt relationship with coach Chris Scott</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/i-was-pissed-with-scotty-cats-star-holmes-eyes-afl-flag/105802834</link><description>Geelong speedster Max Holmes is desperate to put his previous grand-final week anger and heartbreak behind him as the Cats eye AFL premiership glory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd1f4bd169de77ac34368207d9141381</guid></item><item><title>Why locals can’t afford to live in WA’s most loved tourist towns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/why-locals-can%E2%80%99t-afford-to-live-in-wa%E2%80%99s-most-loved/105803092</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1e404019f0d280d16b4760672f88e66</guid></item><item><title>How the ANU's interim leader wants to turn its reputation around</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/how-the-anus-interim-leader-wants-to-turn-its/105803304</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df8f7de39616b92117e7333f3e99b69a</guid></item><item><title>From Donald Trump's speech to Erika Kirk's forgiveness: What you missed at the Charlie Kirk memorial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/charlie-kirk-funeral-arizona-trump-erika-and-other-takeaways/105802396</link><description>From Donald Trump's wide-ranging speech to a potential reunion between former foes, here are the main takeaways from Charlie Kirk's memorial service in Arizona.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3eb1b27c764c94c12dc9506fd3a5f2e</guid></item><item><title>Hunter woman claims self-defence over fatal stabbing during street fight</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/lily-ridgeway-claims-self-defence-raymond-terrace-stabbing-death/105800848</link><description>Hunter woman Lily Ridgeway pleads not guilty to manslaughter over the stabbing death of Jason Adams at Raymond Terrace in 2020, claiming she acted in self-defence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c627f1928a1c4af96c0f00a2c6f4d75</guid></item><item><title>Super Netball's Sunshine Coast Lightning enters new Global Sports Fund Management Group ownership</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/super-netball-sunshine-coast-lightning-new-ownership/105801344</link><description>Almost a decade after being co-founded by the Melbourne Storm and University of the Sunshine Coast, Super Netball's Lightning is entering a new era.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">725e5769d7aa41a90979ec4d3e47f5bd</guid></item><item><title>New hospital a 'jewel in the crown' as premier acknowledges Western Sydney health failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/new-designs-for-2-billion-bankstown-hospital-released/105801478</link><description>Premier Chris MInns vows to make Western Sydney hospitals a "hell of a lot better," saying the current offering "hasn't been good enough."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1874f795f2eeb01b994f72b8afb5ec4</guid></item><item><title>Three alleged kidnappers denied bail after 'hostage situation' in front of kids</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/alleged-kidnappers-hostage-situation-baseball-bat-monash/105803486</link><description>Three alleged kidnappers were trying to recover a $200,000 debt from a 52-year-old man in Monash on September 21, a court has heard, while rejecting their bail application.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d541b8975b82abbe25815a1c564cffb0</guid></item><item><title>Paper Australia sues Victorian government for $402 million over timber supply failure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/paper-australia-sues-victorian-government-timber-supply-failure/105666676</link><description>Paper Australia alleges the state government failed to provide enough raw materials for its Maryvale mill, causing substantial loss and damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3966e123ebc206895cb857b760514b64</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos undecided on halves combination ahead of prelim final against Penrith</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/hunt-on-for-broncos-as-mam-mind-games-begin/105803392</link><description>Brisbane coach Michael Maguire continues to experiment with his halves combinations on Monday as Ezra Mam takes another key step towards a return from injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94b206b4a39973e74852b877af401757</guid></item><item><title>ABC News - Trusted Source of Latest News &amp; Headlines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2022-12-13/harley-and-katya-the-price-of-an-olympic-dream/101557348</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee96c51cbc5b98d83ab9002535dfc647</guid></item><item><title>Alexander O'Sachy faces Brisbane court charged with manslaughter of Angela Godwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-09-22/manslaughter-sentencing-domestic-violence-upper-mount-gravatt/105802410</link><description>The court heard the 47-year-old had a criminal history spanning more than 20 years for more than 50 offences, including the unlawful wounding of a former partner in 2008.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b4cf8d12fdea5712adde0cc2c477aae</guid></item></channel></rss>