<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:46:57 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Rapist restaurateur Alberto Nicoletti jailed for sexually assaulting woman he drove home from South Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/alberto-nicoletti-jailed-for-raping-woman-in-south-perth/105842684</link><description>Como restaurateur Alberto Nicoletti is sentenced for raping a woman he offered to drive home from South Perth, his third sexual assault conviction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">626a6f6fee7ab617592a669418d92e5b</guid></item><item><title>Taylor Swift's The Life of a Showgirl in the spotlight, a track-by-track look</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/taylor-swift-life-of-a-showgirl-track-by-track-look/105849136</link><description>Taylor Swift's new album The Life of a Showgirl will be deconstructed by critics and fans alike, probably for some time to come. Here we get an expert Swiftie's initial reaction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fdfdd148587b2a9b7c1df4607511f78</guid></item><item><title>Israeli military intercepts last flotilla boat sailing to Gaza</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/last-boat-from-intercepted-gaza-aid-flotilla/105850802</link><description>The Israeli military has intercepted and boarded the Marinette on Friday, believed to be the last ship still sailing to Gaza as part of the Global Sumud Flotilla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">543666e08930a39dd970808977d607fb</guid></item><item><title>Israeli military intercepts Flotilla ship 'Marinette'.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/israeli-military-intercepts-flotilla-ship-marinette/105850918</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">301c7a3af77008477e98eedcacffe994</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie quits shadow cabinet, citing disagreement over immigration policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/andrew-hastie-quits-shadow-cabinet/105850958</link><description>Shadow Home Affairs Minister and Liberal leadership aspirant Andrew Hastie has quit Sussan Ley's shadow ministry, citing a disagreement over the party's immigration policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc272f42fa84628b145bc38f5e77a4a1</guid></item><item><title>Australia retains Chappell-Hadlee Trophy after rain washes out second T20I against New Zealand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/cricket-t20i-nrew-zealand-vs-australia-chappell-hadlee-trophy/105850946</link><description>The second men's Twenty20I between New Zealand and Australia is abandoned because of rain, with only 13 deliveries bowled at Tauranga's Bay Oval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b40533ad315a5fdfa4cf03d0f4496bc9</guid></item><item><title>Friday finance with David Chau</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/friday-finance-with-david-chau/105850950</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b617f451c81e86fd313667e26aafb0c2</guid></item><item><title>One of two victims in Manchester synagogue attack may have been killed by a bullet fired by police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/manchester-synagogue-attack/105851062</link><description>One of the victims of Thursday's attack at a synagogue in Manchester was shot by police during their attempts to bring the unarmed attacker under control.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68ac4ae0ba9e12c67901b8dd5f71c2d8</guid></item><item><title>Former WA Health boss outlines missing pieces of puzzle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/former-wa-health-boss-outlines-missing-pieces-of/105846500</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fed0bc5657b6da20e039ca9c89e5ec2c</guid></item><item><title>Tayla Harris stars as Melbourne defeats Essendon by 14 points</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/aflw-melbourne-essendon/105850912</link><description>Melbourne has continued its pursuit of a top two AFLW finish with a 14 point defeat of Essendon at Princes Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db99de8f313630e8472819ab88c8e7f6</guid></item><item><title>Ekkalak Paenoi sentenced to life in prison for Lim Kimya's murder but his widow wants to know who ordered the killing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-03/gunman-sentenced-over-lim-kimyas-murder-in-thailand/105851196</link><description>Lim Kimya was gunned down shortly after arriving in Bangkok earlier this year by Ekkalak Paenoi, but his widow is questioning who is behind her husband's death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ec02d85a1f957f32c7818cb220555d9</guid></item><item><title>At least 13 people killed in Indonesian school collapse in Java as parents demand recovery work speeds up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/indonesian-school-collapse-death-toll-rises/105851242</link><description>As recovery efforts continue, some parents have argued with emergency services, demanding they speed up their work so they can bury their loved ones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3146a3e8f3184498c6049e9d252b20b3</guid></item><item><title>Russia launches its biggest attack on Ukraine's gas network since war began on the eve of winter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/russia-launches-biggest-attack-on-ukrainian-gas-network/105851234</link><description>The overnight attack consisting of 35 missiles and 60 drones hit gas infrastructure in the country's Kharkiv and Poltava regions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0f59525d4b08f0b1fadef97b7d12066</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump tells Israel to stop bombing Gaza, says Hamas is ready for peace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/hamas-agrees-to-release-hostages-trump-gaza-plan/105851412</link><description>Donald Trump says he believes Hamas has shown it is "ready for a lasting PEACE" and he puts the onus on Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu's government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4c218a5246356e401ab0ba66cdd9dbe</guid></item><item><title>A West Bank town symbolises the hurdles to Palestinian statehood</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/west-bank-israeli-settlers-and-palestinian-statehood-challenges/105814136</link><description>A quiet town north-east of Ramallah, is on the front line of a territorial battle in the West Bank. It is playing out against the backdrop of international recognition of a Palestinian state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39e471ebf09bc630a53cf250fc373402</guid></item><item><title>IDF settlers and soldiers clashing with Palestinians</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/idf-settlers-and-soldiers-clashing-with-palestinians/105833430</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09b5837243fde83f76b5db4ae15790a6</guid></item><item><title>The war in Gaza has raised geopolitical tensions that extend right into our region</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/gaza-israel-conflict-geopolitics-trump/105830544</link><description>On Wednesday, Donald Trump proclaimed his Middle East peace deal an "amazing thing". By week's end, things were not as straightforward as they seemed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae9e8c790621efcabcb4f7036a890568</guid></item><item><title>Don't let derangement syndrome throw shade on Anthony Albanese's global wins as steady approach pays off</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/albanese-global-wins-derangement-sydrome/105830526</link><description>This week feels like it's time to officially add Albanese Derangement Syndrome to the diagnostic and statistical manual of political disorders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4970aa055a5a866fd67a141d6f05247c</guid></item><item><title>One in five girls consider dropping athletics and swimming due to periods, new research shows</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/one-in-five-girls-consider-dropping-athletics-swimming-period/105803342</link><description>Research by Federation University has found 63 per cent of girls have missed training, and a third have missed competitions, because of period-related challenges in athletics and swimming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77adb99dfac9e6027f0d3fc0730f1e75</guid></item><item><title>Pete Hegseth announces latest strike on boat near Venezuela he says was trafficking drugs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/us-strikes-alleged-drug-boat-near-venezuela/105851724</link><description>Without providing evidence, Pete Hegseth says the intelligence "without a doubt" confirms that the vessel was carrying drugs and that the people on board were "narco-terrorists".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64e28916ac0322747228d8e559be25c6</guid></item><item><title>Former health boss says a new hospital won't fix WA's health crisis amid record ambulance ramping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/former-wa-health-boss-leads-audit-into-hospital-maintenance-/105847632</link><description>The man tasked with reviewing WA's "old and depleted" hospitals says building a brand new one will not fix a snowballing health crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">969edfc2e2e14dbbe9c1198c4288cda2</guid></item><item><title>Hamas prepared to release all Israeli hostages under Trump's Gaza plan — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/live-blog-hamas-peace-plan-response/105851760</link><description>The US president says "this is a very special day" and thanks other countries for their assistance in the peace proposal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9606c88af9a8a539b48afea879010f0</guid></item><item><title>Sean 'Diddy' Combs sentenced to 50 months' prison after offering tearful apologies in court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/sean-diddy-combs-sentenced-in-new-york-court/105847246</link><description>A New York judge says the disgraced music mogul's violence, coercion and abuse had devastating consequences on his two former partners, and he was unconvinced that Combs would not reoffend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cf4dfca9ee9f35e74ada3699a88df0e</guid></item><item><title>Ratepayers struggle with cost of living as Qld councils increase rates to alleviate financial pressures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/cost-of-living-pressures-on-ratepayers-as-qld-councils-up-rates/105833630</link><description>Advocates say an outdated funding model and cost shifting has left Queensland councils in a risky financial position, with nowhere left to turn for cash except ratepayers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdd3ddc678b450863f4eaa2599b7ef28</guid></item><item><title>What the NSW pill testing trial means for this summer festival season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/nsw-pill-testing-trial-music-festivals-summer/105844544</link><description>The service sits delicately at the intersection of harm reduction strategies by NSW Health and the police's work to stop illegal drug supply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ababb1b74d875c92b23be2e4fdbbc57d</guid></item><item><title>Dave Franco film Together pulled from China over AI censorship of queer couple</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/dave-franco-horror-film-pulled-from-china-over-ai-censorship/105844328</link><description>A film starring Dave Franco and Alison Brie, Together, is pulled from China after AI censorship of a queer couple in early screenings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a41f1774dba022bd5bba37068d0faa6d</guid></item><item><title>HUMANS space project records our thoughts on life, love and the universe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/sydney-records-thousands-of-messages-for-deep-space-broadcast/105835060</link><description>A new project is collecting thousands of messages destined for the cosmos, coinciding with the anniversary of a landmark space mission 50 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2102210edbfd59f53d81e3ab6ca4abc</guid></item><item><title>Carlton's style shift has Blues knocking on door of AFLW top four</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/aflw-carlton-blues-round-eight-analysis/105848936</link><description>Carlton's emergence as a finals threat is no surprise, with the Blues now possessing the personnel to execute an effective game plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe65dbc9e2cf1f1e3370a7053994089d</guid></item><item><title>Teen accused over fatal stabbing in Melbourne had history of offending, court hears</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/chol-achiek-dau-akueng-kon-sein-alleged-gang-crime/105849304</link><description>A court case into the alleged murder of an 18-year-old last year reveals a connection to the fatal attacks on Chol Achiek, 12, and Dau Akueng, 15, on September 6.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4daaad949b115317bb0aa8a49308beb0</guid></item><item><title>Deputy leader confident nuclear will be part of Coalition's energy policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/deputy-opposition-leader-confident-nuclear-in-energy-policy-mix/105848854</link><description>As the federal Coalition looks to resurrect a nuclear policy, an energy analyst and a workers' union fear the impacts of parliament's inability to agree on Australia's energy future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ac20f57d9638dadc774af02f728a0e3</guid></item><item><title>Olivia Dean, Nine Inch Nails, Big Thief lead September's best new albums</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/10-best-albums-of-september-olivia-dean-geese-nine-inch-nails/105843906</link><description>While Taylor Swift's new album might be dominating the conversation, some of the best records of the year also arrived in September, from Olivia Dean to Nine Inch Nails.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f5345cdf90588ae8868abca5d9e931d</guid></item><item><title>The complicated messaging surrounding SA’s algal bloom summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/mike-steer-algal-bloom-stateline/105843082</link><description>The face of South Australia's algal bloom response says the natural event "is not going to ruin summer" and he is looking forward to spending more time with his kids at the beach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d97d1426ebd61b033aa4dba8f13d714</guid></item><item><title>After a week of searching, police have found no signs of missing 4yo in South Australia's outback</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/how-search-for-missing-boy-gus-unfolded-in-sa-outback/105849108</link><description>A week of large-scale land and air searches have found no clues leading to the whereabouts of four-year-old Gus in outback South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdeb05521fb5b8b89aab8020bc84d684</guid></item><item><title>Backyard biobank project sets out to save Tasmania's 'spectacular' alpine plants from bushfire threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/backyard-biobanking-tasmania-alpine-plants-bushfire-threat/105730036</link><description>The backyards of ordinary Tasmanians are becoming urban climate refuges for a "biobank" of alpine plants threatened by climate change and bushfire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45c8f0b04a8f017a2c0ed2385d6ac5b5</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr stuck on the bench again as Chelsea held to WSL draw by Manchester United</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/kerr-on-bench-as-chelsea-held-to-draw-by-manchester-united/105851796</link><description>Matildas skipper Sam Kerr plays just 17 minutes off the bench for Chelsea as they lose their perfect WSL record with a 1-1 draw at Manchester United.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a26e9807d129f2891aeef93602b3d044</guid></item><item><title>What you need to know when tackling Tasmania's Cradle Mountain and Overland Track</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/how-to-visit-the-overland-track-and-cradle-mountain-prepared/105848588</link><description>Tasmania's wild places continue to captivate travellers, but experts say it is easy to underestimate how quickly a sunny day can flip to life-threatening conditions. One SES rescuer shares his advice for staying safe in the wilderness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2ca8270bb0549aa4469d3d941872bfc</guid></item><item><title>Hamas agrees to release Israeli hostages under Trump's peace plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/hamas-agrees-to-release-israeli-hostages-under/105851842</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddd8c61e11d2949cf2dfa642b7ebba7d</guid></item><item><title>Cheesy lemon ravioli is a simple dinner with just three steps - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/easy-lemon-ravioli-with-baby-spinach-cheese/105534228</link><description>The dish is completely unfussy, relying upon two pantry staples, zesty lemon and salty Parmesan, to bring big, punchy flavours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a4daf7b3744c92fb0ea0636c88cb2f6</guid></item><item><title>President Trump says peace in the Middle East is 'very close'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/president-trump-says-peace-in-the-middle-east-is/105851912</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b34ec9e24ee5535e21411fe9d3a94221</guid></item><item><title>Community's Big Lost Band at Pambula's Wanderer music festival 'too joyous' to ignore</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/big-lost-band-at-pambulas-wanderer-music-festival-community/105839362</link><description>With more than 100 members and only four rehearsals before showtime, the Big Lost Band is the ultimate musical challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a1cb2bd9d70714d2a4c4bb2eb85e784</guid></item><item><title>Perth Royal Show vendors upset by price hikes, say crowds are down in 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/perth-royal-show-vendors-say-crowds-lower-2025/105849896</link><description>Vendors are reporting smaller attendances at this year's Perth Royal Show amid a sharp increase in prices, both for visitors and game providers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea9f578d56db957edc70368ef4c2813f</guid></item><item><title>Satellite images show razed buildings, armoured vehicles moving into Gaza City</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/satellite-images-show-israels-assault-on-gaza-city/105848138</link><description>Israeli troops are moving closer and closer to the heart of Gaza City, razing rows of buildings and converting tent cities into front lines, an ABC News analysis of satellite images shows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33b1710702f75158808d410acb921160</guid></item><item><title>How Cairns startup Rainstick is using biotech to transform farming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/rainstick-cairns-biotech-startup-seed-treatment-canola/105844476</link><description>A Cairns biotech startup is combining Indigenous knowledge of "rainmaking" with modern science to develop an electrical seed treatment hoping to improve crop growth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3bb4007ae6a425efddef231001ba667</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie says quitting frontbench not an attempt to replace Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/andrew-hastie-speaks-after-quitting-shadow-cabinet/105852056</link><description>Liberal MP Andrew Hastie insists his decision to quit the frontbench is not part of an attempt to replace Sussan Ley as the federal opposition leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46e1256eabab0a5475878a5a25ce40cb</guid></item><item><title>Small town police officer chases big country music dream</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/wa-police-officer-chases-country-music-dreams/105802288</link><description>West Australian country police officer Darren Gillis writes original music inspired by his day job and the loss of mates he met in the field.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">763fd713ddde8dd99d82cce44d965db4</guid></item><item><title>Oasis guitarist Bonehead to miss Australian shows due to cancer treatment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/bonhead-from-oasis-has-prostate-cancer/105851978</link><description>Paul Arthurs, better known as Bonehead, posted on X: "I'm really sad to be missing these shows but I'm feeling good and will be back."</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16296298c9da95991c1d8a096ddbd499</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie’s resignation over immigration couldn’t be worse timing for Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/andrew-hastie-resignation-bad-timing-for-sussan-ley/105852022</link><description>Hastie says he decided to quit because a letter she sent him earlier in the week made clear he wouldn't be formulating the Coalition's immigration policies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">089f946d1a6a6f1ef557a2a4a939654a</guid></item><item><title>More than 200 skeletons uncovered in mass grave in Sri Lanka, exposing its haunting history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/chemmani-sri-lanka-mass-graves-skeletons-discovered/105808016</link><description>A shocking mass grave discovery in Sri Lanka reignites global attention on one of the world's highest cases of unresolved enforced disappearances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39c66bb5798720a71f2f2777154fa72a</guid></item><item><title>Kangaroos post 20th straight win as AFLW record falls, Lions romp to derby victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/aflw-saints-giants-kangaroos-swans-suns-lions-power-bulldogs/105852414</link><description>The Kangaroos' premiership defence remains on course following a 68-point thrashing of Sydney, while Brisbane snags its third consecutive win of the season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6bff69aaf2c14c2a48f0ac871b60278</guid></item><item><title>Sanae Takaichi set to be Japan's first female PM after winning Liberal Democratic Party leadership contest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/japan-ldp-leadership-election-results/105852408</link><description>The decision comes after the Prime Minister Shigeru Ishiba announced his resignation last month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a720fc526dcf766496a5d9b2baba6b7a</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies fall to 28-14 defeat against All Blacks in Bledisloe Cup contest in Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/live-updates-wallabies-vs-all-blacks-bledisloe-cup-perth/105852258</link><description>Australia's hopes of an unlikely Rugby Championship triumph have been extinguished with a 28-14 loss to New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7c86ac526474fe90d71c39a421320a3</guid></item><item><title>Sam Konstas falls cheaply, Jake Weatherald boosts Ashes hopes on day one of Sheffield Shield</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/konstas-falls-cheaply-sheffield-shield-day-one/105852584</link><description>Australia's incumbent Test opener Sam Konstas is dropped and survives two LBW appeals before being dismissed for four on day one of the Sheffield Shield.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9daf06f12a5fb445516ebd9f3fb7b24d</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds attend justice march for Kaiden Morgan-Johnston in Morwell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/kaiden-morgan-johnston-justice-march-morwell/105843720</link><description>Around 600 people attend a justice march for Kaiden Morgan-Johnston, who died after he was allegedly stabbed while walking to a friend's house in Morwell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9584f7523ceef2892ca4394ae442970</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Women's World Cup match against Sri Lanka washed out in Colombo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/womens-cricket-world-cup-australia-sri-lanka-live-scores-stats/105852128</link><description>Australia's World Cup pool match against Sri Lanka in Colombo was abandoned due to rain, with no play possible due to the inclement weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2063e74bcd4e75b3a7fcd1e6afc214bd</guid></item><item><title>Russian strike hits Ukrainian passenger train at Shostka station, authorities say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/russian-attack-hits-ukrainian-train-in-shostka/105852688</link><description>A Russian drone strike has hit a passenger train in Ukraine's northern Sumy region and injured dozens of people in an act President Volodymyr Zelenskyy has denounced as 'terrorism'.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99488954239e654dcd7be031db995dec</guid></item><item><title>Diamonds defeat Proteas 64-53 in first netball Test in Bendigo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/netball-test-australia-diamonds-south-africa-proteas/105852710</link><description>Australia has overcome a promising start from South Africa to win 64-53 in the first netball Test in Bendigo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d30ac6cd4929422024452e1d1179b428</guid></item><item><title>Mitch Marsh inspires Australia to three-wicket win over New Zealand in third T20I</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/t20-international-australia-new-zealand-tauranga/105852708</link><description>Mitch Marsh's first T20I century helped the Australian men's team record a stunning three-wicket win over New Zealand across the Tasman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">deec40bd1caaefd9d7ce251cbf922de3</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle Jets defeat semi-professional Heidelberg United 3-1 to lift first Australia Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-04/newcastle-jets-win-australia-cup-over-heidelberg-united/105852580</link><description>The Newcastle Jets have defeated semi-professional club Heidelberg United 3-1 to claim their first silverware since 2008.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bc95933e07f6b66ac7c76d17ab84dac</guid></item><item><title>Betting companies keep millions stolen from investors by 'VIP' gambler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/betting-companies-keep-vip-gamblers-stolen-millions-four-corners/105843526</link><description>Nick and Aimee Mazza's hard-earned cash was gambled away by a man they thought was investing it. Bookmakers encouraged him to keep betting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42e39985dc4f61b535e2da312f2a4c6d</guid></item><item><title>Fried shark and maggots: Indonesia's free meal program poisons thousands of children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/indonesia-free-meal-program-poisons-thousands-of-kids/105836302</link><description>The key election commitment of President Prabowo Subianto is facing mounting backlash over its poor oversight, questionable food sourcing and unhygienic kitchens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e2fccd95400de4be56e63556ca69126</guid></item><item><title>Sean 'Diddy' Combs has been sentenced to four years in prison. Here's a breakdown of the case and where to next</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/sean-diddy-combs-sentenced-prison-case-breakdown/105852240</link><description>Sean "Diddy" Combs may have just been sentenced to four years in prison, but he still faces a mountain of lawsuits accusing him of sexual violence and other misconduct.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46698722afdc0b8fd805bb4736cd45e0</guid></item><item><title>AI is creeping into our court system. Will it undermine justice?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/artificial-intelligence-law-robot-legal-judge-jury-ai/105545900</link><description>Artificial intelligence is coming for the law. Are we ready for robots to become judge and jury?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e1797579913bae4cb5a8a9d33306767</guid></item><item><title>Israel, Hamas and US to begin new Gaza peace talks, as Netanyahu says he wants negotiations done quickly</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/new-gaza-ceasefire-talks-to-begin-in-egypt/105852826</link><description>Representatives of Israel, Hamas and the United States are set to begin fresh talks in Egypt about how to implement Donald Trump's Gaza ceasefire plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">431d17bf0343a28b6076558cc09a0c6c</guid></item><item><title>Hard Quiz Kids: Tom Gleeson is back grilling baby-faced brainiacs. Are you smarter than them?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/hard-quiz-kids-weekly-trivia-tom-gleeson/105829672</link><description>I find it interesting you think you could beat the know-it-all tweens on Hard Quiz Kids. How about you prove it? Let's play, HARD!</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a470db20ade13459d37c1802f5f147e9</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian photojournalist Ali Jadallah wins Siena Awards Photo Festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/siena-awards-photo-festival-winning-photographs/105833578</link><description>Ali Jadallah's photo, called Leaving Home, shows three people emerging from the rubble of their damaged building.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19b2e879eed8546fc3e8fb570dff4a4f</guid></item><item><title>Will Labor's housing fund recover from its rocky start and fix decades of decline?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/labor-housing-affordability-future-fund-off-to-slow-start/105852480</link><description>It takes a long time to build anything at all in Australia's dysfunctional housing market, even for the federal government, but Labor's social housing fund is inching towards an impact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d0476c8d77c2594cc1cad40456f936b</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's Gaza ceasefire plan could become the single best hope to end the bloodshed</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/donald-trump-gaza-ceasefire-plan-could-mark-an-end-to-bloodshed/105852952</link><description>For the first time since the conflict in Gaza began nearly two years ago, an American president told Israel to stop — and it did.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24f203f45bd79f84fd5259dce8d21f93</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's record crime wave sees the premier and police chief steering different ships</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/victorian-government-mike-bush-handling-of-youth-crime/105845950</link><description>While Premier Jacinta Allan narrows in on machetes and bail laws, Chief Commissioner Mike Bush is looking to broader horizons as Victoria witnesses record levels of offending.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47749d10a9f736ac9a43c068dac0cc04</guid></item><item><title>The changes hidden within 'cryptic' supermarket ingredient labels</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/supermarket-ingredients-changes-skimpflation/105478516</link><description>The main ingredient in dozens of supermarket products has been reduced, an ABC investigation has found, leading retail and marketing experts to call for more transparency around recipe changes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0b404c438de0f798543e14cbbbc5021</guid></item><item><title>Populist billionaire Andrej Babiš wins Czech Republic parliamentary election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/andrej-babis-ano-wins-czech-republic-parliamentary-election/105853348</link><description>The party of billionaire and self-declared "Trumpist" Andrej Babiš wins the Czech Republic's parliamentary election, near-final results show, which could steer the country away from supporting Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebf46c1ca99f4a6100682da1f8980f37</guid></item><item><title>How the Tallis Scholars opened the world of sacred choral music to new audiences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/how-the-tallis-scholars-opened-the-world-of-sacred-choral-music/105849010</link><description>This English vocal group took centuries-old church music from the archives and became a hit. They're back in Australia sharing this music with local audiences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfc9ac542d3a1aa952c8f8d59dcfbf8c</guid></item><item><title>Economics rather than environmental concerns could sink Woodside's proposed Browse gas project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/economic-doubts-over-browse-gas-project/105838392</link><description>The Browse gas project is staring down the full weight of Australia's climate movement. Analysts say that is the least of its worries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecf5fc2ff00cdd38128ff1bdcd14da3a</guid></item><item><title>One Battle After Another, Paul Thomas Anderson's latest film, already eyed for Oscar</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/one-battle-after-another-paul-thomas-anderson-film/105838240</link><description>One Battle After Another, starring Leonardo DiCaprio, uses the ever-turning wheel of political violence as a backdrop for a screwball adventure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e9722e5be393220e3ef6d51a097c812</guid></item><item><title>Australia was champion of the world three years ago, but now softball teams are struggling to find players</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/softball-decline-struggle-young-players-exposure-olympics/105851876</link><description>It was a schoolyard sport so common it once rivalled cricket as the most popular in Australia. But now grassroots teams are struggling to fill a team sheet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c27d12acae797957e866d7008cdb6895</guid></item><item><title>Some South Australian farmers facing long road to drought recovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/farmers-begin-long-recovery-after-year-long-sa-drought/105850610</link><description>Some South Australian farmers say they are still feeling the strain of drought after inconsistent winter rains left little room for recovery before the coming summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17b9cb9e734d8bd60eb0db15cbdbb695</guid></item><item><title>Alex De Minaur hits career-best mark with win at Shanghai Masters as ATP Finals loom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/de-minaur-hits-career-best-mark-with-win-at-shanghai-masters/105853398</link><description>Alex de Minaur sets a new personal record for wins in a year with a comfortable victory over Camilo Ugo Carabelli at the Shanghai Masters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc0f8ea3048522dab91e7a69c9ce7eed</guid></item><item><title>Prospecting mates who found Ming Dynasty Buddha urge prime minister to help repatriate it to China</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/buddha-found-in-shark-bay-urged-to-be-repatriated/105831250</link><description>A Ming Dynasty Buddha statue found on a roadside in Western Australia's Shark Bay region seven years ago could soon be repatriated to the largest Buddhist population in the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b1dda99c49d71b70e55094f4a9bda4f</guid></item><item><title>Line dancing helps Queensland community connect and keep moving</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/line-dancing-popularity-helps-queensland-community-connect-move/105815880</link><description>Organisers behind line dancing events say more people are coming to their evenings, and social media is driving its popularity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47723861c4ac72827fe3eb93195e70de</guid></item><item><title>Health workers say NT leading the nation in hepatitis B care, as diagnoses jump but mortality rates plummet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nt-hepatitis-b-diagnoses-rising-as-mortality-rates-decrease/105840336</link><description>Health workers say new data showing hepatitis B cases have almost tripled in the NT reflects better access to care, with the territory also leading the nation in reducing mortality rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5fdc774928dc47194833017cc4f13b2</guid></item><item><title>Babe's 30th anniversary celebrated in Robertson where film was shot</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/robertson-celebrates-30-years-since-babe-was-shot-in-the-town/105847244</link><description>Decades after hosting film crews making a children's movie about a loveable piglet, the town of Robertson in New South Wales is transformed into a country fair in tribute.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ee021ffad919f20582293d03868a10f</guid></item><item><title>UK police hold four people on suspicion of terror offences over Manchester synagogue attack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/uk-police-questioning-suspects-over-manchester-synagogue-attack/105853442</link><description>UK police are continuing to question four people arrested on suspicion of terror offences after an attack on a Manchester synagogue on Thursday that left two people dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f504af9ec1ed1ca1c5c9be82bfde77ae</guid></item><item><title>Greens leader Larissa Waters 'doesn't know very much' about wind farm opposed by colleagues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/greens-leader-larissa-waters-unsure-about-tasmanian-wind-farm/105853456</link><description>Larissa Waters says she will be looking closely at the Robbins Island wind farm, which the Greens's two Tasmanian senators say will threaten several endangered species.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04a1ed328b028d7562d776de27573de1</guid></item><item><title>Make-ahead dinners for busy weeknights</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/easy-make-ahead-meal-prep-dinners-for-busy-weeknights/105668174</link><description>Don't have time to cook most nights? These easy meals serve up to eight people and can get you through the week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9395351dbe146c8ee8681dfb00636a06</guid></item><item><title>Community saves endangered tropical sea turtle that washed up on Esperance beach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/esperance-tropical-green-turtle-visitor-north-west-wa/105839222</link><description>A community has sprung into action to nurse a juvenile tropical turtle back to health as wildlife carers question how it found its way to WA's south coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4ac34391201416c37af31bac8b03de5</guid></item><item><title>Harry Lush director of Gondwana Project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/harry-lush-director-of-gondwana-project/105853556</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc052d43324e94b02a9758439e00028f</guid></item><item><title>English springer spaniels Kelly and Milo helping fight dieback in Western Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/dieback-dogs-helping-fight-deadly-plant-disease/105849444</link><description>Two dogs join the fight against one of the biggest threats to Australia's native plants, making dieback detection possible in minutes rather than weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba971c766d020d17dfa85d059b2edf3b</guid></item><item><title>I got an unexpected afternoon tea invitation, and it told me a lot about Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/analysis-on-alexander-stubb-and-donald-trump-relationship/105851222</link><description>An afternoon tea meeting with a president is not the sort of invitation you get every day as a foreign correspondent, but when I met Finland's Alexander Stubb in Helsinki, it taught me a lot about another world leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e77bd18c49c780231a41cb654add893</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with murder of man believed to be her partner, police say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/woman-charged-with-port-pirie-south-death/105853574</link><description>A woman has been charged with murder after a man was reported unconscious in South Australia's mid-north on Friday and could not be revived.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">195d8cc77414e8fdb07fdc21853e9c01</guid></item><item><title>Homicide Squad investigating 'suspicious' death of 84yo woman in Sydney suburb of Melonba</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nsw-body-of-84yo-woman-in-her-melonba-home/105853626</link><description>The Homicide Squad is investigating the circumstances surrounding the death of an 84-year-old woman, who was found in her bedroom about midday Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b4f04ad76b564efa423012267ca9387</guid></item><item><title>Trump authorises deployment of 300 National Guard troops to Chicago</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/trump-deploys-300-national-guard-troops-chicago/105853704</link><description>US President Donald Trump has deployed 300 Illinois National Guard troops to Chicago after Governor JB Pritzker refused to do so.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e09d2adca78710fda0a973cf63b4970</guid></item><item><title>Who is Sanae Takaichi, set to be Japan's first female PM?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/sanae-takaichi-japan-ldp-leadership-prime-minister/105853536</link><description>Sanae Takaichi has won Japan's Liberal Democratic Party's leadership contest and is likely to become the country's first female PM. Here's what we know about her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">168ace564993b12a633f0b1f582bf714</guid></item><item><title>US Treasury unveils draft design for $1 Trump coin to mark 250th independence celebrations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/trump-coil-revealed/105853576</link><description>In 2020, the US Congress passed a law that allows the Treasury Secretary to mint $1 coins in 2026 "with designs emblematic of the US semi-quincentennial".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf499095bc04f4aa61baf295fc27ca60</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos beat Melbourne Storm in epic NRL grand final, Adam Reynolds injured, Brisbane ends Roosters' NRLW streak in decider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nrl-grand-final-live-blog-melbourne-storm-brisbane-broncos/105847434</link><description>The Brisbane Broncos beat the Melbourne Storm 26-22 in the NRL grand final despite losing both halves to injury in the second half.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7354e645e2773f7438e3a91beca5cf8b</guid></item><item><title>Mega-team of heavy horses sets world record at Good Old Days Festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/record-breaking-feat-for-mega-team-of-heavy-horses/105853716</link><description>Scores of heavy horses have been harnessed together at a heritage festival in southern New South Wales in what organisers say is a world record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82701463d0333bf75c6cf5d657e9b923</guid></item><item><title>European Space Agency launches second space antenna in New Norcia, north of Perth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/space-agency-opens-second-deep-space-antenna-new-norcia/105849820</link><description>A second deep space antenna opened in a tiny monastic town in Western Australia could help unlock the secrets of the universe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">897e2da31ddeaef33af502525555b9b4</guid></item><item><title>Rescuers recover more bodies of teenage victims after school collapse in Indonesia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/death-toll-indonesia-school-rises-36-students/105854064</link><description>The number of students confirmed dead after the collapse of an Islamic boarding school building in Indonesia has risen to 50, the country's search and rescue agency says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19795b7fb5c7d14c8fbd253e1749fe5a</guid></item><item><title>Mass civil wedding in Paraguay's capital sees more than 600 couples say 'I do' in unison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/mass-civil-wedding-paraguay/105853878</link><description>The event was part of a government campaign aiming to make civil weddings more accessible across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f3c3cca78b4fbbc1b5508b945213e55</guid></item><item><title>Tigers end AFLW drought in shock 11-point win over Crows as Blues and Eagles enjoy victories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/aflw-tigers-crows-cats-blues-eagles-magpies-round-eight/105854110</link><description>Richmond's dismal losing streak is over, with midfielder Monique Conti playing a starring role in a shock win over competition heavyweights Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebb6f06da858950421d033911c808ba2</guid></item><item><title>Authorities will investigate campfire that sparked major Moreton Island blaze</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/campfire-moreton-island-bushfire-alert/105853820</link><description>A "careless" campfire lit during a fire ban sparked a rapidly moving blaze that has now burnt hundreds of hectares on Moreton Island, according to authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce8c6a567bd717f2cc696fa8de3e838f</guid></item><item><title>Liberty Bell Bay smelter receives first shipment of ore since flagging financial woes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/liberty-bay-bell-smelter-receives-first-ore-shipment/105853550</link><description>A $20 million loan from the Tasmanian government to keep smelter Liberty Bell Bay afloat after it flagged financial woes earlier this year has led to the first shipment of ore being delivered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">091231e8b6fe5383bb688542b2c8f6b2</guid></item><item><title>Mele Hufanga's NRLW premiership-winning try now an unsolvable mystery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nrlw-grand-final-broncos-roosters-hufanga-try-decision-analysis/105854160</link><description>Brisbane and the Roosters played one of the greatest games in NRLW history, but the controversial winning try to Mele Hufanga shapes as a football mystery that might never be solved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43c47d417ebdd6d90d15557efded717f</guid></item><item><title>F1 Singapore Grand Prix: Lando Norris hits Oscar Piastri on first lap, George Russell wins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/f1-live-singapore-grand-prix-oscar-piastri-lando-norris/105845638</link><description>Oscar Piastri has been left furious at his teammate, and his team, after his two drivers' championship rivals gained ground on him in the Formula 1 Singapore Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e56a98a02a87c2eace2bac0d6de54efb</guid></item><item><title>Man in critical condition after shooting in Sydney's Croydon Park as police arrest alleged gunman</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/man-arrested-after-shooting-in-sydney-croydon-park/105854454</link><description>NSW Police say the alleged gunman had been "firing indiscriminately at passing vehicles including police vehicles".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f80a42b7620b731f82ec58637dfdb05</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh wins Clive Churchill Medal to ice Broncos' NRL premiership success</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nrl-grand-final-reece-walsh-wins-clive-churchill-medal-broncos/105854358</link><description>In one of the greatest individual performances in grand final history, Brisbane Broncos star Reece Walsh was judged player of the match after inspiring his side to their victory over the Melbourne Storm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4da114fbdd73820852f227f68040d6f</guid></item><item><title>How the internet reacted to Brisbane Broncos winning the NRL grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/internet-reacted-nrl-grand-final-reece-walsh-brisbane-broncos/105854070</link><description>The internet could barely believe what was happening as Brisbane, fuelled by Reece Walsh's brilliance, came from behind to win the NRL grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a773abe9892dbaf9421d194401021d35</guid></item><item><title>Why Brisbane Broncos's NRL premiership win is more about blood than gold</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-05/nrl-broncos-grand-final-win-reece-walsh-analysis/105854570</link><description>The Brisbane Broncos are flash and have never made apologies for it but, with their premiership win, they've proven they also have the true steel of champions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6201902fe26b76b27ebc4fd091ddb55</guid></item><item><title>Australia's de facto online betting regulator accused of being too close to gambling industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/nt-betting-regulator-accused-close-industry-four-corners/105848692</link><description>Four Corners has uncovered allegations of conflicts of interest and pro-industry bias at the country's part-time regulator responsible for Australia's biggest betting companies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95e49d8f6b396c0b6df1586a0c5a3614</guid></item><item><title>Spring heatwave creates dangerous fire conditions across Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/spring-heatwave-hot-dry-weather-fire-danger-queensland/105853486</link><description>Temperatures could soar to almost 10 degrees above average this week, increasing the risk of bushfires that are already burning across the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55c9a6e7da5d7bc2e446d0a260d21503</guid></item><item><title>Inside the mission to rescue dachshund Valerie from wild 529-day Kangaroo Island ordeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/how-valerie-became-the-worlds-most-notorious-sausage-dog/105832548</link><description>Valerie's disappearance on South Australia's Kangaroo Island unleashed a 529-day hunt. She dodged rescue attempts and traps and had some wondering whether the sausage dog was mocking them and having the time of her life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98688fa4bd2992085d88df58549d292f</guid></item><item><title>Documents reveal Australia's F-35 fighter jet export details 'quietly' disappeared</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/f-35-jet-fighter-supply-chain-israel-gaza-weapons-transfers/105783858</link><description>Department of Defence emails show that a website dedicated to Australia's role in the global F-35 supply chain used by Israel to maintain its fighter jets was removed at the start of the war in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6c999b923749d4e0235e817b0cee3d7</guid></item><item><title>Housing supply without controlling demand suggests National Housing Accord won't fix affordability</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/house-affordability-density-accord-first-home-buyer-cgt-student/105853500</link><description>The national project to fix housing affordability is off to a slow start but, from deposit schemes and negative gearing to immigration and construction delays, the reasons are complex.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f17886ca0bcb641add48e0a7f3cfd6e</guid></item><item><title>Russia launches drone and missile strikes on Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/russia-launches-drone-and-missile-strikes-on-ukraine/105854890</link><description>Authorities say nine regions across Ukraine were targeted by Russian night-time drone, missile and aerial bomb strikes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f563c2b2939092915726701d0a52f84</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Storm's new normal falls short in NRL grand finals and they're running out of chances</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/melbourne-storm-lose-second-straight-nrl-grand-final/105854346</link><description>The new and infinitely more exciting Melbourne Storm are finding out just how hard it is to play their exciting brand of footy when the tension is at its peak.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcc664b062ddc697654eb02247e6160e</guid></item><item><title>SA seafood demand still down as algal bloom safety message struggles to break through</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/sa-seafood-downturn-amid-algal-bloom/105838042</link><description>While industry and government tell consumers South Australian seafood is safe, consumer demand is still down amid the algal bloom, with businesses concerned they may not survive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f24ed267df69707658f158333dbd9ab</guid></item><item><title>SA foster care providers working to bring more culturally and linguistically diverse carers into the system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/culturally-and-linguistically-diverse-foster-carers/105755058</link><description>Masooma came to Adelaide as a refugee from Afghanistan in 2016, and has become the carer of a young girl from a similar cultural background. Experts say it is important carers reflected the diversity of children in care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad4334b7c6f485a97c49e24582a7b6f8</guid></item><item><title>The Sydney street workers helping get young people's lives back on track</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/youth-workers-break-barriers-with-young-people-in-sydney/105815280</link><description>Some of Sydney's vulnerable young people are being steered away from a life of crime, addiction and homelessness by a pair of youth workers who have had their own share of hardships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f11fa1e0d849012711a85134f7fad152</guid></item><item><title>Croydon Park shooting prompts strong police response</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/croydon-park-shooting-prompts-strong-police-response/105855254</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0e51589390fcc5485ccf495c34e1f23</guid></item><item><title>The man most Palestinians want as their leader has spent years in solitary confinement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/palestinian-prisoner-marwan-barghouti-in-israeli-prison/105854460</link><description>Despite spending more than 20 years behind bars, Marwan Barghouti is the man most Palestinians would want as their leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64a109140bf38879a49511d8661efd13</guid></item><item><title>Decades-old 'conversion therapy' resurfaces in today's trans youth healthcare debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/conversion-therapy-trans-paper-pushed-decades-later/105850280</link><description>A decades-old psychiatric study is influencing current debates over transgender youth health care. But a new analysis led by a survivor says the findings were deeply harmful and dangerously misleading.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e95b828d4654c4252282ff2e665291d0</guid></item><item><title>ASX falters short of a record, gold and bitcoin jump and Japan surges on news of a new PM — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates-october-6/105854602</link><description>The ASX was dragged down by selling in banks outpacing demand for gold and rare earth stocks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be521882fb5d64f5bdf480bb82489fec</guid></item><item><title>Blizzard traps hundreds of hikers on Mount Everest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/blizzard-traps-hundreds-of-hikers-on-mount-everest/105855278</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74cf724c543b600e243ef47a036a4323</guid></item><item><title>Older Territorians say they still feel unsafe as residents' homes targeted by armed thugs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/calls-for-nt-ban-on-machetes-and-crossbows/105747486</link><description>There are growing calls for the NT government to ban machetes and crossbows as older residents share horror stories of being targeted in their own homes by armed youths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98526e141c9a7f83758a60d5e4e60adc</guid></item><item><title>East Gippsland volunteer groups left to pick up insurance bill on Crown land</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/victoria-council-insurance-costs-volunteer-groups/105773254</link><description>A council in Victoria's east tells volunteer groups it will no longer pay for their insurance policies, sparking community concerns and raising questions as to whose responsibility it should be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21b82e8865ff6c3735ba98e29ece0eca</guid></item><item><title>Ten years on from 2015, Ben Hunt wins the Broncos premiership he's waited for his whole life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/ben-hunt-wins-nrl-grand-final-with-brisbane-broncos/105854350</link><description>Defeat in the 2015 decider was so scarring, Hunt eventually felt the need to move away from the club he loves. Ten years later and back in his home colours, he's a 350-game, premiership-winning NRL player.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f8db8ef48ab55750750e26bd011f36b</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Anthony Albanese and PNG PM James Marape sign landmark defence treaty — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/federal-politics-live-blog-october-6/105849122</link><description>Anthony Albanese and PNG Prime Minister James Marape have signed a landmark defence treaty in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3160366ab5632d14709b8ac3449ab00</guid></item><item><title>Calls to ban machetes as elderly Territorians terrorised in their own homes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/stateline-nt-calls-ban-machetes-as-elderly-territorians-hurt/105855298</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50227819e4fb3d1211eb8ade2e674398</guid></item><item><title>Outback businesses raise concerns about Services Australia's Centrepay reforms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/outback-wa-retailers-worried-about-centrepay-reforms/105844344</link><description>Business owners worry major changes to a buy now, pay later system used by about 500,000 social security recipients will cause a raft of issues when it begins next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df02be8a6f258116a4f810bdcb01fba1</guid></item><item><title>Griffin Coal failure sees WA taxpayers fork out millions to Indian bank, despite government promises</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/taxpayer-dollars-leak-offshore-amid-griffin-coal-failure/105846232</link><description>The WA government is facing fresh questions over its bailout of Griffin Coal — a mine critical to the state's energy system — amid revelations taxpayer money is leaking offshore.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7f293a0b660fb2a630645a7606afe128</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day one: Essendon firm on Zach Merrett as Carlton set to play hardball with Charlie Curnow</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/afl-trade-period-day-one-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105853514</link><description>Essendon once again firmly states that captain Zach Merrett will not leave the Bombers as all 18 clubs begin the wheeling and dealing on the first day of the AFL's trade period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf92b2ca3ab4ca2c9aa8406b4938bc0c</guid></item><item><title>Mount Everest rescue underway after snowstorm traps hundreds of trekkers in Tibet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/mount-everest-rescue-hundreds-of-trekkers-escape-snowstorm/105855262</link><description>Local villagers and rescue teams help hikers stranded on Mount Everest after a snowstorm pummels the Himalayas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b076459219cbd10758599c14f0f0a0cb</guid></item><item><title>Vintage cars race on historic Lake Perkolilli track in Red Dust Revival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/red-dust-revival-vintage-car-race-lake-perkolilli-kalgoorlie/105852018</link><description>A dusty claypan in outback Western Australia is transformed back into a historic race track, as vintage car and motorcycle enthusiasts re-enact races held a century ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5bff53860ce1456e43f42d40286af3d</guid></item><item><title>The chicken and egg dilemma fuelling house prices – 6 October 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/the-chicken-and-egg-dilemma-fuelling-house-prices-/105856110</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af996de1ea6ee0eff39713353a3ab126</guid></item><item><title>Former NFL quarterback Mark Sanchez charged after being stabbed in altercation with truck driver</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/former-nfl-quarterback-mark-sanchez-stabbed-and-charged/105856006</link><description>Fox Sports analyst and former NFL player Mark Sanchez is charged after being stabbed multiple times in an altercation with a truck driver.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60123ea56faac692d81f8adb084b0967</guid></item><item><title>Defiant Ange Postecoglou says he will fight back as Nottingham Forest lose again</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/ange-postecoglou-defiant-after-another-loss/105856146</link><description>Ange Postecoglou fires up in a post-match press conference after Nottingham Forest lose to Newcastle United 2-0.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">628a8faa39f11e61f1e59c5dc3df9228</guid></item><item><title>US military deployed to quell Chicago riots</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/us-military-deployed-to-quell-chicago-riots/105856336</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da0461e102252d73a65dd51a14781c57</guid></item><item><title>NSW flood victims' personal details loaded to ChatGPT in major data breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/data-breach-northern-rivers-resilient-homes-program-chatgpt/105855284</link><description>The NSW Reconstruction Authority says the breach occurred in March and involved the personal data of applicants to the Northern Rivers Resilient Homes Program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">969bbd087c4743bb4d0cd5d00a3aefeb</guid></item><item><title>Clients of Melbourne builder MJ Harris Group lose life savings as company goes bust</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/melbourne-builder-mike-harris-under-investigation/105849496</link><description>More than a dozen customers of MJ Harris Group have told the ABC they have been left significantly out of pocket after the company went into liquidation this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46d68729bac68ea68b04eb0537f41503</guid></item><item><title>Judge blocks Trump from deploying National Guard troops to Oregon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/judge-blocks-donald-trump-from-deploying-national-guard-oregon/105855384</link><description>A federal judge temporarily blocks Donald Trump from deploying Californian National Guard troops to Portland, after earlier blocking the US President from mobilising local troops in Oregon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcc61c937e41ec58121335fd63529179</guid></item><item><title>Reece Walsh's NRL grand-final heroics with Broncos rewarded with Kangaroos call-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/nrl-kangaroos-squad-ashes-reece-walsh-broncos-grand-final/105856380</link><description>Recognition of Reece Walsh's breathtaking performance in the NRL grand final continues, with the Brisbane Broncos hero set to make his Test debut for Australia later this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8158c6162030b6da5ff5baca267e3263</guid></item><item><title>What is task paralysis and how do you overcome it?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/what-is-task-paralysis-and-how-to-overcome-it/105816676</link><description>Experts say feeling stuck or frozen when trying to start or complete a task can be the body's response to overwhelm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">148760b52f8431484adce2b1a2fde63d</guid></item><item><title>Broncos great Ali Brigginshaw to co-captain Jillaroos after NRLW grand final victory</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/nrlw-australia-jillaroos-brisbane-broncos-ali-brigginshaw/105856578</link><description>Ali Brigginshaw is named as a Jillaroos co-captain after helping steer the Brisbane Broncos to their fourth NRLW premiership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf319e012e91eeee866e7fc0a592b128</guid></item><item><title>As the AFLW begins to even out, North Melbourne remains untouchable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/north-melbourne-aflw-untouchable-as-comp-evens-out/105856458</link><description>North Melbourne claims its 20th win in a row as it looks to go undefeated for another season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4eb6269951bcaae08f99f7462a32cef</guid></item><item><title>Broncos star Pat Carrigan says a wooden spoon from 2020 helped motivate him for the grand final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/pat-carrigan-on-wooden-spoon-motivating-2025-nrl-grand-final-win/105856516</link><description>Fans left wooden spoons on Brisbane's training ground in 2020 — it was a move that helped motivate Pat Carrigan to greatness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3da51a345783afff5c94b8cb122d1f73</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man allegedly 'stormed a home', threatened mother and son with taser and demanded prescription drugs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/act-man-allegedly-threatens-mother-and-son-with-taser-in-home/105856840</link><description>A man who allegedly "stormed a home" and threatened a mother and son with a taser while demanding prescription drugs and cash will remain in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e72e6178e715991086eb171f7ccf0ce</guid></item><item><title>Forensics scour Croydon Park shooting scene as NSW Police probe motive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/sydney-croydon-park-shooting-dozens-injured/105855200</link><description>A suburb in Sydney's inner west was plunged into lockdown overnight after the alleged gunman, Artemios Mintzas, opened fire on passing cars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a20d6987b342fd746c29eecb1a0fa82a</guid></item><item><title>Brooke Street Pier dislodged, shade sail collapses as heavy winds bluster Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/heavy-winds-brooke-street-pier-hobart/105856270</link><description>Wind gusts of about 90 kilometres per hour were measured in Hobart on Sunday afternoon, with the blustery conditions set to continue this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46c97f1829d4d7777934a5f9592e1511</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand pays $5.3 million to Samoa after sinking navy ship Manawanui on pristine reef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/new-zealand-pays-compensation-samoa-manawanui-spill/105856488</link><description>The New Zealand government says it has done "the right thing" in offering a $5.3 million compensation payout to the Samoan government after its navy sunk a ship on a pristine reef off the Pacific island.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99f964ebb4c46ee11f26209f97fd7525</guid></item><item><title>Lando Norris says anyone who criticised his driving after Oscar Piastri incident 'shouldn't be in F1'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/f1-singapore-grand-prix-norris-hits-back-at-piastri/105857140</link><description>Lando Norris says anyone who criticised his driving at the Singapore Grand Prix "shouldn't be in F1", after Oscar Piastri openly criticised Norris's driving.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4083252c6f9dff2e25af2772d6fcbf25</guid></item><item><title>Passengers rescued after V/Line bus crashes near Victorian town of Foster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/vline-bus-crash-foster/105857160</link><description>A V/Line bus carrying a number of passengers plunges down an embankment in Victoria's south east, prompting a high-angle rescue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72f25979bd8ad79b5b0f830a53d26a5f</guid></item><item><title>How much are NRL and NRLW premiership rings worth? What do they look like?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/how-much-nrl-nrlw-premiership-rings-worth-what-do-the-look-like/105856106</link><description>The men's rings are valued at $15,000, while the women's rings have a price tag of $10,000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63575b695f4173281ef2a75ac53c102b</guid></item><item><title>Nathalie Matthews granted bail after airport arrest over sharing intimate image charges</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/nsw-nathalie-matthews-granted-bail-after-sydney-airport-arrest/105856636</link><description>Nathalie Matthews, 38, was arrested on Sunday morning after arriving on a flight from Dubai at Sydney Airport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f7b99fef1350a22661f690e945948c4</guid></item><item><title>Perth obstetrician Rhys Bellinge admits to reckless, dangerous driving days before fatal crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/perth-obstetrician-rhys-bellinge-pleads-guilty-driving-charges/105679920</link><description>Perth obstetrician Rhys Bellinge pleads guilty to driving dangerously and recklessly in the days before he crashed his car in Dalkeith and left a 24-year-old woman dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26d32c644d91222401685a921c93977d</guid></item><item><title>Why Kangaroos coach Kevin Walters is looking to the past ahead of Ashes series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/kangaroo-squad-ashes-kevin-walters-reece-walsh/105857268</link><description>New Kangaroos coach Kevin Walters was part of an era where the green and gold jersey was the highest honour rugby league could offer and ahead of the return of the Ashes it's a legacy he's desperate to pass down to his players.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58a50a4f00610fe11bdd54dcdff1814e</guid></item><item><title>Roosters forward Aliyah Nasio sent to judiciary over NRLW grand final brawl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/nrlw-grand-final-aliyah-nasio-roosters-judiciary/105857520</link><description>Sydney Roosters forward Aliyah Nasio is facing a ban for throwing a punch in the brawl at the conclusion of the NRLW grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d859f0db5c7d1d85425a636873ed3736</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested over Croydon Park shooting</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/man-arrested-over-croydon-park-shooting/105858196</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3294d9266a425c96dbac6c0b6e8763eb</guid></item><item><title>Bushfire on Moreton Island, north of Brisbane, burns 2,300 hectares before being contained</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/moreton-island-bushfire-brought-under-control/105858014</link><description>Investigators believe the fire was sparked by a campfire lit on Saturday morning while an active fire ban was in place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4922de4061c63a1055c9ef36fc8317d</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne hands Ashes selectors reminder with Sheffield Shield century</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/marnus-labuschagne-sheffield-shield-scores/105857408</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne has hit his first century in red ball cricket for over a year just one month out from the first Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a176bd65e86e8cee22777c8998188414</guid></item><item><title>More Optus triple-0 call failures on new dates, customers reveal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/more-optus-triple-zero-fails-outside-of-confirmed-times/105856172</link><description>Optus customers have come forward to report more cases of triple-0 calls failing outside the embattled telcos previously admitted outages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4358d6f86eb6a37293922181877cd73e</guid></item><item><title>Dead hikers yet to be identified as locals warn of High Country danger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/mount-bogong-hiker-deaths-warning/105856534</link><description>Locals in Victoria's High Country are warning visitors about the unpredictable conditions in the alpine region, after the bodies of two women were discovered near Falls Creek.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18a153de7905cf24421857133c950682</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese calls for political temperature to be 'turned down' after alleged death threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/prime-minister-alleged-death-threat-anthony-albanese/105858202</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is calling for the political temperature to be "turned down" after a Queensland man was charged for allegedly threatening to kill him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cae1e40518af609d9b8421b8d76ddf3d</guid></item><item><title>Trump deploys National Guard in city deeply scarred by military force</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/national-guard-chicago-1968-history/105740956</link><description>The National Guard was deployed to Chicago streets in 1968. It changed the city forever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de315904cfb310941c0e5754b3c7116</guid></item><item><title>Homeschool registrations are rising and policy needs to catch up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/australians-homeschooling-registrations-growth-queensland/105857486</link><description>Primary school homeschooling registrations in Queensland grew by 110 per cent from 2021 to 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2da6ac568e30445c88402c2dd8b19cc</guid></item><item><title>Australia and Papua New Guinea sign landmark alliance vowing to defend each other in conflict</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/australia-png-sign-defence-treaty-of-mutual-alliance/105858244</link><description>PNG and Australia formally sign a landmark new defence treaty, elevating the bilateral relationship between the two countries to an alliance and agreeing to "act to meet the common danger" if the other is attacked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">614af408f76065f8117ef33a6b854264</guid></item><item><title>Broncos shares surge 40 per cent after Grand Final win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/broncos-shares-surge-40-after-grand-final-win/105858608</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb9f530fa3b53960f57deb774eadfed4</guid></item><item><title>Turning Point Australia moves into SA, but Opposition Leader says 'votes are won in the centre of politics'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/turning-point-australia-sa-move/105857144</link><description>The Australian affiliate of late right-wing activist Charlie Kirk's Turning Point USA is moving into South Australia ahead of next year's state election, but some politicians say the group is "out of step with mainstream values".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19f9db450ad072ef6bf671c279dc257c</guid></item><item><title>Forensic pathologist unable to say how 19-year-old Melbourne woman Isla Bell died</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/isla-bell-murder-committal-death-court/105856086</link><description>The body of Melbourne woman Isla Bell was so badly damaged that forensic experts were unable to say how she died, a court has been told.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a77bfa1fcf1d9df6ad88ac7f0731821</guid></item><item><title>Embarrassing roadside antics can't halt Tadej Pogačar's continued assault on cycling history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/embarrassing-roadside-antics-tadej-pogacar-european-champs/105858228</link><description>A spectator pulled down his pants and bared his bottom towards two-time reigning world cycling champion Tadej Pogačar, while others slapped stickers on his back. But the Slovenian still won the European Championships road race.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9609baf9b32ea2859f5f97ad797d35ad</guid></item><item><title>York family honours late son with tractor museum to fund cancer research</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/oliver-crane-tractor-museum-raises-money-for-cancer-research/105848104</link><description>Oliver Crane was diagnosed with bone cancer and died at age 17. This week, his family opened a vintage tractor museum in his memory to help raise money for cancer research.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13789f2997dab8a6f7214155c926b1c1</guid></item><item><title>Hikaru Nakamura accused of disrespecting chess world champion with wild celebration</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/chess-player-throws-piece-after-checkmating-world-champion/105857474</link><description>World number two Hikaru Nakamura has beaten the current world champion Gukesh Dommaraju and thrown his king to the cheering crowd, prompting the chess world to debate whether it was showmanship or disrespect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83f02773a09d25c2b8d69f34bb6008ac</guid></item><item><title>Timothy Hunt convicted of murdering Tony Rowe after month-long Supreme Court trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/nt-darwin-man-timothy-hunt-convicted-murder-tony-rowe/105842404</link><description>Darwin man Timothy Hunt has been convicted of murdering Tony Rowe, whose remains were found on the city's outskirts in May 2023, one year after he was reported missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bca0b60fc6589bb7b45b48088fbc19a5</guid></item><item><title>Director of Public Prosecutions to appeal Erin Patterson's sentence over mushroom murders</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/dpp-appeal-erin-patterson-mushroom-murder-sentence/105858980</link><description>Victoria's Director of Public Prosecutions will appeal the sentence handed down to convicted triple-murderer Erin Patterson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63e8bcd098608d6f67fa643fd0271893</guid></item><item><title>Team Australia wins back-to-back Motocross of Nations titles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/team-australia-go-back-to-back-in-motocross-of-nations/105856060</link><description>Queensland brothers Jett and Hunter Lawrence help secure Australia's second consecutive Motocross of Nations title in Indiana.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c01890fe6dc96d2122a816cdf583308a</guid></item><item><title>Newcastle Yowies' dual glory in 2025 Koori Knockout rugby league finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/yowies-win-2025-koori-knockout-rugby-league-competitions/105857270</link><description>Yowies playmaker Kyle Laybutt kicks a mammoth field goal to seal victory in the men's final, while the Yowies women keep a clean sheet in their grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d04374ba9775987a358b27b3e554bf57</guid></item><item><title>Tourists reminded to stay alert as bushfire near Kempsey burns close to Pacific Highway</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/collombatti-bushfire-extreme-fire-danger-pacific-highway/105855400</link><description>Firefighters are able to bring a blaze on the NSW Mid North Coast under control after a Watch and Act alert was issued on Monday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d36e1ac1ba8d41f19907e296fa32fbd</guid></item><item><title>Former Perth teacher Rodney Neville Watkins on trial for alleged historical sexual abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/rodney-neville-watkins-trial-sexually-abusing-boys/105858570</link><description>WA's District Court hears historical allegations a Perth teacher sexually abused multiple boys along with his partner, who was also a teacher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d977a74502395f7542a70b224d7ef0c</guid></item><item><title>Woman bailed as murder charge downgraded over Port Pirie man's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/murder-charge-against-woman-downgraded-over-port-pirie-man-death/105859010</link><description>A Port Pirie woman has been bailed after police downgraded a murder charge laid over the death of a man to aggravated assault.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e23adaa48e62532ba5950aca7687893</guid></item><item><title>Canberra motorcyclist dies after losing control and colliding with tree near Tidbinbilla Nature Reserve</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/canberra-motorcyclist-dies-crash-tree-near-tidbinbilla/105858696</link><description>A 57-year-old Canberra man dies after losing control and colliding with a tree on Tidbinbilla Road. His death is the ACT's fifth road fatality this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e30caa35fd0575c9b7511ba4d7991fef</guid></item><item><title>Singapore PM offers condolences to families of Australians who died in Optus outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/singapore-pm-offers-condolences-to-families-of-optus-victims/105844832</link><description>Singapore's Prime Minister, Lawrence Wong, offers his condolences to the families of four Australians who died during an Optus network technical failure last month, which impacted hundreds of triple-0 calls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92e4a1d3ba99f0f05ba90b8864e4e46b</guid></item><item><title>England's 2003 Rugby World Cup winner Lewis Moody reveals MND diagnosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/england-rugby-world-cup-winner-lewis-moodey-mnd-diagnosis/105859128</link><description>Lewis Moody, a former England rugby captain who helped his side win the 2003 World Cup, has been diagnosed with Motor Neurone Disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0125bfc995e3b0a490581c1e722fb8f3</guid></item><item><title>Whakaari eruption inquest hears from frustrated families calling for answers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/whakaari-white-island-inquest-families-want-answers/105859164</link><description>A close family member of a tour guide who died in the Whakaari White Island eruption in 2019 has given an emotional statement as the inquest into the tragedy continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f4b4fa1270dc88d6b858f6039ee3eb6</guid></item><item><title>Greta Thunberg deported as Australian flotilla activists detained by Israel allege physical abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/australian-flotilla-activists-allege-israeli-authorities-abuse/105858942</link><description>Climate campaigner Greta Thunberg and more than 100 activists from the Gaza aid flotilla have been deported to Greece and Slovakia, Israel says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b714cb3ea153979a61059537e52b1de6</guid></item><item><title>French PM Sébastien Lecornu resigns after less than a month in role</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/french-pm-sebastien-lecornu-resigns/105859512</link><description>Mr Lecornu had just formed a new cabinet, which was met with criticism across all sides of politics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c15c6fa5fac96cdd6f330be716e37ae</guid></item><item><title>Papua New Guinea may sit out potential conflict between Australia and China despite Pukpuk defence treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/png-may-sit-out-australia-china-conflict-despite-defence-pct/105859432</link><description>Papua New Guinea Prime Minister James Marape says there is a "high possibility" the country would not enter a conflict involving Australia and China, despite having signed a mutual defence treaty with its southern neighbour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59feb7c5420f2241d7bceb57053d4049</guid></item><item><title>Monday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/monday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105859530</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">506757f396e017cb4299581c67727f19</guid></item><item><title>Minister puts telcos on notice after triple-zero outages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/minister-puts-telcos-on-notice-after-triple-zero/105859686</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">055d99d9efe42d906ab12bf527d7d600</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Party rift widens as Andrew Hastie quits the frontbench</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/liberal-party-rift-widens-as-andrew-hastie-quits/105859696</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0ff17c5df99e75bbdf407f38f5fbc3e</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested after allegedly driving ute towards woman and baby in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/man-allegedly-drives-ute-towards-woman-baby-in-alice-springs/105859450</link><description>A man is in police custody after allegedly driving a ute towards a woman and baby outside a shop in Alice Springs on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53b09fcf435c97092b892ed91ecc41ce</guid></item><item><title>Australia and PNG sign historic defence treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/australia-and-png-sign-historic-defence-treaty/105859702</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b173d2c5826ece6c20f72b1a9b9bb067</guid></item><item><title>PNG Prime Minister James Marape details Australia's mutual defence treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/png-prime-minister-james-marape-details-australias/105859716</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c75ea4c138faba481fd54c0c16e8de9</guid></item><item><title>Decades-old study influences modern trans youth healthcare debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/decades-old-study-influences-modern-trans-youth/105859724</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c04d8eac2636664efd1ecfda4b2240a</guid></item><item><title>Perth Royal Show attendance slumps to 10-year low</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/perth-royal-show-attendance-slumps-to-10-year-low/105857262</link><description>Attendance at this year's Perth Royal Show has hit a 10-year low, as organisers blame "heavy downpours" amid complaints from vendors about a lack of support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4db393861a1dcdbd2e0e82e56471da9</guid></item><item><title>English author Jilly Cooper, writer of The Rutshire Chronicles, dies at age 88</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/author-jilly-cooper-dies-at-age-88/105859754</link><description>The author was best known for The Rutshire Chronicles, including the novel Rivals, which was recently adapted into a Disney+ series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e8674f08b263feb4ef22338f75cf54a</guid></item><item><title>Trio of scientists win Nobel Prize in Medicine for 'discoveries concerning peripheral immune tolerance'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/scientists-win-nobel-prize-medicine-for-immune-system-work/105859742</link><description>The Nobel Prize for Medicine has been given to three scientists for discovering how our immune systems protect us from microbes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9af5df2f41780faee103603c8684e8f8</guid></item><item><title>Alleged Croydon Park gunman Artemios Mintzas charged with 25 offences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/alleged-croydon-park-sydney-inner-west-shooter-charged/105859136</link><description>Artemios Mintzas, 60, will appear in a Sydney court charged over an alleged shooting spree that shut down an inner west suburb for over 2 hours on Sunday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">986f11a7f0eebec2fb0bf6977ae58fea</guid></item><item><title>At least 63 people killed in Indonesia school collapse disaster in Java</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/indonesia-school-collapse-kills-at-least-63-people/105859952</link><description>The number of people killed in the disaster could still rise, with some half a dozen children still unaccounted for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb0eaac458f1bcf709a21c7c72610701</guid></item><item><title>Top stories from ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-06/top-stories-from-abc-news/105860012</link><description>Listen to ABC News interviews and commentary and analysis from radio programs like AM, PM and The World Today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f304b1f7626fdb2ded5edc137cb765fb</guid></item><item><title>Supreme Court rejects appeal from Ghislaine Maxwell, imprisoned former girlfriend of Jeffrey Epstein</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/supreme-court-rejects-appeal-from-ghislaine-maxwell/105860158</link><description>The US Supreme Court declines to hear Ghislaine Maxwell's bid to overturn her conviction for helping the late financier and convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein sexually abuse teenage girls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d5b59aebdf4950f84d1fdd5f88e9eba</guid></item><item><title>Gisèle Pelicot will face one of her rapists once again in a French appeals case. Here's why</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/gis%C3%A8le-pelicot-to-face-rapist-once-again-in-french-appeals-case/105859998</link><description>Less than a year after the landmark trial which shook the world, Gisèle Pelicot will once again brave a courtroom as one of her rapists appeals his sentence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0842838fb7ae8d253dc4d643711b09f</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds rescued from Mount Everest blizzard as another hiker dies from exposure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/hundreds-rescued-from-mount-everest-blizzard-as-search-continues/105860278</link><description>Villagers have joined rescue crews in attempting to save those who have become stuck in heavy snow on Mount Everest in Tibet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c346ab76f08305bcf69e0890afc2ea2d</guid></item><item><title>Detained Australians report rough treatment after Gaza flotilla detention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-07/australian-flotilla-detainees-rough-treatment-dfat/105860420</link><description>The ABC has obtained details of redacted summaries prepared by Australian diplomatic staff, which include allegations that one Australian citizen was slapped and had his passport "destroyed".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f89f99d6dba0ee5acb1705d6614a360</guid></item></channel></rss>