<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:44:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Split Enz announce reunion with details for 2026 tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/split-enz-reform-australia-tour-2026-neil-tim-finn-tickets/105985202</link><description>It's been 50 years since Split Enz's debut album. Now they're getting the band back together for a string of arena dates in next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71b99c99ed8a5191d9be2589d591f46f</guid></item><item><title>AFL gives teams finishing 10th chance to win premiership through wildcard round in finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/afl-introduces-wildcard-round-to-finals/105990434</link><description>AFL teams ranked ninth and 10th will be in contention to win the premiership from next season, with the league introducing a wildcard round.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cb6fcf04db4b1ef3eea270f6d0ef2f4</guid></item><item><title>Respected engineer sounds alarm on extent of defective Darwin apartment buildings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/darwin-apartment-buildings-engineer-reveals-structural-issues/105977092</link><description>A respected consulting engineer says about 80 per cent of apartment buildings he has inspected in Darwin have serious structural issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4902b737b004599439792c0255411950</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies 'not looking for excuses' after defeat to Italy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/wallabies-not-looking-for-excuses-after-italy-defeat/105990480</link><description>Wallabies coach Joe Schmidt says his weary charges must toughen up rather than seek excuses after falling to Italy in Udine, ahead of two more severe tests to come.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d487d44d41aa3a2c89b904f00063a609</guid></item><item><title>John Laws always knew how to hold an audience in his hand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/john-laws-viral-interview/105989826</link><description>On 7.30 in 2012, John Laws held forth with his customary flair and confidence and then as I wrapped up, he delivered probably the most memorable and amusing ending to any interview I've done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef49ea9deb2e73914aa7bfa51823728f</guid></item><item><title>Mildura Base Public Hospital caught duplicating feedback figures in annual reports</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/mildura-hospital-caught-copy-pasting-feedback-figures/105973940</link><description>A Victorian hospital has been caught copying and pasting its compliments and concerns data, after failing to update figures across multiple years of its annual reports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dd8187203414a0f04b51abe1a89f9f5</guid></item><item><title>Cable car on Kunanyi/Mount Wellington included in draft recommendations, Right to Information documents show</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/cable-car-kunanyi-mount-wellington-recommendations/105989592</link><description>The Tasmanian government has made a draft recommendation for a cable car on Hobart's Kunanyi/Mount Wellington, documents released under Right to Information laws show.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f9cfabb312b05dc2721ee4c9aadb240</guid></item><item><title>Exhibition depicting Geraldton homelessness shown at Canberra's Parliament House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/homelessness-in-regional-wa-depicted-in-exhibition-at-canberra/105979292</link><description>A portrait exhibition of people who have experienced homelessness is opening up conversations to show everyone has a story worth listening to.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ded7cfb57162c9de8a19f9f5fb8bdc3</guid></item><item><title>Why Oscar Piastri was handed a 10-second penalty during the F1 São Paulo Grand Prix</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/f1-brazil-oscar-piastri-penalty-explained/105990632</link><description>Oscar Piastri was involved in the biggest flashpoint of the Formula 1 São Paulo Grand Prix, earning him a costly penalty and damaging his chances of winning the drivers' championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcaafe3c179afa950d7c533a503dfc83</guid></item><item><title>More than 2,800 US flights cancelled in a day as government shutdown persists</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/more-than-2800-us-flights-cancelled-amid-government-shutdown/105990672</link><description>More than 2,800 domestic flights are cancelled in the United States over the course of a single day due to an ongoing shortage of air traffic controllers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64449d9430dae12595997a02f4742400</guid></item><item><title>Eastern ground parrot found in Narawntapu National Park, Tasmania</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/eastern-ground-parrot-found-northern-tasmania/105989568</link><description>The presence of an endangered and "cryptic" parrot species at a northern Tasmanian national park is hailed as "very good news" by a bird expert.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2104aa506842b2bed9427aea7c08501c</guid></item><item><title>This street is home to two cities with opposite laws and politics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/bristol-tennessee-virginia-contesting-laws/105864934</link><description>These two US cities share a name and a main street, but come election time, following the rules on one side of the road could land you in jail on the other.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9d979f11ce8f12b2e58245721afb7ab</guid></item><item><title>US Senate votes in favour of bill to end federal government shutdown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/us-senate-to-vote-on-bill-end-federal-government-shutdown/105991234</link><description>The US Senate votes in favour of ending the longest government shutdown in the country's history, which has lasted for 40 days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">080be43a8de7f4949f0aff2268f47954</guid></item><item><title>Emergency department waits of 35 hours for some SA mental health patients, AMA warns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/mental-health-patients-face-waits-in-sa-emergency-departments/105990492</link><description>About 10 per cent of mental health patients in South Australian hospital emergency departments are being kept waiting "more than 35 hours" for a bed, the AMA says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">775176c6a697379a1d5cf9a064a4e0e5</guid></item><item><title>Radio announcers pay tribute to John Laws's after his death at 90</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/nsw-john-laws-radio-industry-tributes/105990642</link><description>The biggest names in Australian radio have paid tribute to John "Golden Tonsils" Laws, who died aged 90.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6bd44e36e04de2dbb7472eb2e2c6b6e</guid></item><item><title>The trams that made Melbourne: Celebrating 140 years since the city's first cable tram</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/140-years-since-first-cable-tram-melbourne/105988072</link><description>Melbourne's history with trams goes back 140 years. The city got its first tram in 1885 and the fleet has grown to become the world's largest tram network.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbb798baec1dca364ee3a257508ac3f4</guid></item><item><title>Mark Parton elected as Canberra Liberals leader as Leanne Castley steps down, Jeremy Hanson resigns as deputy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/leanne-castley-steps-down-canberra-liberals-leader/105990626</link><description>There has been a complete shake-up in the leadership of the Canberra Liberals, with Mark Parton elected the new leader after Leanne Castley stepped down earlier this morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac613202ade80b75d7f88cf514e111e5</guid></item><item><title>Richmond set to host 'home' AFL fixture in Tasmania for the first time in club's history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/afl-richmond-sells-home-game-to-tasmania-first-time-ever/105991550</link><description>Richmond will run out for a home game in Tasmania for the first time in its history next season in a decision the club says it has not taken lightly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ef62228101692393dfb57e3c98f4130</guid></item><item><title>The AFL's Wildcard Round has been met with negative reviews, so why does it exist?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/nobody-seems-to-want-an-afl-wildcard-round-so-why-is-it-here/105990976</link><description>Footy fans are not impressed with the AFL's new finals-extending Wildcard Round, but it is all part of Andrew Dillon's grand plan for total domination of Australian sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7da2e359d28f840cb75f547b0a412092</guid></item><item><title>Youngest town in WA's Kimberley faces life without a cemetery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/kimberley-town-kununurra-facing-life-without-a-cemetery/105979730</link><description>From a floating coffin to a bed of rock, time is running out for Kununurra's cemetery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e65ba9b2ef9a3d892486b3e54ccb85bc</guid></item><item><title>NSW to review inmate classifications following prison guard bashing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/nsw-government-review-inmate-classification/105991166</link><description>The Commissioner of Corrective Services will undertake a review of inmate classifications after the assault of four prison guards earlier this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87afe2544a202ba531dfa55e4add6f13</guid></item><item><title>On the Myanmar-Thailand border, bombing a scam centre could barely dent the industry</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/myanmar-scam-centre-crackdown-on-border-with-thailand/105983376</link><description>Myanmar junta bombing of a scam centre is little more than "political theatre" to appease the international community, an expert says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">111e3a6cf4b85a3d64a66319423d19c8</guid></item><item><title>South Korea's former president accused of provoking military conflict with North Korea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/south-korea-yoon-suk-yeol-indicted-on-further-charges/105991888</link><description>Yoon Suk Yeol attempted to provoke military conflict between South and North Korea in order to declare martial law, a prosecutor's spokesperson tells a briefing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e101a4e282b69f15f02c31362f86608</guid></item><item><title>Lions are 'unrelenting' and yet again the underdogs for this finals series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/brisbane-lions-aflw-unrelenting-underdogs-going-deep-in-finals/105991986</link><description>The Brisbane Lions secured a spot in their sixth consecutive preliminary with a win over Melbourne on the weekend. Yet with North Melbourne's dominance, the Queenslanders are "underdogs" in the race for the flag once again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eded0898f61897ddb4dfc52317b1c28</guid></item><item><title>Family and police appeal for information linked to Brandon Yates's fatal stabbing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/brandon-yates-fatal-stabbing-family-police-appeal-information/105991536</link><description>Police launch a public appeal to help find the killer of 28-year-old man who died from stab wounds in Wollongong's main street.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be9c6fa88f2f250c07347246735c14f6</guid></item><item><title>Mark Parton elected as new Canberra Liberals leader</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/mark-parton-elected-as-new-canberra-liberals-leader/105992410</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab7fbb71098a914d10c61ae5d94ae412</guid></item><item><title>Redress scheme opens for 3,000 Stolen Generations survivors in WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/wa-stolen-generations-redress-scheme-begins/105992142</link><description>Survivors of the Stolen Generations in Western Australia can now apply for $85,000 in compensation as part of a government redress scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e62621627b22cf1fdee6dabbf4130b4</guid></item><item><title>Cameron Green to test reworked bowling action in Sheffield Shield clash ahead of Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/cricket-cameron-green-bowling-action-tweak-ahead-of-ashes/105992928</link><description>Australia is hopeful that a slight adjustment to Cameron Green's bowling action allows the star all-rounder to have a big say in this summer's Ashes campaign and beyond.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b39a96aa926cffb67630f5844de7ce7e</guid></item><item><title>Thinking about an e-bike or e-scooter for your kid? Here's what's legal and safe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/e-scooters-e-bikes-legal-kids-australia/105977472</link><description>E-bikes and e-scooters might sound like an exciting gift for a teenager or child, but experts say there are several things to consider before buying one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20d60fe9fa6b7f8b4290055a5bc0e226</guid></item><item><title>Measles warning issued for South West and Great Southern as confirmed case numbers climb</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/measles-warning-issued-or-wa-south-west-and-great-southern/105981388</link><description>Authorities and experts urge people in the state's south to be on alert for measles as the number of community transmission cases continues to climb.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79c139f029472d8734f70c7e0dee9903</guid></item><item><title>Cudlee Creek bushfire class action trial begins in SA's Supreme Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/class-action-trial-begins-over-cudlee-creek-bushfire/105992344</link><description>Victims of the devastating 2019 Cudlee Creek bushfire, which caused more than $200 million in damage, are seeking compensation from SA Power Networks, alleging the electricity distributor was negligent in the lead-up to the blaze.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e689dbc63fe763b94f277c5b7118f995</guid></item><item><title>Monday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/monday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/105991852</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">775ee07d4775d1bba51b46d6137b6d3b</guid></item><item><title>Mitchell Starc fires Ashes warning in Sheffield Shield return as Jake Weatherald and Beau Webster fail to fire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/cricket-mitchell-starc-shield-return-ominous-ashes-warning/105993582</link><description>Mitchell Starc enjoys a successful return to red ball cricket while representing New South Wales but Jake Weatherald and Beau Webster fail to grab their opportunities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1f676c07ed701e15ad97d41ccfd17df</guid></item><item><title>Push for a ban on using ‘doulas’ during childbirth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/push-for-a-ban-on-using-doulas-during-childbirth/105993200</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">228d86998e1b9de25ea60bf59ced295e</guid></item><item><title>Remembering veteran radio broadcaster John Laws who has died aged 90</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/remembering-veteran-radio-broadcaster-john-laws-/105993314</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a25429906d6808a12c448b10b1bb5f7d</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump pardons Rudy Giuliani and others involved in trying to overturn 2020 election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-10/trump-pardons-rudy-giuliani-and-others-in-fake-electors-scheme/105993118</link><description>The US president has pardoned his former lawyer Rudy Giuliani and others who were involved in trying to overturn the 2020 election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f77bda47fb6ee844ae6299ce03243389</guid></item><item><title>Former French president Nicolas Sarkozy released from prison pending appeal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/sarkozy-sentencing-discussed/105994052</link><description>Sarkozy became the first former French president to be sent to prison in modern times, this September.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c1a3aa26355c51c56deb3960a81ac13</guid></item><item><title>Trump threatens to sue 'corrupt' BBC for $1.5b over 'salacious' documentary</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/donald-trump-threatens-to-sue-bbc-over-misleading-edit/105994202</link><description>Lawyers for the US president warn Britain's national broadcaster they are preparing to sue it over "fabricated" statements that aired in its Panorama program last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aec9b300e9d1e9cb02530ca4c57bca6b</guid></item><item><title>Infrastructure Victoria calls for upgrade to 'unreliable and infrequent' Upfield train line in Melbourne's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/upfield-gowrie-train-line-infrastructure-train-line-melbourne/105985638</link><description>In one booming growth area, north of Melbourne, locals are forced to drive to avoid long delays for trains during peak periods. Multiple groups are calling on the state government to upgrade its services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04913165bf4962d3b8cd21a2e45e3c6d</guid></item><item><title>Early childhood professors release six-point plan to fix 'broken' childcare system</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/professors-urge-governments-to-fix-broken-childcare-system/105993076</link><description>Some of Australia's leading early childhood education professors join forces to release a six-point action plan to help fix the country's "broken" childcare system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fafc40e3fb89863f0a6b3dc8026cec0</guid></item><item><title>A damning memo shows the BBC's issues are bigger than its coverage of Donald Trump</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/bbc-news-memo-on-donald-trump-raises-other-issues/105992120</link><description>It is not US President Donald Trump who represents the biggest political threat to the BBC, but a leaked 8,000-word letter of complaint to the broadcaster's board motivated by "despair at inaction".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48fb38c8a705fefc5ad44bbbda5d6a2e</guid></item><item><title>Why Australia's ironclad future is under threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/why-australias-iron-clad-future-is-under-threat/105992602</link><description>For decades, China has resented being held hostage over the iron ore price by its own insatiable demand and a handful of Australian producers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dcc6d825b308692b931d5d6b8da1f6d</guid></item><item><title>COP30 kicks off 10 years on from the Paris Agreement. Where is the world at?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/how-the-world-changed-ten-years-from-the-paris-agreement/105915560</link><description>It was a moment of euphoria when the world came together to sign a pact on climate action. Ten years on from the 2015 Paris Agreement we managed to shift the needle. But the problem is it's just not happening fast enough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b5242054f494bc80fb8ca139dac8b60</guid></item><item><title>US risks AI debt bubble as China faces its 'arithmetic problem', leading analysts warn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/marc-sumerlin-federal-reserve-michael-pettis-china/105992570</link><description>Two leading experts on the world's biggest economies warn both countries face serious challenges, and not just over trade with each other.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2a36c95437b825e6f2b965ecc347d86</guid></item><item><title>Cardiac patient reveals urgent surgery at Sydney public hospital was cancelled four times</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/heart-surgery-delays-at-nsw-hospitals-st-vincents-triple-bypass/105950750</link><description>Ian Parker waited more than three months for urgent heart surgery that should have been done within 30 days. He was inspired to share his story after an ABC investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e850f72e292b42d7bcf941ee7c9485e8</guid></item><item><title>Hidden Garden Estate cancels weddings after announcing insolvency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/hidden-garden-estate-weddings-cancelled-glenorchy-council/105991318</link><description>Southern Tasmanian wedding venue Hidden Garden Estate announces its immediate closure, leaving couples scrambling ahead of their wedding day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2097e15f5214d64e0d8ed215f86845d6</guid></item><item><title>Drug drivers involved in more Queensland road fatalities than drunk drivers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/qld-drug-driving-worse-than-drink-driving-cocaine-use-spikes/105992612</link><description>More than 1,000 positive drug tests involving cocaine have been recorded by Queensland Police since the narcotic became part of the state's roadside testing regime as drug driving overtakes drink driving in fatal crashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94112d5c7a194b1548c18be8eacc7a7e</guid></item><item><title>ACT government seeks legal advice as contractor misses MyWay+ deadline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/act-government-legal-advice-contractor-rollout-myway/105993396</link><description>The ACT government is seeking legal advice over the botched MyWay+ transport system, as the company tasked with rolling it out missed the deadline to complete the project.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa841dcab1a077474e6fe456239dc4b4</guid></item><item><title>Bat colony causes Gympie council to consider property buyback scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/gympie-council-to-consider-buy-back-scheme-due-to-flying-foxes/105984172</link><description>A Queensland council will consider seeking government funding for a property buyback scheme as part of a new flying fox management plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b83a7b321185b7a6c5b8ac140432792e</guid></item><item><title>Who is the man that wants to 'leave shit behind' as the new ACT opposition leader?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/act-who-is-mark-parton-the-new-canberra-liberals-leader/105993440</link><description>To be the leader of the Canberra Liberals you need to be thick-skinned, have a lot of persistence, and be very confident — and if Mark Parton's first press conference in the role is anything to go by, he might just be the perfect fit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">348f99bae8e5eac574b7170f26b844e1</guid></item><item><title>Micro parties on the rise as discontent with major parties grows in regional NSW</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/micro-parties-growing-amid-rising-political-discontent-regions/105990772</link><description>As voters demand better political representation in the bush, two new micro parties in the NSW Riverina region promise to be a solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52176e7634c5031d57673d020ffa5f36</guid></item><item><title>Stunning icicle kick by David Rodríguez wins Canadian Premier League final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/watch-icicle-kick-wins-canadian-premier-league-final/105994608</link><description>A blizzard, a sensational overhead kick goal, snowploughs clearing the pitch for extra time — the Canadian Premier League soccer final had it all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a073e011bd5d691b95bfa4a3bae5870e</guid></item><item><title>Owners barred from Beachport holiday units after council fire safety change</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/beachport-southern-ocean-tourist-park-unit-owners-locked-out/105979518</link><description>Meg Longstaff hoped to continue a family tradition of beach holidays this summer, but a council decision on fire safety enforcement means she and other unit owners may be forced to make other plans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9a29753ff779030a84962efed82348b</guid></item><item><title>ASX loses ground, CBA posts $2.6b quarterly profit but sheds 6.6pc in value — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/asx-markets-business-live-news-nov11-2025/105994626</link><description>Commonwealth Bank reported a marginal rise in first-quarter profit, but its share price still lost 6.6 per cent in value, while the ASX200 lost ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b7c35524299db05e3f61ef00ada3e33</guid></item><item><title>NSW Nationals MPs reject net zero emissions target 'in principle'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/nsw-nationals-reject-net-zero-emissions-target-coalition/105994514</link><description>On Monday night, the NSW Nationals held a partyroom meeting to discuss their position on net zero following a report into Australia's energy future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a95cc10f45d2f93cdc1aef1456404b6</guid></item><item><title>Hungarian British author David Szalay wins Booker Prize 2025 for his novel Flesh</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/booker-prize-2025-author-book-david-szalay-flesh/105984642</link><description>Hungarian British author David Szalay bests past winner Kiran Desai and former shortlistee Andrew Miller to win the prestigious Booker Prize for his sixth book, the "extraordinary, singular" Flesh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02bc77d024c17c7e2b51af0f0de9fc62</guid></item><item><title>Whitlam Dismissal live from 1975: How it unfolded, 50 years on</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/whitlam-dismissal-live-blog-how-it-unfolded-50-years-ago/105973458</link><description>Fifty years ago today, prime minister Gough Whitlam was dismissed by governor-general Sir John Kerr. To mark the anniversary, we're putting you right there as it happened, covering the key moments of that fateful day in 1975 in real time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dbee4f931c5c043cd4e4716a19fecec</guid></item><item><title>US Supreme Court rejects call to overturn same-sex marriage legalisation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/us-supreme-court-reject-same-sex-marriage-overturn/105994842</link><description>A former Kentucky court clerk who refused to issue marriage licenses to same-sex couples after a high court's 2015 ruling had been looking to appeal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84e201d1d87111a59f3a4ec5e3b591c5</guid></item><item><title>Borough of Queenscliffe, Victoria's smallest LGA, votes for 'early finalisation' of CEO's contract</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/victoria-queenscliffe-council-ceo-martin-gill/105993726</link><description>Queenscliffe is Australia's last remaining borough, and the smallest and least populated of Victoria's 79 local government areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b96090ae80c9f242fa0c8195f5b352a4</guid></item><item><title>Typhoon Fung-wong leaves eight dead and 1.4 million displaced in Philippines</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/typhoon-fung-wong-philippines/105994804</link><description>The aftermath of a 1,800-kilometre-wide super typhoon has left more than a million people displaced from their homes in the Philippines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29e077741e1697ccfdf4bb6c1a326b65</guid></item><item><title>Bush retreat brings together veterans to talk and lighten their load</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/cockscomb-veterans-bush-retreat-conversation-camaraderie/105917696</link><description>Nestled in the foothills of a mountain, a retreat near Rockhampton in central Queensland brings together veterans, their families and others to talk and lighten their load.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">986984b1ab7bd6ada900e3f8c0e8746b</guid></item><item><title>Influencer fined $830 for lighting fire on World Heritage-listed island K'gari</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/influencer-fined-for-lighting-fire-on-kgari/105995126</link><description>The woman lit a prohibited fire on the protected sand island and used a drone in a restricted area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0dc7a8465d0b1e70f58af6f8640dcbc</guid></item><item><title>New 'radio map' of the Milky Way reveals where stars are born and die</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/milky-way-radio-map-shows-where-stars-live-and-die/105976276</link><description>The Milky Way appears as a dusty band of stars, but by observing its radio frequencies a different view can be seen, revealing parts of the galaxy hidden from sight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67a35ec6ec9a700d7d622b58ce5dfe29</guid></item><item><title>Prosecutors drop sexual assault, rape charges against Geelong AFL player Tanner Bruhn</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/charges-dropped-against-afl-player-tanner-bruhn/105992476</link><description>Lawyers for Geelong AFL player Tanner Bruhn say "false allegations" were made against him and a friend, telling the media the pair have been vindicated in court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d4039eef93fa4061fa0d8cce207a3f4</guid></item><item><title>Charli XCX enlists The Velvet Underground's John Cale for Wuthering Heights collaboration House</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/house-charli-xcx-john-cale-collab-song-wuthering-heights-movie/105995418</link><description>Charli XCX shares an "elegant, brutal" song featuring John Cale, the first for the soundtrack to Emerald Fennell's film adaptation of Wuthering Heights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c47d7dc004c6b5b1343ecd2331546734</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies desperate to avoid 67-year low on draining end of season Tour of Europe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/wallabies-desperate-to-avoid-67-year-low-in-spring-tour/105995694</link><description>After falling to England and Italy, the Wallabies are halfway towards becoming the first Australian tourists since 1958 to lose four straight Tests in Europe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce19fbf3fee7e0b138083582d6643d31</guid></item><item><title>Te Maire Martin ready to aid Eli Katoa's recovery, but warns path may not be comparable</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/rugby-league-te-maire-martin-ready-to-help-eli-katoa-recovery/105995878</link><description>Te Maire Martin knows what it takes to get back on the field after a brain bleed, but warns that Eli Katoa's path is not going to be exactly identical for one reason.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21d1a1efbf5d373e8d6d10be580c132c</guid></item><item><title>Witnesses begin giving evidence in trial of Rajwinder Singh, accused of murdering Toyah Cordingley in Far North Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/qld-rajwinder-singh-accused-of-killing-toyah-cordingley-trial/105995944</link><description>Witnesses in the trial of Rajwinder Singh, who is accused of murdering Far North Queensland woman Toyah Cordingley, have begun being questioned as the trial concludes its second day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b78624cef35adc9f3fee7bf160c72664</guid></item><item><title>Prices rising fastest in inner cities and growth towns during expanded 5 per cent deposit scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/the-suburbs-and-towns-where-entry-level-house-prices-are-growing/105996180</link><description>Inner cities, wealthy suburbs and fast-growing regional centres top the list of house price growth in October, according to a new deep dive focused on homes covered by the 5 per cent deposit scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">251df54c0c0088c2bf14c6407c69896d</guid></item><item><title>A motorised hydrofoiler rides well clear of swimmers off Adelaide's metropolitan coastline</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/a-motorised-hydrofoiler-rides-well-clear-of-swimmers/105990830</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95f075ad4df3f4435a61fd508c99d7ed</guid></item><item><title>Sport Integrity Australia report reveals athletes' and coaches' views on abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/sport-integrity-australia-survey-into-reporting-abuse/105996092</link><description>A new report from Sport Integrity Australia asks athletes and coaches about the misbehaviour they may have experienced from community levels to the elite standard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1c500d3e81af32b4e5e8277aec1e9a2</guid></item><item><title>Magistrate sentences driver following 'highest alcohol reading' she's ever seen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/magistrate-sentences-driver-caught-ten-times-limit/105995684</link><description>A Victorian magistrate praises a man's engagement with counselling services during sentencing after being caught with a blood alcohol reading 10 times over the legal limit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bebf97cb88d3fb2617f9cd1af8d5e42</guid></item><item><title>Non-bank sector in ASIC, RBA's gaze as customers chasing property loans drift their way</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/non-bank-sector-in-asic-gaze-as-customers-chase-property-loans/105995184</link><description>The tapering of super-sized bank profits has shone a spotlight on the growth of the non-bank sector. Regulators have them in sight given the risk they pose to the financial system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b743d75d18f3e93e5eeebf604709ac6</guid></item><item><title>International student awarded $10,000 in compensation after being evicted from UniLodge accommodation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/acat-compensation-for-student-evicted-from-uni-housing/105995962</link><description>An international student has been awarded $10,000 in compensation after a tribunal found she was unfairly evicted from her university accommodation after she made complaints about noisy students.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d4f2e850ad5411e348aa14d4c077a6</guid></item><item><title>Adelaide commercial radio host Leon Byner dies after cancer battle aged 77</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/adelaide-radio-host-leon-byner-dies-after-leukaemia-battle/105996176</link><description>Long-time Adelaide commercial radio host Leon Byner has died at the age of 77 after a battle with acute leukaemia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">869a051fe77cd0b3ff15fca0fe56ae01</guid></item><item><title>Date set for Alan Jones's court hearing with up to 139 witnesses expected to be involved in Crown's case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/alan-jones-court-hearing-august-2026-multiple-witnesses-nsw/105996450</link><description>A court hearing date to determine indecent assault charges against the veteran broadcaster has been set, with a Sydney court told up to 139 witnesses may be involved in the Crown's case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">323f92836ccd96b2f1075de6584ca402</guid></item><item><title>AI could be the ultimate test of Australia's democracy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/ai-could-ultimate-test-australia-democracy-boyer-lectures/105991022</link><description>Developing safe AI is not just an opportunity for a democracy like ours; ever since our superpower ally checked out of its responsibilities on this front, it's an obligation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd3ecd4227d5985d0919b3e195d819eb</guid></item><item><title>Nauruan president makes secretive trip to parliament amid claims bikies won lucrative contract</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/nauru-president-parliament-contract-allegations/105996920</link><description>Nauru's president has made a secretive visit to Parliament House in Canberra amid allegations that bikie gangs won a lucrative contract to provide security for former immigration detainees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1747005400dd69005694c57223e459c9</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian parliament to apologise for body parts kept in pathology museum</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/tasmania-apologies-for-body-parts-kept-in-pathology-museum/105996256</link><description>The Tasmanian government will apologise for the past practice of retaining body parts after autopsies without the knowledge or consent of family members.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb72c9939fd3cc88e7bb24fb79bd6007</guid></item><item><title>Torres Strait Islanders appeal federal court decision on landmark climate case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/climate-case-appeal/105990864</link><description>Two Torres Strait Islander uncles are appealing a federal court ruling that the Commonwealth does not owe a duty of care to protect their people from the impacts of climate change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca7d7ab8673ce37ad206b8bac32fb1ec</guid></item><item><title>Canada loses its measles-free status after ongoing outbreaks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/canada-loses-measles-free-status-after-ongoing-outbreaks/105996706</link><description>Canada has lost its measles elimination status due to ongoing outbreaks as childhood vaccination rates fall and the highly contagious virus spreads across North and South America.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2682bd2d4ed9b1ee35743737e2b268fa</guid></item><item><title>I thought I hated basketball. Now it's given me an amazing life</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/how-para-sport-has-changed-my-life/105952646</link><description>After breaking her back at 19 Katherine's community made sure she knew how special she was. Wheelchair basketball brought her back to earth and made her life "truly amazing".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7670f4c828bd61b3087694a64e71ad4d</guid></item><item><title>Grounds revealed for State of Western Australia's appeal against abuse survivor Dion Barber's $2.8 million payout</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/appeal-grounds-revealed-for-state-case-against-dion-barber/105996250</link><description>The State of Western Australia is appealing the entire basis of a judgement which awarded a Perth man nearly $3 million in compensation for abuse he suffered while he was in state care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2d43cef6475a460e1e93aff9c4e74ae</guid></item><item><title>England cricket great Ian Botham concerned by lack of warm-up matches prior to first Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/cricket-ian-botham-questions-england-ashes-preparation/105997704</link><description>England's only warm-up game prior to the first Ashes Test will be an internal match, a fact that is greatly concerning legendary all-rounder Ian Botham.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d377c420ec9badac5102acc497e2fe6d</guid></item><item><title>Dozens of patients caught up in medical scan bungle at Caboolture Hospital as review ends</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/more-patients-affected-by-caboolture-hospital-medical-scan-error/105997448</link><description>A major review of medical scans at Caboolture Hospital's outpatient clinic finds 38 patients did not get follow-up care, prompting the health service to apologise again for the bungle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c09c833245315ad6881c7fe50007eec8</guid></item><item><title>Former Darwin real estate agent denied bail after allegedly running over foot of BMW repossession agent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/suzanne-milgate-real-estate-alleged-run-over-foot-bmw-agent/105995576</link><description>A Darwin real estate agent accused of running over the foot of a BMW car repossession agent has been refused bail in the Darwin Local Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccc7f5a5cd3d4601b6dd2cb15e5c06cc</guid></item><item><title>West Australian man Patrick Joseph Hunter stands trial over alleged rape of girl under 10</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/patrick-joseph-hunter-broome-district-court-trial/105996402</link><description>Patrick Joseph Hunter, 46, is facing a charge of sexual penetration of a child under 13 and four counts of indecent dealing with a child under 13.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f780d2e4c5a33126cb013ec0cd0c2da8</guid></item><item><title>Childcare centre and supervisors charged after toddler's death outside Darwin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/nt-childcare-centre-workers-charged-over-toddler-death-darwin/105997950</link><description>The Northern Territory government has confirmed a rural Darwin childcare centre and three of its supervisors have been charged after the death of a toddler at the centre in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71b2d9509e98db0f5f836f788ccdc878</guid></item><item><title>Georgia Wareham's all-round brilliance helps Melbourne Renegades sink Sydney Thunder in WBBL</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/cricket-georgia-wareham-leads-renegades-wbbl-win-thunder/105998198</link><description>Renegades captain Georgia Wareham continues her blistering start to this year's WBBL campaign, scoring a half-century with the bat and picking up two wickets with the ball.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2555dba35e455f15a25c19a2dbec6cea</guid></item><item><title>Tuesday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/tuesday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/105997428</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">882a5edd6dc3108a75e41a81b2203ca6</guid></item><item><title>Algal bloom exposes 'limitations' in government monitoring programs, Senate inquiry finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/algal-bloom-inquiry-limitations-monitoring-program/105996478</link><description>A Senate inquiry into South Australia's toxic algal bloom has been tabled highlighting "limitations" in how the government has handled the crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23f3187adba78b7e182fc4e1874b2d21</guid></item><item><title>Council discovers 46 trees mistakenly cut down during park redevelopment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/council-discovers-46-trees-mistakenly-cut-down/105998376</link><description>The Town of Victoria Park has revealed nearly 50 trees were removed without authorisation during redevelopment works to a park and adjacent hospitality precinct, and says it is investigating what went wrong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">438d3ca36f77217344234ca4d6bf6b99</guid></item><item><title>Car bomb explodes outside district court in Islamabad</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-11/car-explosion-outside-court-islamabad/105998568</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7c1e810a2ccdd4ce15b03e96e56c4ac</guid></item><item><title>Chinese 'cryptoqueen' fraud jailed in UK over $9b Bitcoin laundering scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/uk-crypto-queen-jailed-over-9b-bitcoin-laundering-scheme/105998844</link><description>British authorities say Zhimin Qian was the mastermind behind a Ponzi scheme into which around 128,000 people invested billions of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a90ea29d3a1517bfb56ab225e533758</guid></item><item><title>Princess Anne welcomed with open arms during Australian tour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/princess-anne-australia-visit-signals-andrew/105996452</link><description>Whether Princess Anne's visit has been enough to repair the damage to the monarchy's brand wrought by Andrew Mountbatten Windsor remains to be seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bf56bc4aab3d7b926ae9082b8823f2d</guid></item><item><title>Future of three Victorian community hospitals up in the air as references wiped from government website</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/community-hospitals-torquay-emerald-hill-eltham-government/105985488</link><description>The Victorian government is refusing to say whether it will build three community hospitals that were originally meant to be completed more than a year ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99250cab819469edd23c4a1bee9da20b</guid></item><item><title>Spike in dolphin deaths at Huon Aquaculture pens prompts questions from Tasmanian regulator</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/huon-aquaculture-response-to-dolphin-deaths-salmon-pens/105991470</link><description>Tasmanian regulators question major salmon farm operator Huon Aquaculture about the effectiveness of its "predator" nets after a spate of dolphin deaths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d859cad498ca0936341476fc5e0e6629</guid></item><item><title>Nationals nominate hardliner for net zero talks as Liberals meet to settle position</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/canavan-to-join-net-zero-talks-with-liberals/105998148</link><description>One of the Nationals' most strident opponents of net zero will attend talks on a final Coalition policy position. Before then, the Liberals must decide their own stance — but conservatives are now confident net zero will be dropped.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f0bdac6bb6fbfbdfaf0113e1e1a4b77</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley sees the Coalition's young voter problem but may not survive to offer solutions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/liberal-party-woes-attracting-younger-voters/105996134</link><description>The Coalition risks political extinction unless it can reconnect with younger voters who have abandoned it in droves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">766ce17d19ab5c6a20e7bab56577eccf</guid></item><item><title>Are 5 per cent deposits the leg-up first home buyers need, or are they pouring fuel on the fire?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/are-five-per-cent-first-home-deposits-pushing-up-prices/105979708</link><description>It will be some time before the full effects of the government's expanded first home buyer support scheme become clear, but young Australians across the country say it is still a tough market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">375eac2b3eaea97759c707a877b2e479</guid></item><item><title>Michelle Foster's family feels let down by mental health and justice systems</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/family-of-young-mother-calls-for-systemic-change/105994636</link><description>Andrea Foster and her son Peter Spiniello continue to feel let down by a system they believe caused the death of their daughter, and sister, who was killed seven years ago by a mentally unwell man.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd09e4700083bec6a8037752230c598b</guid></item><item><title>Doctors defend emergency department triage policy as 'closing the gap in action'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/closing-the-gap-doctors-defend-melbourne-ed-triage-policy/105991086</link><description>Doctors and medical associations have backed a Melbourne hospital's emergency department triage policy to improve care for First Nations patients, describing criticisms of the closing the gap measure as 'opportunistic, uninformed'.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05bc8583091c7f58e798281d0cc3526c</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia accused of 'twisting facts' as former dictator Suharto named national hero</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/prabowo-gives-suharto-indonesian-national-hero-honour/105995984</link><description>Indonesian President Prabowo Subianto courts controversy by granting his former father-in-law, the authoritarian dictator Suharto, "national hero" status.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3f0855a41e8b8776e35d3da66453bdd</guid></item><item><title>Black Friday sales set to be biggest on record with shoppers spending billions on deals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/black-friday-sales-to-be-biggest-on-record-shoppers-hunt-deals/105997054</link><description>About 6 million Australians are expected to take part in Black Friday sales this year and on average they will fork out $804 each.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfe0cd9b1fca6eaa57b202b0c7c8f21a</guid></item><item><title>Leo relies on exercise physiology to keep him moving but that could change under NDIS review</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/advocates-fear-ndis-review-cuts-to-exercise-physiology/105970108</link><description>Leo depends on exercise physiology to keep him moving, but there are fears that his progress could be halted under an NDIS review.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd9e61829bcc6512de4de29f5c895fea</guid></item><item><title>YouTuber captures moment of fatal blast in Delhi</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/youtuber-captures-moment-of-fatal-blast-in-delhi/105998894</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14402cc4d85fa33e5307590908317d69</guid></item><item><title>Farmers angry as Woolworths imports US butter in green and gold packaging</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/farmer-anger-over-woolworths-importing-american-butter/105738806</link><description>Australia's dairy industry is concerned a US brand, packaged in green and gold with a white colouring and bland flavour, looks as if it's locally made.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddc50cf1dd93b51945b7377cafb0fe5d</guid></item><item><title>Genea patients want IVF giant held to account as cybersecurity expert raises ongoing concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/genea-ivf-data-breach-fallout-ongoing-cyber-concerns-raised/105984716</link><description>Patients of fertility giant Genea want the company held to account for a data breach earlier this year, amid concerns that some of its IT systems continue to fall short of best practice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc9c751eefe8d69c13408c4e8508ed58</guid></item><item><title>Joe Root a new player under Bazball despite previous Ashes struggles in Australia, says batting coach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/roots-pre-bazball-struggles-in-australia-irrelevant-says-coach/105998934</link><description>England insists Joe Root's lack of centuries in Australia is not an issue, pointing to the fact he has thrived around the world under Brendon McCullum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27fb0128ec0861a70973dde3e443797f</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics: Liberals have met to decide fate of net zero policy in closed-door meeting — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/federal-politics-live-blog-nov-12/105997816</link><description>The Liberals have met at Parliament House in Canberra after a marathon meeting to decide on the future of the party's net zero policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2b6368454f2fd5b5ca2d2c770957084</guid></item><item><title>Coral larvae released as part of research project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/coral-larvae-released-lizard-island-research-project/105998566</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fca6132ddf14eee56e1e9f2bf5ca3efb</guid></item><item><title>Scientists work to improve health of Great Barrier Reef during annual coral spawning event</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/great-barrier-reef-coral-spawning-csiro-restoration-work/105997942</link><description>A thick cloud of coral spawn has blanketed parts of the Great Barrier Reef this week, signalling a key window for restoration work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f192d486efdd91769b29e8342201d593</guid></item><item><title>Dallas Mavericks axe manager behind NBA's shocking Luka Doncic trade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/gm-behind-nbas-shocking-luka-doncic-trade-fired-by-mavericks/105998998</link><description>Nico Harrison, the man behind the most shocking trade in NBA history which saw Luka Doncic head to the Lakers, is fired by the Dallas Mavericks as the move continues to backfire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5364b64f5526a8177ad974fb9f8c14d</guid></item><item><title>Taiwan evacuates thousands ahead of tropical storm Fung-wong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/taiwan-evacuates-thousands-ahead-of-tropical-storm-fung-wong/105998928</link><description>Strong winds and rain hit Taiwan as Fung-wong approaches the island's south-west, where it is forecast to make landfall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cda7058197ef7580744549a3d723a5a5</guid></item><item><title>Outback graziers hope approach to tackle mesquite weed infestation is effective</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/mesquite-tree-weed-infestation-far-west-nsw-mark-facer/105983024</link><description>For the past 25 years the "king of weeds", Mark Facer, has been chasing and eradicating weeds. Now he has been called in to help graziers in far west NSW with the worst mesquite infestation he has seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">382661cbaa20f01d1cba3ae7edd725ea</guid></item><item><title>CASA warns of 'zero tolerance' for helicopter safety breaches in wake of Matt Wright trial evidence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/casa-warns-zero-tolerance-on-helicopter-rule-breaking-in-north/105996760</link><description>Australia's aviation watchdog has issued a warning to the sector, after accounts of widespread chopper rule-breaking were aired during the trial of Northern Territory croc wrangler Matt Wright.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e50510e27b904f589b88a6d38b93aee9</guid></item><item><title>Melissa McIntosh supports remaining in Paris Agreement</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/melissa-mcintosh-supports-remaining-in-paris-agreement/105999058</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">becc7f163699df43e3140e41693e4076</guid></item><item><title>Turkish military plane crashes in Georgia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/turkish-military-plane-crashes-in-georgia/105999074</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f77be4aca73ce9edfe3b561f0e41f3f</guid></item><item><title>Menulog to shut down in two weeks, local shares close down — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/asx-markets-business-live-news/105998974</link><description>Food-delivery company Menulog will shut down in two weeks, citing "challenging circumstances", while the Australian share market has closed slightly down. Look back on the day's business and economic news.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42f85951b91d43ca4eeaa39995aec526</guid></item><item><title>Beau Webster, Matt Renshaw shine in Sheffield Shield ahead of Ashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/webster-renshaw-send-timely-shield-reminders-on-eve-of-ashes/105999066</link><description>Beau Webster and Matt Renshaw remind selectors of their talents with stand-out performances in the Sheffield Shield on the eve of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bef79d3557c1983503e3488ea0eeab7d</guid></item><item><title>How WA's outgoing Chief Health Officer Andy Robertson once hunted anthrax in Iraq</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/andy-robertson-retires-after-extraordinary-career/105993126</link><description>For WA's retiring Chief Health Officer Andy Robertson, the 2020 spread of the "novel coronavirus" was not the first time he had been part of a story of global significance — and he also fears the next pandemic could be worse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcc8f28685ef0f3d9f1604a692a9f476</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal team wins national award for suicide prevention work in Alice Springs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/alice-springs-team-wins-award-for-suicide-prevention/105996996</link><description>The Alice Springs team has been rewarded for its culture of listening to reduce high suicide rates in the Northern Territory.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a427e7c5370748aae1d3da18a9a965ad</guid></item><item><title>Vapes reaching country towns across WA despite strengthened laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/vapes-reaching-country-towns-across-wa-despite-strengthened-laws/105997660</link><description>Despite a federal crackdown, shops selling vapes are popping up in regional areas prompting increased calls for education programs in schools.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ea41a7f4e962558255aaae5f284576d</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump asks Supreme Court to throw out E Jean Carroll abuse finding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/trump-asks-supreme-court-to-overturn-e-jean-carroll-verdict/105998988</link><description>US President Donald Trump asks the Supreme Court to overturn a civil jury's finding that he sexually abused writer E Jean Carroll at a Manhattan department store in the mid 1990s and later defamed her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be2d602724981032b016b8c696b38d0b</guid></item><item><title>Cristiano Ronaldo confirms 2026 World Cup will be his last with retirement looming</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/cristiano-ronaldo-confirms-2026-world-cup-will-be-his-last/105999234</link><description>Cristiano Ronaldo says the 2026 World Cup will be his last as he plots retirement in the next two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccb538d2a83774a351e9fbb24b89df44</guid></item><item><title>Abuse lawyer slams WA government's decision to appeal Dion Barber's compensation for historical sexual abuse</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/abuse-lawyer-slams-wa-government-for-appeal-dion-barber/105998046</link><description>A lawyer accuses the WA government of hijacking Dion Barber's $2.85 million compensation case for historical sexual abuse in a bid to "clarify law", instead of legislating it through parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f2bec6a802b90cb61a31e8360ed8683</guid></item><item><title>Jacinta Nampijinpa Price in 'urgent' pre-Christmas 2028 campaign fundraising drive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/jacinta-nampijinpa-price-family-community-nation-fundraiser/105997648</link><description>Northern Territory senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price is asking supporters to dig deep ahead of the festive season and help bankroll a $125,000 campaign fund three years out from the 2028 federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1151776cda33a1199e347578728413c0</guid></item><item><title>Russia loses High Court battle with Commonwealth over Canberra embassy site, but will be compensated</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/russia-loses-high-court-battle-over-canberra-embassy-site/105999328</link><description>The lease was granted to Russia in 2008, but was withdrawn when parliament passed a new law citing ASIO advice that the planned embassy could pose a threat to national security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fa33004123ea22e28c6e843a3e8d33a</guid></item><item><title>Liberal politicians on Qantas plane that made urgent turnaround to Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/adelaide-to-canberra-flight-forced-to-land-after-smoke-in-cabin/105999194</link><description>Three Liberal politicians have been delayed getting to Canberra for climate talks after a Qantas plane was forced to make an urgent landing at Adelaide Airport when crews noticed smoke in the cabin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">797a8d8bcebf6be005f40b602444a1b9</guid></item><item><title>BBC boss rallies staff in face of leadership crisis and Trump legal threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/bbc-boss-rallies-staff-amid-leadership-crisis-trump-legal-threat/105999184</link><description>The outgoing boss of the BBC sought to rally his journalists on Tuesday, as the British broadcaster confronts legal action by US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">789ba736dde580179f8f9b6a5aa1df3d</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur beaten by Lorenzo Musetti but still alive at ATP Finals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/alex-de-minaur-down-but-not-out-at-atp-finals/105999526</link><description>Alex de Minaur's hopes of reaching the ATP Finals semis hang by a thread after a heartbreaking three-set loss to Lorenzo Musetti.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbcc2720ce1d32476c6e82e6baa4af76</guid></item><item><title>Spy chief warns of China espionage threat to business, critical infrastructure</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/spy-chief-warns-of-china-espionage-threat-to-business/105999522</link><description>ASIO director-general Mike Burgess urges businesses to protect their data to prepare for possible attacks from hostile states.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a8f55dd714b7b0654c89de15865c122</guid></item><item><title>Ruby Gold mango variety to hit Australian supermarket shelves this summer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/new-mango-variety-ruby-gold-hits-the-supermarkets/105996270</link><description>The Ruby Gold mango has been produced in commercial quantities for the first time and sellers say they are sure it will be a winner with consumers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">374acf8eaf43a8008c7f14a6aa0a7c25</guid></item><item><title>Sam Kerr scores twice in first club start in 692 days as Chelsea defeat St. Pölten 6-0 in the Women's Champions League</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/sam-kerr-two-goals-chelsea-womens-champions-league/105999572</link><description>Sam Kerr celebrates her first Chelsea start in almost two years by scoring a double, then declaring herself 100 per cent fit and "ready to go" for more game time and goals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d16cd916e7e3b464b6ee2321c26c4d4</guid></item><item><title>Thermal camera drone footage of fur seals at Seal Rocks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/thermal-camera-drone-footage-of-fur-seals-at-seal-rocks/105985896</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c96b13b35bb0384835ca80eb4330b16a</guid></item><item><title>Drones assist researchers in studying hard-to-reach wildlife</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/scientists-turning-to-drones-to-study-hard-to-reach-wildlife/105976234</link><description>Researchers are turning to drones to help them discover the health and habits of large marine mammals and other wildlife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d229a4295539442d7212dcac3c1c3318</guid></item><item><title>Bridge in China collapses months after opening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/bridge-in-china-collapses-months-after-opening/105999560</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb9228cd6d9a652e37e28697f402f132</guid></item><item><title>Hongqi Bridge partially collapses in southwest China just months after opening</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/bridge-partially-collapses-in-china-months-after-opening/105999564</link><description>Video has been captured of the moment a bridge in China partially collapses with the structure becoming engulfed in plumes of dust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">010ae511948ec7689a22d4ad647ff3ad</guid></item><item><title>Menulog to stop Australian operations later this month</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/menulog-to-stop-australian-operations-later-this-month/105999820</link><description>Food delivery company Menulog says it will cease operating in Australia in two weeks' time, prompting questions about whether Australia can maintain a competitive food delivery market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">594c6fc91193ede4f3894d2972067c24</guid></item><item><title>Good chance of aurora tonight, as two-year peak solar activity nears its end</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/chance-of-aurora-as-peak-solar-activity-winds-down/105983750</link><description>One of nature's most magnificent shows, the southern lights, could be on display for large parts of southern Australia tonight with a severe solar storm event impacting on Earth. But the boom in aurora activity will not last forever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3cddc2fcf384406017962a9570fa6ba</guid></item><item><title>Coonawarra wine association apologises for 'disappointing' T-shirts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/coonawarra-wine-sorry-for-t-shirts-drink-more-die-younger-sa/105991132</link><description>The Coonawarra Vignerons, in South Australia's South East, has deleted a post which attracted controversy for celebrating binge drinking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">798a9d5ffba33ad340a755e3c6a23280</guid></item><item><title>Manjimup avocado growers celebrate abundance of 'unusual' avocados</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/south-west-wa-growers-of-quirky-avocados/105962558</link><description>Avocado growers in WA's South West say the oddly shaped fruit popping up on their trees may cause a few chuckles, but that does not affect the taste.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7c093a6d204f9fcb46e48b98dac6fa6</guid></item><item><title>Anthropologist under fire in Andrew Forrest's Ashburton River hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/andrew-forrest-ashburton-river-anthropologist-questioned/105995574</link><description>A lawyer for billionaire Andrew Forrest questions an anthropologist's credibility over his opposition to plans to change a sacred Pilbara waterway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e0f19680f582157c7a90bb348d5c75a</guid></item><item><title>Can we tackle climate change without net zero? Here's what it really means</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/what-does-net-zero-mean-and-why-we-need-it-to-act-on-climate/105996502</link><description>The Coalition is debating whether to dump its commitment to the net zero climate target. Here's what that term actually means.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a95411f87dca676fc98f698afe4a9102</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Mountbatten Windsor shuts down royal business venture Pitch@Palace</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-applies-to-close-down-pitch-palace/105999230</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten Windsor has applied to close down some of his last remaining business interests, weeks after he was stripped of his titles and honours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4a5fd0a987266effc50e837ecad1c4d</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania's Hellyer Gold Mine shut down over unpaid royalties</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/tas-hellyer-gold-mine-closes-over-unpaid-debts/105999334</link><description>The state government has directed Hellyer Gold Mines to cease operations at its mine in north-west Tasmania. It says the company has significantly fallen behind on its debts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb08a561638cff454cc54663093f9deb</guid></item><item><title>Downsizing the Australian dream: Homebuyers adjust expectations in hot housing market</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/australian-homebuyers-lower-expectations-in-hot-housing-market/105996336</link><description>A new report finds that prospective Australian homebuyers are increasingly abandoning their dreams of a freestanding house in favour of more budget-friendly townhouses and units.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a308aeece82e79a103ee0158db6b33e9</guid></item><item><title>Toyah Cordingley's father gives evidence in trial of Rajwinder Singh, who is charged with murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/qld-toyah-cordingley-father-gives-evidence-murder-trial/105999862</link><description>Toyah Cordingley's father has told a jury he paused to rest under a tree during the search for his daughter when he noticed an "odd-shaped mound" at his feet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec68445b75038348bfc06e8533172052</guid></item><item><title>BHP ordered to pay miners $84,000 following Christmas holiday pay dispute</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/bhp-labour-company-ordered-to-pay-for-employees-working/105999642</link><description>The Mining and Energy Union wins an appeal, arguing the mine operated for the pure purpose of profit over the public holiday period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c546ed4e403df01019e66ccf7d3a6f49</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast to host AACTA awards, festival through to 2028</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/gold-coast-locks-in-aacta-awards-festival-next-two-years/105996182</link><description>An Australian film and television awards ceremony that has attracted Hollywood heavyweights, including Margot Robbie, will be held in Queensland until 2028.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7910fab0c15d014386123b7dd273184c</guid></item><item><title>Wollongong council seeks $44,000 for removing whale drowned by shark net</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/whale-cost-cleanup-wollongong/105999632</link><description>Wollongong City Council wants the NSW government to cover the $44,000 cost of recovering a humpback whale that drowned in a Coledale shark net.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c544e2e166a1d444f213d0bf9723941a</guid></item><item><title>Claims secret gas decarbonisation report 'doctored' by WA government to support net zero narrative</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/claims-wa-government-doctored-secret-gas-report-for-net-zero/106000070</link><description>Last year the WA government commissioned a report on whether LNG exports to Asia were helping decarbonisation efforts — but the final report is vastly different to the draft, and analysts and activists say it has been doctored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d389da15c6ef2023f9a268d88c8acf9</guid></item><item><title>Australia suffers Ashes scare with Josh Hazlewood and Sean Abbott having scans on hamstrings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/ashes-josh-hazlewood-sean-abbott-assessed-injury-nsw-victoria/106000740</link><description>Josh Hazlewood's hamstring scare is not serious, but the news was less promising for fellow Ashes squad member Sean Abbott.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f9ad8466ec7dff59fb09c1166ac7968</guid></item><item><title>Louvre heist ‘detective’ Pedro talks about the inspirations behind his viral look</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/louvre-heist-detective-pedro-says-james-bond-his-insirpation/105999138</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51c75a6b982496916592898cad1e32c5</guid></item><item><title>Japanese ambassador calls for security 'triangle' with Australia, US</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/japanese-ambassador-calls-for-security-triangle/105999344</link><description>Japan's ambassador to Australia calls for the two countries to form an "equilateral" security triangle with the United States, while championing the role of gas in the clean energy transition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61c9831e8dc05dc32020f438b4dab3bd</guid></item><item><title>Not introverted or extroverted? You could be an otrovert</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/what-is-the-personality-type-otrovert/105953010</link><description>Unlike extroverts or introverts, otroverts don't look outward or retreat inward to be energised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ce6d0bc0cf0337634cbe8abef79aaad</guid></item><item><title>Ben Stokes calls out 'has-beens' after criticism of England's Ashes preparations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/ben-stokes-hits-out-at-has-beens-over-england-ashes-prep/106000958</link><description>Critics of England's truncated preparation for this summer's Ashes Test series are off the mark, according to touring captain Ben Stokes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97714b0f46625e3bf5122080687a9d5d</guid></item><item><title>Three men to stand trial over Sterling Group's failed retiree housing scheme</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/three-to-stand-trial-over-failed-sterling-group-retiree-scheme/106000456</link><description>Three men linked to a failed housing scheme which left retirees across the country with huge financial losses deny criminal charges levelled against them in a WA court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">144421202a6ecb0094ae051b9301c072</guid></item><item><title>National mental health agreement failing, Productivity Commission finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/productivity-commission-review-mental-health-agreement-failing/106000508</link><description>A scathing Productivity Commission review concludes that Australia's mental health system is failing and needs a rewrite, while warning that 500,000 Australians are unable to access the care that they need.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c479d50ab0bbcffba7aa1d64120ea2bc</guid></item><item><title>Report reveals concerns about restraint techniques used in Adelaide youth detention centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/youth-in-detention-restrained-south-australia-report/106000630</link><description>Children and young people at Adelaide's only youth detention centre are being held to the floor in a restraint technique that "may constitute a breach of human rights and clinical best practice", according to a report tabled in parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b868a79e86a3b308b62ec9996c4d5bf</guid></item><item><title>Protesters clash with security at COP30 climate summit in Brazil</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/protesters-force-cop30-summit-venue-clash-with-security/106001066</link><description>The incident caused "minor injuries to two security staff, and minor damage to the venue," according to a spokesperson for the United Nations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7548bde38b24b7272ea0063a5d5fb661</guid></item><item><title>Louvre heist 'detective' Pedro reveals inspirations behind viral look</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/louvre-heist-detective-pedro-talks-about-the-inspirations/105999952</link><description>Louvre heist "fedora man" Pedro Elias Garzon Delvaux says the inspiration behind his vintage look includes Agatha Christie's famed detective Hercule Poirot and James Bond.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afd8922057322a461605840adbe9591c</guid></item><item><title>Qld youth justice minister praises Hinchinbrook candidate's call for stricter bail laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/qld-youth-justice-minister-praises-bail-reform-proposal/106000328</link><description>The state government has not ruled out the idea, but has stopped short of committing to the proposed reform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29427b762aa5cfe69b7feec24669d2e4</guid></item><item><title>Australia and Indonesia strike landmark security treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/australia-and-indonesia-strike-landmark-security-treat/106001570</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese declares a "new era" in the relationship between the neighbours in a joint appearance with Indonesian President Prabowo Subianto in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2864a5f23743e45c34f543b8a8d5a092</guid></item><item><title>Teenager faces sentencing hearing after pleading guilty to murder of Vyleen White at Ipswich shopping centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/qld-vyleen-white-sentencing-hearing-murder-ipswich/106000756</link><description>A young girl who watched on as a teenager killed her grandmother in an act of "indiscriminate violence" at an Queensland shopping centre says the 70-year-old was not "just a nanny".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e03a827c685e9ec3cb5ff42443fd1ed9</guid></item><item><title>Regulator suspends use of dimethoate insecticide on berries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/apvma-suspends-dimethoate-use-on-berries/106001530</link><description>Australians' surging appetite for berries has prompted the national farm chemical watchdog to suspend a popular insecticide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e3d695e8472d544953e7552938ce25a</guid></item><item><title>NSW Reconstruction Authority sells flood buyback homes for as little as $1</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/house-sells-for-one-dollar-at-flood-buyback-auction-in-nsw/106000336</link><description>Eleven flood buyback homes sell without a reserve price in the NSW Northern Rivers, with more to hit the market before the end of the year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b22530605e34112dada10d4f544c7a76</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Cup-winning jockey Jamie Melham suspended for 30 race meetings for careless riding</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/melbourne-cup-winner-jamie-melham-banned-blake-shinn-race-fall/106002084</link><description>History-making jockey Jamie Melham has hit the headlines for the wrong reasons, with the Melbourne Cup winner banned for 30 race meetings for careless riding that resulted in a race fall for Blake Shinn.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">644ce65cc2a5c8a1124d4b53a8c736c0</guid></item><item><title>Recruitment data shows unemployment rate worse than official figures suggest</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/data-shows-unemployment-rate-worse-than-official-figures/106001550</link><description>The October unemployment rate is crucial because it will either cement the RBA's decision to keep interest rates on hold, or cause more confusion about monetary policy. Early evidence points to a weakening jobs market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62be7b55d9d06400db4aefe6cea1c82a</guid></item><item><title>Rainforest Reserves Australia questioned over submissions against Moonlight Range Wind Farm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/rainforest-reserves-australia-moonlight-range-wind-farm/106000366</link><description>Rainforest Reserves Australia has faced a Senate inquiry amid allegations of using AI and referencing non-existent projects and groups in submissions against an axed wind farm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a5d4bbf7faec0ff1f2e99edb08b50fb</guid></item><item><title>Two-thirds of A-League Women players experience 'psychological distress', PFA report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/a-league-women-players-pfa-survey-full-time-pay-mental-health/106002146</link><description>More than two-thirds of A-League Women players were in psychological distress last season, including experiencing disordered eating, alcohol misuse or disturbed sleep, according to football's players' union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2e34ce8099bb810027402ea83cd081d</guid></item><item><title>Inquest into death of Stanley Obi, allegedly set alight by former partner in murder-suicide, concludes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/stanley-obi-and-sarah-mudge-fire-deaths-inquest-evidence-ends/106001084</link><description>Stanley Obi, 33, died after his former partner Sarah Mudge set him and his then-partner alight. A coronial inquest hears he should have been asked if he was the victim of abuse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c391d2e3ae4427030142eb5c44cc9d47</guid></item><item><title>Preliminary report into fatal Moruya skydiving plane crash released</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/preliminary-atsb-report-moruya-light-plane-crash/106000758</link><description>A preliminary report is released into the fatal crash that killed pilot Paul Smith on the NSW south coast, in which the light plane entered a steep descent less than 90 seconds after eight skydivers jumped out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3f645c936f27d43815028804ce76208</guid></item><item><title>Barcaldine Renewable Energy Zone plans abandoned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/barcaldine-renewable-energy-zone-plans-abandoned/105999132</link><description>Barcaldine Shire Council says it is working with affected businesses to keep them in town after ZEN Energy pulled out of plans for a renewable energy industrial precinct.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83fc071beb66e35c6b1d8fe8056b0812</guid></item><item><title>Man found not criminally responsible for murder of Ray McCormack in Wollongong</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/aaron-lord-not-criminally-responsible-homeless-murder/105999992</link><description>Train station rough sleeper Aaron Michael Lord has been found not criminally responsible for the murder of Ray McCormack in a Wollongong stairwell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">899be91438af9062ffdddc98839fd468</guid></item><item><title>Victoria's raised land taxes hurting property owners and businesses alike</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/couple-fight-land-tax-bill-after-property-incorrectly-valued/105997042</link><description>Emmaly and David Gridley were shocked to learn their rural property had been mistakenly valued at $2.3 million, leaving them with a heavily inflated land tax bill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4136b21f20fce1ac842ba44ca9a6132</guid></item><item><title>A new law will make it easier for Tasmanian renters to keep pets.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/new-pets-in-rentals-law-tasmania/106001364</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13c402ca94be12034006488eac2e3fa9</guid></item><item><title>WA parliamentary committee recommends changes to state's proposed 'post and boast' laws</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/post-and-boast-law-parliamentary-committee-recommends-changes/106002498</link><description>Freedom of speech and peaceful protest could be under threat if WA laws to deter people from boasting about crimes are passed, a parliamentary committee finds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00f567d742b724c0d2618be18e9c3bba</guid></item><item><title>Queensland prisons watchdog report lays bare state of separation rooms at youth detention centres</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/queensland-prisons-watchdog-report-separation-rooms-dirty/106000548</link><description>The Inspector of Detention Services suggests separation rooms at youth detention centres — which have sometimes been found to lack basic amenities — are inhumane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48e6ec01c139238ef17658342c86f492</guid></item><item><title>Kyle and Jackie O escape prosecution over controversial comments during Erin Patterson trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/kyle-and-jackie-o-avoid-charges-erin-patterson-mushroom/106002620</link><description>Victoria's Office of Public Prosecutions says it will not lay contempt of court charges against the controversial radio hosts, who made comments about the Erin Patterson case in the middle of her trial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea40b05b02d4da824edce7057d792e74</guid></item><item><title>Historic timber Cuttagee Bridge to become double-lane concrete bridge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/cuttagee-bridge-design-chosen-bega-valley-council/105991792</link><description>A single-lane historic wooden bridge on the New South Wales far south coast is set to be replaced with a concrete structure, prompting backlash from community members.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8025dceb66034ffd916fd2daaaced69</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Health issues alert after three measles cases attend Jelly Roll concert at Brisbane Entertainment Centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/qld-measles-cases-traced-to-jelly-roll-concert-at-brisbane/106002746</link><description>Queensland Health says the three infected people were at last month's concert of American singer Jelly Roll at the Brisbane Entertainment Centre and is warning others who attended to be alert for symptoms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44286258231058e48bdb396a170a4b83</guid></item><item><title>Four key takeaways from the Eddie Murphy documentary Being Eddie</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/eddie-murphy-documentary-being-eddie-takeaways/106002068</link><description>Eddie Murphy has taken on many characters throughout his career, sometimes even within the same film. But a new documentary explores the "real Eddie Murphy" — someone the actor and comedian says few people actually know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">280b5b989c3c5928b1fa2cf85750ced7</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/wednesday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/106002810</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df1d3958e463a763a0624d7a1224ad41</guid></item><item><title>AC/DC's iconic music video, filmed along Swanston Street in Melbourne's CBD</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/acdc-countdown-music-video-bagpipes/106002764</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e84fa74a5ea74be7598657e12cd8b5a8</guid></item><item><title>The world record for biggest bagpipe ensemble was broken in Melbourne, with 374 pipers playing in unison.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/bagpipe-world-record-melbourne/106003026</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89d88c07bc4de504ef81f3e217c2de98</guid></item><item><title>Bagpipers play tribute to AC/DC in world record attempt in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/world-bagpipe-record-melbourne/106002186</link><description>The biggest ever ensemble of bagpipers gathered in Melbourne's Fed Square to play tribute to AC/DC, smashing a world record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c13dd51f200037361951192672d0ed1c</guid></item><item><title>Macedon Ranges Mayor Dominic Bonanno caught drink driving in mayoral vehicle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/macedon-mayor-caught-drink-driving-speeding/106002772</link><description>Macedon Ranges Mayor Dominic Bonanno says he has been caught speeding and drink driving in his mayoral vehicle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72ddb623432a41e637e1a531a2fc2596</guid></item><item><title>Tasmanian renters wanting a pet just got new protections. Here's how to get approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/tasmanian-government-introduces-pets-in-rentals-legislation/104652212</link><description>Under the updated legislation, landlords now need a "reasonable" rationale to say no to a tenant having pets — and that reasonableness can only be decided by an independent tribunal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07c060cc59daba763377e7155d70b4f3</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Health warns hospitals to strengthen procedures around medical imaging results</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/queensland-health-checking-hospital-procedures-for-medical-scans/106002578</link><description>Authorities fear some patients involved in a medical imaging bungle have suffered long-term or permanent harm due to delays in receiving scan results and follow-up care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8554b8ea0f2e27bfe22e131d46b14b32</guid></item><item><title>Will land tax surcharges discourage investment in Victoria?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/will-land-tax-surcharges-discourage-investment-in-victoria-/106003198</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f1cc785df09e5bfdb35feeb19b41396</guid></item><item><title>Liberals still deciding fate of net zero policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/liberals-still-deciding-fate-of-net-zero-policy/106002484</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">432a33031d91fa96c510d8ee10bc831c</guid></item><item><title>Sawfish found with rostrum cut off on Port Hedland beach sparks anger</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/sawfish-found-dead-with-rostrum-cut-off-port-hedland/105999948</link><description>A video showing a critically endangered sawfish lying dead on a beach with its saw removed is described as "cruel" and "trophy hunting".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a259fc62cf0dd402513d2b8847bf442f</guid></item><item><title>Up to 20 Yipirinya School staff facing job losses amid 'shock' redundancies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/alice-springs-yipirinya-school-shock-redundancies/106002876</link><description>Staff at Yipirinya School in Alice Springs say they will fight back after the school's statutory manager announced up to 20 redundancies amid plunging enrolments and a multi-million-dollar debt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a740c47a0671969e94b78b9df4bc3045</guid></item><item><title>Ley to announce final position on net zero, after Liberals clear path to dump target</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/liberals-pave-way-to-ditch-net-zero-and-settle-infighting/106002684</link><description>Months of bitter infighting between Liberals over the party's climate policy could be drawing to a close, with MPs paving the way for net zero to be formally abandoned at a shadow ministry meeting on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf7a9bdcc4334fa3c2700e1dd53fc1a6</guid></item><item><title>WA Environmental Protection Authority gives expanded ferry network tick of approval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/expanded-perth-ferry-network-gets-environmental-tick-of-approval/106003118</link><description>Western Australia's environmental regulator decides not to formally assess plans to expand Perth's ferry services on the Swan River, despite pressure from the public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">808896e13c5ccf35512222056d2c1382</guid></item><item><title>Allegations against ex-Attorney-General Mark Dreyfus removed from Linda Reynolds action against Commonwealth</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/-mark-dreyfus-allegations-removed-from-linda-reynolds-lawsuit/106001236</link><description>Linda Reynolds is suing the Commonwealth and its lawyers over the handling of Brittany Higgins' $2.4 million compensation settlement, yet has removed specific allegations against the former Attorney-General Mark Dreyfus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d9f795fe54bc791daae29b9ff315b0a</guid></item><item><title>Toombul Shopping Centre site thrown lifeline after Mirvac announces sale with 'priority' to build new retail centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/qld-toombul-shopping-centre-thrown-lifeline-after-sale-by-mirvac/106003186</link><description>Mirvac announces it is selling the site of the Toombul Shopping Centre — devastated by the 2022 Brisbane floods — to a developer who has plans to build a new shopping centre as part of a mixed-use precinct.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1ce2733989616026134668e7b2456ea</guid></item><item><title>Abortion legislation voted down in South Australian Parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/sa-abortion-voted-down/106001338</link><description>A new push to change South Australia's abortion laws to limit terminations after 23 weeks has been voted down in state parliament's Upper House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">978de31879380953a492acefc663c992</guid></item><item><title>Woolworths executive was hospitalised by 100-hour-a-week workload, lawsuit claims</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-12/woolworths-executive-ceo-lawsuit/106002948</link><description>The executive had a suspected stroke, went temporarily blind and was hospitalised five times after regularly clocking more than 100 hours a week on the job, according to documents filed with the Federal Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b293695cfdd1514f13196a402d3af58</guid></item></channel></rss>