<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 09:08:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Update your ABC News homepage for more local stories</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2020-09-03/update-to-abc-news-homepage/12579988</link><description>We've got an ABC News homepage for you. Adjust your settings for the right mix of local and national news.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">146f1699ce6b1b7420a91b6bb80d0309</guid></item><item><title>Call for button battery redesign after new study reveals horrific injuries and fatalities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-08-23/button-battery-warning-danger-deaths-lithium-swallow/103986966</link><description>A new study reveals the horrific injuries suffered after swallowing or inserting button batteries but manufacturers aren't prioritising their redesign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46ab5f96ade65908ecf6b7be8673e61f</guid></item><item><title>Have Your Say: What was the issue, policy or event that decided your vote?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-02-26/federal-election-your-say/104788518</link><description>After a five-week campaign, the results are in with Labor returned to government. Is there a policy or issue that swayed your vote? Have Your Say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">320dfcbec9cd8fe02e449407ce78e618</guid></item><item><title>Australians tell ABC's Your Say they are struggling more than ever with housing costs</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-15/abc-your-say-federal-election-2025-housing-policies/105175180</link><description>Voters tell ABC's Your Say campaign they are struggling more than ever with housing costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54451646ec8e9f100cc2fe59fc9c08c5</guid></item><item><title>Housing advocates seek federal funding election promise for co-op model</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-17/housing-cooperative-solution-proposed-for-rental-crisis/105108816</link><description>Advocates admit co-operative housing models are not for everyone but say for the right residents, they offer more security and affordable pricing than traditional rentals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3608b0c1ae56f5a5b36968898f65df5e</guid></item><item><title>Next-generation voters call for better engagement ahead of federal election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-18/federal-election-rural-next-generation-voters/105173450</link><description>Young people in Albury say issues that directly affect them and their communities are not being addressed by major parties for the 2025 election campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ae182892b8c9591cd9ec35e6e57fcb9</guid></item><item><title>Health, climate and community sport: What older voters in the Tasmanian seat of Bass are talking about this election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-04-29/health-climate-sport-election-older-voters-bass-tasmania/105224138</link><description>The federal seat of Bass is held by a margin of just 1.4 per cent. For these older voters who live in the electorate, health, climate and community sport are the issues that will decide their vote.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3579db910b5a7ee8e11d2618bf798f</guid></item><item><title>Woodstock Farm program helping steer troubled Queensland youth away from life of crime</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-15/woodstock-farm-program-helping-youth-avoid-life-of-crime/106337320</link><description>The rural-based social program in the shadow of Mt Tamborine has had remarkable success in rebuilding the lives of youth who have fallen through the cracks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">421b0aeae39a6049b42963e3f882f283</guid></item><item><title>Whooping cough cases hit record high after 'potentially catastrophic' vaccine rate drop</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-16/whooping-cough-cases-at-record-high-level-in-australia/106332954</link><description>A "potentially catastrophic" decline in Australia's childhood vaccination rates has contributed to the sharpest increase in cases of whooping cough in 35 years, infectious diseases experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df9f56f6aeb1e16c21e2baf9475f1b0a</guid></item><item><title>Mould, asbestos, collapsed ceilings plague some South Australian schools</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/sa-schools-in-need-of-repair/106334244</link><description>Almost two years after a state government report revealed 35 per cent of all buildings within the Department for Education's portfolio were past their design life, many schools are still plagued with issues including mould, asbestos and rotting windows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fabb2b4476c5886be92e1dda09f3283</guid></item><item><title>Albanese says Australian government will not help ISIS-linked families leave Syria or return home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/anthony-albanese-on-isis-families-trying-to-leave-syria/106352492</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese insists the federal government will not repatriate the Australian families with links to Islamic State fighters who remain in Syria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faa866e3881f2d6646422dcbe7b56295</guid></item><item><title>Private health premiums to rise at fastest rate in almost a decade</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-17/private-health-premiums-increase/106355550</link><description>Private health insurance premiums will rise at their fastest rate in almost a decade, after the federal government approved a 4.41 per cent average increase from April.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cf53e80cc9f8f5821a0c50d3aa7dd87</guid></item><item><title>Millionaire Gary Stevenson's dire warning for Australian property market losing the 'fair go'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/economist-gary-stevenson-warns-australia-losing-the-fair-go/106342536</link><description>British economist Gary Stevenson is on a speaking tour, warning Australia will follow the path of the UK with "poverty exploding" unless politicians deal with inequality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f588e11282bda2e3e28ac0a5b4d7af5d</guid></item><item><title>Actor Shia LaBeouf arrested for allegedly hitting two men at Mardi Gras in New Orleans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/shia-labeouf-arrested-for-alleged-fight-mardi-gras-new-orleans/106357346</link><description>The actor allegedly hit a man multiple times with closed fists and allegedly punched another man in the nose.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f284d1a63429f4a42321d1db2ea5e20</guid></item><item><title>Is it ever a good idea to stay together for the kids?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/should-you-ever-stay-together-for-the-kids/106281890</link><description>When a relationships breaks down, sometimes we think staying in the familiar discomfort is less scary — and even protective — for our kids. But is it ever a good idea to stay in an unhappy relationship for the sake of the children?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbe4bbc74caa9ba1918949fae6630fe1</guid></item><item><title>Mazda, Nissan, Hyundai and Subaru face multi-million-dollar penalties under NVES</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-18/new-vehicle-efficiency-standard-results-mazda-nissan-penalties/106358770</link><description>Major car brands are staring down the barrel of multi-million-dollar penalties for exceeding their emissions, the first results of the federal government's climate laws for new vehicles have revealed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45198840bd21329442d531c79bcbff0d</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine reclaims more than 200 square kilometres of territory as Elon Musk blocks Russian army's internet access</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/ukraine-reclaims-territory-as-musk-blocks-russian-army-internet/106356642</link><description>Ukraine has made its largest battlefield gains in more than two and a half years, retaking more than 200 square kilometres of its territory from Russia in just five days, according to a new analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e4eeb80452a2963e88ee75deff26d71</guid></item><item><title>Today in History, February 19: Britpop, beats and a lust for life on Trainspotting's deathless soundtrack</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/trainspotting-soundtrack-30th-anniversary-danny-boyle-britpop/106354570</link><description>Most films are lucky to get just one needle-drop moment embedded in the Zeitgeist. Trainspotting boasted several.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ab3fc2c71c82699927e06d1a58d6cf7</guid></item><item><title>Quiz: Which books are these literary quotes from?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/famous-book-quotes-quiz/106321984</link><description>Are you happiest with your nose in a book? Did you spend summer reading at the beach? This quiz is for you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93263cc459c19ed242af066f07f52020</guid></item><item><title>Senate committee features climate disinformation, the Atlas Network, and Dr Karl's clash with One Nation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/climate-disinformation-senate-committee-dr-karl-atlas-network/106350002</link><description>The scourge of AI-slopaganda, viral disinformation campaigns and online attacks against individuals and institutions is going to get far worse before it gets better, if the latest public hearings on the topic are any indication.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc806ab7e06e7cc45d048d4f225dbed0</guid></item><item><title>Perth couple Jonathan and Amy Carr-Knox locked in international surrogacy battle to bring home daughter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/battle-bring-home-sophie-after-surrogacy-red-tape-argentina/106126626</link><description>Jonathan and Amy had a child via surrogacy in Argentina. They have been stuck there for 12 months, unable to bring their daughter home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e1192412c2820ccafbe31fa94aa760c</guid></item><item><title>Fiji's former prime minister Frank Bainimarama charged with inciting mutiny</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/former-fiji-prime-minister-bainimarama-arrested-charged-mutiny/106360516</link><description>Long-serving Fiji prime minister Frank Bainimarama and a former police commissioner will face court on Tuesday on charges of mutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfb056a8d72b38a8175534edc2ea18aa</guid></item><item><title>Moyne Shire Council never wanted Port Fairy's pool, yet it paid $3.4m for it</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/port-fairy-pool-moyne-shire-cost-belfast-aquatics/106345296</link><description>A Victorian community group promised its local shire a new pool would not cost it money once it was built. In less than three months, the promise was broken.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8cfb04cc8a00decf70f2adc47081828</guid></item><item><title>From crime heists to a BDSM love story, here's what's in cinemas this month</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/what-to-watch-movies-february-pillion-crime-101/106352928</link><description>Australians will also finally be able to catch Sirât and The Voice of Hind Rajab, two movies that will be vying for Best International Film at the Academy Awards next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8040a86763a5a4d748d6c02c57f6603a</guid></item><item><title>The heartwarming tribute to injured aerials star Laura Peel at the Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/heartwarming-aerials-tribute-laura-peel/106361392</link><description>This Winter Olympics aerials competition saw plenty of Aussies achieve lifetime goals, but they never forgot the one person who was missing — injured champion Laura Peel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837dd8955b1207595385711ea5af7ba8</guid></item><item><title>An avalanche in Northern California was the worst in the US for 40 years. Here's how it unfolded</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/how-the-deadliest-avalanche-in-the-us-in-40-years-unfolded/106362394</link><description>An avalanche in California has left eight back-country skiers dead and one missing. Here's how it unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ecbef0cca72889da9fa0ce66f9c81ea</guid></item><item><title>Rugby fans furious over 2027 Rugby World Cup ticket website crashes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/rugby-world-cup-tickets-website-crash/106363344</link><description>Rugby fans from around the world are furious after failing to get tickets to the 2027 Men's World Cup due technical glitches and website crashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4827688c1be1b5c4bd7a18a7c04671b5</guid></item><item><title>For salty South Australians, motorsport revenge is oh so sweet</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/for-salty-south-australians-motorsport-revenge-is-oh-so-sweet/106363660</link><description>The last Grand Prix in Adelaide was held in 1995 before its move across the border to Victoria. Now, Adelaide has poached the MotoGP — but will it be enough to appease resentful SA Formula One fans?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ffda5df5fc99fb91a7d77ce30ebe2be</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with terrorism offences after phones seized in Sydney's south-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/man-charged-with-alleged-terrorism-offences-in-south-west-sydney/106364186</link><description>A 31-year-old has been arrested a second time after police stopped and searched a vehicle in Yagoona and seized three mobile phones allegedly storing violent extremist material.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a42a7ef9a3826f7f12e11df944244901</guid></item><item><title>Vegetable scraps to be turned into bioenergy by Scenic Rim farm as part of $291 million project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/qld-kalfresh-bioenergy-scenic-rim/106363982</link><description>A new $291 million project set to turn farm scraps to energy has begun construction in Queensland's Scenic Rim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db61a8e13ba17ab198287e56aca27dc2</guid></item><item><title>Racing NSW disqualifies stablehand and owner Brian Carey over racehorse death in Maryborough</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/brian-carey-city-limits-racing-nsw-racehorse-maryborough/106362914</link><description>Registered owner and stablehand Brian Carey is disqualified after being found guilty by Racing NSW of failing to ensure his racehorse, City Limits, had sufficient food and water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89c623d6aac3515dcfe6d5527459d333</guid></item><item><title>Man accused of 'controlling' the lives of Venezuelan youth group granted bail</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/bail-granted-over-alleged-youth-group-servitude/106363616</link><description>An alleged religious leader accused of "controlling every aspect" of the lives of a Venezuelan youth group has been granted release on strict home detention conditions by a South Australian court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91bc9f195f669d568f2a90e1fe9c2a44</guid></item><item><title>Police investigate stabbing of 17-year-old at Geelong shopping mall</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/geelong-shopping-mall-stabbing/106365416</link><description>A 17-year-old boy has been taken to hospital with serious injuries after a suspected stabbing at the Market Square shopping centre in Geelong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cd13547a7c5a690d71c004d6eaed927</guid></item><item><title>Coles manager moved product onto 'Down Down' promotion days after price hike to be more competitive</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/coles-accc-federal-court-dog-food-down-down-pricing/106358664</link><description>A second Coles manager has been grilled in the federal court over whether rushing a product onto a "Down Down" promotion could have broken internal guidelines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41ca3a7b1fd4851df375d2220574fd44</guid></item><item><title>Labor Opposition, crossbench call for NT MLA Tanzil Rahman to respond to bullying allegations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/nt-politicians-calling-tanzil-rahman-explain-bullying-claims-clp/106364054</link><description>An MLA accused of bullying by two female staffers is urged to front the public and explain what action has been taken following the claims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1fafc3445b2b59e5354fc437a4169aa</guid></item><item><title>Gas explosion kills 16 after apartment building partially collapses in southern Pakistan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/gas-explosion-kills-16-apartment-building-collapses-pakistan/106365612</link><description>Women and children are among 16 people killed after a gas explosion ripped through an apartment building in Pakistan on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bac5b7cbd5dc5905b6f47c64562d41d5</guid></item><item><title>Greg Lynn applies for bail as retrial for High Country camper murder looms</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/greg-lynn-applies-for-bail-court/106365580</link><description>The former Jetstar pilot awaits a retrial for the murder of Carol Clay, after his 2024 conviction was quashed last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77a388716f1e874a2b4c47724de2d0e3</guid></item><item><title>Employees of Albany lolly shop fined for illegal tobacco sales say they were never paid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2026-02-19/illegal-tobacco-fines-albany-lolly-shop/106364808</link><description>"Vulnerable" staff at a smoke shop disguised as a candy store in Albany say they were never paid by the shop's mystery operators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">504a81865723b70dcc8bc16fa3cc618b</guid></item></channel></rss>