<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 02:32:35 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>South Africa defeat India by three wickets in Women's Cricket World Cup at Visakhapatnam</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/south-africa-defeat-india-womens-cricket-world-cup/105868672</link><description>South Africa defeats co-hosts India by three wickets in the group stage of the Women's Cricket World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">344af34c876b9d1fd805b45a4e937c11</guid></item><item><title>New statistics show Victoria's most dangerous roads are in regional areas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/victoria-most-dangerous-roads-are-regional/105858040</link><description>In regional Victoria, potholes are not being fixed and major rural road projects have stalled, despite the loss of life from accidents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f21ea12d59704621728578e03da03e8b</guid></item><item><title>The NT's first Alice Springs-based police commissioner has a rocky road ahead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/new-nt-police-commissioner-martin-dole-challenges-ahead/105872198</link><description>Martin Dole has been a Northern Territory police officer for nearly 30 years — but as the new commissioner, his most challenging role now lies ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62a4fe70a93c35ff3bf4d9dd3e6e2dbc</guid></item><item><title>Two dead on private property in Tasmania after tree falls in wild winds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/tasmania-wild-weather-two-dead-in-tree-fall/105875332</link><description>Two people have died after a tree fell on them on a rural property in Tasmania's north-west, during Friday's severe winds and wet weather, police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">762b5ecc8c7afc01f1284936da8823ae</guid></item><item><title>What the State of WA’s appeal of Dion Barber’s $2.8 million compensation win could mean for abuse survivors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/-dion-barber-abuse-compensation-appeal-to-set-legal-precedent/105873760</link><description>Less than a decade after the door opened for victims of historic child sexual abuse to seek justice in WA, abuse survivors could be at risk of having that door shut again, writes Cason Ho.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09b69bd78ea93e7d62f375821a7ebad0</guid></item><item><title>Hamas is trusting Trump as his 'eternal peace' in Gaza turns into a shaky ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/analysis-trump-eternal-peace-in-gaza-turns-into-shaky-ceasefire/105874742</link><description>With Israel and Hamas not sticking to Donald Trump's proposed "20-point plan", the deal to bring "eternal peace" in the Middle East looks more like a temporary ceasefire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e597e0e0fb47c628dfaca2d504bc30d</guid></item><item><title>Letitia James, NY attorney general and Donald Trump foe, indicted for bank fraud</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/letitia-james-ny-attorney-general-trump-foe-indicted-bank-fraud/105875568</link><description>New York Attorney General Letitia James, a longtime foe of US President Donald Trump, is indicted for bank fraud.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7794029ca8b380e949956f97889ca8f</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day five recap: Geelong opens Charlie Curnow bidding as Sydney looms, Ben Ainsworth and Campbell Chesser join Blues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/afl-trade-period-day-five-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105875584</link><description>The chase for Carlton star Charlie Curnow heated up on day five of the AFL trade period, with Geelong seeing an offer rejected as Sydney prepared its bid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1af08ce39a4f267630c93fa4dbf8386</guid></item><item><title>Novak Djokovic advances to Shanghai Masters semifinals, qualifier Valentin Vacherot continues fairytale run</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/novak-djokovic-advances-to-semifinals-of-shanghai-masters/105875540</link><description>Fourth seed Novak Djokovic battled past a spirited Zizou Bergs 6-3 7-5 on Thursday to reach the Shanghai Masters semifinals for a 10th time, setting up a clash with surprise package and world number 204 Valentin Vacherot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">745b0675e4a5c74aaa50698faa310769</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia urges respect for its sovereignty after Australia-PNG defence treaty</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/indonesia-responded-pukpuk-defence-agreement-australia-png/105869738</link><description>The landmark agreement commits both countries to "meet the common danger" in the event of an armed attack on either. With that, questions have been raised about Australia's role if the conflict in West Papua escalates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d73f53cf0f068b144851c0c5f4cd706</guid></item><item><title>What NSW court ruling on Sydney Opera House pro-Palestinian march means for future protests</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/what-ruling-on-palestinian-opera-house-rally-means-for-protests/105874496</link><description>The state's three top judges have ruled to block a pro-Palestinian march at the Sydney Opera House this weekend, but experts say an element of their decision sets a precedent that could have major implications on protests going forward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b44cae55f475162efeb8d639c9afc48</guid></item><item><title>Australia's dark matter experiment construction nears completion</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/the-global-race-to-detect-dark-matter-stawell-lab-sabre/105861050</link><description>Deep underground in an old gold mine in regional Victoria, scientists enter a worldwide race to understand the composition of dark matter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20bdfc9fdb6ec2c681a7dae294b644ed</guid></item><item><title>Industrial businesses to ramp-up noise monitoring over humming noise in Sydney's north-west</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/epa-closes-in-on-businesses-over-disturbing-humming-noise-sydney/105870234</link><description>The NSW environmental watchdog has acted on complaints by residents in Sydney's north-west who have been kept awake at night by a disturbing humming noise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c7f8ce47ec86c2e6609ce33551985d2</guid></item><item><title>Principals' power to ban aggressive parents from school grounds to extend to social media behaviour</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/safety-protections-parents-schools-aggressive-parents-review/105875552</link><description>Principals in Victoria already have the power to ban aggressive or violent parents from school grounds, but the state government is looking to apply the power to parents' behaviour on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cfdbdd1cc62140ca01e0eeea675488e</guid></item><item><title>Federal government investigates PFAS spread in Rockhampton amid concern for property prices</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/pfas-contamination-rockhampton-airport-concerns-for-properties/105830932</link><description>Christine Stasch was planning to sell her family farm and retire further north. Now, she is fighting for compensation after discovering PFAS contamination on her property.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8211dd335880fe3781624b719dbbcd7a</guid></item><item><title>Three people detained in Belgium over suspected terror plot to attack politicians with drone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/belgian-drone-terror-plot-against-politicians-foiled-by-police/105876098</link><description>Three people are detained after an "improvised device" is found at the home of one of the suspects in an investigation into terrorist activities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5be15c67882a05b128d36ad6f2c5d4b</guid></item><item><title>David McBride's last-ditch attempt to overturn conviction thrown out by High Court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/high-court-rejects-last-appeal-david-mcbride-jail-sentence/105875970</link><description>The former military lawyer was sentenced to five years and eight months in jail after sharing classified material with journalists in a case that has raised debate about whistleblower laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">175d998fc7a5b5ddf9511c969794f36e</guid></item><item><title>Hollywood icon Paul Feig to take audiences behind-the-scenes of Bridesmaids at SXSW Sydney</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/paul-feig-to-go-behind-the-scenes-at-sxsw-sydney/105876010</link><description>Hollywood director Paul Feig has a special strategy that's served him well when it comes to making popular movies and television shows that stand the test of time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bbf931ff2574bffc35e9ba72be36763</guid></item><item><title>Public health alert for nitazenes issued after person dies in Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/queensland-records-death-from-synthetic-opioid/105875620</link><description>Queensland Health issues a public health alert warning nitazenes have been detected in tablets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74030fde7f87fd50b0bcb255243ada39</guid></item><item><title>Cairns faces prospect of water restrictions at wettest time of year</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/cairns-facing-water-restrictions-wettest-time-year/105874192</link><description>Cairns residents are urged to cut down on their water use as multiple infrastructure failures put the city at risk of water shortfalls heading into summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f3a138386a7fabdb54be0b3faf38c82</guid></item><item><title>Police interview woman after man's death in Broome</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/woman-assisting-police-mans-broome-death/105876636</link><description>A 41-year-old man dies after an altercation with a woman in Western Australia's north.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6844e738285845adb6b85e2275cbcbfd</guid></item><item><title>PM says there's 'nothing unusual' in Treasury meeting on contentious superannuation tax proposal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/albanese-plays-down-treasury-request-superannuation-tax/105875570</link><description>Anthony Albanese says his request for Treasury to examine a controversial proposal to lift taxes on some superannuation balances is "nothing unusual", rejecting claims he is planning to rewrite it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe7afdcdf15f814487b7881f7653bc89</guid></item><item><title>Matildas confirm return of Sam Kerr to squad for England and Wales friendlies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/matildas-confirm-return-of-sam-kerr/105875916</link><description>Sam Kerr is back in the Matildas squad for the first time since late 2023, ahead of friendlies against Wales and England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5aeea9e4dce40106f87d459df2eade18</guid></item><item><title>Judge dismisses Drake's lawsuit over Kendrick Lamar diss track Not Like Us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/judge-dismisses-drake-lawsuit-kendrick-lamar-not-like-us/105876144</link><description>The judge says a reasonable listener could not have concluded that Not Like Us was conveying objective facts about Drake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f5f53f791e2466fdbe508fd95f87668</guid></item><item><title>Working dog makes championship comeback after leg amputation</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/cheese-the-champion-three-legged-dog-comeback/105833270</link><description>Cheese was on track to be a champion when an accident cut his working dog trial career short. A year on from a leg amputation, the border collie is back in the yards and the winner's circle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30087740aaa42038b8fd192bd39249e7</guid></item><item><title>Two dead after magnitude-7.4 Philippines earthquake sparks tsunami warnings</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/magnitude-7-4-earthquake-strikes-philippines-tsunami-warning/105877252</link><description>The quake hit in the Mindanao region at a depth of 62 kilometres below ground level and could cause hazardous tsunami waves along coasts within 300km of the epicentre, seismology authorities say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0203a68b6ef5ddf44b4d1ebd08c9622e</guid></item><item><title>RBA governor Michele Bullock says First Home Guarantee could lead to riskier loans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/rba-governor-michele-bullock-senate-grilling-property-price-rise/105873716</link><description>RBA Governor Michele Bullock says the federal government's First Home Guarantee scheme could see some Australians taking out riskier loans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38ef789309a652d1ddba94eab70c3783</guid></item><item><title>Tasmania Police offers $1 million reward to crack Victoria Cafasso cold case murder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/million-dollar-reward-to-crack-victoria-cafasso-cold-case-murder/105876792</link><description>Italian tourist Victoria Cafasso had been in Tasmania for less than a week when she was brutally murdered in broad daylight on an east coast beach 30 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb4bea5034b435473b42270544f27519</guid></item><item><title>David Pocock reinvited to parliament sports club after prime minister weighs in</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/david-pocock-parliament-sports-club-gambling-lobby-sponsorship/105876446</link><description>The former star Wallabies player turned independent senator was kicked out of the social sports club after raising concerns about its links to the gambling industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd97cdeba6a6b1da2db09b46e5826137</guid></item><item><title>Victorian fruit grower to stand trial over coolroom death of truck driver</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/fruit-grower-trial-not-guilty-plea-coolroom-death-shepparton/105870460</link><description>A fruit-growing company in northern Victoria will stand trial over the death of a 50-year-old man who was found unresponsive in a coolroom in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3e990fdcfe84a1cf57503d815864671</guid></item><item><title>Vladimir Putin says Russian air defences were to blame for Azerbaijani jetliner crash</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/azerbaijani-plane-crash-russian-air-defences-to-blame-putin-says/105876934</link><description>The Russian president makes his first public admission of responsibility for the crash, in an effort to improve relations with Azerbaijan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">397860cc5db8e0d72e7856342cddcf24</guid></item><item><title>Australia 'still optimistic' Pat Cummins will play first Ashes Test against England</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/ashes-australia-england-pat-cummins-first-test/105877424</link><description>With the opening men's Ashes Test six weeks away, Australia coach Andrew McDonald is not willing to rule out Pat Cummins taking the field in Perth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1447a7d5df1ddcc1e1d81f8972e49486</guid></item><item><title>Patients may not see benefits of $8.5 billlion bulk-billing boost for four years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/bulk-billing-incentive-boost-may-not-flow-for-years/105877228</link><description>Patients may not see the benefits of higher bulk-billing for years, and average-out-of-pocket costs are expected to rise, the health department has conceded — despite $8.5 billion being tipped into the GP subsidy scheme from November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59bcd666888fb324634b523eb9d30802</guid></item><item><title>Sydney rock oysters to be grown at Lakes Entrance on the Gippsland Lakes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/victorians-could-soon-enjoy-homegrown-sydney-rock-oysters/105876316</link><description>Victoria could have its own Sydney rock oyster industry after a trial in the state's east yielded positive results.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c3ab285fc280a71bdaa80e9d36de7f0</guid></item><item><title>Can you ever throw out a previous home owner or renter's mail?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/can-you-ever-throw-out-someone-elses-mail/105837974</link><description>Even years after moving in, you might still be receiving someone else’s bills and letters. Here’s what can you do about it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bad6b718ab042dcb408f6ce3edd8d58c</guid></item><item><title>Teens charged with murder after deaths of Dau Akueng and Chol Achiek refuse to attend court</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/teenagers-charged-murder-refuse-to-attend-court/105877662</link><description>Two teenagers charged with murder after the deaths of Dau Akueng and Chol Achiek have refused to board the prison van to attend court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33f4aeff4cdc6b54653b6715a2005368</guid></item><item><title>Donna Nelson drops attempts to overturn Japan drug smuggling conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/donna-nelson-abandons-japan-drug-smuggling-appeal/105877124</link><description>A Perth grandmother duped into becoming a drug mule in an elaborate love scam abandons her final line of appeal on drug importing charges in Japan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">206f27669cbf42ca05647fc2575cb5ab</guid></item><item><title>David Sharaz served bankruptcy papers by former WA Senator Linda Reynolds after defamation win</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/linda-reynolds-brittany-higgins-david-sharaz-bankruptcy-served/105878088</link><description>Brittany Higgins's husband David Sharaz is served bankruptcy papers by former Senator Linda Reynolds, as she tries to recover damages awarded to her by a Perth court for defamation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1256d5d93c57b054c08e985d405d0b7f</guid></item><item><title>Former Olympic basketballer Danny Morseu 'disappointed' retrial abandoned</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/olympic-basketballer-danny-morseu-charges-dropped/105877170</link><description>Danny Morseu's conviction has been wiped but he says he will struggle to find a job, a home, and a source of income after Queensland's Director of Public Prosecutions decided not to pursue a retrial.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">225218dcd9709b51e823ef5322977d84</guid></item><item><title>Kenmore Hills crime scene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/kenmore-hills-crime-scene/105877214</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84e00fdbee91a464bdc196cd0c7426ea</guid></item><item><title>Kenmore Hills crime scene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/kenmore-hills-crime-scene/105877014</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dd19a9ad2d49960810cd6fd22b1ed91</guid></item><item><title>Kenmore Hills crime scene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/kenmore-hills-crime-scene/105877698</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0563904f2e2a99cf3e11cd9fcdbd88c</guid></item><item><title>Kenmore Hills crime scene</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/kenmore-hills-crime-scene/105877500</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3d1a3886c9b53e88315a055c85e1315</guid></item><item><title>LIV's financial losses do not deter SA premier from $50m golf course</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/liv-golf-losses-will-not-impact-sa-golf-course-plan-premier-says/105877386</link><description>Premier Peter Malinauskas has rejected suggestions his government's North Adelaide golf course redevelopment is a risky investment with LIV Golf losing hundreds of millions a year, as he revealed where the Saudi-backed tournament will be hosted in 2027.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a665172221b8b91d065521a8b05f783</guid></item><item><title>Court throws out man's attempt to charge government officials using archaic practice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/port-augusta-council-charged-with-350-common-law-offences/105876884</link><description>A Port Augusta resident's attempt to charge several government officials and his local council with more than 350 criminal offences using an archaic concept of common law is tossed out by court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cedce768bfdc9cc5e2a3e9c63942deb0</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos wary of Canada ahead of international friendly in Montreal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/international-friendly-socceroos-vs-canada/105878752</link><description>In the build-up to Saturday's match in Montreal, Socceroos coach Tony Popovic feels Canada has given his squad the ultimate compliment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8f0c47995749d6a1c13b42cea53e946</guid></item><item><title>Girl dies in hospital days after two-car crash at intersection north of Adelaide</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/girl-dies-in-hospital-days-after-two-car-crash-at-virginia/105878580</link><description>A young girl has died almost a week after she was rushed to hospital following a serious crash involving a ute and a van on the northern outskirts of Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a86abaf39345ab04d1fb13ae071da9ea</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with Mark Akers's murder after body found on roadside</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/woman-charged-with-murder-after-body-found-beside-newell-highway/105878820</link><description>Mark Akers was travelling to Melbourne from Brisbane before his body was found on the side of the Newell Highway near Jerilderie in June.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df7e846a4faf7fa7b1a2af7bf2364d2a</guid></item><item><title>State government urged to reject Comiskey Group's Coochin Fields music festival site</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/qld-regs-coalition-opposes-coochin-creek-development/105875640</link><description>A coalition of Sunshine Coast community groups is calling on the state government to scrap a major music festival development because of ecological concerns raised by the State Assessment and Referrals Agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0539c64bdbb5c4af23a9fcf63d332535</guid></item><item><title>Elderly man hit by truck at Canberra tip dies later in hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/canberra-man-killed-by-truck-at-tip-dies-later-in-hospital/105878718</link><description>ACT police say the man was hit by the truck and knocked into the rubbish collection area, suffering fatal injuries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfe3c4d1dbf5c5d5304e88fc5f3650ba</guid></item><item><title>Correspondent Matthew Doran at Hostage Square in Tel Aviv</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/correspondent-matthew-doran-at-hostage-square-in/105879334</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e83cef0757bfdd6b6e0f297912844fe</guid></item><item><title>Australians travelling to Europe warned of long delays at airports after new entry rules</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/border-rules-change-europe-schengen-zone-security/105877556</link><description>Facial scans and fingerprinting will replace passport stamps across 29 countries in the Schengen Zone from October 12.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74bdcf2255b838d3cd2899c4e4240842</guid></item><item><title>Protecting rock art from wasp nests in Central Australia's Trephina Gorge with chopsticks and brushes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/rock-art-cleaning-at-trephina-gorge/105867252</link><description>Rock art has significant cultural importance to traditional owners, and is a highlight for visitors who make the hike to see it. These Ltyentye Apurte Rangers are working to help keep them protected from wasp nests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e32adeeb4bd3293608b4c2b5f2f9468a</guid></item><item><title>Hoop pine may set record as Australia's tallest rainforest tree</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/hoop-pine-discovery-might-be-tallest-rainforest-tree/105876058</link><description>Researchers mapping millions of trees as part of a climate change study think they have found Australia's tallest rainforest tree.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5b9000e787551f9b2e1e6206dd33c0d</guid></item><item><title>Coalition frontbencher tries to reframe immigration policy debate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/paul-scarr-reframes-immigration-policy-debate/105878470</link><description>Shadow Immigration Minister Paul Scarr has called for a "measured and considered" debate over migration levels after incendiary comments by members of the party's right flank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">009be0aa615f933c89b4f08de8b7d5ef</guid></item><item><title>SA government 'cautiously optimistic' about toxic algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/sa-government-cautiously-optimistic-about-toxic-algal-bloom-/105879314</link><description>SA government officials say there are some positive signs around the toxic algal bloom crisis as it continues to affect the state's metropolitan beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff7f4f2252b7d9c923a41ed25ffcc4d9</guid></item><item><title>Latest finance news</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/latest-finance-news/105879480</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83b3f6cc6c027d4ba22acdae17f46292</guid></item><item><title>Ceasefire begins but IDF to remain in Gaza Strip until Hamas disarms, Netanyahu says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/ceasefire-in-gaza-starts/105879726</link><description>The Israel Defense Forces announces a ceasefire has begun, but Benjamin Netanyahu says Israeli forces will remain in Gaza to pressure Hamas until it disarms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e522f39f337f20a791e2d552f3cf9189</guid></item><item><title>Western Bulldogs extend Essendon's losing streak with 57 point thrashing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-10/western-bulldogs-thrash-essendon/105879214</link><description>The Western Bulldogs have kept their faint AFLW finals hopes alive with a commanding 57 point drubbing of Essendon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac92bfe6e1f2c52e8561d9563d00cbb4</guid></item><item><title>International Criminal Court rejects Rodrigo Duterte's bid for release from detention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/icc-rejects-rodrigo-duterte-bid-to-be-released-from-detention/105879846</link><description>Former Philippine President Rodrigo Duterte must remain behind bars while awaiting trial, judges at the ICC have ruled, saying he might use his freedom to interfere with the legal process and suggesting he was a flight risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ec05a77bae27bbba4cacc40494c16dd</guid></item><item><title>Liberals find brief lull in internal hostilities for a passable week</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/coalition-andrew-hastie-tony-pasin-anika-wells-chris-bowen/105858494</link><description>If there was some internal call within the Liberals to show some discipline after the last few weeks, it worked at a basic level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98db697ba6641fa4f18bac1f61add805</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump to impose new 100 per cent tariffs on China after Beijing restricts rare earths</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/trump-new-china-massive-tariffs-threat/105880136</link><description>The US President takes to Truth Social to say he sees "no reason" to meet Xi Jinping after Beijing's "hostile" move to restrict rare-earth exports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c593e331aa58e6e28231bfbe40174ca6</guid></item><item><title>Memories from the rubble</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/verify-tracking-the-destruction-of-a-neighbourhood-in-gaza/105814932</link><description>When 25-year-old Nour imagines herself back home in Gaza City, she remembers the things that made her smile. Now that's all gone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef31548e58d9f19f9724991b39be12c6</guid></item><item><title>Older borrowers taking out later-in-life loans risk post-retirement mortgage pain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/housing-prices-older-borrowers-risk-mortgage-debt-in-retirement/105867244</link><description>Property analysts, brokers and banks report more borrowers are taking on big housing debts in their late 40s and 50s and, potentially, a retirement still saddled with mortgage repayments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cea624f58afd0c1f6bdfb886c7aaa758</guid></item><item><title>Japan's decorated trucks face 'extinction' but fans and truckies are trying to bring them back</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/japan-culture-of-dekotora-decorated-trucks-under-threat/105862672</link><description>The dekotora, large decorated trucks covered in colour and bright lights, were once a common sight across Japan. Now they are fighting for survival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eb195808234a2a8b67b318263d22ece</guid></item><item><title>Queensland plan to extend life of coal-fired power stations sends 'mixed messages'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/queensland-coal-fired-power-stations-energy-plan/105879574</link><description>Communities across Queensland have welcomed plans to keep coal and gas burning across the state, though some warn a lack of future planning could undermine short-term benefits.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa49ed8303cabfa57e2ba899e8da02ed</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump deserves credit for stopping the war on Gaza, but his key claim is overblown</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/donald-trump-gaza-ceasefire-plan-lyons-analysis/105880080</link><description>In the tragic arc of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, Donald Trump may have closed the latest — and most violent — chapter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35343a2a556ecc6c9cc2d961d8d4a821</guid></item><item><title>UN agencies still waiting for details on aid rollout for 'critical' relief as ceasefire takes effect — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/palestinian-families-return-to-ruins-ceasefire-takes-effect/105880190</link><description>Displaced for the past two years, Palestinians begin returning to their destroyed homes in Gaza as the Israel-Hamas war ceasefire takes effect. Look back at how the day unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50449524b9592c37aa0873df2d052902</guid></item><item><title>Queensland heating up with weekend thunderstorms forecast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/hot-conditions-and-thunderstorms-forecast-for-qld/105876568</link><description>The weather bureau says much of the state can expect above average temperatures with possibly severe thunderstorms in the south-east today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd2bd926a0f251fc64594556239145cf</guid></item><item><title>Chaotic weather outlook raises prospects of summer bushfires across eastern states</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/chaotic-australia-weather-outlook-a-forecasting-nightmare/105878032</link><description>An atmospheric "tug of war" for control of Australia's weather is taking place this spring, and it is a forecasting nightmare.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b71072a2e473fdafe1fcd7f320252c0</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians stream north and hostage families wait anxiously as Gaza ceasefire begins</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/palestinians-stream-north-as-gaza-ceasefire-begins/105874744</link><description>Thousands of Palestinians sheltering in southern Gaza rush to the north, hopeful the ceasefire will hold long enough for them to return home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b1a6a9142fe1ed3903c13142c480d8e</guid></item><item><title>Timor-Leste workers part of PALM scheme helping to fill NT workforce gaps</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/palm-scheme-workers-timor-leste-nt-workforce-shortages/105876688</link><description>The Northern Territory struggles to find workers for low- and semi-skilled jobs, but with increasing numbers of foreign workers arriving under the Pacific Australia Labour Mobility (PALM) scheme, that may be changing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2c6d5a6c01ae7f403bd6befbcc0d5bb</guid></item><item><title>Alameddine crime network suspected in murder of UFC fighter Suman Mokhtarian</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/gunned-down-sydney-ufc-fighter-suman-mokhtaria-alameddine-links/105879342</link><description>Police had intelligence that Sydney's Alameddine organised crime network wanted a former UFC fighter dead more than 18 months before his shooting murder this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f204ff3bc4b1ce27c00eca55cb4de20</guid></item><item><title>Alex de Minaur loses 6-4, 6-4 to Daniil Medvedev in Shanghai quarterfinals to miss out on career milestone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/de-minaur-bows-out-to-medvedev-in-shanghai/105880016</link><description>Alex de Minaur is eliminated from the Shanghai Masters, going down 6-4, 6-4 to former world number one Danil Medvedev in the quarterfinals, denying the 26-year-old Australian a chance of his 300th tour win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d00438342ad763a6953e65f8b5283119</guid></item><item><title>Rockbank man charged with murder over the death of woman at Epping</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/rockbank-man-charged-with-murder-after-womans-death-epping/105880244</link><description>A 50-year-old man faces court charged with murder after the death of a 44-year-old woman in Epping on Thursday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f854561e09dcbd87bdb467eff3f1f23</guid></item><item><title>Concord Hospital's Ebola practice run-through tests department's emergency response plans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/hazmat-ebola-emergency-practice-exercise-at-sydney-hospital/105877344</link><description>A high-stakes mission was undertaken at Concord Hospital this week — an exercise to test how multiple government agencies would react to any future infectious diseases outbreak.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae1003d959fd5041db58be9e5f30a1fe</guid></item><item><title>Fashion's misogyny problem might end up in your wardrobe</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/fashion-gender-equality-dior-chanel-misogyny/105858400</link><description>Men sit at the top of the world's fashion houses while women designers get torn apart online.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35cb2c216556832c5dcdb317d8f6718a</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous elder Alby Clarke remembered for ultramarathon and cycling feats</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/indigenous-elder-alby-clarke-endurance-athlete-remembered/105827808</link><description>An Indigenous elder well-known for his sporting achievements, including using long-distance running and cycling to advocate for Aboriginal reconciliation and health, is remembered by loved ones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">571dd2ed6d993a3e06e1bc1389cb6c92</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Fish Market to open doors on January 19 next year as old site enjoys its 'last hurrah' in lead-up to Christmas</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/new-sydney-fish-market-opening-january-next-year/105880252</link><description>Sydney Fish Market CEO Daniel Jarosch says the new development will be able to "open with a bang" on January 19 next year, even though construction at Blackwattle Bay is set to be completed in mid-November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54c5a9b8f2381f45c8f60f3575214ab2</guid></item><item><title>GFG Alliance accused of not meeting Tasmanian loan conditions over manganese ore supply</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/gfg-accused-of-failing-to-meet-loan-conditions/105879418</link><description>Australia's only manganese smelter is at the centre of a dispute, after failing to restart a troubled smelter in Tasmania's north despite being given a $20 million loan from the Tasmanian government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">caf8a13e8bda652ad5f5cb908b30f461</guid></item><item><title>Art courier Laurie Burgess grows his collection as he travels Australia delivering to galleries</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/laurie-burgess-art-courier-delivery-driver-collector/105878528</link><description>Laurie Burgess has dedicated two decades to transporting artwork across the country, and has developed an appreciation and knowledge of the Australian art world few could rival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3379fa8a63412be8885047e73fac3f8</guid></item><item><title>Hotel owner mocks Wollongong Council's palm tree art after renovation refusal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/illawarra-hotel-renovation-refusal-protest-mocks-palm-tree-art/105870512</link><description>A Wollongong hotel owner goes to unusual heights to mock a controversial piece of public art and protest against a council decision to knock back a development application.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b1031ea2e23cee5d58514f5c7757b2a</guid></item><item><title>Tennessee military munitions plant explosion leaves 19 people missing and feared dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/tennessee-blast-leaves-19-missing-at-munitions-plant/105880274</link><description>The explosion at Accurate Energetic Systems in rural Tennessee on Friday morning is heard from miles away and is described by local law enforcement as "one of the worst" tragedies the area has seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd7733098257e94b3ae5d1ffeab531e4</guid></item><item><title>Crispy pita bread, warm chickpeas and garlic yoghurt is an easy dinner - ABC News</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/fattet-hummus-crispy-pita-bread-warm-chickpeas-yoghurt-sauce/105774760</link><description>This popular vegetarian Lebanese dish with crispy pita bread, warm chickpeas and a garlicky tahini yoghurt sauce is ready in 30 minutes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5fb42664c5b17dc7aa90f429712af7f</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos beat 2026 FIFA World Cup co-hosts Canada 1-0 with Nestory Irankunda scoring only goal in Montreal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/socceroos-vs-canada-internatonal-friendly-live-blog/105880362</link><description>Nestory Irankunda's late strike has given the Socceroos a 1-0 victory over FIFA 2026 World Cup co-hosts Canada in in Montreal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beb7355019e2604569237fb868f651b4</guid></item><item><title>Soccer the name of the game in Borroloola, even reigning over Australian Rules Football</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/borroloola-strikers-remote-aboriginal-womens-soccer-team-revived/105874590</link><description>Aussie Rules football is life for many in remote NT Aboriginal communities but in Borroloola, barefoot young women and girls dream of following their hero into soccer's A-League.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbd37b3db762ecdab8799d372f09e535</guid></item><item><title>Drone video shows displaced Palestinians moving north following ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/drone-video-shows-displaced-palestinians-moving/105880384</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31830d36f949fc9ebc02ee6a4125e872</guid></item><item><title>Mount Burr Swamp thriving after rehabilitation from farmland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/mount-burr-swamp-revival-wetlands-conservation/105869900</link><description>The Mount Burr Swamp in South Australia is brimming with water, giving conservationists hope its success can be a blueprint for the future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e20e0fc5376bd3364f7296a6c0e9c3c</guid></item><item><title>Watchdog says Synergy not the only energy company overcharging amid $40m bungle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/synergy-billing-mistake-could-affect-other-companies/105879468</link><description>A $40 million overcharging bungle by WA's largest energy retailer was a result of serious governance failures and other businesses may have also fallen foul according to the state's economic watchdog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89094235c0602560ac4d9fb70e033767</guid></item><item><title>Machete brawl between groups spills into shopping centre in Melbourne's north</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/vic-broadmeadows-machete-brawl/105880438</link><description>Investigators say a brawl between two groups armed with machetes spilled into a shopping centre in Broadmeadows on Friday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5dab909acd080dba0340e61fed2aa5d</guid></item><item><title>Kimberley woman part of Seven Sisters project makes submission to UN in fight for justice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/irene-davey-seeks-justice-with-un-for-daughter-kimberley/105870006</link><description>It has been close to three decades since Irene Davey's daughter disappeared, now she is taking her case to the United Nations in an attempt to finally get justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">157d801424833657379f8a718b6fc70c</guid></item><item><title>Only four people in Australia have been diagnosed with rare genetic disease CHOPS</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/rare-genetic-disorder-chops-syndrome/105648828</link><description>Fourteen-year-old Isla Steed has unique challenges as one of just four people in Australia diagnosed with CHOPS syndrome.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eebec15926b1d18c6a3efe3b4cef5a61</guid></item><item><title>Sydney FC's Amelia Cassar likened to Matildas World Cup heroes ahead of A-League Women season</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/alw-sydney-fc-recruit-amelia-cassar-likened-to-matildas-stars/105880668</link><description>At 17, Amelia Cassar is likened to some of Australia's World Cup heroes, as she embarks on her first season with the Sky Blues in the A-League Women competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">520e9770ff315b1b3d2a8cbba1880f38</guid></item><item><title>Defunct NDIS provider given record $2.2 million penalty after Queensland man fatally hit by car</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/qld-ndis-penalty-two-million-death-participant-federal-court/105880582</link><description>Proceedings began against the now-defunct provider following the death of a Queensland participant in 2023. The penalty is the highest civil sanction imposed on an NDIS provider to date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6acb3225c56ca35a28372adb3d37a9f0</guid></item><item><title>National Rugby League award for Karratha Kangaroos named best community club</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/karratha-nrl-community-club-award/105620432</link><description>WA may traditionally be an AFL state but a club in the Pilbara has been named among the nation's best in another footy code.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b809a8c9f2b25b721e97ba288e56b42</guid></item><item><title>'Brilliant time capsule' of historical street images returns to Bendigo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/allan-doney-photographic-collection-returns-to-bendigo/105867172</link><description>A collection of photographs taken by an amateur photographer in a regional Victorian city in the 1950s, 60s and 70s has been returned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">827179a8b6679bc401bc821dbe6910f8</guid></item><item><title>Roaring jet boats to return to Victoria for first time in 15 years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/jet-boats-find-home-in-elmore-victoria/105865604</link><description>From tractors to jet boats at Elmore, as Victoria prepares to host Australian series jet boat event in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8bd1a38cda11cf4c394fc5acf0033196</guid></item><item><title>Israel announces list of Palestinian prisoners to be released, but one key name is absent</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/israel-announces-250-palestinian-prisoners-to-be-released/105880378</link><description>Israel's Ministry of Justice provides the names of prisoners it will release in exchange for Israeli hostages, but Hamas says no agreement has been reached.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">057adbbf0cd2e62eda8543f65fbc9bd0</guid></item><item><title>Trump allies at odds as US moves forward with Qatari military training facility 'on the sacred soil of America'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/us-qatar-military-training-facility-idaho/105880722</link><description>The US military is moving forward with plans to build a dedicated facility in Idaho to train pilots from Qatar. But not everyone is happy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">226b076a0d46540239264bdbf91a8727</guid></item><item><title>Genomic medicine could be huge but 5 million Australians may miss out</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/genomic-medicine-could-be-huge-but-5-million/105878606</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ed6e2fb9d4d9d0324e237a7c8b62bfe</guid></item><item><title>Genomic medicine researchers work to fix 'European bias' in DNA databases</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/diverse-communities-needed-for-national-dna-project/105865644</link><description>Researchers are trying to fix the "Western bias" contained in many DNA databases with a new national project targeting multicultural communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c6b641519f66ec459f59a401ceae20d</guid></item><item><title>North Melbourne closes in on remarkable winning record, Brisbane downs Port</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/aflw-crows-eagles-cats-giants-hawks-suns-lions-kangaroos-tigers/105881094</link><description>The Kangaroos extend their extraordinary AFLW winning streak with a 36-point thumping of the Tigers, while the Lions stay in touching distance of the league's top four with victory over Port.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c0d11a9c91e626275ddd1a919085b2e</guid></item><item><title>Hackers release Qantas customers' data on dark web</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-11/hackers-release-qantas-customers-data-on-dark-web/105881266</link><description>Hackers have released personal data from Qantas customers onto the dark web, following a cyber attack in July.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89f0546c7b3bb23647757cb38ea11506</guid></item><item><title>Former US President Joe Biden undergoing radiation therapy for cancer, spokesperson says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/joe-biden-radiation-therapy-for-cancer/105881476</link><description>The spokesperson added the radiation treatment is expected to continue for five weeks and is a new stage in his level of care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d799ae80234a2e4df342c09a033526e7</guid></item><item><title>Trump's frustration with Modi over Russia ties misses the memo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/india-united-states-russia-modi-trump-putin/105830580</link><description>Regardless of its historical defence ties to Russia, or its economic reliance on the United States, India is politically non-monogamous.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5ce563ddba7d51b1b5b81df3ce64d8e</guid></item><item><title>How did a mother and daughter at the centre of a suspected murder-suicide 'slip through the cracks'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/queensland-tiffany-wilkes-suspected-murder-suicide-clementine/105874684</link><description>The suspected murder-suicide of a mother and her daughter has raised serious questions about whether there were missed opportunities to intervene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">685fed94a266c8c69def78ef7fb17984</guid></item><item><title>A new supermarket has been invited to Australia. Here's what that might mean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/australia-supermarkets-uae-lulu/105862384</link><description>Last month, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese invited Emirati hypermarket chain LuLu Group to compete with Coles and Woolworths for market share. But some retail experts say entry into Australia's supermarket sector isn't so simple.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5530ab19189c8c30a7193932fff28eb</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government's BetStop scheme not working, former gambler says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/betstop-scheme-not-working-former-gambler-says/105878872</link><description>Diehard Richmond fan "Tiger Shaun" says he's watched on in horror as gambling advertising and sponsorships have come to dominate football — and become a constant reminder of the addiction he has struggled with.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6b9cac18f3f5518da8b3cd291770331</guid></item><item><title>Jared Kushner, Trump's son-in-law, was a key player in the Israel-Hamas peace deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/jared-kushner-a-key-player-in-the-israel-hamas-peace-deal/105876736</link><description>Jared Kushner was a familiar face sitting beside Israel’s PM as a first-phase peace agreement was finalised. According to senior US officials, it was because he was a key player in closing the deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47123b86788c992ca0ca1a3375c9a521</guid></item><item><title>What the EU's biometric border checks mean for travellers to Europe from October 12</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/european-union-new-biometric-checks-schengen-area/105868148</link><description>A new entry/exit system will require all non-European Union citizens to register their personal details, including fingerprints and facial images.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62facbca3ba3d4ef71cb10ac95f353ff</guid></item><item><title>Women express disappointment with some Chinese matchmaking platforms in Australia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/women-disappointed-with-some-chinese-matchmaking-platforms-/105844094</link><description>Chinese Australian women are paying thousands of dollars to find love on matchmaking platforms in Australia, but behind the glossy promotions lies a different reality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de33ea3b1474e557375d1f80e4808280</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump praised, Benjamin Netanyahu booed as Israelis rally in Tel Aviv — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/israel-gaza-ceasefire-live-updates/105881288</link><description>US special envoy to the Middle East Steve Witkoff — as well as Donald Trump's daughter Ivanka Trump and son-in-law Jared Kushner — attend a rally in Tel Aviv. Look back at how the day unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bbf8d824a9f9c8f75f8a6f2db0df0b9</guid></item><item><title>Platypus vanish from river where Charles Darwin pondered evolution</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/platypus-vanish-from-charles-darwin-evolution-river/105752248</link><description>Almost 190 years on, in the place where Charles Darwin first spotted a platypus, the egg-laying mammal seems to have disappeared.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c8747945cd98a902fc15be69eaa2b36</guid></item><item><title>Cost blowout fears cloud $3.2b Women's and Children's Hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/cost-blowout-fears-womens-and-childrens-hospital/105874396</link><description>The Malinauskas government has become well-versed in the language of cost blowouts, and the $3.2 billion Women's and Children's Hospital is another chance for it to flex its vocabulary.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9b04e9ea7523146654258bde9dae142</guid></item><item><title>In one of Australia's fastest-shrinking regions, towns are fighting to remain</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/yarriambiack-warracknabeal-victoria-town-population-shrink/105774946</link><description>In the Yarriambiack Shire, 350 kilometres from Melbourne in Victoria's rural north-west, virtually all of the towns are shrinking.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13fe880a8b293197899b32ff61524a1d</guid></item><item><title>Diane Keaton, star of Annie Hall, The Godfather films dies at 79</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/diane-keaton-dies/105881842</link><description>The unexpected news of Keaton's passing has been met with shock around the world, with stars remembering their time with the actor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">880393f1a8884001569183fb7e30b624</guid></item><item><title>Koori Formal an incentive for Mid North Coast students to finish high school</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/koori-formal-motivates-students-to-finish-high-school/105758224</link><description>The longest-running year 12 formal for First Nations people in New South Wales proves to be an incentive for students to complete their HSC.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5457a819c0978a19e0fdcb577672cd0d</guid></item><item><title>Buyers priced out of market and left in limbo claim developer is exploiting sunset clauses to cancel contracts</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/queensland-buyers-call-for-tighter-sunset-clause-legislation/105827656</link><description>Buyers who bought off-the-plan at a Gold Coast housing development years ago weren't just purchasing a home — they were purchasing a dream. Now, the developer is trying to cancel their contracts, but they don't want to accept that lying down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ff4603f3a806b4835203f98d8f982f6</guid></item><item><title>Brandon Starcevich 'good to go' after trade to West Coast despite concussion concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/starcevich-good-to-go-at-west-coast-concussion-concerns/105881284</link><description>West Coast recruit Brandon Starcevich says he has no concerns over his history of concussions after completing a trade to the Eagles from premier Brisbane.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5459b8a3b694e98ebc45576e5a61e82</guid></item><item><title>Nick Offerman from Parks and Recreation stars as sovereign citizen Jerry Kane in new movie Sovereign</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/nick-offerman-sovereign-citizen-jerry-kane-christian-swegal/105867130</link><description>In Sovereign, Nick Offerman stars as real-life radical-right sovereign citizen Jerry Kane, who, with his son, killed two cops in Arkansas in 2010, drawing parallels to Australian fugitive Dezi Freeman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f83d47504974cf5d7dcf916a63e8e8</guid></item><item><title>Benjamin Netanyahu booed as Steve Witkoff speaks ahead of return of hostages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/netanyahu-booed-steve-witkoff-gaza-israel-ceasefire/105881584</link><description>Thousands of Israelis have gathered in Hostages Square in Tel Aviv, where US envoy Steve Witkoff spoke to the crowd in anticipation of the release of the remaining hostages in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">834ca4b7e6bf4f98a9e0415e2b761690</guid></item><item><title>Alyssa Healy backs Australia's batters to fire against India despite stuttering start to World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/alyssa-healy-backs-australias-batters-to-fire-india-world-cup/105881892</link><description>Ahead of a crucial match against World Cup host India, Australia's captain Alyssa Healy says she has faith her side's top order can turn around its recent batting struggles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ca940a6ad8f7318299ae41819020fb6</guid></item><item><title>Israelis jeer Netanyahu during Witkoff's address at Tel Aviv rally</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/israelis-jeer-netanyahu-during-witkoffs-address-at/105881936</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a447aba502d7583ab15517014fb0c569</guid></item><item><title>West Coast Council's vehicle fleet left unregistered for a week after 'administrative error'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/west-coast-councils-fleet-of-vehicles-unregistered-for-week/105878164</link><description>Tasmania's West Coast Council has blamed an "administrative error" for a week-long lapse in the registration for its entire fleet of vehicles, compromising insurance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeef7d3ebe41a78cf42f59c21e055f69</guid></item><item><title>Gregory Porter on turning personal pain into powerful music</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/gregory-porter-interview-australia-mister-holland-no-love-dying/105866372</link><description>From the pain of racism to the joy of love, Gregory Porter's voice carries it all with power and purpose.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a61497653a2cd8967d2930635faab18</guid></item><item><title>Spring rains sow seeds of hope among Limestone Coast farmers after months of drought</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/south-east-emerges-from-drought-and-price-slump/105848144</link><description>After months of dust and dry skies, farmers on South Australia's Limestone Coast have welcomed early spring rain and a promising season ahead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2051346c282334589fac6a762170c40e</guid></item><item><title>Three teenagers charged after alleged stabbing of father and son in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/three-teenagers-charged-stabbing-melbourne-southbank/105881880</link><description>The men were allegedly attacked on the Yarra Promenade overnight. Police arrested five teenagers and have charged three of them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecfea06173ada53fdc54ddd5008d5a61</guid></item><item><title>Bathurst 1000 results: Matt Payne and Garth Tander win at Mount Panorama, Cooper Murray taken out late</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/live-updates-bathurst-1000-supercars/105865890</link><description>Matt Payne and Garth Tander have won a remarkable edition of the Bathurst 1000 featuring seven safety cars at a rain-soaked Mount Panorama.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6cf91c2a3824e89a05e10bdb9f643282</guid></item><item><title>Mango the muster cat draws attention to western Queensland's ongoing recovery</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/mango-the-muster-cat-draws-attention-to-western-qld-recovery/105783150</link><description>Raised alongside working dogs, Mango isn't your average feline and comes complete with his own Facebook page, loyal followers and fan mail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63b26a87a12960a7f43cb484f5d058c7</guid></item><item><title>The NT has changed the way it responds to domestic violence. Here's what that means.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/domestic-violence-response-nt-co-responder-model/105862072</link><description>The NT has Australia's highest rates of domestic and family violence, with an intimate partner homicide rate seven times the national average.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07816eca6f1c61f284cb6e5bd7fd185f</guid></item><item><title>Two arrested after Ian Watkins, disgraced former Lostprophets singer, killed in UK prison</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/two-arrested-ian-watkins-lostprophets-singer-killed-in-uk-prison/105882008</link><description>British police have arrested two men on suspicion of murder after Ian Watkins, the disgraced former Welsh rock band Lostprophets singer who was serving a 35-year jail sentence for child sex offences, was killed in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">223e07d6ac712b874d9d5ff2a114ff36</guid></item><item><title>Indigenous community Bidyadanga hosts From the Desert to the Seaside music festival</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/bidyadanga-music-festival-from-the-desert-to-the-seaside/105879698</link><description>From the Desert to the Seaside arts and music festival brings Western Australia's largest remote community of Bidyadanga together.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bd7b22727457c514f2c9772ca9393b8</guid></item><item><title>Roads in WA's East Pilbara need millions of dollars in repairs eight months after Cyclone Zelia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/road-cyclone-damage-repairs-pilbara/105857014</link><description>Australia's largest shire says it needs state and federal support to repair roads damaged during a cyclone, which provide a "lifeline" to remote communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d923148ba64c43bdcc00574fb481443</guid></item><item><title>Kelpies for Kids fundraiser at Perth Royal Show raises nearly $50k for sick children</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/kelpies-for-kids-runs-for-second-year-raising-money-for-children/105862942</link><description>A working dog auction at the Perth Royal Show raises nearly $50,000 for charity Telethon to support sick children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">181b1baf4cc31df1c53d52860f37c8fe</guid></item><item><title>From The Godfather to The First Wives Club — here are Diane Keaton's best films</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/diane-keaton-movies-woody-allen-where-to-watch/105882070</link><description>With a career beginning in the late 1970s, Diane Keaton would star in more than 100 films and earn several Oscar nods.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14d0a28df6e1de7e26d3c91ac4faf413</guid></item><item><title>Record beach patrols in South Australia this summer as life savers help battle algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/sa-life-savers-summer-beach-patrol-algal-bloom/105882102</link><description>A record number of beaches in SA are set to have Surf Life Saving patrols seven days a week this summer, as the state grapples with its toxic algal bloom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f070b8801a8bfee9819fde617335d087</guid></item><item><title>Tennessee military munitions plant explosion death toll reduced as community mourns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/tennessee-military-munitions-plant-explosion-death-toll-reduced/105882158</link><description>Authorities in the US say 16 people died in a massive explosion at a Tennessee munitions facility that has left a shocked community in mourning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c462b3a9d478f95023770bd769a2230</guid></item><item><title>Police search for man who disappeared during camping trip with wife in Victoria's east</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/vic-missing-camper-troy-milne-sale/105882390</link><description>Police are appealing to the public for help in locating a man who left to pick up supplies while camping with his wife in Gippsland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f4f698753fa2532b5dc1e4ddde87d54</guid></item><item><title>At least 41 dead in Mexico's Veracruz region after landslides, floods</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/dozens-dead-in-mexico-veracruz-after-landslides-floods/105882420</link><description>Authorities have attributed the deadly downpours to Tropical Storm Priscilla, formerly a hurricane, and Tropical Storm Raymond, both off the western coast of Mexico.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">849ea547c18416e2aa0d551a85bfe9f1</guid></item><item><title>Afghan Taliban forces attack Pakistani border posts as 'retaliation' for Kabul air strikes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/afghanistan-taliban-pakistan-border-fight-air-strike/105882450</link><description>Afghan Taliban forces say they have captured Pakistani border posts, while Pakistani security officials say their military is responding "with full force" to the attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d678035ddccbdb622c7446a6f1d07e9e</guid></item><item><title>China accuses US of 'double standards' over new tariffs threat</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/china-responds-to-us-tariff-threat/105882356</link><description>Donald Trump says he will impose extra levies in response to what he called "extraordinarily aggressive" new Chinese export curbs on rare-earth minerals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47e859acbd6ffddc89eb03d8b3a76cf1</guid></item><item><title>How long can you safely store and reheat leftovers?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/how-long-can-you-safely-store-leftover-food/105844878</link><description>Experts share their tips on how to best store cooked food to save money and avoid food waste.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce0d4f73a17f91c0b31eb05a75824b09</guid></item><item><title>Dockers stun Demons in 5-point AFLW upset, Swans snap losing streak, Saints down Magpies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/aflw-swans-blues-saints-magpies-demons-dockers/105882626</link><description>Fremantle keeps its faint AFLW finals hopes alive with a five-point nail-biter against Melbourne, Sydney arrests a massive form slump against Carlton, while St Kilda notches its fifth consecutive win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df3573f2cc285db9b9466558e3598502</guid></item><item><title>Why the Gaza ceasefire could collapse over coming days</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/why-the-gaza-ceasefire-deal-might-collapse/105880872</link><description>There is any number of ways the ceasefire could fall over — perhaps within days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e18514bb800ce6837a2e1588c9a2da4</guid></item><item><title>PM's XIII hammer Orchids 50-0 in Port Moresby</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/pms-xiii-orchids-png/105882744</link><description>In their annual clash, the Prime Minister's XIII outclass the Orchids 50-0 in Port Moresby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8613c3f1ac993b642b76ac402d167fb4</guid></item><item><title>Thousands join pro-Palestinian rallies in towns and cities across Australia amid ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/nsw-national-pro-palestinian-rallies-ceasefire-gaza-israel/105879264</link><description>The rallies in cities and towns dubbed the Nationwide Rally for Palestine come less than a week after the second anniversary of the October 7 terrorist attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b24458462cf08439745476381b92baf</guid></item><item><title>Australia could be left behind on renewables – 12 October 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/as-the-world-shifts-away-from-fossil-fuels,/105882858</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcdc037acd4e65b4d364c1b8b9c3d38d</guid></item><item><title>Record-breaking Melbourne Marathon Festival as 50,000 runners hit the road</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/record-breaking-numbers-for-melbourne-marathon-2025/105881966</link><description>Melbourne's Jack Rayner won the men's marathon for the second year in a row with a time of 2 hours, 15 minutes and 2 seconds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdcdedd29e83e0274fd3058187812027</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Diamonds defeat South Africa's Proteas 65-42 in third netball Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/netball-test-australia-diamonds-defeat-south-africa-proteas/105882776</link><description>Australia warms up for the eagerly anticipated Constellation Cup with a convincing 65-42 victory over South Africa in the third and final Test in Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f1ff5a0a480446ef675b46afe105c3f</guid></item><item><title>Ethan Strange stars as PM's XIII defeat Papua New Guinea 28-10</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/strange-stars-pms-xiii-down-png/105882870</link><description>Ethan Strange underlines his case for Kangaroos selection and Trai Fuller scores four tries in the Prime Minister's XIII 28-10 defeat of Papua New Guinea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eed2497e30235bd850a45f4d7782c62</guid></item><item><title>Bathurst 1000 quick hits: Chaz Mostert drinks beer with fans, Erebus owner protests, and drama on Mount Panorama</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/bathurst-1000-quick-hits-chaz-mostert-beer-erebus-trophy-protest/105882090</link><description>Wild weather and hard racing were combined with bold and colourful personalities to create a truly memorable day of Supercars racing. Here are the quick hits from the 2025 Bathurst 1000.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56dcf83a7f85000c36d8a88c92eb8787</guid></item><item><title>Australia beats India by three wickets in Women's World Cup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/australia-beats-india-by-three-wickets-in-womens-world-cup/105882054</link><description>Skipper Alyssa Healy scores a super ton and Ellyse Perry sees Australia home in a world-record women's ODI chase to beat India by three wickets in a World Cup thriller.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">793b5b7cd7bd870847524ccb5b3a51ca</guid></item><item><title>Government holds firm on not negotiating with hackers in wake of Qantas breach</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/government-will-not-negotiate-with-hackers-after-qantas-breach/105882936</link><description>The federal government is sticking to its position of not negotiating with cyber criminals, despite hackers releasing personal data from millions of Qantas customers onto the dark web and threatening to target Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5f206d6dfa9993e776c0fc59eca158a</guid></item><item><title>Vacherot becomes lowest-ranked ATP Masters winner after defeating his cousin Rinderknech in Shanghai</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-12/valentin-vacherot-wins-shanghai-masters-atp-tournament/105883038</link><description>He beat his cousin Arthur Rinderknech 4-6, 6-3, 6-3 on Sunday local time to claim the first title of his career after a stunning run from the qualifying rounds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb81965abf5ff6abbfd51d7bc8b541f5</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump accused of profiting from presidency as crypto ventures rake in hundreds of millions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/trump-president-wealth-family-business-crypto-four-corners/105876782</link><description>Donald Trump's wealth has skyrocketed since his return to the White House nine months ago, leading to accusations that he is profiting from the presidency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a085f22828b5fca9aac9493ad39f159</guid></item><item><title>Australians join race for fusion energy as AI pressure on electricity sector starts to bite</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/the-australians-in-the-race-for-fusion-energy/105882230</link><description>The two great technology revolutions of the modern era — artificial intelligence and renewable energy — are colliding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e55bc7ba701556faca8e00198d03be1</guid></item><item><title>Western Sydney University consultants paid almost $3k a day, leaked documents show, as redundancies loom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/western-sydney-university-consultants-paid-thousands-a-day/105873714</link><description>As Western Sydney University prepares to shed hundreds of staff due to its dire finances, leaked documents reveal it is paying consultants as much as $2,850 a day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b53eac6b9f8be6dc73b9a78e468e290</guid></item><item><title>Russia expresses 'extreme concern' over US providing Tomahawk missiles to Ukraine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/russia-expresses-extreme-concern-over-us-tomahawk-missiles/105883082</link><description>Kyiv and the US are openly floating the idea of providing Ukraine with long-range Tomahawk missiles, in a move Russia says would mark "a very dramatic moment".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3276f5d539ed6330fde6aaa1c0c8618</guid></item><item><title>Pakistani military vision shows attacks on Taliban positions</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/pakistani-military-vision-shows-attacks-on-taliban/105883528</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">726a672e1e8b8ad11b1da9d968fd8aaa</guid></item><item><title>Pakistani military vision shows aerial views of strikes on Taliban targets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/pakistani-military-vision-shows-aerial-views-of-strikes/105883548</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83e8a655e215d9482663c08560a1293f</guid></item><item><title>Uber drivers refusing rides due to guide dog, handler says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/guide-dog-handlers-call-for-harsher-penalties-for-uber-refusals/105754360</link><description>Sarah Maculans says she was refused rides by four Uber drivers within a week due to her guide dog, Sunny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4767c5abe70ec191abca333f88092f6b</guid></item><item><title>Israel 'ready to receive all of our hostages' from Gaza, Netanyahu's office says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/gaza-hostages-to-be-released/105883378</link><description>The final 20 living Israeli hostages in Gaza are set to be released by Hamas in a matter of hours, with preparations by Israeli defence and medical authorities to receive the captives after more than two years hidden away from the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b9a5eb8243f6852bb6c4f770512b950</guid></item><item><title>Aid convoys enter Gaza during Israel-Hamas ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/aid-convoys-enter-gaza-during-israel-hamas-ceasefire/105883574</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a492d678557b656caaa8a144bed4d723</guid></item><item><title>Koala killed by a car on Appin Road after being hailed a conservation success story</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/appin-road-in-sydney-claims-life-rescued-koala-gage/105879322</link><description>Koala deaths on Appin Road are not unusual this time of year, but the fatality of rescued koala Gage is cause for more than the usual frustration and despair.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a01be949d5b85d86fa6ff42ba3ea7c6d</guid></item><item><title>Former tennis star Jelena Dokic grapples with complex grief after abusive father Damir's death</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/jelenadokic-says-abusive-dad-showed-no-remorse/105849988</link><description>Jelena Dokic was abused by her father for years, with no tennis success enough to stop the beatings. She reveals the complex grief of losing a parent who showed no remorse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69cd6af49b40951598418e7e78d42249</guid></item><item><title>Gaza updates live: Donald Trump to visit Tel Aviv as hostage releases expected</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/israel-gaza-hamas-ceasefire-live-updates/105882948</link><description>Israel says it expects the release of hostages will begin in the coming hours, as a ceasefire with Hamas continues to hold in Gaza. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be02b702b81f90b4f983344fa10ab6ad</guid></item><item><title>NSW planning overhaul removes corruption and environment safeguards, legal experts say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/enviornment-and-corruption-concerns-raised-over-planning-laws/105875992</link><description>There are growing fears that a major overhaul of planning laws promoted to fast-track housing development will bypass environmental protections and remove safeguards against corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6548805197d576b0fdf65ffd6faae9c</guid></item><item><title>Sunset clause laws differ around the country. Here's what they are and when they can be used</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/sunset-clause-laws-explainer-states-and-territories/105869886</link><description>Stories about developers enacting sunset clauses and leaving would-be buyers priced out of the market are nothing new. Here's what's being done to tighten those rules.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94aaf4ee2af725dbe108763035c3096d</guid></item><item><title>Wetland ecosystem welcomed at Tasmanian sheep farm after 20-year restoration effort</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/tasmania-saltmarsh-wetland-restoration-on-merino-sheep-farm/105883488</link><description>A sheep farmer has welcomed the restoration of an internationally significant wetland on his property outside of Hobart. The collaboration of a non-profit organisation with landowners, scientists, the Aboriginal community and governments has allowed the return of a vital ecosystem.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1e6acb760d399a693f75e216ea48417</guid></item><item><title>Federal politics live: Labor's super tax changes will raise less revenue: Chalmers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/federal-politics-live-blog-oct-13/105877648</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers announces major changes to the government's superannuation taxation proposal. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22eb92a4486e0d8d964006fe84a55693</guid></item><item><title>Social media ban will further isolate regional and rural youth, LGBTIQA+ advocates say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/social-media-ban-will-isolate-regional-queer-teens-more/105829530</link><description>LGBTIQA+ advocates are concerned the social media ban will have a significant impact on queer youth in regional and remote areas of Australia. They say there are not enough offline, physical supports for these teens to access when the ban comes into effect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0cbc396370d50cfb8a5287d529e393b7</guid></item><item><title>Markets live updates: ASX slips after Wall St tumbles on renewed trade war fears, Treasury Wine Estates tumbles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/asx-markets-business-news-live-updates/105883026</link><description>Local investors react calmly to Wall Street's hair-on-fire session on Friday. Follow the day's events and insights from our business reporters on the ABC News live markets blog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc3926b7bdeb6ef03007675c20ec8918</guid></item><item><title>Rebecca, the haunting story adapted into a Hitchcock classic, is now a gripping psychological stage play</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/rebecca-melbourne-theatre-company-hitchcock/105863212</link><description>First dismissed as "Gothic romance" when it was published by Daphne du Maurier in 1938, the haunting tale has evolved into a modern thriller about the expectations placed on women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1669144caa73fcb084b2ee6660bce19d</guid></item><item><title>Isolated storms forecast for Queensland after weekend hail storm</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/isolated-storms-forecast-for-queensland-this-week/105882378</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology is also predicting a return to regular spring temperatures after a spell of warmer days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78ba8aa6dcb095d740cbead406d25d9e</guid></item><item><title>Michael Pratt, George Cross recipient and former Victorian police officer, dies</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/michael-pratt-victorian-police-officer-george-cross-recipient/105883558</link><description>Former Victoria Police officer Michael Pratt has been remembered for his bravery when he confronted three armed bank robbers in Melbourne in 1978.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">387d0a1122baa4ab5a5052fc5f8da703</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar's President Andry Rajoelina says student protesters are attempting a coup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/madagascar-president-claims-coup-attempt-underway/105883466</link><description>Troops from an elite unit of the country's military are urging fellow soldiers to disobey orders and back student protesters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f041025445012537603be910fd6490a</guid></item><item><title>WA lawyers write to attorney-general calling for in-person court hearings to return to remote Balgo</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/kimberley-based-lawyers-struggling-to-support-balgo-residents/105866646</link><description>With in-person court hearings suspended and video links cancelled, lawyers are struggling to ensure access to justice for the remote community of Balgo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08e509522e73a26e49192e99129f2347</guid></item><item><title>'We are going to have a good time': Trump heads to Middle East</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/we-are-going-to-have-a-good-time-trump-heads-to-mid-east/105883718</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">274f7712adfab2b0d1b7c51ba07665d6</guid></item><item><title>Nick Offerman from Parks and Recreation stars in new movie about sovereign citizen</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/nick-offerman-from-parks-and-recreation-as-sovereign/105883712</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fdbce41047ee2b8b481df4bcbfb1fb6</guid></item><item><title>Climate Integrity says 'distorted research' behind government policy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/climate-integrity-accc-to-investigate-gas-lobby-ey-modelling/105866988</link><description>Advocacy group Climate Integrity has accused the gas industry of using "distorted research", produced by the accounting firm EY, to influence the Australian government's Future Gas Strategy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28322136f22de6e61de34a7e4e872c4b</guid></item><item><title>Brad Pettitt questions WA Labor's commitment to increasing Perth's tree canopy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/brad-pettitt-questions-wa-labors-commitment-to/105879012</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74296c695f705429cfd19d9d6685f4d5</guid></item><item><title>Fresh doubts over WA Labor election commitments to boost Perth’s tree canopy</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/wa-tree-canopy-election-promise-walked-back/105865416</link><description>The WA government is facing renewed questions over its plans to boost Perth's tree cover, with experts saying current funding will not come close to delivering on Labor's election promises.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">755ddb616df68a32d5fd28309f6717e9</guid></item><item><title>AFL trade period, day six live updates: Zach Merrett, Charlie Curnow and Christian Petracca remain in limbo seeking moves</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/afl-trade-period-day-six-live-updates-merrett-curnow-petracca/105883736</link><description>Zach Merrett is one of a number of former All-Australians currently in limbo as West Coast continues to wheel and deal after another wooden spoon. Follow live as the AFL trade period kicks into its second week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b30b12b2a3a7724532b5ba22d8a1df3b</guid></item><item><title>Mount Magnet Shire councillor Ian Black suspended after no apology for defamatory notice</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/mount-magnet-shire-deputy-suspended-after-defamatory-notice/105880958</link><description>Mount Magnet Shire deputy president Ian Black is suspended after failing to apologise for posting a defamatory notice about staff to a public noticeboard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56ad1f0b0ee68c823f21a856debc307a</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Minjee Lee finishes third at LPGA Shanghai, behind winner Jeeno Thitikul</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/minjee-lee-finishes-third-in-epic-lpga-shanghai/105883722</link><description>Thai world number one Jeeno Thitikul wins the LPGA Shanghai tournament on the fifth play-off hole, with Australian superstar Minjee Lee settling for third.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98cfc762883593126e34eacce9a9c23f</guid></item><item><title>Judy Dent recalls how her husband became the first person to die through legally accessible voluntary assisted dying.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/judy-dent-recalls-how-her-husband-became-the-first/105868394</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91d55f7f4a73d7d9a89ec19cf0f58fc2</guid></item><item><title>Committee formally recommends NT government adopt voluntary assisted dying</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/nt-government-voluntary-assisted-dying-report-recommendation/105515296</link><description>On the verandah of their Darwin home, Judy Dent held her husband's hand as he became the first person in the world to die through legally accessible voluntary assisted dying. That world-first would not be possible in the Northern Territory today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3da225f565d839bdf449bf4b26951d4</guid></item><item><title>Lidia Thorpe threatens to 'burn down Parliament House' over Palestine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/lidia-thorpe-threatens-to-burn-down-parliament/105884070</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99f363be50ece9b52ed6fd4c4972f332</guid></item><item><title>Rabin Medical Center deputy director explains recovery plan for returned Israeli hostages</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/rabin-medical-center-deputy-director-explains-rehab-plan/105884082</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c23d37454033682278e6815373b4e440</guid></item><item><title>Tony Burke says to remain vigilant of scams after Qantas data leaks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/tony-burke-says-to-remain-vigilant-of-scams-after/105884134</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c7ba861c300741d21c3dbd2cb425fed</guid></item><item><title>Australian cricket captain Pat Cummins says he is 'probably unlikely' to play in first Ashes Test</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/pat-cummins-unlikely-to-play-first-ashes-test/105883832</link><description>Pat Cummins all but rules himself out of the first Ashes Test, saying he is still a way short of completing his condensed recovery schedule from a back injury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b1d8292aabc1b91a7c4ac0cc55cdb3a</guid></item><item><title>Diane Keaton's death shocked many. US media says family kept her sudden decline private</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/diane-keaton-cause-of-death-private-health-decline/105883902</link><description>The actor's cause of death has not been made public, but with US media reporting her family chose to keep her health decline private.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b575d070be7336c702ea5c37aec3f74</guid></item><item><title>Hawthorn man chases and detains teenager after alleged break-in at his home</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/melbourne-owner-detains-alleged-youth-offender-in-hawthorn/105883852</link><description>Grant Brown chased down a teenager after he disturbed two people who had allegedly broken into his home in the early hours of Monday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c91bf8e690c34125a68ae393aeb4c319</guid></item><item><title>Fox Resources collapses, but fight against coal exploration in Bundaberg food bowl continues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/fox-resources-collapse-bundaberg-coal-mine-exploration/105884008</link><description>Exploration company Fox Resources has gone into administration, but the community that successfully fought off its mining advances vows to keep fighting to cancel the tenement altogether.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bfdc45a674d8408b12424221c8e22b2</guid></item><item><title>World's biggest light installation to illuminate landscapes of Albany, WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/biggest-light-installation-ever-on-earth-planned-for-albany/105866412</link><description>A light installation, projected onto King George Sound in Albany, will be the largest ever created.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0c3fad2d619ba1d36ef0034dc9d4ec0</guid></item><item><title>Israeli settlers say Gaza peace plan prevents them claiming more land</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/israeli-settlers-say-gaza-peace-plan-prevents-them/105884648</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c37746503a45664a601b407260d84511</guid></item><item><title>Treasurer announces rework of stalled superannuation tax increase plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/treasurer-announces-rework-of-stalled-super-tax-increase/105884568</link><description>Treasurer Jim Chalmers announces the federal government's stalled superannuation tax increases will be reworked after criticism over the plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6423e004d64ee9090f2694aa27bcd949</guid></item><item><title>Travel and dining vouchers on offer in SA's algal bloom summer plan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/summer-algal-vouchers-south-australia/105883636</link><description>Some travellers to South Australia's coast over summer will be able to access $500 accommodation vouchers and $50 cashback on their meal, under a state and federal government plan to stimulate tourism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c47d767109a71d2102d3268c1f6df24</guid></item><item><title>Video games could fall under the social media ban, researchers say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/video-games-could-fall-under-social-media-ban-researchers-say/105859842</link><description>Online video games are excluded from the social media ban, but digital media researchers say the definitions are too broadly defined and games could yet be included.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b0b6fa140b851f58a53917e93936fe0</guid></item><item><title>Eugowra flood inquest told official information was not accurate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-13/eugowra-inquest-day-one/105876674</link><description>A coronial inquest is told residents and emergency responders got inaccurate information from the Bureau of Meteorology (BOM) and Water NSW during a devastating flood that claimed two lives in the NSW town of Eugowra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc07e6547d3e61d1a0eaa5688225170b</guid></item></channel></rss>