<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>ABC News (EN) – Aggregated (Unofficial)</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:41:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>David Fifita reunites with Wayne Bennett at South Sydney Rabbitohs, ending five-season stint at Gold Coast Titans</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/nrl-david-fifita-joins-rabbitohs-ending-titans-stint/105948768</link><description>After flirting with exits from the Titans previously, David Fifita makes his move official, joining the South Sydney Rabbitohs on a deal for the next two seasons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a7d6650f1f2a868e723add1b427db9d</guid></item><item><title>How Hurricane Melissa was supercharged by hot oceans in the Caribbean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/hurricane-melissa-was-supercharged-by-hot-oceans/105946230</link><description>Dubbed the "storm of the century", Hurricane Melissa shook off three different meteorological conditions that normally weaken major hurricanes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0be7639dda91b9aa88872f21575294c1</guid></item><item><title>Wednesday finance with Alan Kohler</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/wednesday-finance-with-alan-kohler/105948206</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77695cc8d65bb365fa7b869adade0363</guid></item><item><title>Former Australian Signals Directorate employee accused of selling trade secrets to Russia by US prosecutors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/australian-signals-directorate-former-employee-secrets-russia/105949188</link><description>The man, who has been accused by the US of selling secrets to Russia, worked for the Australian Signals Directorate, the national agency responsible for cyber security and foreign signals intelligence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa60984ad968f8494e3e130f5b313a45</guid></item><item><title>Rain washes out first Australia—India men's T20I at Canberra's Manuka Oval</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/cricket-australia-india-first-t20i-canberra-live-scorecentre/105949000</link><description>India is left frustrated after rain washed out the men's T20I series opener against Australia at a cold and dreary Manuka Oval.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21323d085fb72579fd9f7b6b8a5b09f9</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese joins Donald Trump and other leaders for dinner on sidelines of APEC summit</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-29/albanese-meets-with-trump-at-apec-dinner/105949774</link><description>A select group of world leaders have dined with United States President Donald Trump in South Korea, including Prime Minister Anthony Albanese.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efdc12f379ed13df79f2a28b06ca8a00</guid></item><item><title>Australian Diamonds defeat Silver Ferns to claim Constellation Cup in extra-time thriller</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/aus-diamonds-beat-nz-ferns-to-win-constellation-cup/105949798</link><description>The Diamonds's trophy cabinet is again complete after they snapped their New Zealand drought against the Silver Ferns in a thrilling extra-time period to bring the Constellation Cup back to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e030d85adf16bc107d198d4e1697ace</guid></item><item><title>WOMADelaide 2026 first line-up announced: full list of artists and dates</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/womadelaide-line-up-2026-adelaide-yothu-yindi-obongjayar/105948966</link><description>Icons, innovators, and unexpected gems — WOMADelaide's 2026 line-up promises a truly unique festival experience.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff56c4c896b7b48ed13f3bfd64f374de</guid></item><item><title>Russia bombs Ukrainian children's hospital as Vance says war will end 'eventually'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/russia-bombs-children-s-hospital/105949914</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy says the attack shows that Russia is the "largest terrorist organisation in the world".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">991e1803324353746dc617a35b5098b9</guid></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa devastates Caribbean countries and leaves dozens dead</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/hurricane-melissa-devastates-caribbean-countries-kills-dozens/105949964</link><description>Hurricane Melissa, one of the strongest Atlantic hurricanes on record with top winds of 295 kilometres per hour, has left dozens dead across the Caribbean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07a5dc8ab4fae72d8a52841732e0f4ca</guid></item><item><title>Labor is frustrated with Rio Tinto as 'all options' on table for Tomago smelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/tomago-bailout-energy-transition-rio-tinto-labor/105943642</link><description>The government can't hide its frustration with Rio Tinto, but at the same time it's preparing to dip deeper into taxpayers' pockets to help the company out. Again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">045601015e805e925a78c9dee0ff8612</guid></item><item><title>Older people risk losing some at-home services despite 'no worse off' promise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/older-people-risk-losing-some-at-home-services/105949520</link><description>With major changes to the aged care system looming this week, price hikes for older people accessing support at home could mean their aged care packages will not stretch as far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73c0d2c33907338c341e2384ff530429</guid></item><item><title>Sunscreen maker at centre of recalls blocked by US regulator for years</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/sunscreen-maker-wild-child-laboratories-on-us-fda-red-list/105949030</link><description>The Australian sunscreen manufacturer at the centre of a spate of recent product recalls has been blocked from exporting sunscreens to the United States for the past three years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">def1ebde8611ed41ea01abbbe39712ba</guid></item><item><title>Bendigo mother helps others survive postnatal mental health struggle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/parent-infant-units-for-postnatal-mental-health-struggle/105926618</link><description>After battling suicidal thoughts as a new mother, Monique Aulich now supports others going through the same pain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a159b06dc3069d62a4ecf9f562ecb57</guid></item><item><title>Regulator fines crypto ATM operator Cryptolink as part of crackdown that is too late for many</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/austrac-fines-crypto-atm-operator-cryptolink-in-scams-crackdown/105941804</link><description>A pensioner tells her nightmarish story as the financial crimes regulator takes action against a second Australian player in the booming crypto ATM business linked to lucrative scams and money laundering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e5d3bc08158f8c004f282f4567763ee</guid></item><item><title>Australian man Peter Williams faces lengthy US jail term after selling trade secrets to Russian broker</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/peter-williams-faces-us-jail-time-after-selling-trade-secrets/105945752</link><description>Intelligence insider Peter Williams faces more than a decade in a US jail after pleading guilty to selling a Russian broker his employer's trade secrets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45188245cc7c837f9eea8610a739e43b</guid></item><item><title>Anna Creek Station owners charged for alleged illegal dams</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/sa-anna-creek-station-illegal-dams-charge/105947060</link><description>The owners of Anna Creek Station, the biggest cattle station in the world, have been charged over allegedly building illegal dams on inland rivers and waterholes in outback South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7e3896460e3a2c36fe26247a6c0e393</guid></item><item><title>Gold Coast considers $1.6 billion waste-to-energy plan to deal with its rubbish</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/waste-to-energy-plan-gold-coast-landfill-solution/105869872</link><description>Gold Coast residents could soon be charged 300 per cent more for their waste as landfill runs low. The council is betting on waste-to-energy as part of the solution, but the technology comes with caveats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aacd6eba565001c74980a22918954a07</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane teen wins world triathlon title in honour of terminally ill father</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/sam-fothergill-wins-world-triathlon-for-father-with-cancer/105941324</link><description>Nineteen-year-old Sam Fothergill is now racing against time to qualify for the professional circuit and honour his father through the sport they both love.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4af5c62dc34d1bfdf890bd648c7085f8</guid></item><item><title>South Africa dominates England to reach Women's World Cup final</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/cricket-world-cup-south-africa-defeats-england-semifinal/105950104</link><description>As Australia prepares to play India in the second semifinal, South Africa books its berth in the tournament decider following a commanding performance against England.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcffb0a1975e8044812f4ae9c5bae573</guid></item><item><title>As Donald Trump and Xi Jinping prepare for trade talks, China comes with a strong hand</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/donald-trump-and-xi-jinping-prepare-for-us-china-trade-talks/105943374</link><description>The meeting with US President Donald Trump and his Chinese counterpart Xi Jinping is one of the most highly anticipated bilaterals of the year, as the leaders seek to strike a deal while also saving face.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1da64d4411874afdc06c285ee726a65</guid></item><item><title>Major bank economists rule out November RBA interest rate cut, future moves in doubt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/big-four-banks-expect-no-cash-rate-cut-in-november/105948378</link><description>A shock from the all-important consumer price index has left economists rewriting their rates outlooks, ahead of the Reserve Bank meeting next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63a93d856688653f9869f88b819d3192</guid></item><item><title>If Kamala Harris wants a second run at the White House she has to move past her Joe Biden issues</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/kamala-harris-joe-biden-issues-behind-her-for-white-house/105947760</link><description>Richard Nixon did what Kamala Harris wants to. But for her to get to the White House, she is going to have to make tough decisions she has failed to in the past.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4ae9a728d643eef3f3ddd8192b02bfd</guid></item><item><title>Chaotic end to Senate QT as Labor responds to opposition, crossbench revolt — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/federal-politics-live-blog-oct-30/105949134</link><description>Senate Question Time ends in chaos as the government responds to an opposition and crossbench move to add more questions to the parliamentary session.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0980da633fc9dfebdc9d26de25fe9c50</guid></item><item><title>Site of $20 million Sydney council car park awarded to Indigenous aged care provider</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/sydney-car-park-earmarked-for-aged-care-centre-indigenous-elders/105938836</link><description>City of Sydney Council has awarded a car park site in Redfern worth $20 million to Wyanga Aboriginal Aged Care for the nominal fee of $1.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd9e9d5fc3255bd6b6b642e7782d4181</guid></item><item><title>Australian number one Maya Joint reaches Hong Kong Open quarterfinals</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/wta-tour-maya-joint-reaches-hong-kong-open-quarterfinals/105950220</link><description>Teenager Maya Joint is thriving in her new position as Australia's top-ranked women's tennis player, reaching the last eight at the Hong Kong Open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd9177a4e941aca8f954719e7a722cbd</guid></item><item><title>Two Phar Lap musicals open in Australia, on eve of the famous racehorse's 100th birthday</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/phar-lap-the-electro-swing-musical-wonder-horse-life-afterlife/105922314</link><description>As the 2025 Melbourne Cup approaches, two musicals celebrating — and satirising — the life of Phar Lap premiere, with "Australia's greatest racehorse" brought to life with an actor and a puppeteer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45b01794f67020d3fb5462fd79c4621f</guid></item><item><title>After 30 years, residents of Wadeye may soon be able to meet up for a beer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/wadeye-social-club-dry-community-remote-nt-alcohol/105949614</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cc178161cb7f93e3ccf6142417bac8c</guid></item><item><title>Remote NT community of Wadeye to reintroduce liquor sales after 30 years as dry community</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/nt-wadeye-alcohol-sales-social-club-returns-dry-community/105943922</link><description>Decades after Wadeye's last licensed social club was smashed to pieces amid a storm of controversy, locals will soon be able to have an after-work drink again.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a1f224324aefe2fbdcd3958bc23d3b9</guid></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa leaves a trail of destruction across the Caribbean</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/hurricane-melissa-carves-trail-of-destruction-across-caribbean/105950138</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c990908fbf27485f85b3f401fff38077</guid></item><item><title>Young cricketer Ben Austin dies in hospital after being struck by ball in practice nets</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/teenage-melbourne-cricketer-dies-after-being-struck-by-ball/105950250</link><description>The family of Ben Austin, who died after being struck by a ball during cricket practice in Melbourne earlier this week, issues a statement mourning the 17-year-old and saying their thoughts are with the teammate involved in the incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07ce50a8d31f60b20d78dca51c5dc506</guid></item><item><title>Australia waiting on Alyssa Healy's Women's World Cup fitness call ahead of semifinal against India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/cricket-world-cup-australia-vs-india-alyssa-healy/105950298</link><description>Australia is leaving India guessing over whether Alyssa Healy will be passed fit to lead the defending champions in their Women's World Cup semifinal in Navi Mumbai.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a3572f686ad8d284ee8b45b33fb53c4</guid></item><item><title>A mystery illness is threatening endangered ringtail possums.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/ringtail-possum-illness-identified-/105949538</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24ae211ea8a06cd12f9af4ac82194533</guid></item><item><title>Mystery illness leaves endangered ringtail possums blind and paralysed in South West WA</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/mystery-possum-virus/105939450</link><description>A mystery disease is leaving critically endangered western ringtail possums blind and paralysed, with carers concerned that things will only get worse in summer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb90573bda037fd815e363265211a2ef</guid></item><item><title>Acacia system returning to Royal Darwin Hospital emergency department despite concerns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/nt-acacia-health-patient-record-system-rdh-return-staff-concerns/105948200</link><description>The Acacia system was switched off at Royal Darwin Hospital's emergency department in January 2024 after it became a threat to patient safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ce9fbe8dc385f95d2cc991b8806ee1a</guid></item><item><title>Microsoft deploys fix for Azure cloud service after outage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/microsoft-deploys-fix-for-azure-cloud-service-after-outage/105950166</link><description>Microsoft says it is rolling out a fix to address an outage of its Azure cloud portal which left users unable to access Office 365, Minecraft and other services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b6ef90449a1627c91c8050eba437ba0</guid></item><item><title>Redland Bay aged care employee charged after allegedly stealing debit card from 104yo man</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/qld-woman-charged-aged-care-facility-stealing/105950332</link><description>Detectives started investigating after another employee at the aged care facility made a report on behalf of the 104-year-old.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c40b6a57176c92620d93547154e0e1ca</guid></item><item><title>NSW animal shelter under pressure over number of abandoned Rottweilers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/abandoned-rottweilers-put-pressure-on-nsw-animal-shelters/105911124</link><description>An animal shelter specialising in large dogs works overtime to care for the number of Rottweilers being abandoned and surrendered in Australia, amid rising costs and funding shortages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7614663587797f84d3d6fd21285bcdfe</guid></item><item><title>A select group of world leaders join Donald Trump for dinner on the sidelines of the APEC summit.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/exclusive-leaders-dinner-in-honour-of-trump-ahead/105950392</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cff24ad9a567cb1ec2216b68460535b3</guid></item><item><title>AFL players Dion Prestia and Steven May charged over alleged involvement in brawl</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/afl-dion-prestia-steven-may-charged-by-police/105950486</link><description>Dion Prestia and Steven May are charged by police over their alleged involvement in a brawl in a Victorian coastal town last December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06903ee7911f6c653295b1af3a2708e6</guid></item><item><title>Government refuses to release translation of public interview about opaque Nauru deal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/foi-denied-translation-interview-adeang-nauru-deal/105941610</link><description>The federal government has refused to release a translation of an interview with Nauruan president David Adeang concerning a deal with Australia to deport hundreds of people, despite the Nauruan government publishing the video on Facebook.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f30fb61f5457fd2544f109d4ea0ed029</guid></item><item><title>Drake appeals defamation loss over Kendrick Lamar's Not Like Us</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/drake-appeals-defamation-loss-over-kendrick-lamar-not-like-us/105950556</link><description>Superstar rapper Drake is appealing the dismissal of his defamation lawsuit against Universal Music Group over the Kendrick Lamar diss track Not Like Us.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">632b9a8a65e7b85cf15965237f4d7828</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane bus driver handed suspended sentence over CBD crash that killed Tia Cameron</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/qld-brisbane-cbd-bus-driver-verdict-tia-cameron/105950410</link><description>A Brisbane bus driver charged over a crash that killed a teenager in the CBD has been found guilty of driving without due care causing death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">434c483633187b943901fb24e74f8cfe</guid></item><item><title>Senators claim Labor is threatening punishment after chamber stunt on transparency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/labor-punishment-threat-transparency-senate-jobs-for-mates/105950660</link><description>The Senate has erupted after a stunt yesterday where the Coaliton, Greens and crossbench teamed up to pressure the government to release a secret report — with claims Labor is vowing retribution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d1b410927815cbaa8eca1f82900ccda</guid></item><item><title>Israel's strikes inside Gaza highlight a complicated truth about the ceasefire</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/gaza-ceasefire-technically-holding-despite-israeli-strikes/105950142</link><description>Despite more than 100 Palestinians being killed by Israel in little more than 12 hours, the ceasefire continues to hold, though that technicality does not mean much to those on the ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d11ab87689e4d9611aa5c950c8fbfe91</guid></item><item><title>Caravan street parking solution stifled by council red tape, storage owners say</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/councils-may-hold-key-to-caravan-street-parking-solution/105943790</link><description>A Queensland council struggling to solve a caravan street parking crisis is hampered by its own planning laws, a storage business says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c7d53cb5cb69021542c53ecf6bb5c3ef</guid></item><item><title>Mudgee's Lowe Wines becomes Australia's largest winery to go off grid</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/mudgee-off-electricity-grid-winery-lowe-wines/105941576</link><description>Going off the electricity grid has been transformative for Mudgee's Lowe Wines, which had been struggling with high power bills and supply shortages for years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b0bf1355ca93ba6aeb7ebb4fe57471b</guid></item><item><title>How to watch Australia's Women's ODI World Cup semifinal clash with India and everything you need to know about the game</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/all-you-need-to-know-australia-vs-india-icc-world-cup/105946228</link><description>Australia is looking to continue a near-perfect tournament in Thursday's Women's ODI World Cup semifinal. This is all you need to know ahead of the blockbuster clash in Mumbai.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">948a706c7db074171441871ac362bc9f</guid></item><item><title>Camp oven legend Ned Winter brought south-west Queensland to the world</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/ned-winter-remembered-south-west-qld-to-the-world/105946908</link><description>Known far and wide for his famous dampers and establishing the Australian Camp Oven Festival, Ned Winter will be laid to rest today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc409a5e2e1af6928b47141f120e80dd</guid></item><item><title>Commissioner recommends watchdog to steer government efforts against domestic, family and sexual violence</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/violence-against-women-national-watchdog-micaela-cronin/105949568</link><description>The Domestic, Family and Sexual Violence Commission found systems meant to keep governments accountable are so fragmented they are leading to authorities passing the buck on responsibility.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d0345d8806617fa726c08570bd488a2</guid></item><item><title>NSW farmers condemn threat of compulsory land acquisition for Santos Narrabri Gas Project</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/farmers-condemn-narrabri-gas-project-aquisition-threat/105950352</link><description>The NSW premier has warned farmers they may face compulsory land acquisition if they cannot reach a compromise with Santos on a multi-billion-dollar project at Narrabri.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9a16d403a4db8139bbda803ea40cadd</guid></item><item><title>US President Donald Trump says South Korea has approval to build nuclear-powered submarine</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/south-korea-permission-to-build-nuclear-submarines/105951210</link><description>US President Donald Trump says he has given South Korea approval to build a nuclear-powered submarine, a dramatic move that would admit Seoul to a small club of nations possessing such vessels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3debcd97fa1ff01df9125b386728fc79</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with alleged hit-and-run murder of former police officer in Ulmarra</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/man-charged-with-murder-former-police-officer-hit-run-death/105950406</link><description>Dion Anthony Craig has been refused bail following the death of a 55-year-old woman at Ulmarra, NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2de4d07df6e69dbf48646dbac0ef04fe</guid></item><item><title>Family calls for coronial inquest into mother's death on Queensland's Lizard Island</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/lizard-island-cruise-passenger-death-daughter-calls-for-inquest/105950816</link><description>An 80-year-old cruise ship passenger who was found dead on Lizard Island in Far North Queensland on the weekend has been identified as Sydney woman Suzanne Rees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c68790ff4e2794f439f424ab54248d3d</guid></item><item><title>No progress on Tasmanian public sector pay deal as more industrial action flagged</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/tas-public-sector-teacher-strikes-no-deal-with-gov/105950894</link><description>A week of strike action by public sector unions has wrapped up with no progress on a new pay deal for thousands across health, education, and more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f3d531d68f862822aff718e98ae62e8</guid></item><item><title>Canberra childcare director Emma Morton jailed after defrauding more than $300,000 from centre</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/emma-morton-jailed-300000-fraud-childcare-centre/105950734</link><description>A woman who used credit cards from the childcare centre where she worked to purchase personal clothes and cosmetics has been sentenced to jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4e092d3410db2ce7b54bc2cf2dfcffa</guid></item><item><title>South Korea welcomes Trump with highest award, golden crown and ketchup</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/donald-trump-visits-south-korea/105950680</link><description>From menus featuring ketchup and American beef to the gifting of a massive replica gold crown, Donald Trump's visit to South Korea was carefully crafted to please the US president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99d6823b7b34b2c322a3d2f89185f0e6</guid></item><item><title>Trump to reduce tariffs on Beijing amid resumed US nuclear weapons testing order</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/trump-orders-resumption-of-nuclear-weapons-testing/105951930</link><description>The United States last tested a nuclear weapon in 1992, and appears to be making the move in reaction to Russia successfully testing a Poseidon nuclear-powered super torpedo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f08704e14d43aa20f45b59645f4f0d12</guid></item><item><title>Vanuatu patrol boat RVS Takuare transported to Australia for repairs after hitting reef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/vanuatu-patrol-boat-rvs-takuare-to-australia-after-hitting-reef/105947254</link><description>Almost four weeks after a $25 million Australian-gifted patrol boat ran aground on a reef while ferrying government officials, the Vanuatu government has yet to reveal the circumstances around the grounding, saying "an investigation is continuing".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a4536577a609584ebfb39c782db4ab2</guid></item><item><title>Three men charged over Stuart MacGill 'drug rip-off' assault avoid jail sentences</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/former-cricketer-stuart-macgill-three-men-assault-drugs-sentence/105951332</link><description>The former test cricketer was taken from his Sydney home to an abandoned property, where he was held and assaulted over a botched cocaine deal in 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3943ee6cce05f851dcff9d5332ea3dc2</guid></item><item><title>Cricket Australia defends $11.3m loss arising from India visit amid criticism from Victorian chair</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/cricket-australia-defends-11m-loss-victorian-chair-criticism/105952134</link><description>Cricket Australia insists record numbers are ahead despite facing criticism after losing more than $11 million in a summer that included a five-Test home series against India.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a28bc7a2339ca7503f706518392cc97</guid></item><item><title>Video captures person standing on dead whale</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/-video-captures-person-standing-on-dead-whale/105951562</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c69475d4b7d077bb46fda3201cc5635d</guid></item><item><title>Video of person climbing on dead humpback whale shared with police</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/marine-volunteer-films-person-on-dead-whale-at-coledale-nsw/105951420</link><description>A video appearing to show a person climbing on a humpback whale found dead, entangled in a shark net in NSW, has been criticised by a marine rescue group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffb44efada0f624df60bfa7d2369083c</guid></item><item><title>Oyster farmers blockade trucks carrying oysters from algal bloom waters</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/streaky-bay-oyster-farmers-block-oyster-trucks-sa/105951284</link><description>Oyster farmers have formed a blockade at Haslam in South Australia to prevent oysters from an area affected by the algal bloom being put in the waters around Streaky Bay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97901e580ccfa96c7bd7857d732b6022</guid></item><item><title>Albanese confident on AUKUS despite Trump's Korean subs promise</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/albanese-confident-on-aukus-despite-us-korean-subs/105952342</link><description>As the US president promises South Korea can have nuclear submarines, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese insists this can be delivered alongside the AUKUS boats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a339c0a4dcf9a3b8643977ffa5d213f1</guid></item><item><title>Prison officers striking over sentence for NSW inmate who bashed guards ordered back to work</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/prison-officers-walk-off-job-over-guard-bashings-nsw/105951998</link><description>Thousands of NSW prison officers have walked off the job over the sentence handed to a prisoner who bashed four guards at Cessnock Correctional Complex.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44ab0a884521dddb1093588cd4e3b30e</guid></item><item><title>Trial begins for three Australians accused of killing Zivan Radmanovic in Bali villa</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/trial-begins-for-three-australians-accused-of-killing-a-man/105952536</link><description>A trial has begun in Bali for three Australian men accused of killing a Melbourne father in an alleged premeditated hit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a624a10ba2043124ec917a3399039497</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government flunks transparency test while Coalition fixates on PM's T-shirt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/coalition-split-albanese-tshirt-labor-transparency/105938072</link><description>In a week when Labor earned a poor scorecard for its transparency, the Coalition was wasting time responding to yet another self-inflicted saga.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cba1a7da63e9bce4e9280c47a31ae8c</guid></item><item><title>Man who injected girlfriend with meth 'played Russian roulette' with her life, grieving mum says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/family-of-amy-bowden-delivers-victim-impact-statements/105952350</link><description>The mother of 26-year-old Amy Bowden, who died after her partner injected her with methamphetamine, has told an Adelaide court the man "played Russian roulette with her life" instead of getting help.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94a26d5545d9fc996ae7858f5dab47d7</guid></item><item><title>Young Aboriginal woman mourned after death in Tasmanian prison custody</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/death-in-custody-chelsea-bracken-indigenous-incarceration/105950914</link><description>The family of a young Aboriginal woman who died while in custody in Tasmania say she will be remembered "as a loving and vibrant individual".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">137f16898636d5f05decf9df0da35e4b</guid></item><item><title>Neighbour who discovered bodies of two murdered women in 1977 appears at Easey St hearing</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/victoria-easey-street-committal-hearing-perry-kouroumblis/105950548</link><description>Witnesses, including a former neighbour and a former homicide detective, have told a Melbourne court what they saw at the crime scene following murders in Collingwood nearly 50 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53dd5c6ec5fe7c60cf52aaeb25d5e998</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of cases of child-on-child abuse are the fresh childcare system horror</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/child-on-child-abuse-is-the-fresh-childcare-system-horror/105947226</link><description>Parents are demanding answers from centre operators after their children were allegedly sexually abused by other children while in child care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e24dda233dcdb375e7ec47e75f25583f</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce denies allegation he yelled at staffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/barnaby-joyce-denies-yelling-allegation/105952654</link><description>The prominent Nationals MP, who is taking time away from his party, says he will respect the formal process into the allegation but denies it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fed2631876839c27ebd4126b7bc7bd07</guid></item><item><title>Chris Marco jailed over Ponzi-style fraud involving hundreds of Perth investors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/chris-marco-jailed-after-stealing-from-perth-investors/105951910</link><description>A Perth businessman who defrauded clients of more than $34 million in what was described as a "Ponzi scheme" has been sentenced to 14 years in prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fc24b5b53c2a9c2def6cf37729e39e7</guid></item><item><title>Angry oyster farmers stage a blockade to stop oysters relocation.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/angry-oyster-farmers-stage-blockade-to-stop-oyster-relocation/105953600</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d35c1b67a441a77488698ee1a3a5bad5</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos coach Tony Popovic says restoring Australia's football DNA is key to creating World Cup history</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/socceroos-coach-tony-popovic-pursues-greatness-fifa-world-cup/105949386</link><description>The Socceroos have historically been seen as plucky underdogs at the FIFA World Cup. Now, Tony Popovic believes those same traits can see his side create history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7050d95216cea24d2baa5d8678bea0bf</guid></item><item><title>How size inclusivity at fashion shows can have a big impact on broader society</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/victorias-secret-show-body-inclusivity-positivity/105946528</link><description>Curve model Annika Nielsen says representation is sometimes "something that you don't realise that you miss or that you need until you see it".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee35875fadf41007bb2da7bddbc03068</guid></item><item><title>Snowy Monaro councillor Andrew Thaler disqualified after third misconduct suspension</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/snowy-monaro-councillor-andrew-thaler-suspended-third-time/105937678</link><description>Snowy Monaro councillor Andrew Thaler has been notified he will be disqualified from council for five years after receiving a third suspension for misconduct. He is only the second NSW councillor to be dealt with under the three-strike system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dff6b5022c9ff8283d50012f2dce39a</guid></item><item><title>What is a wanger and how is it used in cricket training?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/what-is-a-wanger-and-how-is-it-used-in-cricket-training/105953456</link><description>Australia's cricket community is in shock following the death of Victorian teenager Ben Austin, who was fatally struck by a cricket ball that was released from a "wanger".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cf35f5295f5537d9c9324163b4e8f99</guid></item><item><title>Townsville Hospital CEO says some patients may die after urology bungle</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/ceo-says-patients-may-die-after-townsville-hospital-failings/105951302</link><description>Some patients affected by a healthcare bungle at a major Queensland hospital may die as a result, the health service's chief says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1239cb264a593ae21d20848fb5d0cbbd</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump's campaign against Venezuelan drug boats is rooted in past failure and a hatred of Nicolas Maduro</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/trump-blowing-up-boats-as-maduro-arms-venezuelans/105947824</link><description>Donald Trump is on a revenge tour during his second stint in the White House and now his gaze has shifted to an enemy who once "humiliated" him — Nicolas Maduro.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">322e4374aa993498dd5dadd4ad39a7a1</guid></item><item><title>Rallen Australia loses trademark battle with gas company over 'Tanumbirini'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/tanumbirini-loses-trademark-battle-with-gas-company-tamboran/105943810</link><description>One of the Northern Territory's largest beef producers has failed in its bid to stop a gas company from trademarking the name of one of its cattle stations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7aef25b816ffa33b5eb1d56096cdd302</guid></item><item><title>'Blood on the floor': How James Hardie's board came undone</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/why-the-james-hardie-board-was-gutted/105954054</link><description>James Hardie has a long history of attempting to avoid its responsibilities. The drama began when the company announced a $14 billion purchase of a rival firm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d22c75d89d4c6110b70519c09d3d75f</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne Dhamma Sarana temple head monk found guilty of sex offences against six girls</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/victoria-buddhist-monk-dhamma-sarana-sexual-offences/105954014</link><description>Naotunne Vijitha, the former head monk at Dhamma Sarana temple in Melbourne, was found guilty of sex offences against six girls from 1994 to 2002.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dee117bb0a6416df915e32c181f600e</guid></item><item><title>Thursday finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/thursday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/105952128</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc7ad92476c51f5f1be54c586e8ad294</guid></item><item><title>Court documents reveal land council boss offered to settle senator's defamation case</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/nt-jacinta-nampijinpa-price-60000-defamation-settlement-offer/105952936</link><description>Court documents reveal the Northern Territory senator rejected a $60,000 settlement offer two months before making a public appeal for help to fund her defamation defence in the Federal Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2295ef69171178470c36e7f9deb386ca</guid></item><item><title>Five new suspects arrested over Louvre robbery, Paris prosecutor says</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/five-new-suspects-arrested-over-louvre-museum-jewels-robbery/105954530</link><description>French police have arrested five new people, including a main suspect, over this month's daring jewellery theft from the Louvre museum, the Paris prosecutor says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f66a6b6ed86347d9864cb1614d632c6</guid></item><item><title>Satellite images lay bare the extent of Hurricane Melissa's damage</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/in-pictures-hurricane-melissa-aftermath-in-cuba-jamaica-haiti/105953684</link><description>Pictures of the aftermath of Hurricane Melissa, the "storm of the century" that tore through Jamaica, Cuba and Haiti, reveal a trail of damage and displacement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d0da543519d76d87ab4b55e0a21ac36</guid></item><item><title>What Donald Trump and Xi Jinping discussed in their 'amazing meeting' in Busan, South Korea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/key-takeaways-from-october-trump-and-xi-meeting/105952166</link><description>The settling of tariffs, a lengthy discussion on the war in Ukraine, and effusive praise for the Chinese leader — here are the main takeaways from the meeting between Donald Trump and Xi Jinping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca66208ee05f7fb3cd9684ccb2e1fbe9</guid></item><item><title>Australia out of Women's Cricket World Cup as India completes miracle semifinal run chase</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/australia-vs-india-womens-odi-world-cup-semifinal-live-blog/105954326</link><description>Australia's Women's Cricket World Cup dream is over, ended by India and the greatest run chase in tournament history in a gripping semifinal. Follow live.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b41ea78ff43db936ff7b8e3cf93318b8</guid></item><item><title>Review finds more Caboolture Hospital patients with medical scans not followed up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/more-impacted-by-caboolture-hospital-medical-scan-bungle/105953130</link><description>The number of patients requiring follow-up rises to 21, after a medical imaging bungle at Caboolture Hospital's outpatient service in which test results went unchecked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2aa717a6bda41606d6f834286049a45b</guid></item><item><title>Kevin Frederick Combes jailed over 1990s sex attacks on two teens in Perth CBD, South Boulder</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/kevin-frederick-combes-jailed-over-1990s-teen-sex-attacks/105950490</link><description>A Perth man who raped two teenagers more than 30 years ago but was only charged last year after a genetic genealogy breakthrough, is jailed for 13 and a half years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8066d3ea9411217dd0f1a89fefcf0fe4</guid></item><item><title>Dr Richard Scolyer speaks on his fight with brain cancer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/dr-richard-scolyer-speaks-on-his-fight-with-brain-cancer/105953964</link><description>Sarah Ferguson presents Australia's premier daily current affairs program, delivering agenda-setting public affairs journalism and interviews that hold the powerful to account. Plus political analysis from Laura Tingle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57f2a4888d60d35b077acc898a65a122</guid></item><item><title>Eight-year-old boy dies following head-on e-bike crash on the Sunshine Coast</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-30/qld-ebike-death-sunshine-coast-crash-primary-school-boy/105954782</link><description>An eight-year-old boy on the Sunshine Coast has died in hospital after a crash between two e-bikes on Thursday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a405d0dfa114c3dec31b71f738e704da</guid></item><item><title>Dutch centrist Rob Jetten 'confident' as Geert Wilders' far-right party suffers setback in election</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/dutch-election-results-d66-pvv/105955042</link><description>Geert Wilders' Freedom Party lost ground in elections which had been seen as a potential test of the far-right's staying power in European politics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5fc08e7649fc4cd7a689ec6fe14c478</guid></item><item><title>US politicians call for Trump to act on 'unspeakable atrocities' in Sudan</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/sudan-violence-calls-for-trump-to-act/105955336</link><description>The UN and others are condemning paramilitary Rapid Support Forces, which reportedly attacked civilians as it moved to seize new territory in the North African country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4647407e6690012cff6270e64ddda409</guid></item><item><title>The ACT has made a historic decision. What about survivors elsewhere?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/act-bird-defence-survivors-canberra-nsw/105939314</link><description>Survivors watched on as the ACT took a historic step on Tuesday in passing a bill to overturn a High Court decision that allowed a church to avoid litigation over the actions of one of its priests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">780cb6dea5f8dafb6d21a246f90031ee</guid></item><item><title>Experts call for mandatory neck protection across all levels of cricket following death of Ben Austin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/cricket-safety-neck-head-helmet-ben-austin/105954522</link><description>Following the death of 17-year-old Ben Austin, experts, including the former doctor for the Australian cricket team, say more focus needs to be put on neck protection at all levels of the sport.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">266acb18f3a1d734c3e89ffb6a00fde2</guid></item><item><title>Questions from ratepayers group over $20m redevelopment to historic Albert Hall in Launceston</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/questions-over-20m-reno-to-launceston-albert-hall/105953582</link><description>A ratepayers' group is calling for an audit of the $20 million redevelopment of Launceston's heritage-listed Albert Hall for what it says are design flaws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70abdd6a0c4d4b668b92e2fd6fe21469</guid></item><item><title>Leaked emails show NBN Co fast-tracked upgrade for Sky News host Andrew Bolt</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/nbn-co-fast-tracked-upgrade-for-sky-news-host-news-corp-pundit/105953892</link><description>Senior managers at the National Broadband Network intervened to accelerate a home internet upgrade for News Corp pundit Andrew Bolt and resolve a technical problem for a top executive's friend during the final stages of the infrastructure project's rollout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92d6ce6e334e5bfc610ac7d88cdbd5ad</guid></item><item><title>Bulk-billing changes are coming into effect — what does it mean for you?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/bulk-billing-changes-medicare-gp-incentives/105953126</link><description>The government is pouring billions into Medicare so you have a better chance of being bulk-billed but the decision to charge or not charge still rests completely with your doctor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5cccbaed84752a4d9473f3630eeec4a5</guid></item><item><title>Dangerous anti-renewables rhetoric, bullying and intimidation creates growing chasm in rural communities</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/anti-renewables-campaigns-fuel-community-division-in-regions/105938440</link><description>There are grave concerns that dangerous language and bullying of farmers who are hosting renewable energy projects on their properties could turn into violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94ae62deffe3f1f0a779fa3cb29f51ef</guid></item><item><title>No plans to change Tim Tam recipe after rival UK biscuit can no longer be called chocolate</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/tim-tams-vs-penguins-cocoa-price-challenges/105931332</link><description>Food manufacturers are responding to high cocoa prices, and a change to the UK's Penguin biscuit may have all but cemented Australia's Tim Tam as the better of the two.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7790956298a772ceb7f53385e4f57c9f</guid></item><item><title>Family of Frank Coleman say death in custody findings show prison system failures</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/nsw-frank-coleman-coronial-inquest-death-in-custody/105952756</link><description>Just three months into 2021, Frank Coleman was the ninth Indigenous death in custody in New South Wales.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32d6e0b1f3429b2e25aa52ab6cf6a9cf</guid></item><item><title>Australian-first treaty legislation passes in Victorian parliament</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/victorian-first-nations-treaty-legislation-passes/105954864</link><description>Historic legislation has passed that will see the creation of an Indigenous council that will be consulted on laws and policies affecting Indigenous communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">094f68669c519d3627b4518f411e27dd</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump sets US refugee cap at 7,500, white South Africans given priority</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/donald-trump-asylum-cap-white-south-africans-priority/105955480</link><description>The US president paused all refugee admissions when he took office in January, saying they could only be restarted if established to be in the best interest of the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ec2688779308bc0ea4e1b06e6a5d8c3</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew stripped of title by King Charles and told to leave Royal Lodge</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/prince-andrew-to-leave-royal-lodge-lose-title/105955534</link><description>Prince Andrew will have his royal titles removed and surrender the lease of the Royal Lodge on the grounds of Windsor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95dc5197db309c553f2c48e9b30c09b9</guid></item><item><title>Award-winning youth advocate Cody Schaeffer charged over alleged assaults on teenagers</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/award-winning-advocate-charged-alleged-assault/105953562</link><description>The radio host and youth mental health charity founder has been charged with assaulting several teenagers, according to Queensland authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89678fbe79c70982746ee521bf01731d</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of thousands of ultra-orthodox Israelis protest against military draft</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/ultra-orthodox-israelis-protest-against-military-draft-jerusalem/105954936</link><description>Hundreds of thousands of ultra-orthodox Jews have shut down one of the busiest junctions at the entrance to Jerusalem in protest against moves to force them to serve in the Israeli military.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e28f558c03bb655111e2400565fbe214</guid></item><item><title>City of Kalgoorlie-Boulder gets legal advice on stalled golf course resort amid $12.5m commitment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/city-of-kalgoorlie-boulder-gets-legal-advice-on-golf-resort/105937880</link><description>The development of a resort at the Kalgoorlie Golf Course — the long-time home of the WA PGA Championship — has hit the rough and could cost ratepayers more than $12 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71a3a935d175dccbd96638cc1b5ffe73</guid></item><item><title>Canberra is a step closer to getting its first dementia care village</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/canberra-dementia-care-village-on-site-of-sold-school/105942542</link><description>Specialised accommodation will be built in Curtin to house those living with the nation's deadliest disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">109e5e3f66c2731acc1db56469f50fba</guid></item><item><title>New-found love of running takes SA man all the way to New York Marathon</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/indigenous-marathon-foundation-squad-prepare-for-new-york/105950978</link><description>Six months ago, Jack Atkinson had little running experience. But this weekend he will tackle the world's largest marathon alongside NRL great Johnathan Thurston and AFL giant Lance 'Buddy' Franklin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7467324170fc51e789bcdb91a79dbeb8</guid></item><item><title>Heartbroken dad wants Senate inquiry into doctor suicides</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/calls-for-senate-inquiry-into-doctor-suicide-deaths/105885252</link><description>There are calls for a Senate inquiry into the suicide deaths of Australian doctors amid allegations of untenable rosters and payback for whistleblowers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cb120622fea746f458abf16cfc11b4e</guid></item><item><title>Australia rues batting and fielding mishaps in Women's World Cup semifinal loss to India</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/cricket-world-cup-semifinal-australia-loses-to-india/105955560</link><description>Australia captain Alyssa Healy says her side only have themselves to blame as the defence of their World Cup crown comes to an end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">551400f1ea68e61d7c2004c80df270f7</guid></item><item><title>Finley Bone, 21, identified as Cooroy sports complex lightning strike victim</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/lightning-strike-fatal-sporting-complex-cooroy/105955574</link><description>The mother of 21-year-old Finley Bone, who was struck by lightning and later died, says her daughter's life was "taken away in a minute".</description><guid isPermaLink="false">202bc04d39718c24a84583972b05eb0d</guid></item><item><title>Queensland hit by hailstones and storms as residents brace for weekend supercell</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/queensland-weather-friday/105951150</link><description>Damaging storms are forecast from the New South Wales border, west to the Darling Downs and all the way up the coast to the Capricornia, Mackay and the Central Highlands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eac52fde04dd02bad5734ec2e33b632</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew updates: King's brother loses his titles and will be evicted from Royal Lodge — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/prince-andrew-stripped-of-royal-title-live-blog/105955606</link><description>King Charles will remove Prince Andrew's royal title and evict him from the Royal Lodge in Windsor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e80e1c2810fba7489333c40e8922ed7d</guid></item><item><title>Tame Impala, Lily Allen, Dave lead October's best new albums</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/10-best-albums-october-lily-allen-tame-impala-dave-baker-boy/105952214</link><description>From Lily Allen's devastating divorce record to Tame Impala's polarising return, here are October's best new music releases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f72053d7b5ec4a8e348657728b9cce1</guid></item><item><title>Emma Stone reunites with director Yorgos Lanthimos for fourth time in Bugonia</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/bugonia-film-review-yorgos-lanthimos-emma-stone-jesse-plemons/105941636</link><description>Yorgos Lanthimos continues his journey as the king of absurdist dark comedies with this latest offering, which delves into conspiracy theories in the most bizarre way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbc0f9ae9ce94e731361cd72b3bca372</guid></item><item><title>Women paid thousands less per year than men in Victoria's forest firefighting ranks</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/deeca-pay-inequality-gender-gap-ffmv-firefighters/105941598</link><description>The Australian Workers' Union says Victorian female forest firefighters have been short-changed by an average of more than $4,000 in pay growth since 2019.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0024a9616b7afb244d67da54e5511a2</guid></item><item><title>Doctors say Chinese Australians should get checked for breast cancer earlier. Here's why they don't</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/chinese-women-get-breast-cancer-younger-than-in-the-west/105927052</link><description>As Breast Cancer Awareness Month draws to a close, support groups urge Chinese women to get screened for breast cancer, as doctors highlight how the disease impacts this cohort differently.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6c6f672d3fe7b2a88fbdf8accb2e6cc</guid></item><item><title>Democrats are 'fighting fire with fire' in California. Is a political inferno coming for American democracy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/california-gerrymandering-election-map-november-4/105944438</link><description>A debate is underway about American democracy, as California's governor campaigns for voters to approve a set of gerrymandered maps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5988d8b075ecfb55c7e7600d64328b68</guid></item><item><title>Attracted to 'shiny' objects, children in Gaza mistake unexploded bombs for toys</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/unexploded-ordinance-israel-ibombs-gaza-clearance-war-remnants/105937500</link><description>Many Palestinians returning to what is left of their homes face the risk of unexploded bombs hidden under rubble, which aid groups say may take decades to clear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bac5ba74e7e090503cf614616e0f10d3</guid></item><item><title>Tech stocks weigh on Wall Street but Apple and Amazon rally, ASX rises after Trump-Xi meeting — as it happened</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/asx-markets-business-live-news-31-oct/105955602</link><description>The Australian share market is higher on Friday but still on track for a weekly loss. ANZ has flagged a $1.1 billion profit hit due to redundancy costs and fines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37144f5a29a306a3825703a3902c8956</guid></item><item><title>Royal commentator says Queens Camilla had a role in removing Andrew's titles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/royal-commentator-says-queens-camilla/105955786</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72a58f3e64c2b71eaffd20e9e46fc7d9</guid></item><item><title>Olympic Leisure Centre swimmers left high and dry as historic aquatic venue closes</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/olympic-leisure-centre-heidelberg-west-pool-closure/105953220</link><description>The closure of the Olympic Leisure Centre public pool in Melbourne's north-east today has left local swimmers adrift, with many saying there are no other options for them to swim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bfd54566fce4635de0595faa7676d1a</guid></item><item><title>Wallabies forced to play by World Rugby's rules in England Test at Twickenham</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/rugby-union-australia-wallabies-england-twickenham-test/105955734</link><description>Wallabies coach Joe Schmidt is not concerned about rules prohibiting some of his key overseas-based players from lining up against England at Twickenham this weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d53a4b0a677e6666d19d4b6c9c34eb26</guid></item><item><title>Albanese government has not walked its talk about accountability and integrity</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/labor-transparency-david-pocock-jobs-for-mates/105938080</link><description>Labor came to power in 2022 promising a new form of transparent, accountable politics. As recent incidents have shown, there is little sign of it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8fc78e5f2229acc225d8f3826a21c3c</guid></item><item><title>Dozens of shoppers report experiencing static shocks at Sunshine Coast supermarket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/dozens-of-shoppers-experience-static-shocks-at-supermarket/105943202</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eaf22f7cc0cd77576a651d7cd1645712</guid></item><item><title>Aldi shoppers report static electricity shocks at Nambour supermarket</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/aldi-investigates-static-shocks-nambour-store/105942226</link><description>Something is giving shoppers a shock at this Queensland store — and it is not the grocery bill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4352a60254432b657cbc85242bd1a54f</guid></item><item><title>WA tourist town of Onslow could soon be left without a postcode</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/wa-town-could-be-left-without-a-postcode-without-a-buyer/105951270</link><description>People living in this "bustling" town could be facing a 600-kilometre round trip for banking and postal services if a buyer for the local store cannot be found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">672d82f32b8b17604b35c7f85a0fb9b6</guid></item><item><title>How ancient knowledge is making modern science sit up and pay attention</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/how-ancient-science-is-driving-modern-science/104872844</link><description>From dinosaur footprints to volcanic eruptions, First Nations knowledge is helping to drive modern science.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50095967b7a3c44455a6763a4dcc6e41</guid></item><item><title>Decades after the 'final' seance, hundreds still hope to contact Harry Houdini</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/harry-houdini-seance-halloween/105899090</link><description>On Halloween night in 1936, the tiny, white-haired widow of Harry Houdini made her final attempt to contact him from beyond the grave. Today, the tradition continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fa0dd9dced651720e47d86f4f127aa5</guid></item><item><title>Woman charged with murder of baby in Baldivis in Perth's south</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/woman-charged-with-murder-of-baby-in-baldivis-in-southern-perth/105956052</link><description>Police investigating the death of an eight-month-old baby at a Baldivis home charge a 28-year-old woman with murder and say she will face court at a later date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43f9d07e3d08873f7b0ca8eaab05b549</guid></item><item><title>SA coastal tourism struggling, even in areas outside the algal bloom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/coastal-accommodation-down-amid-sa-algal-bloom/105938456</link><description>Coastal towns in parts of SA's south-east have seen significant drops in visitation, despite being free of harmful algae.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29fdc88051c2f790be6cbd769bad13a0</guid></item><item><title>'Admiral' Peter Cowell spotted on quiet suburban Perth street</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/-admiral-peter-cowell-spotted-on-quiet-suburban-perth-street/105956028</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">507ce80666e41978a3a1e071ca099d73</guid></item><item><title>Andrew's last appearance as a prince on September 16, 2025</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/andrew-s-last-appearance-as-a-prince-in-september-16-2025/105956352</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7a387f306eb76ba32cc66ba8e782aa1</guid></item><item><title>Black bearded irises bloom just in time for Halloween</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/black-bearded-irises-bloom-on-flower-farm-in-time-for-halloween/105942068</link><description>While red roses have their moment on Valentine's Day, these "black suited" irises come into bloom close to Halloween.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0300dc3c24cf3c0c6c94e637f12407c3</guid></item><item><title>Darling Downs 'inundated' with reports of snakes, bites and near misses</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/snakes-becoming-more-prevalent-on-the-darling-downs/105953444</link><description>Gunter Glasser has been catching snakes for almost 30 years across Southern Queensland, but October has been an especially busy month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2100cbd5d77935766d6b6ffb955cbc42</guid></item><item><title>Australia's Jillaroos lose Tamika Upton for Pacific Championships Test against New Zealand's Kiwi Ferns</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/pacific-championships-australia-jillaroos-new-zealand-kiwi-ferns/105956360</link><description>The Jillaroos will have to cope without one of their stars in Sunday's Pacific Championships Test against New Zealand in Auckland.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8990b682f325b3db20d4e2be39f5884d</guid></item><item><title>Strong prices, good conditions encourage Queensland farmers to trial canola</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/queensland-growers-trial-canola-with-strong-prices/105948370</link><description>While they are a long way off from rivalling the plantings in Western Australia or New South Wales, growers in Queensland are experimenting with canola and reaping the rewards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94383f29d34d12c50fd4da46186ddeb2</guid></item><item><title>Yacht salvage team innovates with geotextile to protect Lady Elliot Island reef</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/yacht-salvage-team-protects-lady-elliot-island-reef/105952960</link><description>After a fibreglass yacht ran aground on Lady Elliot Island's pristine reef, a bespoke salvage team worked tirelessly to save the environment from irreparable harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9467c32a312dd00ab73dcf2d4f4984ce</guid></item><item><title>World War II bomb blast shakes Solomon Islands capital Honiara, injuring one</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/solomon-islands-explosion-capital-second-world-war-bomb/105955910</link><description>Police say a large explosion that rocked the capital overnight was caused by a World War II bomb.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f1ac991d02d3935396e460387eae1a3</guid></item><item><title>Man removes 18km of barbed wire fencing from Victorian property to save wildlife</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/man-removes-18km-of-barbed-wire-fencing-to-help-wildlife/105890356</link><description>Wongarra man Doug Gimesy removes more than 18 kilometres of barbed wire from his property to create a wildlife haven.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c0bf85e258a086971d52698dadb06eb</guid></item><item><title>Isla Bell's alleged murderer Marat Ganiev and co-accused Eyal Yaffe ordered to stand trial</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/isla-bell-alleged-murderer-marat-ganiev-to-stand-trial/105955932</link><description>A judge rules there is enough evidence to send Marat Ganiev and co-accused Eyal Yaffe to trial over the death of the 19-year-old, whose body was found at a tip in Melbourne's south-east last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cee456ae8a921c1fd69aa9d7a925242</guid></item><item><title>Commissioner to hear submissions why Vlassakis should not be released on parole</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/review-commissioner-to-hear-submissions-on-vlassakis-parole/105956792</link><description>The South Australian Parole Administrative Review Commissioner will start hearing submissions in December as to why Snowtown killer James Vlassakis should not be released on parole.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">439e785752a90799dbeee740133a76b4</guid></item><item><title>Opposition implies Labor scuttled Sussan Ley's planned visit to Tomago smelter</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/ley-visit-to-tomago-cancelled/105956788</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley has revealed her scheduled tour of the plant was cancelled at the last minute but she was given a meeting with its chief executive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">820a2b867c39bbf6525d378e4f6c1551</guid></item><item><title>Disgraced ex-Kiama MP Gareth Ward sentenced for sexually abusing two young men</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/gareth-ward-ex-nsw-liberal-minister-sentenced-sexual-abuse/105948558</link><description>Former New South Wales Liberal minister and independent Kiama MP, Gareth Ward, is sentenced to five years and nine months in jail for sexually abusing two young men.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d281453559a8c08f93e743b390016947</guid></item><item><title>GWS Giants player Katherine Smith on playing AFLW through pain of endometriosis</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/endometriosis-elite-athlete-katherine-smith-aflw-gws-giants/105952810</link><description>Endometriosis remains a silent struggle for many women and elite athletes alike. GWS Giants leader Katherine Smith spent years playing through the pain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06acb9ae31170ef7ae2f73da7ee838ed</guid></item><item><title>Queensland Health confirms homemade food products as source of rat poisoning cluster</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/qld-health-rat-poisoning-cluster-homemade-food/105956778</link><description>Queensland Health says the three products were made in a home kitchen and were either gifted or purchased in the local area.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c97948fdc15caee9a8849ba2ed48a6bc</guid></item><item><title>Perth men charged over seizure of more than five tonnes of illicit cigarettes, vapes and loose tobacco</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/perth-men-charged-illicit-tobacco-seizure/105957130</link><description>Two Perth brothers are charged after the seizure of more than four million cigarettes, around 50,500 vapes and almost 900 kilograms of loose-leaf tobacco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49eee83c8197cb719016445cd2eb17ca</guid></item><item><title>How 5 Seconds of Summer stayed together after all these years together</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/how-5-seconds-of-summer-stayed-together/105950350</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad363607af4109b7fd0698bd4684f26f</guid></item><item><title>Perth brothers charged over massive seizure of imported cigarettes, vapes.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/perth-men-charged-illicit-tobacco-seizure/105957498</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7de76233e13ab1e21658cb0c12971e9c</guid></item><item><title>International stars and everyday Australians pay tribute to cricketer Ben Austin</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/victoria-ben-austin-cricket-death-tributes/105954270</link><description>Cricketers at the highest levels of the sport have paid tribute to 17-year-old Ben Austin who died on Thursday after being struck by a ball at a training session.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4636cc0519b40a31b1b015f294a1291e</guid></item><item><title>What are the origins of Andrew Mountbatten Windsor's name?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/why-prince-andrew-will-go-by-andrew-mountbatten-windsor-/105956622</link><description>Buckingham Palace has announced Prince Andrew will lose his royal titles and honours. But where does his surname Mountbatten Windsor come from?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75b3f50397aff310430b7706b45da405</guid></item><item><title>Waroona Shire suggests blowing up rotting whale carcass to save money</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/waroona-shire-suggests-blowing-up-dead-whale-to-save-money/105954240</link><description>A coastal shire in WA suggests towing a rotting whale carcass out to sea and blowing it up, saying it cannot afford to dispose of the whale itself.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc10ef67425429fffc19d164c6b3c365</guid></item><item><title>Canberra man sentenced for emptying friend's bank account while victim was recovering in hospital</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/man-sentenced-for-defrauding-quadriplegic-friend/105956780</link><description>After a severe car accident, the victim spent a year recovering in hospital. Then one day he discovered his bank account was empty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acb4b57c65e93c86ed4fc73cf2a21422</guid></item><item><title>Will Hayward and Ollie Florent left hurt by brutal conversation with Sydney before Carlton trades</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/afl-hayward-florent-hurt-by-swans-trade-with-carlton/105957592</link><description>Will Hayward and Ollie Florent were both locked into long-term deals with Sydney before being told they needed to leave while holidaying in South America.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d162ed07f21a01a0b3a8570205c0a6b1</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal Community Controlled Health Service clinics in remote NT desperately need additional resources</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/nt-remote-aboriginal-community-controlled-health-service-funding/105953720</link><description>Imagine visiting a health clinic where you may be exposed to asbestos, leaking roofs and lead in the water pipes. That's the reality for remote NT, according to a new report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa8f587b08c0afef95e1f20ba455024e</guid></item><item><title>Stripped of his titles and his home, Andrew's humiliation is complete</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/prince-andrew-loses-titles-royal-lodge-and-dignity/105955874</link><description>Once considered the darling of the royal family and the "favourite" son of Queen Elizabeth II, the King's brother will now be known only as Andrew Mountbatten Windsor. It's a humiliation for the history books.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e0ae4adf6d8a924fed09f5ab76eea08</guid></item><item><title>Rescuers scramble to recover bodies after landslide in Papua New Guinea</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/papua-new-guinea-landslide-kukas-enga-province/105957220</link><description>Police say 21 people have been killed in a landslide in Papua New Guinea's highlands overnight, with bodies still being recovered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a16fc758622edfecffc8a0cf8bad37cf</guid></item><item><title>Queensland mayors to lead local disaster recovery after long-running dispute at Ipswich City Council</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/ipswich-dispute-forces-ldmg-mayor-change-across-queensland/105953990</link><description>The changes form part of a larger Empowering Councils Bill set to be introduced by the Queensland government later this year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b378d6900dd497b8d7a9943df7b37de6</guid></item><item><title>High Country killer Greg Lynn faces court in bid to quash Carol Clay murder conviction</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/high-country-killer-greg-lynn-faces-court-of-appeal/105956096</link><description>Greg Lynn's lawyer says the prosecution "played outside the rules" during the former Jetstar pilot's double-murder trial last year as he appeals his conviction and sentence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23257b674ca089842d8280cbae5e00c3</guid></item><item><title>Port Adelaide dismisses Warren Tredrea from board of directors</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/warren-tredrea-dismissed-from-port-adelaide-board/105958182</link><description>AFL great Warren Tredrea has been dismissed from the board of the Port Adelaide Football Club, the Power has confirmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00a1f95f5595f68b1322b46d966bb1c6</guid></item><item><title>Broncos legend Corey Parker fears Reece Walsh's stardom may mean eventual code switch</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/corey-parker-fears-reece-walsh-could-join-rugby-union-all-blacks/105958064</link><description>After setting the NRL and international rugby league alight in recent months, Reece Walsh's next move could be one that leads him to global stardom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9306a06732f9206cf10fe969dd0e50d1</guid></item><item><title>What happens to Prince Andrew's children? Princess Beatrice and Eugenie to keep their titles</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/future-of-princess-beatrice-and-eugenie-in-royal-family-/105957580</link><description>What to know about the future of Andrew Mountbatten Windsor's daughters and their role in the royal family going forward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d60de38bc3440b6a030db534d2c3ed3d</guid></item><item><title>Jury finds man guilty of rape of woman he found unconscious on Shepparton nature strip</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/dexley-bule-meme-found-guilty-in-shepparton-rape-abduction-trial/105938504</link><description>A jury has found a 29-year-old Vanuatu national guilty of the rape and abduction of a woman in Shepparton in August last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ee7f6ddf2dd631515b0c843bc7f1eda</guid></item><item><title>2025 Bournda Bird Olympics</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/2025-bournda-bird-olympics/105958854</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc85e6f5e6c57a03f79a8367b36280ce</guid></item><item><title>What moving overseas for love and work looked like for Alex</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/what-moving-overseas-for-love-and-work-looked-like-for-alex/105884670</link><description>Having recently ended a seven-year long-distance relationship, Alex Bowyer wasn't keen on repeating history when he met his now-boyfriend Tony in Japan. So he packed up his life and moved overseas — but not without a safety net.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">caec662cdc4fc573eada2d7389b3da29</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of jobs to go as AGL speeds up energy transition</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/hundreds-of-agl-power-station-workers-warned-of-job-losses/105958582</link><description>AGL is preparing to shed hundreds jobs as part of a massive restructure aimed at freeing up capital to accelerate its transition away from coal and towards renewables.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">045a93aaafc9d62c988ce78be54f5abf</guid></item><item><title>Liberals hope for climate consensus but fear Nationals will dump net zero first</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/liberals-hope-for-climate-consensus-fear-nationals-net-zero/105958676</link><description>After most federal Liberal MPs attended a net zero meeting in Canberra, there is cautious optimism a consensus position can be found, but the junior Coalition partner could be poised to strike first.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c06019f6d84d6edfa042cd70bde80a35</guid></item><item><title>Encrypted police group chat stops case against Canberra Raiders star Josh Papalii</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/act-raiders-josh-papalii-permanent-stay-threaten-police-charge/105958068</link><description>Charges against Canberra Raiders prop Josh Papalii have been permanently stayed after it was revealed police had been discussing the case in a group chat on encrypted messaging service Signal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aaef57b417d822531d4e3545b641262e</guid></item><item><title>Queensland teachers reject state government pay offer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/queensland-teachers-reject-state-government-pay-offer/105957054</link><description>Queensland Teachers' Union members vote against an offer of an 8 per cent pay rise, vowing to keep up their campaign for better wages and working conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e82d59d224db7979d5b013d33339d4df</guid></item><item><title>NT government should proceed with Darwin ship lift project despite cost blowout, report finds</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/darwin-ship-lift/105956418</link><description>The NT government will gain no direct revenue from the ship lift project, despite spending $820 million on its construction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8330844966b5854ef8825bdc377eb1b</guid></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology reverts to previous rain radar after wave of complaints</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/bom-reverts-to-previous-rain-radar/105959362</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says it will revert to its previous colour scheme on its rain radar and weather map following a wave of complaints about its new $4.1 million website.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c44668557c0d90e065695a2571e3d444</guid></item><item><title>Miners asked to reconsider using industrial explosives involved in underground explosion which killed two</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/cobar-explosion-investigation-unearths-new-details/105958148</link><description>Regulator may ban the type of explosive used in fatal mining accident which claimed the lives of two workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8440ef045985b51177cebf0f6e2bf398</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Andrew's journey from favourite son to outcast prince</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/prince-andrew-fall-from-grace-in-pictures/105956194</link><description>Prince Andrew has been stripped of his royal titles and removed from the Royal Lodge. Here's a photographic timeline of his scandalous downfall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f904ca72952e2c64ca743e707322f50a</guid></item><item><title>Report shows gender pay gap increases for women as they age</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/gender-pay-gap-australia-data-shows-gap-grows-for-women/105956842</link><description>At the start of their careers, men and women earn almost the same. But by the time women reach their 30s their earnings flatten, while men's climb.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58a602cae8995628fbc1ff2d97145926</guid></item><item><title>Residents in Peregian Beach filmed hail.</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/peregrain-beach-hail-beach/105959710</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dacfd8815f070af612e0a8479ec058c</guid></item><item><title>Large hailstones in Placid Hills, Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/large-hailstones-in-placid-hills-queensland/105959238</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2123c2aba2f8ec0e2c5de58fee26fdf3</guid></item><item><title>Large hailstones hammer parts of south-east Queensland as severe storms loom</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/hailstones-hammer-parts-of-queensland-as-severe-storms-hit/105959310</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology issues a "very dangerous" thunderstorm warning for parts of south-east Queensland, with residents urged to prepare for supercell storms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da9a472a6b0b5b9df5698ecf4df74d92</guid></item><item><title>What do we know about Sandringham and Prince Andrew's new home?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/where-will-prince-andrew-live-next-mountbatten-windsor-/105955954</link><description>The disgraced royal will be moving to a house somewhere on the sprawling Sandringham Estate owned by King Charles — but the exact location has not been made public.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3313032bdb329eee1ed90bbc10830d3c</guid></item><item><title>Marnus Labuschagne happy to open in Australia's Test side for upcoming Ashes series</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/cricket-marnus-labuschagne-ready-to-open-australia-ashes/105959688</link><description>Marnus Labuschagne is prepared to do whatever it takes to get back into Australia's Test side, even if that means batting in a non-preferred opening slot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aaceba17d7858f2de1a829904e732ca9</guid></item><item><title>Canberra will get its first dementia care village</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/canberra-will-get-its-first-dementia-care-village/105959468</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fb4bf48a55298218731fa4663c10083</guid></item><item><title>Hailstorm across parts of Queensland</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/hailstorm-across-parts-of-queensland/105959796</link><description>Follow the latest news headlines from Australia's most trusted source. Read in-depth expert analysis and watch live coverage on ABC News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e74d6778d9df1fe7451e3c5d267d15c9</guid></item><item><title>Friday Finance with Daniel Ziffer</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/friday-finance-with-daniel-ziffer/105959882</link><description>News from the world of finance and business. Top stories in text, video and audio. Business video news bulletin. Features and analysis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42a32d74df89994c443a844112fee9dd</guid></item><item><title>Australia vs India second T20: Hazlewood and Marsh dominate in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/cricket-australia-india-second-t20i-melbourne-live-scorecentre/105959222</link><description>A lethal spell from Josh Hazlewood has propelled Australia to an emphatic four-wicket Twenty20 win over India in front of 82,438 fans at the MCG.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c924fd75cf27f00160799d33b1310dce</guid></item><item><title>Australian climber dies on Nepal's Himlung Himal</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/australian-climber-dies-on-nepals-himlung-himal/105960032</link><description>An Australian mountaineer dies while descending one of Nepal's highest peaks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8379708eb1b3b21aaea13f1683c02e4</guid></item><item><title>Report details 'extreme risk' tied to Parramatta's Riverside Theatres redevelopment</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/parramatta-riveriside-theatres-redevelopment-an-extreme-risk/105958910</link><description>The redevelopment of Parramatta's Riverside Theatres is part of a plan to revitalise the CBD and turn it into a buzzing arts and cultural precinct.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30b3ad48bae85fb3e35233b7d40bf842</guid></item><item><title>WA man fined over neglect of two dogs which 'suffered greatly'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/wa-regs-animal-cruelty-sentence/105959396</link><description>A man in Western Australia's far north has been fined and banned from owning pets for five years after being found guilty of neglecting two dogs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">648d1b522382b84d5b061d66a9095663</guid></item><item><title>NACC chief Paul Brereton steps away from all defence investigations</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-10-31/brk-nacc-chief-steps-away/105960096</link><description>The head of the National Anti-Corruption Commission will step away from all defence-related corruption referrals following questions over his handling of perceived conflicts of interest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13a8b7f086a3df61488d0f5e662ed821</guid></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa death toll continues rising as Caribbean nations embark on clean-up</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/hurricane-melissa-death-toll-continues-rising/105960218</link><description>The death toll in the wake of Hurricane Melissa has climbed to at least 49, according to official reports, after wreaking destruction across much of the northern Caribbean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">843dc0cbb292fbf6e9889e26b4c70374</guid></item><item><title>Dutch centrist leader Rob Jetten claims election victory and is set to become country's youngest PM</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/dutch-centrist-d66-party-confirmed-as-election-winner-anp-says/105960122</link><description>Dutch centrist party D66 is now expected to take the lead in a first round of talks to form a coalition government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837e28c07f59e4f52cf2bada907deebe</guid></item><item><title>Albanese's salad days are stalked by the spectres of stagflation and soaring bills</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/albanese-trump-rba-interest-rates-jim-chalmers/105956176</link><description>The PM and his government are sitting in the often-fleeting sweet spot that comes early in the second term under our Westminster system of government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3dc79fc50f5fd23410b6265f04496499</guid></item><item><title>The mystery of Prince Andrew's finances and why there are calls for more transparency</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/former-prince-andrew-mountbatten-windsor-questions-about-fina/105950742</link><description>Andrew remains the subject of a mystery many are flummoxed by. The king's brother has not had a paid job for large chunks of his life, yet somehow he has managed to fund a luxury lifestyle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a8d36fbdb037f6b85cc3fffb504e0fd</guid></item><item><title>What does the average house price get you in regional Victoria?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/what-does-the-average-house-price-get-you-in-regional-victoria/105947516</link><description>The median house price in regional Victoria is $636,500. But what that will get you can look very different from place to place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b1f9e66e750a2e3439cf8f1491d2ba9</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew's downfall is Virginia Giuffre's justice, but can it save the monarchy?</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/andrew-mountbatten-windsor-virginia-guiffre-charles-jury-out/105959842</link><description>Prince Andrew has been exiled to a kind royal house arrest but the jury is still out on whether it's enough to stem damage to the monarchy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3a2ba1ff4cef4efc1e36e9eae1cde57</guid></item><item><title>Older Australians say new aged care reforms will make them 'feel more imprisoned' after change in fees</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/older-australians-aged-care-reforms-fees-services/105956238</link><description>Older Australians were promised "a world class aged care system", but as "once in a generation" changes roll out, some feel they are being delivered anything but.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34fe2e8c50daaaf0a5a43fdf4bbe460d</guid></item><item><title>Conjoined twins in PNG could be sent to Germany for surgery after Australia hopes fall through</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/png-conjoined-twins-not-getting-treatment-in-sydney-australia/105952802</link><description>The parents of conjoined twins in PNG who were hoping to send their babies to Sydney for an operation are now trying to go to Germany instead because Australia is too expensive</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ebb82535b2f5b422a620c992c9c6562</guid></item><item><title>Zohran Mamdani's pledge to arrest Benjamin Netanyahu in NYC 'unenforceable campaign promise'</title><link>https://www.abc.net.au/news/2025-11-01/zohran-mamdani-pledge-to-arrest-netanyahu-impossible-say-experts/105955338</link><description>Zohran Mamdani, the man many predict will become New York City's next mayor, has made plenty of promises — his one to arrest Israel's PM is causing a particular stir ahead of Tuesday's election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c9b853f87c7a320d38dd90f5df5463d</guid></item></channel></rss>