<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>SBS English News (Unofficial Aggregation)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 11:57:06 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>CEO Series: Coles&amp;apos; Leah Weckert, Fortescue&amp;apos;s Dino Otranto &amp;amp; Tyro&amp;apos;s Jon Davey</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ceo-series-coles-leah-weckert-fortescues-dino-otranto-tyros-jon-davey/3bara37ny</link><description>In this special extended edition of SBS On the Money, join SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves as he speaks with Coles Group CEO Leah Weckert to find out how shoppers are feeling, Fortescue CEO Dino Otranto on how the political landscape is impacting his operations while Stephanie Youssef discusses Tyro&amp;apos;s results with CEO Jon Davey, plus hear from Jamie Hannah from VanEck on the day on the sharemarket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ae27d8ff28119004a584258251b342d</guid></item><item><title>Australia - allergy capital of the world</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australia-allergy-capital-of-the-world/vhzcx29zj</link><description>The number of Australians living with allergy has doubled in nearly 20 years, according to a new report, which examines the financial and personal costs of the chronic condition. Demand for services is unprecedented, and experts warn allergy does not just impact health - it can reshape sufferers’ lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5c5b09e2183e0b6e630ce20bf72a50b</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s most wanted man is a sovereign citizen. What do they believe?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australias-most-wanted-man-is-a-sovereign-citizen-what-do-they-believe/oi1z4odsa</link><description>Dezi Freeman has been described as a &amp;quot;very active sovereign citizen&amp;quot; who is held in &amp;quot;high regard&amp;quot; by followers of the movement that has alarmed extremism experts and law enforcement authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c00a46c3e3e9af023ae347b60e4e7dc3</guid></item><item><title>CEO Series: Flight Centre&amp;apos;s Graham Turner on airfares, AI and flights to the US</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ceo-series-flight-centres-graham-turner-on-airfares-ai-and-flights-to-the-us/f3heo0je5</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Flight Centre CEO Graham Turner following the group&amp;apos;s results announcement to find out more about the operating environment, airfares and consumer trends, plus Michael Wayne from Medallion Financial Group goes through the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action including a look at the surprise rise in inflation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9e6cd6326b1f10c5c539185b44f614f</guid></item><item><title>FBI investigating Minneapolis school shooting as &amp;apos;hate crime targeting Catholics&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fbi-investigating-minneapolis-school-shooting-as-hate-crime-targeting-catholics/kzluygaxs</link><description>The FBI is investigating the shooting as an act of terrorism and an anti-Catholic hate crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">172113b9ca6a171c301a68d17211843f</guid></item><item><title>FBI investigating Minneapolis school shooting as &amp;apos;hate crime targeting Catholics&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/two-children-killed-and-17-injured-in-minneapolis-catholic-school-shooting-heres-what-we-know/kzluygaxs</link><description>The FBI is investigating the shooting as an act of terrorism and an anti-Catholic hate crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f24d4ed189c138dc5cee552773672ddb</guid></item><item><title>Gun ownership is rising in Australia. Who owns them, and why?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gun-ownership-is-rising-in-australia-heres-why/ldde2tb0g</link><description>Australian gun ownership is being driven by a wide range of different influences — many of which remain largely invisible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8a1d79a4258f90f10168b9ad738f07d</guid></item><item><title>Two dead in another US school shooting</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/two-dead-in-another-us-school-shooting/4avk4dbdn</link><description>Two children have been killed and 17 people wounded in a Catholic school shooting in Minneapolis in the United States. Authorities say they&amp;apos;re investigating the shooting as an act of domestic terrorism and a hate crime targeting Catholics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2af1512b3bcb7137ab56cabe03609767</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Incredibly alarming&amp;apos;: Albanese&amp;apos;s proposed rules for deporting non-citizens criticised</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/human-rights-groups-criticise-governments-dangerous-law-making-as-attack-on-migrants/rareugmif</link><description>Human rights lawyers are concerned about a new government proposal designed to remove legal obstacles to resettling three people in Nauru who were released as a result of the landmark &amp;quot;NZYQ&amp;quot; High Court decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dabaecfdc92ee418beaf9f193b85e33</guid></item><item><title>CEO Series: Wesfarmers Rob Scott calls for action on Victorian retail crime</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ceo-series-wesfarmers-rob-scott-calls-for-action-on-victorian-retail-crime/d63yt5qil</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Wesfarmers CEO Rob Scott about the company&amp;apos;s $2.9bn profit, bonus shareholder returns and the economic environment, plus a look at the day on the sharemarket including Qantas&amp;apos; second best profit result ever, with Angus Geddes from Fat Prophets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d784b90f3193e230ab1ff086702870ca</guid></item><item><title>Knights of the (productivity) roundtable ft. Senator Jacqui Lambie</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/knights-of-the-productivity-roundtable-ft-senator-jacqui-lambie/tdqs2qw1z</link><description>A lot has happened since the last sitting week. The Prime Minister announced Australia&amp;apos;s plan to soon recognise Palestinian statehood, and the best economic minds gathered to solve the productivity crisis. We break down why you should care about productivity at all, and Jacqui Lambie talks through her idea for a &amp;apos;climate army&amp;apos;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">445aea6c00308c02661970de98df1296</guid></item><item><title>Accused cop killer Dezi Freeman is still on the run. Here&amp;apos;s what we know about him</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-to-know-dezi-freeman/mge7c8xyn</link><description>The suspect behind the Porepunkah police shooting is still at large in the Victorian high country. Here&amp;apos;s what we know about accused cop killer Dezi Freeman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e253f5f3850ec21c70a1ecd09377df95</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;It creates a worry in your head&amp;apos;: International students plan to stay home during protests</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/it-creates-a-worry-in-your-head-international-students-holed-up-in-fear-ahead-of-protests/fbw6p37ia</link><description>International education is Australia&amp;apos;s fourth largest export, but with protests looming that demand dramatic cuts to migration, some experts think the event could &amp;quot;cast a shadow over the brand of Australia&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83576a4828238dac9816d9fe0bae6a23</guid></item><item><title>Iran ambassador expelled, Trump’s military crackdown &amp;amp; KPop Demon Hunters</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/iran-ambassador-expelled-trumps-military-crackdown-kpop-demon-hunters/p5uwy192i</link><description>In this episode: Australia punishes Iran after dramatic revelations in Canberra, Trump’s latest threats to set troops on more Democrat-held cities in the US, and a mass deportation pitch from the UK’s far right. Plus, why Venezuelan housewives are joining Maduro’s militia and South Korea’s supernatural export pops on global streaming.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e5a966272c6518d1d483190fc488c3d</guid></item><item><title>Why Anthony Albanese was chased by angry farmers on tractors</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-anthony-albanese-was-chased-by-angry-farmers-on-tractors-today/wqm0o39zi</link><description>Protesters at the annual Bush Summit event also used tractors and fire engines to block Victorian Premier Jacinta Allan from leaving.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fa21526833ba13796aa41ccc0a4f773</guid></item><item><title>Khawaja&amp;apos;s proposed Israel sports ban would violate &amp;apos;equal rights&amp;apos;, Olympic body says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/usman-khawajas-proposed-israel-sports-ban-would-violate-equal-rights-olympic-committee-says/8nv32y55s</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s opening batsman Usman Khawaja has argued international sporting bodies should consider removing Israel, over its treatment of Palestinians in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e993430baaf3653badf70f8d02eb307e</guid></item><item><title>Australian families could be sitting on a goldmine, but many are torn about selling</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/price-of-gold-surges-how-much-to-sell-it-for/koafq7847</link><description>The price of gold has gone up around 70 per cent in the last five years, leaving more people torn between selling items to make ends meet or keeping them for sentimental reasons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5374a616b22873f637ef5c4890362b9</guid></item><item><title>Scottish brothers reach Cairns after record-breaking row across the Pacific Ocean</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lachlan-jamie-ewan-maclean-brothers-cairns-rowing-pacific-ocean-scottish/4qgv8mys7</link><description>After more than four months at sea, the brothers reunited with loved ones — along with pizza and beer — as they reached their final destination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac9549f38c3e408b6db2d36bd90a1aee</guid></item><item><title>Scottish brothers reach Cairns after record-breaking row across the Pacific Ocean</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lachlan-jamie-ewan-maclean-scottish-brothers-cairns-rowing-pacific-ocean/4qgv8mys7</link><description>After more than four months at sea, the brothers reunited with loved ones — along with pizza and beer — as they reached their final destination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53880f8926f2556582b6c95c8afaf9f1</guid></item><item><title>The &amp;apos;crucified boy&amp;apos; of Donbas: How Russian propaganda makes its way to Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-russian-propaganda-makes-its-way-to-australia/14d547fci</link><description>The Donbas region of Ukraine has become a fault line in possible peace talks between Ukraine and Russia. But, as SBS News explores, its position as a hotbed for Kremlin propaganda is one of the reasons Putin won’t easily relinquish control of the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05d8abb74ab077add1b9c9b5381a3dd1</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Marathon 2025: Records broken as Sifan Hassan, Hailemaryam Kiros win</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sydney-marathon-2025-sifan-hassan-hailemaryam-kiros-win-titles/gsusgonxt</link><description>Dutch superstar Sifan Hassan and Ethiopia&amp;apos;s Hailemaryam Kiros have triumphed in the Sydney marathon as Kenyan legend Eliud Kipchoge battled to ninth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">538665abcb422e0ae3130e53d71a8143</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;An attack on multiculturalism&amp;apos;: government&amp;apos;s new Nauru deal greeted with alarm</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/an-attack-on-multiculturalism-governments-new-nauru-deal-greeted-with-alarm/rjgfvsyfn</link><description>The Federal Government has struck a $400 million deal with Nauru that it says paves the way for deportation of the so-called NZYQ cohort. The announcement has been met with outrage from advocates, human rights lawyers, and the Greens. Critics say the deal threatens fundamental legal rights in ways that could be applied more broadly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">216e9a31d9fc4baf24f2499581e99f26</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 1 Sep 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-1-sep-2025/c774abcmk</link><description>A daily 5-minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9b80654f039a36f7b13f920703069c0</guid></item><item><title>US makes plans for post-war Gaza, while flotilla aims to break Israel&amp;apos;s blockade</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-makes-plans-for-post-war-gaza-while-flotilla-aims-to-break-israels-blockade/03us9fe5l</link><description>A post-war plan for Gaza is circulating within the US government. Meanwhile, Israel&amp;apos;s Defence Minister says its forces have killed a Hamas spokesman in a strike on Gaza.And a flotilla of 20 boats has set sail from Barcelona for Gaza, in hopes of getting past Israel’s blockade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30e14a7b2f3ae4b4051b20081900a275</guid></item><item><title>Thousands rally against immigration with neo-Nazis taking the spotlight</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/thousands-rally-against-immigration-with-neo-nazis-taking-the-spotlight/amfab4ulu</link><description>A wave of nation-wide anti-immigration rallies have swept Australia&amp;apos;s capital cities, with thousands joining marches and clashing with police and counter-protesters across the country. Organisers say the events were calling for an end to what they consider &amp;quot;mass migration&amp;quot; into Australia, while neo-Nazi groups infiltrated a number of the events to stir up chaos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b6668353c17b48410a1d7344cc81ff6</guid></item><item><title>Protesters claim high migration levels have &amp;apos;torn&amp;apos; Australia. Here&amp;apos;s what experts say</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fact-checkers-assess-march-for-australia-immigration-claims/8yorv67wp</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s migration numbers and policies were the target of March for Australia&amp;apos;s anti-immigration rallies over the weekend. Here&amp;apos;s what experts have to say about their claims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c8f82e4e807cc1d18a06dd4afca0887</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Wake-up call&amp;apos;: Government urged to address rise in far-right extremism after racist rallies</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/wake-up-call-government-urged-to-address-rise-in-far-right-extremism-after-racist-rallies/3ejockt9q</link><description>Politicians have condemned the racism and xenophobia displayed at various anti-immigration protests over the weekend. After violent clashes and a large neo-Nazi presence, the Greens are calling on the government to urgently address rising right-wing extremism in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91eab1031e2660a3602ed50e8ab19c09</guid></item><item><title>Spring season property hotspots &amp;amp; reporting season fallout</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/spring-season-property-hotspots-reporting-season-fallout/u6jn8r0fh</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Goncalves speaks with Tim Lawless from Cotality Australia about the direction for home prices as the Spring selling season begins and to find out where the property hotspots are, plus Mathan Somasundaram from Deep Data Analytics takes a look back at the reporting season that was and looks ahead at what to expect now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">823ecf0ba615002992542f409f091c8b</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal Camp Sovereignty site attacked by anti-immigration protesters</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/mob-attacks-aboriginal-site-known-as-camp-sovereignty/hfbna9tt3</link><description>An Aboriginal gathering place and burial ground was attacked in Melbourne on Sunday by participants in the city&amp;apos;s anti-immigration rallies. Police are investigating the incident, which witnesses say involved self-proclaimed neo-Nazi Thomas Sewell and up to 100 others. The incident has been condemned by political leaders, with Senator Lidia Thorpe calling for a federal inquiry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ff6076053c0835e23fb203200d67764</guid></item><item><title>Cap on Australia&amp;apos;s migration numbers to stay the same, government confirms</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cap-on-migration-numbers-to-stay-the-same-government-confirms/wx1ftxfsy</link><description>The government said it has undertaken consultations with the states and territories, which recommended maintaining the size and composition of the migration program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63e9aa81d2e8e8ca12b36c83be4bb3ce</guid></item><item><title>No end in sight: famine tightens its grip on Gaza as Israeli families mourn hostages</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/no-end-in-sight-famine-tightens-its-grip-on-gaza-as-israeli-families-mourn-hostages/sz30yjm8x</link><description>Hungry Palestinians have queued at a soup kitchen in Khan Younis, empty pots in hand, as famine tightens its grip on Gaza. Families say aid is failing to reach them, while shortages and soaring prices have left markets bare. The United Nations says nearly half a million people in Gaza face catastrophic hunger, nearly a quarter of the territory&amp;apos;s population.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e73f7d25bc56ef2849a800c96f17bcb</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 2 Sep 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-2-sep-2025/nte6lpfva</link><description>A daily 5-minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89f4f62d7213f4dab0e96018aa0d25fb</guid></item><item><title>Spain prepares for future extreme weather after &amp;apos;environmental catastrophe&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/spain-prepares-for-future-extreme-weather-after-environmental-catastrophe/c8dgmob01</link><description>After a summer in which much of western and southern Europe were impacted by catastrophic fires and searing heat, Spain now forming a plan to prepare for future disasters.Scientists say action is needed to reduce emissions and increase resilience, in the face of inevitable worsening conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad6afe03228b625046485667e1148f5c</guid></item><item><title>Racism in the health sector can kill, research shows. What can be done to save lives?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/racism-impacting-health-sector-research-shows/dcyng1gmq</link><description>Racism is a &amp;quot;critical issue&amp;quot; in health, which can lead to a breakdown in trust between patients and healthcare workers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df4ffbd6bc80730836b7bf76b5ecb36c</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s greatest threat: Not war, not terror, not pandemic... but the climate</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australias-greatest-threat-not-war-not-terror-not-pandemic-but-the-climate/l8awp106c</link><description>As the Coalition remains divided over net zero emission targets, former security leaders are warning the government that climate change poses an immediate national security threat.In the Senate, the Greens are pushing for the release of the National Climate Risk Assessment Report while Nationals Senator Matt Canavan is pushing ahead with a bill to repeal net zero.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4be7eef0bd51253e32c781f9529976a8</guid></item><item><title>Gold and silver prices hit milestones &amp;amp; ASX hit by ex-dividend stocks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gold-and-silver-prices-hit-milestones-asx-hit-buy-ex-dividend-stocks/77logsn0k</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Goncalves speaks with Josh Gilbert from eToro to find out why gold prices hit a new record while silver reached a 14 year high, plus why the ASX fell as a number of companies traded ex-dividend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92b6528409b6e3cb0f3ceb139ac8c6e7</guid></item><item><title>I&amp;apos;m an Australian and wanted nothing to do with religion. Here&amp;apos;s what changed my mind</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/christianity-is-declining-in-australia-meet-the-gen-z-converts-bucking-the-trend/kpgccwiom</link><description>While latest Census data pointed to a significant downward trend in Australians identifying as Christian, there was an uptick in religious diversity. Some research suggests 38 per cent of gen Z identify as spiritual and there is an increase of gen Z men turning to religion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e17da9d041a976bbc9059bfd0dab3c4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Overwhelmed with fear&amp;apos;: Entire village wiped out, hundreds dead in Sudan landslide</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/overwhelmed-with-fear-entire-village-wiped-out-hundreds-dead-in-sudan-landslide/xfc3fkibf</link><description>A Sudanese rebel group has appealed for international aid after a landslide buried Tarseen village in Darfur, killing up to 1,000 people and leaving only one survivor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05684e4ee7e5c2b86e3981f1d2b86430</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 3 Sep 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-3-sep-2025/rqbzuecm0</link><description>A daily 5-minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc1e50f5913792e815ab35e44f2d7890</guid></item><item><title>ASX 200’s worst day since April; Australian economy grows faster than expected</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asx-200s-worst-day-since-april-australian-economy-grows-faster-than-expected/xkhcq18co</link><description>The Australian sharemarket has experienced its worst single-day drop since April, with all 11 sectors finishing in the red. For more, Rena Sarumpaet spoke with Perpetual’s Head of Investment Strategy, Matt Sherwood. Plus, Australia’s GDP expanded by a larger-than-expected 0.6% in the June quarter. SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Goncalves spoke with NAB Chief Economist Sally Auld about what that means for the economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76b3432d097b0c048c854c1813b1b733</guid></item><item><title>20,000 more aged care packages more quickly after Labor agrees to Coalition deal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/20-000-more-aged-care-packages-more-quickly-after-labor-agrees-to-coalition-deal/pdu4c7kvr</link><description>20,000 more home care packages are to be available to vulnerable older Australians after the federal government was forced to make a deal with the Coalition. It was the first major test faced by Labor since it was re-elected, which was cornered in the senate to make changes to its aged care reform policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd020b2e1fadbd229f3a864f66e4e853</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 4 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-4-september-2025/6tsull01j</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec2718b67b168f48fb689b8d3154b80e</guid></item><item><title>Liberals distance themselves from Price&amp;apos;s Indian migrant remark as backlash grows</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/liberals-distance-themselves-from-prices-indian-migrant-remark-as-backlash-grows/f4471dxhb</link><description>The Northern Territory senator falsely claimed Labor was prioritising Indian migrants to bolster its vote. She walked back the remarks, but later said she did not believe she had anything to apologise for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e54eec2128623fa36f0aa6ac1bdf36d</guid></item><item><title>After Australia&amp;apos;s economic surprise, here&amp;apos;s what could happen to your mortgage</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/after-australias-economic-surprise-heres-what-could-happen-to-your-mortgage/pl4mjloqq</link><description>Public holidays and the latest release of a video game console were all important elements in Australia&amp;apos;s recent GDP growth, something that might mean there may not be many interest rate cuts left to come.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ec63d565519799ed7afcc96fa470ba5</guid></item><item><title>Is Victoria Australia&amp;apos;s crime state and what does it mean for insurance premiums?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/is-victoria-australias-crime-state-and-what-does-it-mean-for-insurance-premiums/iqp477ah1</link><description>Car theft claims rose to a record $233m in Victoria last financial year, but fell in every other state so Stephanie Youssef speaks with Insuance Council of Australia CEO Andrew Hall to find out what can be done about it and what it means for premiums, plus SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves takes a closer look at the sharemarket with Ben Clark from TMS Private.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5522aef409671e89a18893236459103b</guid></item><item><title>Xi’s &amp;apos;new world order&amp;apos;, Indonesia unrest &amp;amp; Thailand’s political plight</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/xis-new-world-order-indonesia-unrest-thailands-political-plight/gf52cf61m</link><description>In this episode: China’s military parade and its guests of honour the US media has dubbed ‘the Axis of Upheaval’, protesters mobilise across Indonesia as parliamentary allowances trigger mass unrest. Plus, Thailand faces yet another political crisis while environmental concerns escalate across the border in Myanmar. And the holographic warning to all would-be criminals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a301c53679e2f46c08e8310db39c9bd</guid></item><item><title>The paradox at the heart of calls to end &amp;apos;mass migration&amp;apos; in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-paradox-at-the-heart-of-calls-to-end-mass-migration-in-australia/u6c8ekkaz</link><description>Community leaders say Senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price’s comments are fuelling division, as experts warn migrants are being unfairly blamed for housing and cost of living pressures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62e00b54e2b9b6bcd63b79e2a26a835c</guid></item><item><title>A blood moon will soon be visible across Australia. Here&amp;apos;s everything you need to know</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/a-blood-moon-will-soon-be-visible-across-australia-heres-everything-you-need-to-know/suf9uujsc</link><description>This will be the final chance for Australians to see the blood moon in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8a8c415acf18bee03021b9e59682070</guid></item><item><title>Are neo-Nazis REALLY gaining traction in Australia?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/are-neo-nazis-really-gaining-traction-in-australia/hi4h1lcnw</link><description>What was sold as a rally against mass immigration had far right ideology from the start. With neo-Nazis attending the rally and attempting to recruit new members, is far-right extremism on the rise in Australia? Dr Callum Jones and Professor Greg Barton break down what&amp;apos;s behind these rallies, and how the government should respond.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6631df6c77df81a81e2dc6666893c110</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 5 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-5-september-2025/dn8y3bjig</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09f805b8314d81e4ff90e19d59400831</guid></item><item><title>Aftershocks hit Afghanistan after more than 2,200 people die in earthquakes</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/afghanistan-earthquakes-aftershocks/7l4iuyi72</link><description>Two aftershocks have struck Afghanistan in the space of 12 hours, after a series of quakes that have devastated parts of the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad5f990ac6ba2ed76bc915f19940c41d</guid></item><item><title>Taxpayer hit or investment? Australia&amp;apos;s 2035 emissions target raises $500bn question</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/530-billion-dollar-road-to-net-zero-explained/c4wh5abq3</link><description>As the government is set to announce Australia&amp;apos;s 2035 emissions goal, the Business Council of Australia warns an ambitious goal could carry a $500 billion price tag. The Coalition says the figure represents a warning of soaring costs but others say it&amp;apos;s an investment opportunity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">629b5bb51db63d4cafb03c6341d3a8fb</guid></item><item><title>ARIA chart changes to bring diversity of artists - and is the RBA done with cutting interest rates?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/aria-chart-changes-to-bring-diversity-of-artists-and-is-the-rba-done-with-cutting-interest-rates/7qp73zdz6</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with ARIA CEO Annabelle Herd about the changes to the ARIA Charts will highlight diverse artists in the industry, Madeline Dunk from ANZ explains why she thinks the RBA may be done cutting interest rates, and Bryce Anderson from Morningstar goes through the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29ae3a67eb9f2f8cb68d64e44190573c</guid></item><item><title>Gob has been making rafts in his local river his whole life. It&amp;apos;s never made him sick until now</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-this-river-ended-up-with-arsenic-levels-three-times-higher-than-the-safe-limit/5r0buyf12</link><description>Several major rivers flowing across the border from Myanmar to Thailand have been contaminated with dangerously high levels of arsenic, threatening to cause a public health crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d5cbc117f5dd1db1f7bf8ce7fde711f</guid></item><item><title>Gob has been making rafts in his local river his whole life. It&amp;apos;s never made him sick until now</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-rare-earth-mining-is-destroying-vital-rivers/5r0buyf12</link><description>Several major rivers flowing across the border from Myanmar to Thailand have been contaminated with dangerously high levels of arsenic, threatening to cause a public health crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">099299c6b157b78a58d625ca13a16916</guid></item><item><title>Anti-immigration rallies ignore Australia&amp;apos;s economic dependence on migration</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/anti-immigration-rallies-ignore-australias-economic-dependence-on-migration/gez59p6r5</link><description>Australia in anti-immigration marches.At the heart of what organisers called the &amp;apos;March for Australia&amp;apos; rallies was a call to end &amp;quot;mass migration&amp;quot;, which protesters claimed is to blame for issues like the housing crisis and rise in cost of living. Experts say a paradox exists in the anti-immigration ideas put forward at these rallies: the very people protesters want fewer of are the ones propping up the nation&amp;apos;s economy, workforce, and future.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faec4584bdc2aef11e3ce223ecdbed89</guid></item><item><title>How a grandmother&amp;apos;s curry tells the story of a family&amp;apos;s migration journey</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/how-a-grandmothers-curry-tells-the-story-of-a-familys-migration-journey/i14qux4th</link><description>Making a chicken curry on stage is not what you would usually expect when visiting the theatre. But for actor Joshua Jamil Hinton, it&amp;apos;s the centrepiece of his show, due to open in Brisbane this month, telling his story of living between different cultures and grappling with his own identity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb11456a496394e0ae0104a778f0b51d</guid></item><item><title>Loveness says she experienced racism while working as a nurse. She isn&amp;apos;t the only one</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/racism-nursing-nsw-report/f3go0btpx</link><description>A new report has shed light on the experiences of racism nurses and midwives from culturally and linguistically diverse backgrounds face at work.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1fd1a409a6a7af6ad4fe868b697ecfa</guid></item><item><title>A surfer&amp;apos;s death in Sydney could stir up the shark net debate. So why are they so controversial?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sydney-surfer-shark-attack-death-shark-net-controversy/wv1hqtzrn</link><description>A fatal shark attack on Sydney&amp;apos;s Northern Beaches has come amid debates about the efficacy and environmental effects of shark nets. So do they actually protect swimmers, and what are the alternatives?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17612a2e8210fdd34cd3db530ec9abe3</guid></item><item><title>Beaches closed after fatal shark attack on Sydney&amp;apos;s Northern Beaches</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/beaches-closed-after-fatal-shark-attack-on-sydneys-northern-beaches/4izgbuqp2</link><description>Drones are being used to monitor shark activity, after a fatality on Sydney&amp;apos;s Northern Beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a6b373d6edce7c2ba12ce1456e229c4</guid></item><item><title>Melanie was sceptical of this underutilised cancer treatment. It saved her life</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cancer-patients-are-missing-out-on-this-life-saving-treatment/7gvsskz2v</link><description>One in five eligible Australian cancer patients never receives this form of treatment, according to research cited by Australian oncologists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa19076cff7c5e7f80ef947e1b65f922</guid></item><item><title>An Australian couple bought a French palace for $1.2m. Strangers are helping pay to restore it</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/an-australian-couple-bought-a-french-palace-for-1-2m-strangers-are-helping-pay-to-restore-it/yhko3767h</link><description>Palatial French estates are being snapped up by overseas buyers for less than a median-priced home in Sydney. But the initial outlay is usually just the start of long and expensive restoration journey. One Australian couple is funding their project in unique ways.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1f0196efa288448d47ab6bb196f5524</guid></item><item><title>Calls for justice after two boys stabbed to death in &amp;apos;heinous&amp;apos; Melbourne attack</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/two-boys-stabbed-to-death-in-targeted-melbourne-attack/n2pfjf50a</link><description>Two boys have been killed in western Melbourne in what police suspect is a series of targeted attacks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a001df7eaf16b49f1a626d97d73bbceb</guid></item><item><title>Hope and hate: how governments around the world are responding to &amp;apos;illegal&amp;apos; immigration</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/hope-and-hate-how-governments-around-the-world-are-responding-to-illegal-immigration/8uvravt9r</link><description>Recently, local news headlines have been dominated by stories about anti-immigration rallies which were held across Australia on the last day of August. But it&amp;apos;s not just in Australia where migration has created such deep feelings - it&amp;apos;s also an issue that has been front and centre in the US as Donald Trump fulfils his election campaign promise to carry out mass deportations. There are now at least a million fewer immigrants in the US, raising questions about the impact of their absence on key industries like agriculture and construction. Migration is also a major concern in Europe, which has long grappled with what to do with the scores of people fleeing war and poverty in their home countries. This episode of the TOO HARD BASKET focuses on these complexities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94a74b43b5d6abf4754d72ad1f63660e</guid></item><item><title>Australian women are living longer but it&amp;apos;s not all good news</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australian-women-are-living-longer-but-its-not-all-good-news/c1eyxv21t</link><description>The Australian Institute of Health and Welfare has produced a snap shot of Women’s health across the life course. While rates of cancer have gone down for women over the last 25 years, younger women continue to experience higher rates of depression and other mental health conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8056d8719478d2f56082cfc82a3f0561</guid></item><item><title>Radiotherapy could save your life: dispelling the misconceptions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/radiotherapy-could-save-your-life-dispelling-the-misconceptions/uno2r91al</link><description>Despite being a proven life-saving treatment, 1 in 5 Australians who need radiotherapy never receive it. This year, on September 7, the first-ever World Radiotherapy Awareness Day will be launched, and experts say it&amp;apos;s an opportunity to dispel fears of the treatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2be2c9a4a00462aa89c636361cd468ff</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Loved by everyone&amp;apos;: Shark attack victim remembered as community &amp;apos;keystone&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/loved-by-everyone-sydney-shark-attack-victim-remembered-as-community-keystone/0xww0e922</link><description>Tributes are being paid to Mercury Psillakis, the 57-year-old victim of a fatal shark attack on Sydney&amp;apos;s northern beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc780a6a738c4ba51a5b755e7069bf8a</guid></item><item><title>Russia unleashes biggest air barrage on Ukraine, sets government building ablaze</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/russia-attacks-main-ukrainian-government-building-for-first-time-since-war-began/gqcqphhhx</link><description>Russia fired at least 810 drones and 13 missiles at Ukraine over the weekend in a new record, according to the Ukrainian air force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8ce7ad3d0ac6461b41ef2bf9760f1d8</guid></item><item><title>I went to search a car for drugs while on duty. What happened next made me re-evaluate my life</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/greg-was-run-over-while-on-duty-it-made-the-police-detective-re-evaluate-his-life/n45nsyhh9</link><description>Police recruitment drives in response to chronic shortages have led to more people applying to join their local force. But what were the factors that led to the shortages in the first place?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9049ee608eae75f0ac91bb2c95569d0a</guid></item><item><title>PM Ishiba&amp;apos;s resignation plunges Japan into political uncertainty. Here&amp;apos;s what happens next</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/shigeru-ishibas-resignation-plunges-japan-into-political-uncertainty-as-leadership-race-looms/x6ajr5l8d</link><description>Since Shigeru Ishiba came to power in October 2024, his ruling coalition has lost its majority in both houses of parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc6dbc974d4d16e496a7659fffd5cc4e</guid></item><item><title>Massive drone attack on Kyiv sees Government buildings hit for the first time</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/massive-drone-attack-on-kyiv-sees-government-buildings-hit-for-the-first-time/s1687j8a7</link><description>Russia’s heaviest drone and missile barrage since the war began has struck Kyiv’s Cabinet of Ministers building, leaving four dead, including an infant. Ukraine is now calling for greater global support and tougher sanctions on Russia, targeting its economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6de8f7dbf9936674a82b1142c83cecb9</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 8th September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-8th-september-2025/61mlt1juv</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38941ecffd40a862ef31ae721b722543</guid></item><item><title>Woolworths and Coles say underpayment court decision could cost them $1 billion</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/woolworths-and-coles-say-underpayment-court-decision-could-cost-them-1-billion/yvdzqzkcr</link><description>The supermarket giants were found not to have complied with their obligations to keep accurate employment records and paid workers&amp;apos; salaries without tracking other entitlements.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">636596933cf8b494e7c1090adaaf96d8</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Not serious about ceasefire&amp;apos;: What Russia&amp;apos;s major attack means for the war in Ukraine</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/russias-biggest-air-attack-yet-could-prolong-war-in-ukraine/4ayseob3b</link><description>The strike on Kyiv is less about causing damage, but more a signal from Russian President Vladimir Putin towards the West, an expert says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a3e9c7b045a4a1528d9d4fb8e1349cc</guid></item><item><title>K-pop is a global phenomenon. Some of its biggest stars are from Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/k-pop-korea-australia-rose-blackpink-stray-kids/vexkcpgn1</link><description>From BLACKPINK&amp;apos;s Rosé to Stray Kids&amp;apos; Bang Chan and Felix, Australia is slowly making its presence in Korean pop music felt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b529a9ae6fa43f25ffe64f8507a9b171</guid></item><item><title>Fed up with flight delays? Passengers could soon get refunds under new scheme</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fed-up-with-flight-delays-the-federal-government-is-looking-at-refunds-other-compensation/yh0nvmjdw</link><description>The federal government aims to implement a new consumer protection scheme for travellers, which could lead to refunds and the establishment of a new complaints-handling body to address flight disruptions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">381db833a7c74adb20cc9f1335ccc8c0</guid></item><item><title>Weak US data spurs rate cut chance, and the supermarkets court case</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/weak-us-data-spurs-rate-cut-chance-and-the-supermarkets-court-case/hxkq8noia</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Raymond Chan from Morgans about the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action including the weak US jobs data, a rebalancing of the market&amp;apos;s main indexes and the potential implications of a supermarkets underpayments court case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd0d8ba22d0571807220c65c575aac5a</guid></item><item><title>The new regional hotspot that&amp;apos;s seen a 1,500 per cent surge of city folk</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/new-regional-hotspot-surge-city-folk-albury/c7cjpr0yj</link><description>More city dwellers are packing their bags and heading for this regional border location, according to the latest Regional Movers Index.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf13cee1fb8316fb523acbc4757535f0</guid></item><item><title>Logging halted to create a koala retreat</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/logging-halted-to-create-a-koala-retreat/64fd0qz5b</link><description>Australia will halt logging in a large stretch of woodland on the east coast to create a retreat for koalas, in an attempt to save the local population from extinction. The announcement, which will impact six timber mills and hundreds of workers, has caused outrage in the forestry industry. New South Wales Premier Chris Minns says the decision wasn&amp;apos;t taken lightly and those affected will be supported.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cde7f4cc5de291c527a8992240b314a2</guid></item><item><title>Six killed, 20 injured in gun attack on East Jerusalem bus stop</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/six-killed-20-injured-in-gun-attack-on-east-jerusalem-bus-stop/oei3mvzop</link><description>Six civilians were killed and 20 injured when two Palestinian gunmen opened fire at Jerusalem’s Ramot Junction bus stop, sending commuters running in terror. Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu vowed Israel would retaliate, linking the assault to Israel’s ongoing war in Gaza, where airstrikes have destroyed dozens of high-rise buildings and a ground invasion is imminent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c64e99130ad2f25835fecaad0487656</guid></item><item><title>Banksy mural at Royal Courts of Justice swiftly covered after appearing overnight</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/banksy-mural-at-royal-courts-of-justice-swiftly-covered-after-appearing-overnight/q2kpfb4i8</link><description>The new Banksy mural appeared to be a commentary on the arrest of hundreds of demonstrators in London for their support of proscribed terrorist organisation Palestine Action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">640bffb71b07374da6148ed5f690ab17</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 9 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-9-september-2025/7pl65i7q0</link><description>A Five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">645638e8c6be4a78aaa6378a1dca6105</guid></item><item><title>French political fiasco as Macron faces finding fifth new PM in 24 months</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/french-political-fiasco-as-macron-faces-finding-fifth-new-pm-in-24-months/2493813c4</link><description>France is facing a new political crisis after the country&amp;apos;s parliament voted to oust its Prime Minister, François Bayrou. It comes as part of the opposition party&amp;apos;s plan to bring down the government in the face of increasing national debt, and a deepening political crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">171ed2d54cac1d81c171fa129cf2770e</guid></item><item><title>ANZ slashes 3,500 jobs, are there more to come?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/anz-slashes-3-500-jobs-are-there-more-to-come/jxdumykdc</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves takes a closer look at ANZ&amp;apos;s decision to cut 3,500 employees and 1,000 contractors and what it means for the sector with Nathan Zaia from Morningstar and Damien Boey from Wilson Asset Management.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">223c7b8b1e2de62d573cecc3428e0fb9</guid></item><item><title>Albanese in the Pacific: Australia&amp;apos;s struggle for influence — and a key hope</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anthony-albanese-heads-to-solomon-islands-for-pacific-islands-forum/3pvtc942h</link><description>This year&amp;apos;s Pacific Islands Forum has become a flashpoint in a broader tussle for influence between China and Australia and China and Taiwan — and is also likely to see Australia firming up its bid to co-host a major climate conference with the Pacific in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bc95b180b079310ef361ba586f51ac3</guid></item><item><title>Gaza aid flotilla reports second attack after Tunisian authorities say &amp;apos;no drones&amp;apos; involved in first</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gaza-bound-ship-carrying-two-australians-allegedly-struck-by-drone/y5i09a63n</link><description>The vessel was off the coast of Tunisia when it was struck by a drone, organisers of the Global Sumud Flotilla allege. Tunisian authorities have rejected the claim, saying the explosion originated inside the boat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c67d16c1252314a3439a15f66585085</guid></item><item><title>Gaza aid flotilla reports second attack after Tunisian authorities say &amp;apos;no drones&amp;apos; involved in first</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gaza-aid-flotilla-reports-second-drone-attack-off-tunisian-coast/y5i09a63n</link><description>The vessel was off the coast of Tunisia when it was struck by a drone, organisers of the Global Sumud Flotilla allege. Tunisian authorities have rejected the claim, saying the explosion originated inside the boat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db814b20420d90fab30f2f59ce811cb6</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians flee Gaza City as Israel airdrops leaflets ordering them to leave</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/palestinians-gaza-city-israel-ordered-leave-assault/219e65653</link><description>Israel has warned it will launch a full-scale assault on Gaza City.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bbb96b8d1961bf4990549689d635b533</guid></item><item><title>The simple shopping swap that could save you $4,000 a year</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-simple-shopping-swap-that-could-save-you-4-000-a-year/v30obn3he</link><description>A comparison group examined the cost of 20 staple items at two major supermarkets. Here&amp;apos;s what it found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00a0f1ae3c3076476213a122c781625b</guid></item><item><title>A car bomb exploded outside my work. Three decades on, thunder still scares me</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/i-was-a-constable-on-duty-when-a-car-bomb-exploded-hearing-thunder-still-scares-me/cd9wvvk4h</link><description>On 27 March 1986, Debra Richardson was at her desk at Russell Street Police Headquarters in Melbourne when a car bomb detonated on the street outside. The former senior constable says the explosion, that killed fellow officer Angela Rose Taylor, changed her life forever.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d903e20f4572846327009362e7e2065b</guid></item><item><title>Lifting caps from first home buyer scheme will help some but fuel wider price rise</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lifting-caps-from-first-home-buyer-scheme-will-help-some-but-fuel-wider-price-rise/qufj0whee</link><description>The federal government will expand its Home Guarantee Scheme in October, lifting income and property caps to give first-time buyers greater access, but it will also fast-track price rises, a new analysis has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71f1d32104dd7cab1f85b9385a5703e4</guid></item><item><title>Lifting caps from first home buyer scheme will help some but fuel wider price rise</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lifting-caps-from-first-home-buyer-scheme-will-help-some-but-fuel-wider-price-increases/qufj0whee</link><description>The federal government will expand its Home Guarantee Scheme in October, lifting income and property caps to give first-time buyers greater access, but it will also fast-track price rises, a new analysis has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ec3a25aa5c73604ea010b377fa16240</guid></item><item><title>Lifting caps from first home buyer scheme will help some but fuel wider price rise</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/expanded-home-scheme-lifts-caps-but-risks-fuelling-price-rise/qufj0whee</link><description>The federal government will expand its Home Guarantee Scheme in October, lifting income and property caps to give first-time buyers greater access, but it will also fast-track price rises, a new analysis has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1e36aab6f1de41d7d5bf5fcd6f3c098</guid></item><item><title>Will Israel&amp;apos;s attack on Hamas officials in Qatar derail peace talks?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/will-israels-attack-on-hamas-officials-in-qatar-derail-peace-talks/eduploh5d</link><description>Israel has struck the Qatari capital of Doha, killing five Hamas members and one Qatari security official. It has led to an outcry from Qatar, Washington, and humanitarian groups, with concern the strike will jeopardise fragile ceasefire talks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a063e8e93e28ef32936c9b1eecebc735</guid></item><item><title>Australian-Nepalis dismayed and distressed at protests and violence in Nepal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australian-nepalis-dismayed-and-distressed-at-protests-and-violence-in-nepal/7118llp22</link><description>Nepal&amp;apos;s Prime Minister has resigned amid anti-government protests, as demonstrators set fire to Parliament and the homes of some of the country&amp;apos;s top political leaders. It comes as a &amp;quot;Gen Z&amp;quot; protest movement was triggered by a ban on social media, which has now been overturned. Concerns have been raised by the Nepali community in Australia, calling for peace in the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cc0d9588d0163904aafcb98796f269a</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 10 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-10-september-2025/hh3zlp7ve</link><description>A daily 5-minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41a086b5616544320d925dff8713e1aa</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Absolutely reckless&amp;apos;: NATO condemns Russia&amp;apos;s violation of Polish airspace</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/poland-says-it-has-shot-down-russian-drones-violating-its-airspace/sw40mxumz</link><description>Poland invoked NATO&amp;apos;s Article 4 for urgent talks after Russian drones violated the country&amp;apos;s airspace.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">687de4b007b0d5151ac4159260821c79</guid></item><item><title>How much you need for a comfortable retirement? | NAB latest to cut jobs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/how-much-you-need-for-a-comfortable-retirement-nab-latest-to-cut-jobs/lvwy0rsjq</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Marcus Bogdan from Blackmore Capital about the day&amp;apos;s market action including why banks seem to be on a job cutting cycle, plus Stephnie Youssef speaks with ASFA CEO Mary Delahunty to find out how much money is needed in super to fund a comfortable retirement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89a3a01df5e55e9682b60616942b381f</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Incredibly rare&amp;apos;: The million-dollar question on Dezi Freeman&amp;apos;s arrest reward</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/1-million-is-being-offered-for-the-arrest-of-dezi-freeman-but-do-financial-rewards-work/1vwshxni5</link><description>There&amp;apos;s $1 million available for anyone who can help facilitate the arrest of accused double murderer Dezi Freeman. But do financial incentives actually help solve crimes?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc9acaf306e3f7b3749755fce0ac903c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Wrongful act&amp;apos;: Vanuatu warns Australia may break international law if gas project goes ahead</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/wrongful-act-vanuatu-warns-australia-may-break-international-law-if-gas-project-goes-ahead/gk5isms7e</link><description>A senior Pacific minister has warned Australia&amp;apos;s energy transition is no longer defensible, following a landmark legal ruling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab73c4f0c023245fa33132c7c7d6af4f</guid></item><item><title>Trump &amp;apos;filled with grief&amp;apos; over Charlie Kirk&amp;apos;s shooting. Here&amp;apos;s what to know about the right-wing activist</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/conservative-influencer-and-trump-ally-charlie-kirk-shot-at-us-university-event/tdpq9ytcy</link><description>The shooting prompted condemnation of political violence and calls for unity from US leaders across the political spectrum.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4831e4dd545ff5c0b19978dfa1e19281</guid></item><item><title>Qatar says &amp;apos;regional response under way&amp;apos; after Israeli strike on Doha</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/qatar-says-regional-response-under-way-after-israeli-strike-on-doha/4zl864b98</link><description>Gulf leaders have rallied in solidarity with Qatar as global condemnation over the strikes grows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8255137c41c0a31613dc27dc03babd23</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Girt by sea&amp;apos; explained: National anthem now in 60+ languages</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/girt-by-sea-explained-national-anthem-now-in-60-languages/z1ycvk2zl</link><description>Ever wondered what &amp;quot;girt by sea&amp;quot; means, especially if your first language isn&amp;apos;t English? SBS Audio has brought Australia’s national anthem to life in more than 60 languages, so everyone can understand the words behind the music.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04079c2c5f6e829b610f96ef72903390</guid></item><item><title>Bali floods leave at least 19 people dead and five missing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bali-floods-leave-15-people-dead-and-10-missing/05funve0t</link><description>Floodwaters rose to over 2.5 metres in some areas, with more than 800 people forced into temporary shelters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ade30020ec35fafac954ba6dfcbdbe8e</guid></item><item><title>Bali floods leave at least 19 people dead and five missing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bali-floods-leave-19-people-dead-and-five-missing/05funve0t</link><description>Floodwaters rose to over 2.5 metres in some areas, with more than 800 people forced into temporary shelters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86c7ef56559860dfa062ba2b88867059</guid></item><item><title>Bali floods leave at least 19 people dead and five missing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bali-floods-at-least-nine-killed-and-two-missing-indonesian-officials-say/05funve0t</link><description>Floodwaters rose to over 2.5 metres in some areas, with more than 800 people forced into temporary shelters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f257de43412c3dd175d5d74472facf97</guid></item><item><title>Bali floods leave at least 19 people dead and five missing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/indonesia-flash-floods-leave-15-dead-while-10-are-missing-officials-says/05funve0t</link><description>Floodwaters rose to over 2.5 metres in some areas, with more than 800 people forced into temporary shelters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">501cb2e8781d2674e83ad31c22ddba0f</guid></item><item><title>Europe on high alert after Russian drones shot down over Poland</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/europe-on-high-alert-after-russian-drones-shot-down-over-poland/48cdawj73</link><description>Poland has reported its most serious airspace breach since Russia’s invasion of Ukraine, after nearly 20 drones entered from Belarus and Ukraine. European leaders have condemned Moscow for reckless escalation, with the Kremlin saying such accusations are baseless.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e789191f3e56aad122212e8a88c4f70c</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 11 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-11-september-2025/cmk9s3xbb</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d85ecaf226af85d3584b0eef3f689ef0</guid></item><item><title>Australians on Gaza flotilla say they remain &amp;apos;steadfast&amp;apos; after alleged drone attacks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-on-gaza-flotilla-steadfast-after-alleged-drone-attacks/ybr5gq8x0</link><description>There are believed to be about 10 Australians involved in the Global Sumud Flotilla, which is attempting to break Israel&amp;apos;s naval blockade of Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ee2e658fa589e3c6d2762554aa8e9b1</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I won&amp;apos;t be silenced&amp;apos;: Jacinta Price axed from Coalition frontbench in fallout over Indian migration remarks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/i-wont-be-silenced-jacinta-price-axed-from-coalition-frontbench-in-fallout-over-indian-migrantion-remarks/geqqnw8vj</link><description>Northern Territory Senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price has been removed from the Coalition frontbench, following fallout from remarks she made about Indian migrants. Sydney Lang takes a look at how the last week unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13bcf7a28a8f461d56412fee1914bde1</guid></item><item><title>Israel strikes Qatar, why it&amp;apos;s been a bad week to be a PM &amp;amp; the real &amp;apos;Succession&amp;apos; finale</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israel-strikes-qatar-why-its-been-a-bad-week-to-be-a-pm-the-real-succession-finale/v3tnyfj2b</link><description>Israel&amp;apos;s strike on Qatar blows up ceasefire talks, the prime ministers of Nepal, Japan and France depart in a hurry, and Albanese battles for influence in the Pacific, while Moldova battles to stop Putin’s influence ahead of elections. Plus, the Murdoch succession is finally settled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7e0eaabc8585d03e4f518e25a324473</guid></item><item><title>What you might not know about tornadoes in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-you-might-not-know-about-tornadoes-in-australia/dfw1ghg9x</link><description>There are about 60-80 tornadoes each year in Australia, according to a meteorologist. But you&amp;apos;re unlikely to see them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab96cfe0fd73d7a74e83c59b8c3dea29</guid></item><item><title>US stocks benefit from Oracle surge; home ownership dream slipping</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-stocks-benefit-from-oracle-surge-home-ownership-dream-slipping/lva29gz3x</link><description>The ASX 200 has closed 0.3% lower with healthcare stocks dragging the index down, despite gains by gold miners. That’s almost despite Oracle’s shares soaring almost 40% in its best one-day performance since 1992, lifting the S&amp;amp;P 500 and other global markets to record highs. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Mark Gardner from MPC Markets. Plus, new analysis from Domain shows the dream of owning a home is becoming further out of reach – with deposit hurdles, coupled with climbing house prices and mortgage repayments, driving the sharpest generational divide in decades. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Domain’s research chief, Dr Nicola Powell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09067c9fdf20c9801c040532d3c16c92</guid></item><item><title>Sydney sets 146-year rainfall record as severe weather eases</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sydney-sets-146-year-rainfall-record-as-severe-weather-eases/1a8fcxhhy</link><description>Over the 24 hours to 9am on Thursday, Sydney received a total of 122mm of rain, marking its heaviest daily rainfall for September since 1879.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d1c543899ec6a382083579988d9ea50</guid></item><item><title>Julie Bishop hits back at bullying claims and vows to stay at ANU after deputy quits</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/julie-bishop-vows-to-stay-on-as-anu-chancellor-after-vice-chancellor-quits-following-months-of-controversy/k2mna1162</link><description>ANU chancellor Julie Bishop has rejected bullying allegations, and has vowed to serve out her term after vice-chancellor Genevieve Bell quit following months of controversy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f32e7cf1ee9284ea22bb713d365f37b</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;People starting to act out&amp;apos;: How the Charlie Kirk shooting suggests a &amp;apos;vicious spiral&amp;apos; in the US</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/people-starting-to-act-out-how-the-charlie-kirk-shooting-suggests-a-vicious-spiral-in-the-us/a105398va</link><description>Is the US seeing a rise in political violence, and could it spread to Australia?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeedaa8ed91e546ae737e8dd9f9ef74f</guid></item><item><title>Former Brazilian president Jair Bolsonaro sentenced to 27 years in jail for plotting coup</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jair-bolsonaro-brazil-president-coup-conviction/g4yjsnf6c</link><description>The firebrand ex-president was convicted of plotting a coup after his 2022 election loss, and accused of acting &amp;quot;with the purpose of eroding democracy and institutions&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d23e8b2153625ef3c78983ad7017de1e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Doesn&amp;apos;t cut the mustard&amp;apos;: Indian Australian community leaders demand Price apology</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-indian-community-leaders-demand-price-apology/3t2yqrt2p</link><description>While welcoming an apology from Opposition leader Sussan Ley, one Indian Australian community figure said &amp;quot;the Liberal Party has their work cut out to repair the damage&amp;quot; caused by senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price&amp;apos;s comments on Indian immigration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e627c942f9c9434aaec1553129c384be</guid></item><item><title>Ireland says it will boycott Eurovision 2026 if Israel is allowed to participate</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ireland-israel-eurovision-2026-participation-gaza/yf4scypng</link><description>Irish broadcaster RTE said it would be &amp;quot;unconscionable&amp;quot; to take part in the contest alongside Israel, given its ongoing assault on Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62cffd1bb18419483053a0ea72f1e5f3</guid></item><item><title>Brazil&amp;apos;s former President Bolsonaro sentenced to jail</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/brazils-former-president-bolsonaro-sentenced-to-jail/v1s50igk9</link><description>Brazil&amp;apos;s former President, Jair Bolsonaro has been sentenced to prison after being convicted of plotting a coup to remain in power after losing the 2022 election. Mr Bolsonaro, who has denied any wrongdoing, has not attended the court and has only sent his lawyers.He is the first former president in the country&amp;apos;s history to be convicted for attacking democracy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d59efe136133d39a3417df21ab88006</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 12 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-12-september-2025/la1ex1kfj</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6152830b72d22eecc9fd00ff5b880c68</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk shooting: More clues as search for shooter intensifies</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/charlie-kirk-shooting-more-clues-as-search-for-shooter-intensifies/t1xz9eoy5</link><description>The hunt for the killer of conservative activist Charlie Kirk continues, with US federal investigators pursuing new leads in Utah. The FBI has released images of the suspect and is offering a reward of up to A$150,000 (US$$100,000) for information.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1faa8d1a144aa699f9be42e7e44c86f9</guid></item><item><title>A 5-minute guide to the World Athletics Championships – and how to watch from Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/your-guide-to-2025-world-athletics-championships/p7wrafboj</link><description>Australia has kicked off one of its biggest track and field campaigns in history, with a record number of athletes in Tokyo to contest the 2025 World Athletics Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6857921f0cef4d27931a5efa26154bbe</guid></item><item><title>Federal government approves Woodside gas project extension, with some conditions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/federal-government-approves-woodside-gas-project-extension-with-some-conditions/goc08nvfr</link><description>The country&amp;apos;s largest gas project&amp;apos;s potential operating life has been extended to 2070.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a12ecbec94d2b938be29e759dfc967ac</guid></item><item><title>Why the final approval for North West Shelf gas plant has Indigenous groups and environmentalists worried</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/why-the-final-approval-for-north-west-shelf-gas-plant-has-indigenous-groups-and-environmentalists-worried/v12sc9i5e</link><description>The federal government has given the final approval for the Woodside North West Shelf gas project with a series of conditions. The approval comes ahead of the Albanese government&amp;apos;s announcement of a 2035 emissions reduction target, and after Australia emphasised its commitment to tackling climate change to Pacific leaders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0996f56dc4418abd3998966386a8cca9</guid></item><item><title>Former Virgin CEO’s $50m payday; &amp;amp; is a US rate cut locked in?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/former-virgin-ceos-50m-payday-is-a-us-rate-cut-locked-in/l8f9hkzjz</link><description>Former Virgin Australia CEO Jayne Hrdlicka is collecting a $49.9 million pay packet, which includes 10 million shares, as revealed in the company’s annual report. For more on this and the ASX-200’s performance this week, Stephanie Youssef spoke with IG Markets analyst Tony Sycamore. Plus, US inflation has risen 2.9% in August, paving the way for the first US interest rate cut of the year when the Federal Reserve meets next week. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with AMP Chief Economist Shane Oliver.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">926fab565460dcb2749e5787e0bab9e0</guid></item><item><title>$548.5 million: The price the government is willing to pay &amp;apos;to avoid a public trial&amp;apos; of robodebt</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/robodebt-class-action-compensation-whats-next-for-victims/yturl57q3</link><description>The robodebt class action settlement has been billed as the largest of its kind in Australian history. However, one expert argues it represents &amp;quot;accountability avoided&amp;quot;, leaving questions of misfeasance unanswered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb35343dd6e2c4f482035b0f9dc74135</guid></item><item><title>Bruce McAvaney on Australia&amp;apos;s emerging athletics &amp;apos;golden age&amp;apos; and the run that inspired us all</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australias-emerging-golden-age-and-the-run-that-inspired-us-all/qtxwgdtgj</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;golden age&amp;quot; in athletics is gathering steam, esteemed sports commentator Bruce McAvaney says, as the World Athletics Championships gets underway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12469788e8cbbc9ab99a655b9d1b3dd5</guid></item><item><title>A suspect arrested in the shooting of Charlie Kirk | Morning Bulletin 13 September</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-suspect-arrested-in-the-shooting-of-charlie-kirk-morning-bulletin-13-september/a2wlwmlsw</link><description>In this bulletin, A suspect arrested in the shooting of Charlie Kirk as local supporters hold a vigil; Australia&amp;apos;s Muslim community welcomes a report into Islamophobia; and in sport, Australian basketball star Tiana Mangakahia dies of cancer at the age of 30.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4c95131de8bfa331f42b43694b49170</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Three years after the death of Mahsa Amini in Iran, what&amp;apos;s changed?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-three-years-after-the-death-of-mahsa-amini-in-iran-whats-changed/gn6snvk02</link><description>Dr Dara Conduit at the University of Melbourne explains the impact of the death in custody of Mahsa Jina Amini three years ago on women&amp;apos;s rights in Iran today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40f0a02fa058d6a63a37c49475557849</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Supermarket sweep: How making wise choices could save you money</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-supermarket-sweep-how-making-wise-choices-could-save-you-money/h0onz3s69</link><description>Making the switch from branded products to a store&amp;apos;s home brand alternatives could save shoppers thousands of dollars each year at checkout, according to a financial comparison website. SBS&amp;apos;s Cameron Carr has been finding out more from Compare the Market spokesman Phillip Portman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46c5b54df60d5bfd31cffb7f7816a7a9</guid></item><item><title>PM&amp;apos;s wardrobe malfunction and SUV diplomacy: What you missed from the Pacific summit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-you-missed-from-the-pacific-islands-forum/87abvie53</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s fossil fuel exports remain a source of tension as Pacific leaders double down on their support for a bid to co-host global climate talks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e8c889433678ad7787f91cfa68e8584</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Paradigm shift&amp;apos;: Over 2 million homes to get internet speed boost starting this weekend</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/paradigm-shift-over-2-million-households-to-get-internet-speed-boost-this-weekend/yun6p6kua</link><description>The free speed boost is one of the biggest changes to Australian internet in history, according to one expert.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e4e40db6344bf6e5692f51b1208b2ac</guid></item><item><title>Police in Australia raise concerns ahead of protests | Afternoon Bulletin 13 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/police-in-australia-raise-concerns-ahead-of-protests-afternoon-bulletin-13-september-2025/uobvjm6fm</link><description>In this bulletin, Police are concerned about chaos, as left and right wing protests begin; Social media platforms urged to take down videos of the Charlie Kirk shooting; and in sport; Officials found to have placed hundreds of bets on races in Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ffa6752eba31ad8e0a0bb20946e7394</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We got him&amp;apos;: Authorities arrest a suspect in fatal shooting of Charlie Kirk</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/we-got-him-authorities-arrest-a-suspect-in-fatal-shooting-of-charlie-kirk/yb2y56vi5</link><description>A 22-year-old man has been arrested over the shooting death of Charlie Kirk at a Utah University. He&amp;apos;s been identified as Tyler Robinson, a Utah resident who family members say had recently become more &amp;apos;political&amp;apos; and increasingly vocal in his opposition to the conservative activist&amp;apos;s ideas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5b9492c38fe03283c54abc173f62c6e</guid></item><item><title>Nepal announces interim leader, sets election date after week of violent protests</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nepal-elections-date-interim-leader-gen-z-protests/lw4fj0gsu</link><description>Sushila Karki has become Nepal&amp;apos;s first woman prime minister, following two days of intense negotiations between the president, army chief and protest leaders behind the country&amp;apos;s worst upheaval in years, which left at least 51 people dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef4f5549e3c7082a2fee06bfd86a5079</guid></item><item><title>Muslim leaders call for more government action to mend &amp;apos;severely fractured relationship&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/islamophobia-report-muslim-leaders-call-for-more-government-action/vir8xta2w</link><description>Prominent Muslims have called on the Australian government to mend its &amp;quot;fractured&amp;quot; relationship with their community, as Anthony Albanese says he will &amp;quot;carefully consider&amp;quot; the special envoy to combat Islamophobia&amp;apos;s recommendations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb156927053370682e56d998d743a45b</guid></item><item><title>Evening News Bulletin 13 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/evening-news-bulletin-13-september-2025/vr99s3bc2</link><description>Police deployed to separate rival protests in Australia&amp;apos;s capital cities and regional centres; the widow of conservative political activist Charlie Kirk speaks out; and in sport, Australian Jai Hindley closing in on a podium finish at the Vuelta a Espana.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ef389784f5cf8a5867adb178b7b612c</guid></item><item><title>Protesters clash in Melbourne as rival rallies unfold across the country</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/protesters-clash-in-melbourne-as-rival-rallies-unfold-across-the-country/zc1vt18mt</link><description>Opposing protests took place across all capital cities and some regional areas on Saturday and, as police had predicted, things got most heated in Melbourne</description><guid isPermaLink="false">257c6581530463bd11e3e3a800defacf</guid></item><item><title>Concerns over political extremism after rival rallies held across Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/concerns-over-political-extremism-after-rival-rallies-held-across-australia/xpog5r6wa</link><description>Politicians are warning against the risks of extremism and political violence, after rival rallies were held in Australia&amp;apos;s capital cities and regional centres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c9c122776c42c5cbb71d81f2ff790f3</guid></item><item><title>Nick was a &amp;apos;subservient&amp;apos; child in church, but &amp;apos;tiny little cracks&amp;apos; eventually shattered his faith</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/medium-build-on-songwriting-after-leaving-the-church/kqdhzqhpt</link><description>It took an &amp;quot;unravelling&amp;quot; for musician Nick Carpenter to be able to reckon with his religious upbringing in America&amp;apos;s south and find his voice in songwriting. But he still thinks about the person he could have been.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">743eb4c72a0b26c411a6f28267959cae</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I&amp;apos;m ready to be arrested&amp;apos;: How women in Iran fight &amp;apos;state-sanctioned sexual violence&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-women-in-iran-fight-sexual-violence-three-years-after-mahsa-amini/9v83cmn02</link><description>Three years after the death in custody of Mahsa Jina Amini, which sparked the widespread &amp;quot;Woman, Life, Freedom&amp;quot; movement, women are still finding ways to protest against the regime&amp;apos;s new methods of crackdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc2cc7131206c3bdc0469ff032a56026</guid></item><item><title>What next for the Coalition after its &amp;apos;entirely unedifying week&amp;apos;?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-next-for-the-coalition-after-its-entirely-unedifying-week/asgpia7ch</link><description>Liberal senator Jane Hume says the Coalition is looking to &amp;quot;move on&amp;quot; after demoting colleague Jacinta Nampijinpa Price over controversial comments about Indian immigration. But what are the lessons the Coalition should draw from the episode?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b96bd7ba968acbb423e4994f2636729</guid></item><item><title>Loo scrolling: Study investigates link between this bathroom habit and a painful health condition</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/loo-scrolling-study-investigates-link-between-this-bathroom-habit-and-a-painful-health-condition/jil9sefun</link><description>Using your phone while on the toilet could be linked to an increased chance of haemorrhoids, according to a study from the United States. So if you&amp;apos;re a loo scroller, the extra time spent on the toilet could be doing you more harm than good.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d68f532b8f5de1a660dc2def01ba5438</guid></item><item><title>Competing protests in Australia&amp;apos;s major cities | Morning News Bulletin 14 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/competing-protests-in-australias-major-cities-n-morning-news-bulletin-14-september-2025/czwixtla2</link><description>Police intervene to stop protesters clashing in Melbourne; a vigil held for slain conservative activist Charlie Kirk; and in sport, Alex de Minaur crashes out of the Davis Cup in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">965a95c1c37e1fbcaa245364177b9c2a</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: The new Aged Care Act and the &amp;apos;unintended consequences&amp;apos; preventing transformational change</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-the-new-aged-care-act-and-the-unintended-consequences-preventing-transformational-change/inu3t2y1l</link><description>A new Aged Care Act is weeks away from coming into effect, but there are aspects that has the Inspector-General of Aged Care concerned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0739cf9bc163793802ea255b32f86b4c</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Is there life on Mars? New research seems to show there was, once.</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-is-there-life-on-mars-new-research-seems-to-show-there-was-once/ssg4qoqep</link><description>This week, NASA announced findings of potential biosignatures on Mars. Does that mean there&amp;apos;s proof that there was once life on Mars? In this edition of Weekend One on One, Dr Micheal Tice, geology professor at Texas A&amp;amp;M University, who&amp;apos;s involved in the ongoing research project, explains what the findings mean.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7eea0c4518eee48e07e510e3a97f336</guid></item><item><title>Torrie Lewis breaks her own Australian 100m record at World Athletics Championships 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/torrie-lewis-breaks-her-own-australian-100m-record-at-world-athletics-championships-2025/3md4p5y2e</link><description>Sprint queen Torrie Lewis has given Australia a flying start to the world athletics championships with a record-breaking 100m run.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f71bf220394240b9cf6a2cd0c7e13d1f</guid></item><item><title>Government to spend $12 billion on &amp;apos;world-class&amp;apos; AUKUS defence facility in WA</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/government-to-spend-12-billion-in-building-aukus-defence-facility-in-wa/mhnhgl41y</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has announced a $12 billion investment into a Western Australian defence precinct, which is set to bolster Australia&amp;apos;s ability to build warships and host nuclear-powered submarines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f7baf8f732f0227121154291274a55a</guid></item><item><title>Romania scrambles fighter jets in response to Russian drones | Midday News Bulletin 14 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/romania-scrambles-fighter-jets-in-response-to-russian-drones-midday-news-bulletin-14-september-2025/t52olpbhh</link><description>The government announces $1.2 billion in defence spending linked to the AUKUS agreement; Romania scrambles fighter jets in response to Russian drones; and in sport, the Lions book their spot in the AFL preliminary finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcfca782f87ad98b2de3052e87180f8e</guid></item><item><title>Australia announces more defence funding| Evening News Bulletin 14 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australia-announces-more-defence-funding-evening-news-bulletin-14-september-2025/1sz4wk20a</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s AUKUS partners will benefit from a $12 billion boost to defence spending; nine people charged in raids targeting online child abuse; and Australian sprinter Torrie Lewis through to the 100m semi final at the World Athletics Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fe9a6f12ce98aa811b768011dfd05f5</guid></item><item><title>This common bathroom habit could be doing you more damage than you think</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/toilet-phone-use-can-raise-risk-of-haemorrhoids-researchers-claim/6ck0ksg1w</link><description>Using your phone on the throne could lead to an increased risk of haemorrhoids, according to a new study, but some experts say it&amp;apos;s not the full story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7162d0e1b722b82bce8171d0b2ccf80d</guid></item><item><title>Rubio reiterates unwavering US support for Israel as dozens killed in Gaza City offensive</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rubio-reiterates-us-support-for-israel-dozens-killed-in-gaza-city/we6ro0jnl</link><description>The US secretary of state said Israel&amp;apos;s recent airstrike in Qatar was &amp;quot;not going to change the nature of our relationship with the Israelis&amp;quot; but the two nations were &amp;quot;going to have to talk about&amp;quot; its impact on Gaza ceasefire negotiations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">007bf062c640b56c6f9e467fb90ea633</guid></item><item><title>Cali lives a proud &amp;apos;trad life&amp;apos;. But a former tradwife says the lifestyle left her &amp;apos;dead inside&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/cali-lives-a-proud-trad-life-but-a-former-trad-wife-says-the-lifestyle-left-her-dead-inside/ckepi38nl</link><description>&amp;apos;Tradwife&amp;apos; influencers like Cali believe a woman’s most important roles are as a wife and a mother — and they also believe in sharing that lifestyle to their online followers. But a former tradwife says the growing popularity of this content is extremely concerning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2de39b54dd6f6c7cd9b3641db58cc6d6</guid></item><item><title>Qatari prime minister says &amp;apos;time has come to punish Israel&amp;apos; after unprecedented strike on Doha</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/qatar-pm-response-israel-strike-doha/twv76e7fp</link><description>Sheikh Mohammed bin Abdulrahman Al Thani has called on the world to reject what he called &amp;quot;double standards&amp;quot; after an Israeli strike on Doha, as Arab and Islamic leaders attend an emergency summit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db74914be97b8658131b938399a809d1</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese set to sign a defence pact with PNG | Morning Bulletin 15 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/prime-minister-anthony-albanese-set-to-sign-a-defence-pact-with-png-morning-bulletin-15-september-2025/cupwr1njz</link><description>In this bulletin, Australia&amp;apos;s Prime Minister will be signing a defence pact with Papua New Guinea; Leaders gather in Qatar&amp;apos;s capital to discuss Israel&amp;apos;s airstrikes on Doha; and in sport, Final stage of Vuelta a Espana abandoned as protestors block the circuit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8293362ba0fe056c7c1db396fa2a4485</guid></item><item><title>Albanese says Australia-PNG defence treaty on par with US and New Zealand</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/treaty-australia-papua-new-guinea-pacific-security/x532pqku7</link><description>More detail will be provided once the defence agreement is signed on Wednesday, the prime minister said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87427b510736d56e5ebf5c00c70ddfd4</guid></item><item><title>Albanese says Australia-PNG defence treaty on par with US and New Zealand</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-says-australia-png-defence-treaty-on-par-with-us-and-new-zealand/x532pqku7</link><description>More detail will be provided once the defence agreement is signed on Wednesday, the prime minister said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e94f5367ce1d5747e9a4356ca8cf3262</guid></item><item><title>Suspect in Charlie Kirk shooting &amp;apos;not cooperating&amp;apos; with investigators, Utah governor says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/suspect-in-charlie-kirk-shooting-not-co-operating-with-investigators-utah-governor-says/m2aoqggxg</link><description>Police investigating Tyler Robinson, the Utah man suspected of shooting right-wing commentator Charlie Kirk, have yet to establish a motive for the killing. Utah&amp;apos;s governor said he would be formally charged on Tuesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a005cb8cf3e5885a6f9015c407f49471</guid></item><item><title>Iranian women find new ways to resist three years on from Mahsa Amini&amp;apos;s death</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/iranian-women-find-new-ways-to-resist-three-years-on-from-mahsa-aminis-death/a77dgrlcw</link><description>In Iran, mandatory hijab laws sparked nationwide protests three years ago over death in custody of Mahsa Jina Amini. While the presence of morality police on the streets has declined, the regime says it is instead using digital tools such as citizen-watch apps, drones and facial recognition to enforce its crackdown. But women are finding new ways to resist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90eaf9e595df0c69023cd5432b31c720</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;A real slap in the face&amp;apos;: ANZ to be handed record fine for misconduct</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anz-penalties-widespread-misconduct/lezz3xmob</link><description>The penalties the financial watchdog and ANZ will request include a record $80 million fine for unconscionable conduct.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e78ee65a2954afeb22fccab5feb502c4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Does my head in&amp;apos;: Albanese closes electorate office, blaming pro-Palestinian protesters</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anthony-albanese-closes-sydney-electoral-office/j8e5qywza</link><description>Announcing the closure, the prime minister cited protesters who have &amp;quot;repeatedly blocked access&amp;quot; to the electorate office over the past two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d55484de0511cb20be369603389bcfe</guid></item><item><title>No Australians immune: What 2050 and beyond will look like for your city</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-national-climate-risk-assessment-report/mjepqlp6u</link><description>Australia is likely to experience more intense and extreme climate hazards — in some cases where people and places haven&amp;apos;t experienced them before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6597382a6317fff6e22fec7fc86056e4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;quot;widespread misconduct&amp;quot; ANZ hit with major fine | Midday News Bulletin 15 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/widespread-misconduct-anz-hit-with-major-fine-midday-news-bulletin-15-september-2025/gcu6gutyg</link><description>In this bulletin, ANZ admits to misconduct that impacted nearly 65 thousand customers, new findings that climate change could threaten the lives of three million Australians by 2090. And in football, a stellar return to the game for Sam Kerr, scoring a 100th goal for Chelsea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">427017ab23b591814127956fd388edbf</guid></item><item><title>Arab leaders urge international community to stop applying &amp;apos;double standards&amp;apos; to Israel</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/arab-leaders-urge-international-community-to-stop-applying-double-standards-to-israel/usbjwt647</link><description>An Israeli strike on Doha last week has set off a wave of condemnation, with Arab and Islamic leaders gathering in Qatar to arrive at a united response. Israel, meanwhile, is standing firm, deepening its alliance with Washington as the war in Gaza rages on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3653d263be203116438f7672fa22bbe</guid></item><item><title>Urgent calls for the federal government to adopt recommendations to combat Islamophobia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/urgent-calls-for-the-federal-government-to-adopt-the-special-envoy-to-combat-islamophobias-recommendations/y9k9vtir1</link><description>Prominent calls are being made for the federal government to adopt newly-introduced recommendations, following a report by the government-appointed Envoy to Combat Islamophobia. It follows data from the Islamophobia Register Australia, revealing a 530 per cent increase in incidents since October 7, 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f1b1f088d91a57c3e9b1941b9f6d79c</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 15th September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-15th-september-2025/sbnl9okv6</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d11c5dbd624e4b995766a4d36eb1d63f</guid></item><item><title>Adolescence star Owen Cooper becomes youngest male actor to win an Emmy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/adolescence-star-owen-cooper-youngest-male-actor-emmy-award/bs6xak09v</link><description>The four-part series he starred in recorded 140 million views in its first three months on Netflix, and drew rave reviews.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88b9cdd5a554d3787a15cef54e87bbb4</guid></item><item><title>Trillions of dollars at risk due to climate change | Evening News Bulletin 15 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trillions-of-dollars-at-risk-due-to-climate-change-evening-news-bulletin-15-september-2025/1c0ddo4zj</link><description>In this bulletin, Australia faces a wealth loss of more than 4 trillion dollars due to climate change, Victoria&amp;apos;s Premier lands in China, promoting direct links with the state. And in sport, tensions as fierce rivals India beats Pakistan at a T20 match in the Asia Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1364588fd75d95880af25d0a71c3398</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;No Australian spared&amp;apos;: National Climate Risk Assessment delivers dire warning</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/no-australian-spared-national-climate-risk-assessment-delivers-dire-warning/dv11b9bvw</link><description>Coastal hazards driven by climate change could put three million people at risk by 2090 if Australia warms by 3 degrees, according to a major body of new climate research released by the federal government. The National Climate Risk Assessment has been released, as the government prepares the ground to announce its carbon emissions reduction target for 2035.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f97c0aa4761f1a3ffcd5412c41816d0</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We take it very seriously&amp;apos;: Queenslander charged over Nazi salute at AFL game</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/we-take-it-very-seriously-queenslander-charged-over-nazi-salute-at-afl-game/yl67p2juy</link><description>A spectator has received a lifetime AFL ban after being accused of performing a Nazi salute at a major finals clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5914a8ddfe870a62368edabcf5190c91</guid></item><item><title>ANZ cops $240m fine for widespread misconduct</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/anz-cops-240m-fine-for-widespread-misconduct/bmgq0k3yc</link><description>The Australian share market has begun the week lower, despite optimism ahead of the US Federal Reserve’s expected interest rate cut this week. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Macquarie Private Bank Division Director Martin Lakos. Plus, ANZ has been fined $240 million for what ASIC has called widespread misconduct, including allegations of failing to respond to customer hardship notices and failing to refund fees charged to thousands of dead customers. For more, Asha Abdi spoke with Professor Allan Fels from the University of Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5d13edf20e0ec5fc15dd1f0095cd1c1</guid></item><item><title>Experts warn rates double for some sexually transmitted infections</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/experts-warn-rates-double-for-some-sexually-transmitted-infections/bgyvsfinv</link><description>The latest snapshot of sexually transmitted infections in Australia shows some alarming trends over the past 10 years. A report from the University of New South Wales&amp;apos; Kirby Institute suggests testing gaps and accessibility issues are contributing to a rise in cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4758b85b951da32ea805c05ce223ec1c</guid></item><item><title>Papua New Guinea celebrates 50th anniversary of independence from Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/papua-new-guinea-celebrates-50th-anniversary-of-independence-from-australia/a2mdgx3ne</link><description>Papua New Guinea is celebrating the 50th anniversary of its independence from Australia. The occasion is being marked with festivities in the capital Port Moresby as well as Papua New Guinean communities in Australia. The ongoing relationship remains crucial to both counties - even more so with the signing of an landmark defence agreement in Port Moresby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">533c0e21ced3d638050d3ca2364db55b</guid></item><item><title>Rubio says US will provide &amp;apos;unwavering support&amp;apos; for Israel in Gaza war</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rubio-says-us-will-provide-unwavering-support-to-israel-in-gaza-war/tck43qmq8</link><description>Benjamin Netanyahu said Marco Rubio&amp;apos;s visit was a &amp;quot;clear message&amp;quot; the United States stood with Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24a59313b71886b6e3fb40d20b727cbe</guid></item><item><title>Rubio says US will provide &amp;apos;unwavering support&amp;apos; for Israel in Gaza war</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rubio-says-us-will-provide-unwavering-support-for-israel-in-gaza-war/tck43qmq8</link><description>Benjamin Netanyahu said Marco Rubio&amp;apos;s visit was a &amp;quot;clear message&amp;quot; the United States stood with Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4da78ee6097d3e907fb995f14656e968</guid></item><item><title>How much money do you really need to be happy? Here&amp;apos;s what the research says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-much-money-do-you-need-to-be-happy/4wiladly5</link><description>Recent data shows that economic inequality in Australia is increasing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4088fd69be648f99c3bda2c7527648cd</guid></item><item><title>Inside the &amp;apos;hyper-connected&amp;apos; nationalist groups fuelling protests in Australia and the UK</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/far-right-movements-australia-uk/qg4lpzb6n</link><description>There is a complex picture behind the recent mobilisation of the far-right across Australia and the UK. But experts say it&amp;apos;s happened before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9daae4521c2c5f20a914b428a4563f2b</guid></item><item><title>Baby killed in a tragic carpark accident in Sydney | Morning Bulletin 16 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/baby-killed-in-a-tragic-carpark-accident-in-sydney-morning-bulletin-16-september-2025/wedqnvj51</link><description>In this bulletin, A five month old baby killed in a tragic carpark accident in Sydney; Qatar hosts an emergency summit after an Israeli strike on Hamas in Doha; and in sport, Spain calls for Israel to be banned from future sporting events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">032c8edd65c86851e303573d281d94fa</guid></item><item><title>US, China reach &amp;apos;framework&amp;apos; deal on TikTok ownership ahead of Trump&amp;apos;s call with Xi</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-china-reach-framework-deal-on-tiktok-ownership-ahead-of-trumps-call-with-xi/xvlyuelm9</link><description>The United States and China have reached a framework agreement to shift TikTok to US-controlled ownership, with final confirmation expected in a call between Donald Trump and Xi Jinping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9fcdbae0102de44abb914f5234c79c8</guid></item><item><title>Israel threatens Hamas &amp;apos;wherever they are&amp;apos; as Arab leaders review ties after Qatar attack</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-threatens-hamas-wherever-they-are-as-arab-leaders-review-ties-after-qatar-attack/tugexdrv1</link><description>Arab and Muslim leaders called for a review of ties with Israel after emergency talks in Doha following last week&amp;apos;s strike in the Qatari capital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9913c1dc91ac24db84b8f3d52832a748</guid></item><item><title>Kurtis Marschall takes pole vault bronze for Australia at World Athletics Championships 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/kurtis-marschall-takes-pole-vault-bronze-for-australia-at-world-athletics-championships-2025/04sycae6g</link><description>Pole vaulter Kurtis Marschall has won Australia&amp;apos;s first medal of the Tokyo world championships and Mondo Duplantis has broken his own world record in the event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e6d4e4819da4612df4aec0b6e792707</guid></item><item><title>When Gout Gout is running at the World Athletics Championships — and how to watch</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/when-gout-gout-is-running-at-the-world-athletics-championships-and-how-to-watch/wxcgdxhi1</link><description>The Australian sprinting sensation will be making his senior international debut in Tokyo this week. Here&amp;apos;s everything you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f827afa27127359f3e334562ecad2985</guid></item><item><title>Liberal senator warns of &amp;apos;mass exodus&amp;apos; from Coalition frontbench over net zero</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/liberal-mp-warns-of-mass-exodus-from-coalition-frontbench-over-net-zero/bdze7eboy</link><description>The Liberal party is once again at loggerheads over the party&amp;apos;s stance on net zero, with another frontbencher warning against adopting a policy &amp;quot;at any cost&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">128743e323d67bc42866ac5b3b5aebf9</guid></item><item><title>One man dead, several police injured after gas leak at Sydney restaurant</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/one-dead-several-injured-after-gas-leak-at-sydney-restuarant/y7qyvenii</link><description>The police had tried to help a man who was found unconscious in the restaurant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25c51b58fa4a4fcd0468c1cd53a6d9f2</guid></item><item><title>One man dead, several police injured after gas leak at Sydney restaurant</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/one-man-dead-several-police-injured-after-gas-leak-at-sydney-restuarant/y7qyvenii</link><description>The police had tried to help a man who was found unconscious in the restaurant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a350a1481099c18058aec0d8544027e0</guid></item><item><title>Political fallout over climate action | Midday News Bulletin 16 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/coalition-mps-threaten-to-quit-over-climate-policy-midday-news-bulletin-16-september-2025/bpqtu35qt</link><description>In this bulletin, Coalition MPs threaten to quit over emissions targets, in the wake of a bombshell climate report, a former British paratrooper pleads not guilty to murder in Northern Ireland&amp;apos;s Bloody Sunday killings. And in sport, the AFL is to revive its State of Origin series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0530d7283855de5c224bb54ca909d349</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Israel is fighting a war of slavery&amp;apos;: Strong criticism from emergency summit in Qatar</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israel-is-fighting-a-war-of-slavery-strong-criticism-from-emergency-summit-in-qatar/3h32qdqlj</link><description>Arab and Islamic leaders have met in Doha following Israel’s strike that killed Hamas officials and a Qatari security officer. Qatar’s Emir accused Israel of seeking dominance, while Iran, Turkey and Egypt called for sanctions, isolation and regional defence coordination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de90d414b7efa5a9f88bf3f078625899</guid></item><item><title>Moldova heads to an election: but will Russian interference change the result?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/moldova-heads-to-an-election-but-will-russian-interference-change-the-result/sltvas0hu</link><description>Voters in Moldova head to the polls later this month, in an election authorities warn is being undermined by a campaign of vote buying and digital propaganda, orchestrated by Moscow. Independent investigators believe up to 40% of votes will be the result of the Russian interference campaign, which seeks to promote pro-Kremlin parties and slow Moldova’s plans to join the European Union.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1531cc991179d17c8ba351315b2a6f60</guid></item><item><title>What social media platforms will — and won&amp;apos;t — have to do under Australia&amp;apos;s under-16s ban</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/social-media-ban-guidelines-for-platforms/py4ll7x14</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s eSafety commissioner has unveiled guidelines for social media companies to comply with age restriction laws that will come into effect on 10 December. Here&amp;apos;s what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b879f0b6c80c03ba96e0dde6e7570be</guid></item><item><title>Doctor &amp;apos;furious&amp;apos; after being told to leave Virgin Australia lounge for expressing breast milk</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/doctor-furious-after-being-told-to-leave-virgin-australia-lounge-for-expressing-breast-milk/oudyn2xsw</link><description>Virgin Australia has apologised, saying the way the matter was handled &amp;quot;fell short&amp;quot; of its standards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ca052eb3cfc0e53a425fd7a1aa91978</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 16 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-16-september-2025/31fthx5k3</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ab9a66db86207a08fe5b80ad88d414a</guid></item><item><title>Cash-for-votes, deepfakes and propaganda: Russia&amp;apos;s latest bid for influence</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cash-for-votes-deepfakes-and-propaganda-russias-latest-bid-for-influence/xmp4569qg</link><description>As Russia&amp;apos;s neighbour prepares to head to the polls, a pro-Russian alliance appears to be on the rise thanks, in part, to a disinformation and propaganda campaign some believe is backed by the Kremlin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4aa7ab05869477868278a2d54ed7348</guid></item><item><title>PM &amp;apos;confident&amp;apos; as PNG delays signing defence pact | Evening News Bulletin 16 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pm-confident-as-png-delays-signing-defence-pact-evening-news-bulletin-16-september-2025/xv7z2u8i1</link><description>In this bulletin, the Prime Minister gives assurances as Papua New Guinea delays signing a new security pact, three charged over alleged assisted suicides, as police open probes into previous deaths. And in athletics, Australia&amp;apos;s Jessica Hull confident she could take first in the 1500 metres at tonight&amp;apos;s World Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc21df8741e55aa1137331ff8e09a29c</guid></item><item><title>Australian dollar hits a 10 month high against the US</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australian-dollar-hits-a-10-month-high-against-the-us/a3vmn3yt3</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves takes a look at the driving forces in the currency markets with Chris Weston from Pepperstone and previews the US Federal Reserve&amp;apos;s Thursday morning interest rate decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8f4e843fec3119fba965a843fc9c962</guid></item><item><title>Israel has committed genocide against Palestinians in Gaza, UN inquiry finds</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-has-committed-genocide-in-gaza-un-inquiry-finds/vuen505p5</link><description>The UN commission of inquiry concluded that Israeli authorities and forces had, since October 2023, committed &amp;quot;four of the five genocidal acts&amp;quot; listed in the 1948 Genocide Convention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd9543e763cd97308302a62d53ddc57a</guid></item><item><title>Deep rifts widen further within Coalition under climate change pressure</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/deep-rifts-widen-further-within-coalition-under-climate-change-pressure/1zvkaao65</link><description>Liberal senator Jonathan Duniam has warned the Coalition will face a &amp;quot;mass exodus&amp;quot; from its frontbench if it adopts a net zero policy without caveats, handing Opposition leader Sussan Ley a fresh test over the party&amp;apos;s stance on climate action. The warning comes a day after Liberal MP Andrew Hastie threatened to quit the party if it pursued a policy of net zero emissions by 2050.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">348807a5b201db1ec34ef79aa7b88747</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;As data-minimising as possible&amp;apos;: under-16 social media ban guidelines published</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/as-data-minimising-as-possible-under-16-social-media-ban-guidelines-published/8u91iu8ae</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s eSafety commissioner has published regulatory guidelines for social media platforms, giving effect to the government&amp;apos;s under-16 social media ban. While the ban won&amp;apos;t be in place until December 10th, the eSafety commissioner says they want it to be as minimally invasive as possible. Under the guidance, social media platforms will not have to verify the age of every user on their platforms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90e4f62ebaf692b332097cf37f780736</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Gaza is burning,&amp;apos; Israel declares as it launches major ground offensive</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-declares-gaza-is-burning-as-it-launches-major-ground-offensive/njxzr0v5w</link><description>The ground incursion into Gaza City comes as a UN independent commission concluded in a report that Israel has committed genocide in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b2abadd9ca4233c9d51b8619faaf864</guid></item></channel></rss>