<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>SBS English News (Unofficial Aggregation)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 20:58:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>States face fresh scrutiny in youth justice shake-up after &amp;apos;deeply disturbing&amp;apos; evidence</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/states-face-fresh-scrutiny-in-youth-justice-shake-up/bsy80t1kx</link><description>Inquiry to examine if children&amp;apos;s rights are violated in custody and if Australia is upholding its international obligations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91da6bd20bb15ca7b102bdfe72769fdb</guid></item><item><title>Kidney disease drug added to PBS, helping 65,000 Australians</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/kidney-disease-drug-added-to-pbs-helping-65-000-australians/89175q6wh</link><description>The federal government will add a medicine for chronic kidney disease into the Pharmaceutical Benefits Scheme. More than 65.000 Australians are expected to benefit from the cheaper access to Jardiance , also known as Empagliflozin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41c1a47f2d2760d29b0f6fd89063a804</guid></item><item><title>CSL and Wisetech shares smashed &amp;amp; Australia&amp;apos;s ASEAN opportunities</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/csl-and-wisetech-shares-smashed-australias-asean-opportuntties/jii8rdy49</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Australia&amp;apos;s Special Envoy to Southeast Asia Nicholas Moore to find out how regional leaders feel about doing business with Australians as he attends the ASEAN summit; plus Michael Jenneke from UBS Management takes a look at the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action as CSL and Wisetech shares crash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4116e867e4db9740f377779a0fe97ec</guid></item><item><title>The diseases that dominate Australia&amp;apos;s $270 billion health bill</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-diseases-that-dominate-australias-270-billion-health-bill/ym74nnf8o</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s disease and injury spending has grown by more than $10 billion. Here&amp;apos;s what we spent it on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9db622f635f98b26f237b03e04181b03</guid></item><item><title>Israel launches deadly strikes on Gaza, but US says ceasefire is holding</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-planes-strike-gaza-after-netanyahu-orders-powerful-attacks/d9olkhwly</link><description>US vice president JD Vance said that despite the latest flare-up, &amp;quot;the ceasefire is holding&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">790b84da77adf83f25eeaaf0c4eb6a6a</guid></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa: &amp;apos;Storm of the century&amp;apos; takes aim at Cuba after roaring across Jamaica</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hurricane-melissa-makes-landfall-in-jamaica/0h3oa42ih</link><description>At its peak, the storm packed ferocious sustained winds of 300km/h.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">225264d1b35601c72199cdcb2df4dc87</guid></item><item><title>Housing and migration the big issues as Dutch voters cast their ballots</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/housing-and-migration-the-big-issues-as-dutch-voters-cast-their-ballots/q3d1mo0fv</link><description>Voters in the Netherlands have begun casting their ballots in the country’s general election. Polls suggest the hard-right anti-immigration party led by Geert Wilders is likely to win the most seats, however that doesn’t mean he’ll lead a new government. The campaign has been dominated by housing and immigration with concern about asylum seekers being scapegoated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e23c72d18d079668daaf9b2fc73a3bd</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Didn&amp;apos;t make it lightly&amp;apos;: BoM apologises for &amp;apos;challenges&amp;apos; amid $4.1m website furore</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bureau-of-meteorology-website/vya3xrizg</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology says there will be &amp;quot;improvements&amp;quot; in the coming weeks as changes to its controversial new website are urged.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd3544401a85a01ea77da2fa75eaed84</guid></item><item><title>‘Time for truth’: Western Australia Governor apologises for Pinjarra Massacre, nearly 200 years on</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/time-for-truth-western-australia-governor-apologises-for-pinjarra-massacre-nearly-200-years-on/afox5g42o</link><description>The Western Australian Governor has apologised for his predecessor&amp;apos;s role in a state-led violent attack against Noongar men, women and children almost 200 years ago, known as the Pinjarra massacre. Descendants of the Bindjareb Noongar people received the long-awaited apology saying it is a meaningful step towards reconciliation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dd91a6a8668dd7ac97fd4a8c28b8889</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 29 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-29-october-2025/ne0880ogi</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">505250730453beb59a0e5505ac54eed0</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Had to tie myself to the bed&amp;apos;: Aussie details Hurricane Melissa terror in Jamaica</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/aussie-details-hurricane-melissa-terror/m4se6hvgc</link><description>Hurricane Melissa — one of the most powerful hurricanes on record — has ripped a path of destruction through Jamaica.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43064630b32e8561a81426325011cea1</guid></item><item><title>No more interest rate cuts: Inflation sparks bank warning</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/no-more-interest-rate-cuts-inflation-sparks-bank-warning/8mf85t0x9</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Belinda Allen from the Commonwealth Bank who is now predicting an end to the Reserve Bank cutting cycle, following a stronger than expected rise in September quarter inflation, while Sally Auld from NAB says there&amp;apos;s still a chance of a cut in May; plus a look at the market reaction with Jun Bei Liu fom TenCap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">157dc3a7b61e0b29d566f21d64ef01b9</guid></item><item><title>Government housing affordability scheme under pressure</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/government-housing-affordability-scheme-under-pressure/3b16i6zgj</link><description>The Housing Australia Future Fund (HAFF) is under intense political scrutiny following the launch of a forensic nine-month federal audit. The $10 billion scheme, intended to boost social and affordable housing, is accused by the Opposition of wasting taxpayer funds and overpaying for properties. The debate has been dominated by the fund&amp;apos;s slow delivery and expert concerns that its structure incentivises market-tied &amp;quot;fake affordable&amp;quot; rents over genuine public housing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a2af1852a1526ac60113750d2afa4e6</guid></item><item><title>How much does it really cost to raise a child in Australia? Here are the numbers</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cost-of-raising-children-in-australia/u83g69rcz</link><description>Calculating the cost of raising kids is a complicated beast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68c5565cc2e048eec3bffd88e8752cca</guid></item><item><title>More than 100 Palestinians killed in Israeli airstrikes on Gaza, health ministry says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gaza-palestinians-killed-israeli-strikes/m1lm32cyi</link><description>Israel&amp;apos;s strikes mark the worst escalation of violence in Gaza since a ceasefire came into effect earlier this month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b230b68f93678a5bd259e682eb4b5325</guid></item><item><title>Dozens dead, thousands homeless after Hurricane Melissa batters Caribbean</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/dozens-dead-thousands-homeless-after-hurricane-melissa-batters-caribbean/sfpek691k</link><description>Hurricane Melissa has carved a path of devastation through the Caribbean this week, first battering Jamaica, then surging into Cuba. It&amp;apos;s left tens of thousands homeless, power grids faltering, and nations mobilising aid. At least 27 people are confirmed dead across Jamaica, Haiti, and Cuba, with early estimates suggesting hundreds of millions of dollars in damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8c7597293c84357801976a0c53d2bd6</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 30 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-30-october-2025/2ineeoz3k</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd7b31450cfdeccefcd850da1d675aba</guid></item><item><title>$136,000 superannuation warning as Australia faces a &amp;apos;silver tsunami&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/136-000-super-warning-as-australia-faces-a-silver-tsunami/evvouelwc</link><description>Millions are heading into retirement over the next decade — and some could be left thousands of dollars behind, a new report says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c5cd17af0b1414f0620ea9cc9dbebdc</guid></item><item><title>Rio de Janeiro governor defends raid that favela residents say was a &amp;quot;massacre&amp;quot;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/rio-de-janeiro-governor-defends-raid-that-favela-residents-say-was-a-massacre/q3gtg7i6o</link><description>A week out from hosting thousands of international visitors for the United Nation&amp;apos;s climate summit, Brazilian authorities are clearing the aftermath of what has become one of the deadliest police raids in the nation&amp;apos;s history. The president says he had no warning of the scale of Rio de Janiero&amp;apos;s police raid and the U-N is calling for an independent investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c0ee7f191a6b35383c707993bb82198</guid></item><item><title>Trump touts Asia triumph - and a third term, Russia&amp;apos;s oil sanctions &amp;amp; &amp;apos;et tu&amp;apos; Queensland?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trump-touts-asia-triumph-and-a-third-term-gaza-ceasefire-tested-et-tu-queensland/em6e6nis3</link><description>Donald Trump talks up tributes and tariff deals on his Asia tour, as well as the possibility of a third term as he stops in on the ASEAN and APEC summits. In Gaza, Israel and Hamas accuse each other of ceasefire violations. US sanctions on Russian oil piles the pressure on Putin, and a curriculum catastrophe for Queensland students.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4041c4814ecece35093963a46e1274a</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Xi meeting &amp;apos;amazing&amp;apos; as he cuts tariffs and claims rare earths &amp;apos;settled&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-and-xi-wrap-meeting-leaving-tight-lipped-after-albanese-calls-for-trade-truce/j4se2un93</link><description>Talks between Donald Trump and Xi Jinping follow months of friction over tariffs and security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a66610009874f3f203d0d4355310d1b</guid></item><item><title>Government introduces environment laws to Parliament - but hurdles remain</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/government-introduces-environment-laws-to-parliament-but-hurdles-remain/di6dn84oi</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s most significant environmental law reform in decades has been tabled in Parliament, but it faces immediate political deadlock with opponents in the Senate ready to delay the vote. As Minister Murray Watt pushes for a swift resolution, he must navigate an environment where both the Coalition and the Greens are demanding major concessions on accountability, climate, and industry protection.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">460f554e95e386ca88562e8b2798d783</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce denies female staffer abuse allegations ahead of parliamentary investigation</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/barnaby-joyce-denies-female-staffer-abuse-allegations-ahead-of-parliamentary-investigation/d46wmb1vq</link><description>A formal complaint against the former deputy prime minister has been lodged with parliamentary support services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a211637d4ec1d79c9813e184cd80730e</guid></item><item><title>First Nations businesses forge new connections in India</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/first-nations-businesses-forge-new-connections-in-india/c47i2gc9l</link><description>A group of First Nations Australian business owners and operators are in India showcasing their businesses, as part of a push to build ties between Indigenous communities in the two countries. The aim is to expand opportunities for Indigenous participation in international trade, three years after a historic trade agreement was signed between India and Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f17264f156aa94a4d31ea9692a49035</guid></item><item><title>The future of AI investment if interest rates don&amp;apos;t fall as much as expected</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-future-of-ai-investment-if-interest-rates-dont-fall-as-much-as-expected/le6a4miut</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with market analyst Evan Lucas about the implications of another US interest rate cut, talk a follow up in December isn&amp;apos;t assured and what it means for AI investment; plus the AFR&amp;apos;s Yolanda Redrup on the trends making young people rich.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e82a577757c44d93903b9c9c393069d</guid></item><item><title>Family and friends &amp;apos;taken or killed&amp;apos;: From Australia, Emad is watching horrors unfold</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-sudanese-community-concerned-for-family-in-sudan/h5nvsojzx</link><description>As Sudan&amp;apos;s Darfur region faces an escalating crisis, hundreds are dead and families abroad wait helplessly for news of loved ones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0669c8323034c6c1d36cfbebc90f959</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Out of order&amp;apos;: Senate descends into chaos as Coalition accused of silencing women</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/senate-descends-into-chaos-as-coalition-accused-of-silencing-women/36tw2lqye</link><description>The chaotic scenes occurred during a marathon three-hour Question Time — the longest since federation nearly 125 years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70d099bbae40c38ac237bc2d1ef53909</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew stripped of royal title, forced to leave Windsor mansion</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/prince-andrew-royal-title-lose-royal-lodge-buckingham-palace/ntb69vlyw</link><description>King Charles&amp;apos; brother will be known as Andrew Mountbatten Windsor, amid criticism over his ties to sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0feaf7eab63fec810b82ed0a718f3970</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump&amp;apos;s nuclear testing order sparks pushback from Russia, China and the UN</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-nuclear-testing-order-pushback/a21zghnl1</link><description>Trump said the Pentagon will immediately resume testing the US nuclear arsenal on an &amp;quot;equal basis&amp;quot; with other nuclear powers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1d106fd2899170796d8a92e886b1051</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Swiss cheese&amp;apos; reforms: What&amp;apos;s wrong with Australia&amp;apos;s nature laws?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/swiss-cheese-reforms-whats-wrong-with-australias-nature-laws/vfmei8p1r</link><description>This sitting week has brought a storm over the BoM&amp;apos;s new website, controversy about a t-shirt and some massive proposed reforms to Australia&amp;apos;s environmental laws. To help us sort through what on earth is happening with the EPBC (and explain what it is) we spoke with Dr Kirsty Howey from the Environment Centre NT.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cf8c6248dc2d7c64bc03fba9369c9c9</guid></item><item><title>Environmental reform architect hails end to &amp;apos;torturous&amp;apos; years, hits out at Greens and Coalition</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/satisfied-after-five-torturous-years-review-author-backs-labors-environment-reforms/moll43285</link><description>Graeme Samuel beamed as he praised laws sparked by his landmark review, while saying the Greens and Coalition don&amp;apos;t get them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bbf76b7d4581fde12f2f93548ec462c</guid></item><item><title>King Charles wants Andrew evicted, but Virginia Giuffre&amp;apos;s family wants him &amp;apos;behind bars&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/guiffre-family-speaks-andrew-titles/6mwrykq6p</link><description>The comments come after Buckingham Palace announced it was stripping Andrew of his &amp;apos;prince&amp;apos; title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70066a2c92a1f54119d58d98654a4942</guid></item><item><title>Former MP Gareth Ward sentenced to five years in prison for sexual assault</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gareth-ward-sentenced-to-prison/xoobwijth</link><description>Gareth Ward&amp;apos;s non-parole period of three years and nine months is set to expire on 29 April 2029.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d44b10b49e019b150f249e8613945dbe</guid></item><item><title>From prince to pariah: A timeline of Andrew&amp;apos;s alleged acts and long fall from grace</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/prince-andrew-alleged-acts-fall-from-grace-timeline/nvqzqv5wa</link><description>Andrew Windsor has faced criticism for his ties to Jeffrey Epstein for more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2ed29ecb4bac45076f21eabd83c1af5</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 31 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-31-october-2025/phm2edzjb</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b693828ce02aa043d5062939cdc15aa</guid></item><item><title>Calls for help as Melissa leaves a trail of destruction across the Caribbean</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/calls-for-help-as-melissa-leaves-a-trail-of-destruction-across-the-caribbean/7rz9pgav4</link><description>Hurricane Melissa has left a trail of devastation across the northern Caribbean, striking Jamaica, Cuba and Haiti before sweeping towards Bermuda. One of the most powerful Atlantic storms on record, it has killed at least 30 people, displaced thousands and crippled vital infrastructure. Recovery efforts are now under way across the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc7bc53454d3180b31687a67e691fec4</guid></item><item><title>Victoria passes Australia’s first treaty law, creating permanent Indigenous voice in parliament</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/victoria-passes-australias-first-treaty-law-creating-permanent-indigenous-voice-in-parliament/0wag2yw4z</link><description>After almost a decade of activism and community efforts, Victoria has passed Australia&amp;apos;s first ever treaty legislation establishing a permanent Indigenous representative body in the state parliament. The landmark agreement between the Victorian Government and the First People&amp;apos;s Assembly of Victoria marks a historic step towards recognising and reckoning with Victoria&amp;apos;s violent colonial history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">207edd60ba49039a97709be7664bf6ec</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Jill Gallagher, VACCHO, on the new Victorian treaty</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-jill-gallagher-vaccho-on-the-new-victorian-treaty/rcrciwjve</link><description>Victoria&amp;apos;s First Nations community is celebrating a historic milestone - legislation to establish the first treaty in Australia&amp;apos;s history passed through state parliament on Thursday night. It&amp;apos;s expected to enter force by the end of the year, after an official signing ceremony and royal assent from Victoria&amp;apos;s governor, in the culmination of a whole decade of negotiations. The legislation establishes a permanent Aboriginal advisory and decision-making body, to be known as Gellung Warl, which will remain outside the state&amp;apos;s constitution. Aunty Jill Gallagher is the C-E-O of the Victorian Community Controlled Health Organisation, and served as the Treaty Advancement Commissioner in 2018. She&amp;apos;s been talking to SBS&amp;apos;s Tee Mitchell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe7cd96b2ca20ce757f890ee6c9498df</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Power grab&amp;apos;: Labor under fire over new move to cut off Centrelink payments</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/labor-under-fire-over-new-move-to-cut-off-centrelink-payments/fxtw14lr2</link><description>The last-minute additions have been called into question, with advocates arguing they set a &amp;quot;dangerous precedent&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b130f6b8afd2cae2571b91d4bf50f85</guid></item><item><title>The Australians facing a $53k pay problem — and the age it hits hardest</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gender-pay-gap-age-hits-hardest/4jxzii4dc</link><description>A new report has revealed for the first time that the gender age gap starts at 30, and only increases as women get older.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4218d1b68974926bf5c5844f2b3e78e9</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;It’s the beginning&amp;apos;: Next move after Victoria&amp;apos;s historic Treaty milestone</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-treaty-is-not-the-end-of-the-journey-but-the-beginning-of-a-new-one/5o1f46tig</link><description>Victoria is the first state or territory in Australia to pass legislation that paves the way for a Treaty with First Peoples.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ed8faa864fa0aaef4a1226b9c019736</guid></item><item><title>Investors consider rate pause and AI investment costs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/investors-consider-rate-pause-and-ai-investment-costs/p56jho150</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Grady Wulff from Bell Direct about the day&amp;apos;s market action including how the interest rate outlook is impacting the market and AI profitability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ce6bdaaa6228528a6453a7aa73b6fd1</guid></item><item><title>Sudanese-Australians face terrifying ordeal after ransom demanded for cousins</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/abdullah-answered-a-call-from-his-cousin-and-found-armed-men-instead/4azhkfnxa</link><description>Cut off from loved ones in Sudan, Abdullah Gaka&amp;apos;s phone is his only link to a city gripped by siege, starvation and fear.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bee3a3c93201148d8b6712449c178f60</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;No idea how much they&amp;apos;re having&amp;apos;: The party drug on the rise among young women</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ghb-use-overdoses-young-australian-women/xqajkwio0</link><description>Once thought of as mostly a &amp;apos;date rape drug&amp;apos;, GHB is being used recreationally by more Australians and experts say it&amp;apos;s causing problems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eec9085167e58ec6b1b64300e40247d2</guid></item><item><title>At the edge of survival: report says half of uncontacted Indigenous peoples facing extinction</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/at-the-edge-of-survival-report-says-half-of-uncontacted-indigenous-peoples-facing-extinction/c956bnh6y</link><description>A not for profit organisation says almost half of Indigenous communities living cut off from the world face extinction within the decade due to logging, mining and tourism. Survival International says they want the world - especially governments and industries - to recognise and address the problem as a global emergency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">770252d83f1678fa6a2f13d799d7d333</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Graeme Samuel tells SBS why he endorses the government&amp;apos;s environmental bill</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-graeme-samuel-tells-sbs-why-he-endorses-the-governments-environmental-bill/24u0totta</link><description>The author of the review that triggered the government&amp;apos;s environment reforms has fully endorsed Labor&amp;apos;s nature legislation. Professor Graeme Samuel has told SBS the bill implements the &amp;apos;totality&amp;apos; of the recommendations he made in his report, five years after it was delivered. The Greens and Coalition have objected to the bill, with Greens leader Larissa Waters describing it as 1400 pages gift-wrapped for big business. But Professor Samuel says environmental groups and business interests alike had substantial input into his report, and their desires were fully taken into account in the recommendations. He&amp;apos;s been talking to SBS chief political correspondent Anna Henderson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a80d0ff3621f5c274930bd8e4b00647</guid></item><item><title>Aged care reforms: Who will pay more under the new system?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/aged-care-reforms-who-will-pay-more-under-the-new-system/8aqjfk7wy</link><description>A long-awaited Aged Care Act comes into force today [[Nov 1]], four years after a Royal Commission recommended major reforms to the sector. The federal government says it will give older Australians more choice and access to in-home support, but there are concerns many people will end up paying more for care.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4509330f3eacbfe7e1c7d846fdec0db7</guid></item><item><title>Multicultural communities report a greater sense of belonging, new SBS report reveals</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/multicultural-communities-report-a-greater-sense-of-belonging-new-sbs-report-reveals/66w4wujfz</link><description>A new report by SBS and the University of Canberra have found there is an increased sense of belonging among multilingual communities compared to 2023. It also details factors that could affect the levels of civic participation among multilingual communities, and the different attitudes toward sense of belonging between younger and older generations of multilingual Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d655152d177f2722b6bff129b1ad9141</guid></item><item><title>They&amp;apos;re the world&amp;apos;s most hidden societies — and they&amp;apos;re &amp;apos;under attack right now&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/major-threat-facing-worlds-most-hidden-societies/q8fbd3k2q</link><description>The world&amp;apos;s uncontacted Indigenous groups are facing growing threats, according to a human rights organisation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a237f210211bd9425e306a4400a0f994</guid></item><item><title>Fast fashion giant H&amp;amp;M investigated over multimillion-dollar underpayment claims</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/h-m-investigated-over-multimillion-dollar-underpayment-claims/9jhsf7x33</link><description>H&amp;amp;M says it discovered widespread payroll discrepancies dating back to 2016 and has launched a remediation process, including back pay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c6ef8faaa5e20903d94da371a33b817</guid></item><item><title>Nationals members vote to ditch net zero, paving the way for party to dump target</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nationals-members-vote-to-ditch-net-zero/xem7pldre</link><description>The motion passed by Nationals&amp;apos; grassroots members called on the party to &amp;quot;abandon its support for a net-zero mandate&amp;quot; while still reducing emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b6aef5496d1462c9508562a5d9dbaf04</guid></item><item><title>Snipping and sharing: The young people posting about their vasectomies online</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/act-of-rebellion-the-childless-men-getting-vasectomies-and-posting-about-them-online/nmqjq4xpn</link><description>With an ageing population, China wants more people to have babies. But some men are posting on social media about their vasectomies instead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccbd52a8544a790c77f236c8fa0e1de1</guid></item><item><title>The facial tattoos sending a &amp;apos;very clear statement&amp;apos; after decades of suppression</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/maori-ta-moko-tattoos-cultural-revival-and-resistance/3jlov8vtt</link><description>Tā moko is part of a sacred tradition. For some, it&amp;apos;s also a message to the government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73ffffeb5fc7e16ff0472a8d4a4f6b52</guid></item><item><title>Early super access let Damian fix his teeth. For Melinda, it was a $48,000 nightmare</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/early-release-of-superannuation-for-dental-and-medical-treatment/clzz7fmbg</link><description>More Australians are dipping into super for dental care. But for some, it&amp;apos;s left them with both financial and physical pain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b4f78e3bec4baeead1787a24f408579</guid></item><item><title>How Australia&amp;apos;s north is being used by defence allies for regional security</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/how-australias-north-is-being-used-by-defence-allies-for-regional-security/7gud4aq1c</link><description>As Australia deepens its engagement in the Indo-Pacific region, strategic partners are more important than ever. Australia&amp;apos;s longstanding military alliance with American forces is being expanded into the future. Josh van Staden takes a look inside the US Marines base near Darwin, where thousands of US Marines have recently departed as part of an annual rotational force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d054b596a1f929a1df2a02475fb1b33c</guid></item><item><title>As battle for &amp;apos;gateway to Donetsk&amp;apos; intensifies, Ukraine says its troops are still holding out</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/battle-for-pokrovsk-intensifies/h9p4sqaia</link><description>Pokrovsk, in Ukraine&amp;apos;s Donetsk region, lies on a major supply route for the Ukrainian army and has been in Moscow&amp;apos;s sights for over a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5c14f343882c47108d7cd0b7bfb2ecf</guid></item><item><title>Youth justice: Is jailing failing First Nations kids, inquiry asks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/youth-justice-is-jailing-failing-first-nations-kids-inquiry-asks/3neuigg01</link><description>State and territory governments in Australia will face scrutiny as part of a parliamentary inquiry on the outcomes and impacts of youth incarceration. The over-incarceration of First Nations children will also be a key focus.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b98b761b0eb11dad7da19c084ee2b8a</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Mary Wooldridge, CEO of the Workplace Gender Equality Agency</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-mary-wooldridge-ceo-of-the-workplace-gender-equality-agency/avdh8sd5t</link><description>A new report released this week by the Workplace Gender Equality Agency (WGEA) has found the financial cost of the gender pay gap accelerates across a woman’s lifetime, peaking in the late 50s at a difference of $53,000. WGEA’s Ages and Wages report investigates how and why the gender pay gap changes at different stages across a lifetime. It lists key actions employers can take to address it. WGEA CEO Mary Wooldridge spoke to SBS On the Money&amp;apos;s Stephanie Youssef</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cbd874444c1edac7153f335947751f4</guid></item><item><title>One man in custody after UK train stabbing leaves two with &amp;apos;life-threatening&amp;apos; injuries</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/multiple-people-stabbed-on-uk-train-one-arrested/9uxboev58</link><description>UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer said the &amp;quot;appalling&amp;quot; incident was &amp;quot;deeply concerning&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93d3735cb761178eb4dcbbb450bc7bf7</guid></item><item><title>One man in custody after UK train stabbing leaves two with &amp;apos;life-threatening&amp;apos; injuries</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/multiple-people-stabbed-on-uk-train-two-arrested/9uxboev58</link><description>UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer said the &amp;quot;appalling&amp;quot; incident was &amp;quot;deeply concerning&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b739b117421da56ecfaabf02ecdccfd2</guid></item><item><title>One man in custody after UK train stabbing leaves two with &amp;apos;life-threatening&amp;apos; injuries</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/two-arrested-after-multiple-people-stabbed-on-uk-train-police-say/9uxboev58</link><description>UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer said the &amp;quot;appalling&amp;quot; incident was &amp;quot;deeply concerning&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38211691975bf2260c34e8ea87081a50</guid></item><item><title>Peter is part of Australia&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;silent epidemic&amp;apos;. A new initiative offers hope</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/addition-of-kidney-disease-medicine-to-pbs-expected-to-benefit-over-65-000-australians/i75n8la4w</link><description>One in twenty Australians aged 75 and above is diagnosed with kidney disease but authorities suspect the vast majority of cases go undetected.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7045dfa9f1a0c891a316074ec24cd8c</guid></item><item><title>Nationals abandon net zero after members vote to dump climate target</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nationals-abandon-net-zero/nn0yon1pn</link><description>The Nationals say Australia&amp;apos;s commitment to net zero emissions by 2050 is driving up power prices and shutting down industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de8296067e9eaf879f77e533c901958</guid></item><item><title>Infant peanut feeding prevented thousands of children from developing allergies</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/infant-peanut-feeding-prevented-thousands-of-children-from-developing-allergies/osjtg7pg4</link><description>New US research reveals early introduction of peanuts has prevented about 60,000 children from developing dangerous food allergies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2f6aaa22012d40e6b7a4729db49ca1a</guid></item><item><title>What is net zero, and why have the Nationals abandoned it?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-is-net-zero-and-why-have-the-nationals-abandoned-it/lgsux43si</link><description>An environmental expert says the Nationals are &amp;quot;representing the big mining bodies&amp;quot; instead of regional Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdc5ffef41733d16af61040eba033fd5</guid></item><item><title>The &amp;apos;Hotel California effect&amp;apos; and how Australians are spending more on subscriptions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-hotel-california-effect-and-how-australians-are-spending-more-on-subscriptions/tnrcf1fve</link><description>Australians are paying more than ever for their subscriptions, but not because they’re watching or listening more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5bde35db3d3500b5cab9622b0e20c2c</guid></item><item><title>My son begged me not to tell anyone he was being bullied. I didn&amp;apos;t listen</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/my-son-was-bullied-what-the-school-did-astonished-me/7yq7yeqqc</link><description>Nama Winston&amp;apos;s son was being bullied over his sexuality. She told his school principal, whose response &amp;quot;blew her away&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6e9b382b48de778aaedd051aef4f3ed</guid></item><item><title>Powerless: The hidden crisis of prepaid energy and First Nations communities</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-households-facing-prepaid-energy-crisis/w5to5n2r1</link><description>In Western Australia&amp;apos;s remote north, tens of thousands of people are living in fear of sudden disconnection and being forced to ration power.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3b00a732d3a471d81bd14223d8a1f0b</guid></item><item><title>Nationals ditch net zero as Liberals ponder their own climate policy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nationals-ditch-net-zero-as-liberals-ponder-their-own-climate-policy/v8bfx3mhi</link><description>The Nationals have formally walked away from support of Australia&amp;apos;s net zero emissions by 2050 policy after a party room meeting in Canberra. The decision sets up a potential showdown with their coalition partner the Liberals, who are also reviewing their approach to climate change after their disastrous election defeat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ddf1d6c26a189a3ae50b1c2803c42c8</guid></item><item><title>Hamas hands over three more hostage bodies as Israel continues deadly strikes</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hamas-says-it-will-hand-over-three-more-hostage-bodies-as-israel-continues-deadly-strikes/gf7vq8dx3</link><description>Israel and Hamas have accused each other of violating a ceasefire in the Gaza Strip, as the militant group handed over more bodies of hostages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ee0dc19931f63e5e4d0beb4d5282758</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;What were you doing?&amp;apos;: Optus executives grilled over 17-hour delay during triple-zero outage</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-were-you-doing-optus-executives-grilled-over-17-hour-delay-during-triple-zero-outage/rpjblcn5c</link><description>During a Senate inquiry, Optus executives were asked why they left the government &amp;quot;in the dark&amp;quot; following a triple-zero outage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53a72e804e9af26f63be34cad7eade0e</guid></item><item><title>UK Train stabbing attack: One in custody, not terrorism say police</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/uk-train-stabbing-attack-one-in-custody-not-terrorism-say-police/w1fgwx45h</link><description>After a mass stabbing on a train in the UK left 11 people hospitalised, police say they have no evidence suggesting the attack was related to terrorism.With one suspect now in custody, authorities in the UK are urging the public to give time for a full investigation into the motives behind the incident.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f64622603afad375d925ecb16d2a42a5</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Eliza Owen from Cotality on the RBA&amp;apos;s impact on the property market</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-eliza-owen-from-cotality-on-the-rbas-impact-on-the-property-market/p8a5j3qei</link><description>Spring is historically the time of year that sees the most new listings in the property market - and the highest sales volumes. But with rumours that the RBA is likely to keep interest rates on hold until next year, what effect will that have on sales? Eliza Owen from Cotality (formerly Corelogic) spoke to SBS&amp;apos;s Cameron Carr</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e7803bac87c172765e22bc0453b05e9</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Dignity&amp;apos;: Baby Priya bill passes, protecting parental leave for stillbirth and infant deaths</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/priyas-bill-passes-senate/v2h2abf01</link><description>The Albanese government said the laws give grieving parents financial certainty after stillbirth or infant death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22d25f29ccec2783c8d8d2a65417d231</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Dignity&amp;apos;: Baby Priya bill passes, protecting parental leave for stillbirth and infant deaths</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/landmark-baby-priyas-bill-protects-parental-leave-for-stillbirth-and-infant-deaths/v2h2abf01</link><description>The Albanese government said the laws give grieving parents financial certainty after stillbirth or infant death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e659e6eec5bba208801528dc54c19b83</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 3 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-3-november-2025/w3nm8fst6</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20cf70a94982f16f8b50bcecba2b7e9d</guid></item><item><title>Ley downplays net zero rift, with Liberals divided after Nationals dump policy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/leys-net-zero-challenge-with-liberals-divided-after-national-policy-dump/ub6jg21oc</link><description>The Nationals’ decision to dump support for net zero has renewed questions about the Coalition&amp;apos;s unity, as Sussan Ley downplays internal divisions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12c544795c49d7cb107e34944b9948fb</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;What on earth?&amp;apos;: Optus defends fatal outage response at Senate inquiry</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/what-on-earth-optus-defends-fatal-outage-response-at-senate-inquiry/o7muelt2u</link><description>Under-fire Optus executives have copped a parliamentary bashing for their response to a triple-zero outage linked to the deaths of three people. The proceedings have immediately zeroed in on CEO Stephen Rue, who is being pressured to explain a significant delay in reporting the fatalities to both the government and the regulator.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0bc2171bdd352031f7fdfdb8987efbe</guid></item><item><title>What the RBA decision means for the &amp;apos;sense of urgency&amp;apos; in the property market this spring</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-the-rba-decision-means-for-the-sense-of-urgency-in-the-property-market-this-spring/i8zqcbq8n</link><description>Spring has meant a bump in the number of new listings, which could offer an &amp;quot;opportunity&amp;quot; for first-time buyers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3eecd67551113f80d4010ae6e44051f5</guid></item><item><title>Traditional owners object to movement of &amp;apos;Old Faithful&amp;apos; crocodile made famous by Steve Irwin</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/traditional-owners-object-to-movement-of-old-faithful-crocodile-made-famous-by-steve-irwin/tj1m04p4a</link><description>Traditional owners in far north Queensland are calling for an iconic saltwater crocodile to be returned to country. The croc, named &amp;apos;Old Faithful&amp;apos;, featured in the Crocodile Hunter series alongside the late Steve Irwin - but he&amp;apos;s been re-homed far from his natural habitat following concerns over aggressive behaviour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa1b2b4c4160777b141152e254596470</guid></item><item><title>COP30 summit kicks off in Brazil, as business leaders push for clean energy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cop30-united-nations-climate-summit-kicks-off-in-brazil/x1rm8h71x</link><description>Brazil&amp;apos;s turn as this year&amp;apos;s host marks 33 years since the Rio Earth Summit, where countries first signed the United Nations treaty to tackle climate change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a7ee439372c6874b92a5c40a8f3f7e42</guid></item><item><title>CEO SERIES: Westpac CEO Anthony Miller on results, rates outlook, restructure and AI</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ceo-series-westpac-ceo-anthony-miller-on-results-rates-outlook-restructure-and-ai/dzgvgbffy</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Westpac CEO Anthony Miller about the bank&amp;apos;s full-year results to find out what will drive growth in the future, and takes a look at the market reaction with David Walsh from Sarto Advisory Pty Ltd.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8334737ea7935dbe59be3c1440a1976f</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with attempted murder after mass stabbing on UK train</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/man-charged-with-attempted-murder-after-mass-stabbing-on-uk-train/1zgz0ppos</link><description>A 32-year-old man faces 10 attempted murder charges after a mass stabbing on a London-bound train that left 11 people injured and a crew member fighting for life.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f000974c7d9db8319a1c03a4cd7e380b</guid></item><item><title>Why these skincare products with a banned ingredient are still being sold in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-these-skincare-products-with-a-banned-ingredient-are-still-being-sold-in-australia/6zz7tsa7t</link><description>Six skincare brands have been ordered to withdraw their products from supermarket shelves in NSW after being found to contain banned microbeads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afaec5c160ccd5fe66df422053179ab1</guid></item><item><title>Magnitude-6.3 earthquake kills at least 20 people in Afghanistan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/magnitude-6-3-earthquake-kills-at-least-20-people-in-afghanistan/ny5mmmx1k</link><description>The US Geological Survey said the quake hit at a depth of 28km near Mazar-e Sharif, a city of around 523,000 people famous for its shrines and historic sites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a21660a635fd4b5cdc28163345064d3</guid></item><item><title>Mushroom murderer to appeal convictions | Morning News Bulletin 4 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/mushroom-murderer-to-appeal-sentence-morning-news-bulletin-4-november-2025/objqwsbok</link><description>The death toll rises from an earthquake in northern Afghanistan,Mushroom murderer Erin Patterson lodges an appeal against her convictions, 24 local and international horses to compete in the Melbourne Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ee9db7951c70fe5d5a1ef54e6b0d5cc</guid></item><item><title>UN-backed hunger monitor confirms famine in Sudan&amp;apos;s Al-Fasher and one other city</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ipc-confirms-famine-in-sudans-al-fasher-and-kadugli/sz83z3nxd</link><description>The Integrated Food Security Phase Classification has concluded that the cities recently taken by the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces are in famine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52a8b1eee2a5d70f92960a33b89d7468</guid></item><item><title>When power isn’t guaranteed: Indigenous families in northern Australia face deadly risks in extreme heat</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/when-power-isnt-guaranteed-indigenous-families-in-northern-australia-face-deadly-risks-in-extreme-heat/ax4dvkwbk</link><description>Thousands of Indigenous households across northern Australia live with prepaid power, where disconnection can happen at any moment. Now a new report has warned that without stronger protections, the system could turn deadly in extreme heat. SBS’s Christopher Tan travelled to the Kimberley to see what life is like when power is a privilege, not a guarantee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e46f58cd22b380e0238c4c337e4d29db</guid></item><item><title>New concussion guidelines launched to help patients get the right care</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-concussion-guidelines-launched-to-help-patients-get-the-right-care/qf7c6wjso</link><description>New national clinical guidelines for the treatment of concussion have been released. They are aimed at helping healthcare professionals treat patients with greater consistency, amid concern that providing the right care can still be a blind spot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bd745b3f59d8906988e9901f4434a04</guid></item><item><title>Will you benefit? Here&amp;apos;s how Labor&amp;apos;s three hours of free power will work</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/free-power-labor-solar-sharer/hnternt0d</link><description>Several parts of the country will have access to the Solar Sharer program in its initial phase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e388f4e2e005e1dc51e81f74476dbe</guid></item><item><title>Israeli army&amp;apos;s former top lawyer arrested after leaking video of alleged detainee abuse</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/yifat-tomer-yerushalmi-arrested-after-alleged-palestinian-detainee-abuse-video-leak/7rx33v6nc</link><description>The leaked video, which allegedly shows soldiers abusing a Palestinian detainee, piled pressure on Israel&amp;apos;s political and military leaders during the Gaza war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67a926bd0595acf0a41a26e789bd9e21</guid></item><item><title>RBA &amp;apos;not wedded to a particular path&amp;apos;, Bullock says, after rates kept on hold again</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/reserve-bank-leaves-rates-on-hold-again-after-surprise-inflation-figures/sebbqc4up</link><description>For the second meeting in a row, the central bank has left the official cash rate target at 3.6 per cent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24a6641181951bd60bae071273addaf8</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 4 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-4-november-2025/13i1wbfr1</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0bea7cde18b3834b76be1280ccedf06</guid></item><item><title>Multiple arrests after police and protesters clash at Sydney weapons expo</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/multiple-arrests-after-police-and-protesters-clash-at-sydney-weapons-expo/iz7if18dh</link><description>The exhibition includes Israeli weapons manufacturers and other firms supplying that nation&amp;apos;s military.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">747be68bffda2ab5c58a91ef8562cf20</guid></item><item><title>Unlikely alliance forces Senate showdown over Labor’s ‘Jobs for mates’ report</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/unlikely-alliance-forces-senate-showdown-over-labors-jobs-for-mates-report/5uruyzqes</link><description>An unusual alliance of crossbenchers and the Coalition has forced an ongoing extension of Question Time in the Senate. They are demanding the Labor government immediately release the &amp;quot;jobs for mates&amp;quot; report, which it has withheld for two years. Critics, including Transparency International, say the government&amp;apos;s refusal to release the report is further evidence of a &amp;quot;culture of secrecy&amp;quot; at a time when its integrity standards are under heightened scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c009c462b64a26dfd41ddd400b70db2e</guid></item><item><title>Rates on hold as RBA lifts inflation forecast</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/rates-on-hold-as-rba-lifts-inflation-forecast/fwyie69b0</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Laura Cooper from Nuveen and Gemma Dale from nabtrade about the RBA&amp;apos;s decision to leave interest rates on hold and why its revised inflation forecasts risks an end to its rate cutting cycle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51c4caa7d9e9aefd9c646f4e8b17e8a8</guid></item><item><title>Three free hours of power under new plan - or is it?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/three-free-hours-of-power-under-new-plan-or-is-it/erx9ank1n</link><description>Australians in three states are to be offered three hours of free electricity in the middle of the day, under a scheme to share abundant solar energy harvested in non-peak hours. The plan has been welcomed by environmental groups, but some in the Opposition are unimpressed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">866a92e4947d6e7a271e3e7c2efd7688</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Little did they know&amp;apos;: ASIO boss reveals spy confrontation, and fresh Russia threats</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/asio-boss-reveals-spy-confrontation-and-fresh-russia-threats/8x648j2mc</link><description>Mike Burgess said his agency foiled an elaborate plot by spies from a country that claims it &amp;quot;does not spy on Australia&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">717ac186335134082a26fd78f8a25474</guid></item><item><title>These women beat &amp;apos;incurable&amp;apos; cancers, but others can&amp;apos;t access their treatment</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/these-women-beat-incurable-cancers-but-their-treatment-may-never-get-to-market/hrgufnruq</link><description>Two Australian scientists have developed a cancer treatment that has the potential to save millions of lives — if people can access it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">830bd88240a835100dc2b7e1423f328e</guid></item><item><title>Temu, a plug-in heater that &amp;apos;doesn&amp;apos;t plug in&amp;apos;, and more: 2025&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;Shonkys&amp;apos; revealed</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/choice-shonky-awards-2025-commonwealth-bank-temu-hcf/idn9r4kbv</link><description>Consumer advocacy group Choice has released its annual report card of products, services and companies it deems dodgy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c65c663b7760601c5c5442c94bba9b08</guid></item><item><title>More platforms added to under-16s social media ban, others still under consideration</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/reddit-and-kick-added-to-under-16s-social-media-ban/v0xe9i0ri</link><description>Reddit and live-streaming platform Kick have been added to the social media ban for under-16s, with other apps still being considered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82147f365eb7e6eac46dae6c95f45b6a</guid></item><item><title>Typhoon death toll soars past 90 in the Philippines as survivors confront destruction</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/typhoon-kalmaegi-philippines-death-toll/nw4syiuot</link><description>The death toll from Kalmaegi in the Philippines has risen as heavy rains and floods devastated the central region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77c8012c0cfdd0b3e3387df1959323e2</guid></item><item><title>Typhoon death toll soars past 90 in the Philippines as survivors confront destruction</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/typhoon-kills-at-least-46-in-philippines-leaves-thousands-stranded/nw4syiuot</link><description>The death toll from Kalmaegi in the Philippines has risen as heavy rains and floods devastated the central region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d44c9725ad222081790c7ab7a562837a</guid></item><item><title>When will we know the results? Key details as New Yorkers vote for who should be mayor</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/voting-is-underway-in-new-york-city-and-mamdani-looks-set-to-become-mayor/wullvrlaz</link><description>Once virtually unknown, Zohran Mamdani has led by double digits over rival Andrew Cuomo, with Republican nominee Curtis Sliwa a distant third in most polls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d85e503aa018900fba649033bfb15092</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I feel guilty that I&amp;apos;m safe&amp;apos;: Sudanese-Australians fear for families after Al-Fasher massacres</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/i-feel-guilty-that-im-safe-sudanese-australians-fear-for-families-after-al-fasher-massacres/ev01ias40</link><description>Members of the Sudanese-Australian community are anxiously awaiting news from their family trapped in the city of Al-Fasher after an explosion of violence. The city was captured by the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces one week ago, with experts believing thousands may have been killed in widespread massacres. With internet and phone services cut off, those living abroad are forced to sit and wait to learn if their loved ones are still alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2235058b9b51b18f07ba6699022d351b</guid></item><item><title>Shark Bay: where Indigenous knowledge and marine science meet</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/shark-bay-where-indigenous-knowledge-and-marine-science-meet/oikkw7tur</link><description>Professor Michael Wear, a Malgana Traditional Custodian from Shark Bay, has been honoured at the 26th Prime Minister’s Prizes for Science for his groundbreaking work uniting Indigenous knowledge and marine science. He is the inaugural winner of the Prime Minister’s Prize for Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Knowledge Systems. Through his company Tidal Moon, Professor Wear is leading a world-first seagrass restoration project that employs Aboriginal divers, supports sustainable livelihoods, and restores cultural connections to Sea Country. His work highlights how traditional wisdom and Western science can come together to protect Australia’s oceans and climate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6dcad2213b5c53306a8310a0757d7b0</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Stay away&amp;apos;: Fresh threat after Kentucky crash as authorities fear death toll will rise</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cargo-plane-crashes-after-take-off-in-us-state-of-kentucky/y32zhdpzw</link><description>Several buildings in an industrial area beyond the runway were on fire after the crash, with thick black smoke rising into the evening sky.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beb951a1709fffb943707c743dec8939</guid></item><item><title>Dick Cheney, former US vice president and key Bush-era figure, dies aged 84</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/dick-cheney-former-us-vice-president-and-key-bush-era-figure-dies-aged-84/2fmelzp8y</link><description>Former US Vice President Dick Cheney has died at the age of 84 from complications related to pneumonia and cardiovascular disease. Mr Cheney became one of the most powerful vice presidents in US history as George W Bush’s number two during 9/11 and the wars in Afghanistan and Iraq.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01d5985e0c08a9ac39ff0104a9c1af40</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Foodbank Australia CEO Kylea Tink</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-foodbank-australia-ceo-kylea-tink/lw84dygf8</link><description>One in three Australian households experienced food insecurity in the past 12 months, according to the Foodbank Hunger Report 2025. The report paints a stark picture of widening food insecurity across the nation, debunking the myth that hunger only affects the unemployed or homeless. The report reveals that cost-of-living pressures remain the number one concern for 91% of food-insecure households, followed by housing and the broader economy. Behind the data are the real stories of families forced to skip meals so children can eat, workers going hungry to pay rising rents, and people living with disability or illness struggling to put food on the table. Foodbank Australia CEO Kylea Tink spoke with SBS&amp;apos;s Cameron Carr</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73e91f139f597f3d44b6dfb5806dd383</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Turn the volume up&amp;apos;: Mamdani speaks after historic win as Trump reacts to Democrat victories</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/zohran-mamdani-elected-as-mayor-of-new-york-city-in-historic-win/c5abq2a8k</link><description>Zohran Mamdani&amp;apos;s win caps a meteoric rise from a little-known state politician to one of the nation&amp;apos;s most visible Democrats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb701b977cbd05db5bae3d370512185f</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 5 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-5-november-2025/0718v85ph</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English Language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">526c43852bd6ffc95f27b5bb7cf70404</guid></item><item><title>The &amp;apos;insidious problem&amp;apos; leaving Australians like Jessica &amp;apos;lucky&amp;apos; to eat twice a day</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/food-insecurity-worsening-in-australia-according-to-foodbank/w2sediuu0</link><description>Millions of Australian families are struggling with hardship that &amp;quot;is not getting better&amp;quot;, a charity warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64e3f190d88b1017c2da715a7fe4ed0b</guid></item><item><title>Questions linger over which platforms to ban as Reddit and Kick included in eSafety list</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/questions-linger-over-which-platforms-to-ban-as-reddit-and-kick-included-in-esafety-list/0ali0sxt7</link><description>Reddit and live-streaming platform Kick will be added to the platforms required to ban 16s when the new rules come into effect in December. Australia&amp;apos;s impending social media ban for under-16s, which covers eight major platforms, hinges on ongoing eSafety assessments that distinguish between social media, messaging, and gaming services, explaining why platforms like Steam and Twitch were not initially included.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3450acf78f552bde8836f53d392484ca</guid></item><item><title>Bitcoin bear market &amp;amp; AI valuation fears</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/bitcoin-bear-market-ai-valuation-fears/i26uo5hfr</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Rachael Lucas from BTC Markets about bitcoin&amp;apos;s latest plunge while Luke Laretive from Seneca Financial Solutions takes a look at the day&amp;apos;s trading action including a global sell-off triggered by interest rate and AI valuation concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85bcde19ed3f31c81ec448208f46b6c2</guid></item><item><title>Could new sanctions on Russia affect cost of living in Australia?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-fuel-prices-turning-point/zlp3yj79y</link><description>Could disruptions to Russian and other global oil supplies impact Australians? And, if so, how?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd9e3c72f128d418906e15b74c83de21</guid></item><item><title>New government powers to keep ASIO, AFP in check as intelligence agencies expand</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/asio-afp-on-notice-under-new-intelligence-agency-oversight-powers/iwhqz74jw</link><description>In the biggest reforms since the 1980s, intelligence agencies such as ASIO will have their functions increasingly scrutinised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7b3865be8873ba0dec5069779abbd5f</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;In a precarious situation&amp;apos;: Why experts say Australia needed a centre for disease control</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-cdc-passes-senate/iewdbc758</link><description>While experts say the agency will improve Australia&amp;apos;s public health response, there are concerns it could initially miss key issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b59f5cfa545efabb329d916646d7e77</guid></item><item><title>&amp;quot;We have to act now&amp;quot;: &amp;apos;Stubborn&amp;apos; workplace racism sparks call for major inquiry</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/we-have-to-act-now-stubborn-workplace-racism-sparks-call-for-major-inquiry/uxihgtcdy</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s race discrimination commissioner Giridharan Sivaraman says Australia needs a national inquiry into racism in workplaces. He has made the remarks as community leaders, advocates and trade union gathered in Canberra to examine systemic barriers faced by First Peoples and other racialised communities in the workplace.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">172fc7c48ce03dfb066d236b0711db8c</guid></item><item><title>Should you be freaking out about microplastics?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/should-you-be-freaking-out-about-microplastics/2l6tlt0rg</link><description>Microplastics are turning up everywhere, but some scientists say how harmful they are to our bodies is still uncertain. Here&amp;apos;s why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f46657b2dd2d5a3933091ab79069a36</guid></item><item><title>Teaching was the &amp;apos;perfect career&amp;apos; for Rachel. Racist comments pushed her to quit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-last-straw-that-led-to-rachel-quitting-her-perfect-career/u2xtr0ec7</link><description>A problem that spanned staff and students led Rachel to quit a teaching career she loved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edcf6a6c815d878b3554588e77047632</guid></item><item><title>US Supreme Court scrutinises legality of Trump&amp;apos;s sweeping tariffs in landmark case</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-supreme-court-scrutinises-legality-of-trumps-sweeping-tariffs-in-landmark-case/av4gvkivl</link><description>Since returning to the White House, US President Donald Trump has brought the average effective tariff rate to its highest since the 1930s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc0cb82210a206291bb7e6527161064</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Communism or common sense&amp;apos;: Trump says Americans have a choice after Mamdani&amp;apos;s win</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/communism-or-common-sense-trump-says-americans-have-a-choice-after-mamdanis-win/2u88w5qfb</link><description>New Yorkers on Wednesday voted overwhelmingly for democratic socialist Zohran Mamdani to be their next mayor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a037e81e0c2ad88773086c654a8abbb</guid></item><item><title>Japan deploys military to combat wave of deadly bear attacks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/japan-deploys-troops-as-bear-attacks-surge-across-the-country/8yuk1frcs</link><description>Bears have attacked customers inside a supermarket, jumped a tourist waiting at a bus stop and mutilated a worker at a hot spring resort.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0963f20c2e8c3be7a1ce574c3dd04ee8</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Can Zohran Mamdani deliver on his election promises?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-can-zohran-mamdani-deliver-on-his-election-promises/afo89blkp</link><description>New York City Mayor-elect Zohran Mamdani led a new generation of Democrat victories this week with his victory over the old guard and Andrew Cuomo. Mr Mamdani, the first Muslim to be elected mayor of the biggest U.S. city, defeated former Democratic Governor Andrew Cuomo, who ran as an independent after losing the nomination to Mamdani earlier this year. Mr Cuomo, who resigned as governor four years ago after sexual harassment allegations that he has denied, painted Mr Mamdani as a radical leftist whose proposals were unworkable and dangerous. Mr Mamdani himself has proposed raising taxes on corporations and the wealthy to pay for ambitious policies such as rent freezes, free childcare and free city buses. But like other winning candidates from the off-year elections, Mr Mamdani focused intensely on economic issues, particularly the cost of living, an issue that helped propel U.S. President, Donald Trump, to the White House last year but has remained top-of-mind for voters. In this episode of weeke nd omne-on-one, we hear from Eric Gander, who&amp;apos;s the chair of the Department of Communications at New York&amp;apos;s Baruch College.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">046921ed942ac4494c7aad60edace58e</guid></item><item><title>Behind Zohran Mamdani&amp;apos;s historic win, and what it means for the Democratic Party&amp;apos;s future</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-will-zohran-mamdani-affect-us-politics/nwxpbg5cj</link><description>The mayor-elect of New York City was just one of the Democrats to win an election this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">780bb083212a6ecfc7e941d85376da46</guid></item><item><title>Mexico&amp;apos;s president was groped on the street. She&amp;apos;s now calling for tougher sexual assault laws</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/mexicos-president-was-groped-on-the-street-shes-now-calling-for-tougher-sexual-assault-laws/5az1ujs5t</link><description>The incident highlighted Mexico&amp;apos;s troubling record on women&amp;apos;s safety as rights groups warned of a femicide crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e4ddf1a577e2761aee7ed8f44a3da77</guid></item><item><title>Wong warns about foreign interference| Midday News Bulletin 6 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/wong-warns-about-foreign-interference-midday-news-bulletin-6-november-2025/3ymju8wc1</link><description>In this bulletin, Australia imposes sanctions on cybercriminals funding North Korean weapons, Microsoft to refund customers after A-triple-C sues the tech giant. And in sport, Team Australia unveils its new uniform ahead of the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c14d34addbf9291b00b37da1f8efb95</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 6 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-6-november-2025/niagalysh</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbcc38ec52622e6ce76b380376edbcad</guid></item><item><title>US election results: Mamdani’s win and Democratic landslide spell trouble for Trump’s Republicans</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-election-results-mamdanis-win-and-democratic-landslide-spell-trouble-for-trumps-republicans/nwljlui9w</link><description>The Democrats have secured landslide victories in a number of elections across the United States, with Zohran Mamdani making history in his election as New York City mayor. A year out from the midterms, analysts say the resounding Democratic victory should serve as a warning to Republicans that Donald Trump&amp;apos;s more hard-line actions aren&amp;apos;t going over well with voters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">724b98c696197d4463100026f29fb2e1</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Many will be misled&amp;apos;: A superannuation boost for workers comes with a warning</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/superannuation-boost-for-workers-comes-with-a-warning/xzbkhafo5</link><description>Omitted superannuation changes have sparked concern some Australians may face unnecessary costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7409317f67254367dd36d815f1573de</guid></item><item><title>Hanson outlines One Nation agenda at surprise Mar-a-Lago address</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hanson-outlines-one-nation-agenda-at-surprise-mar-a-lago-address/fyjltejve</link><description>The speech to American conservatives comes as polling suggests support for One Nation has surged.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb724d6bd8fdbf0836bf1a84604a7726</guid></item><item><title>State of Emergency declared after deadly Philippine typhoon | Evening News Bulletin 6 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/state-of-emergency-declared-after-deadly-philippine-typhoon-evening-news-bulletin-6-november-2025/ncmi7o18v</link><description>In this bulletin, the Philippine president declares a state of emergency, as hundreds are confirmed dead in a typhoon, environmental law reforms pass the house of representatives with a single amendment. And in football, Manchester City cruises to victory against Dortmund in the Champions League.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e8dac9c72d602f6d59318db596a1797</guid></item><item><title>Advocates flag &amp;apos;make or break time&amp;apos; for planet as COP30 begins</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/advocates-flag-make-or-break-time-for-planet-as-cop30-begins/ljmniw6xk</link><description>This year&amp;apos;s global climate summit - COP30 - is being hailed as the most significant in ten years, with experts describing it the &amp;quot;make or break decade&amp;quot; for action on global warming. But doubts are being raised about whether enough can be achieved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca7d43271a48b8580e9302498f009a2f</guid></item><item><title>Sudan’s civil war ‘spirals out of control’, Mamdani takes on Trump &amp;amp; would you snip and share?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sudans-civil-war-spirals-out-of-control-mamdani-takes-on-trump-would-you-snip-and-share/l5ds2hdw6</link><description>Confronting reports of mass killings in Sudan, after a key city in Darfur falls to the RSF. The plan for an international stabilisation force for Gaza makes its way to the UN and it’s ‘GAME ON’ after the democratic socialist Zohran Mamdani wins NY – with Donald Trump threatening to cut federal funding to the city. Plus, why young men in China are opening up about getting the snip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef5b5bb5513cd823d32536cac4d1c1df</guid></item><item><title>NAB results disappoint &amp;amp; bank sector challenges</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nab-results-disappoint-bank-sector-challenges/818xmrp7p</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Michael Wayne from Medallion Financial about the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action including why investors were disappointed with NAB&amp;apos;s $7.1bn cash earnings full- year report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed40291d26cd6911585095e31d214ff9</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s first LGBTIQ+ redress scheme is approved, yet some will never see it</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/victims-of-discriminatory-laws-now-eligible-for-compensation-in-tasmania/6u9hx9o6s</link><description>Tasmania has become the first state to establish a redress scheme for people affected by discriminatory laws.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b5268c9f539c335d2a2945c8fe27c43</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested after groping Mexican President on the street</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/man-arrested-after-groping-mexican-president-on-the-street/ipodk4tac</link><description>Mexican President Claudia Sheinbaum has called for sexual harassment to be made a criminal offence nationwide after being groped on the street. The incident occurred as she walked to an event near the presidential palace, shaking hands and taking pictures with people along the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c67bffa2106e3f2d549664366841aa49</guid></item><item><title>The US government shutdown is now the longest ever. When will it end?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-government-shutdown-longest-ever/le4mvi0fa</link><description>A blame game between Republicans and Democrats continues, although there have been signs of hope.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a32961ef13faba005a6122a50607e16</guid></item><item><title>Australians react to victory of Zohran Mamdani in New York</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australians-react-to-victory-of-zohran-mamdani-in-new-york/zsiujsxq2</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a0121fd0b296134f2e435c65386fb06</guid></item><item><title>These Aussie regions have posted &amp;apos;astronomical&amp;apos; price gains — but there&amp;apos;s a catch</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/astronomical-price-gains-regional-property/nh4mia09c</link><description>Looks — even when pristine and coastal — can be deceiving.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bb46c3cfc26aa0a0a4b87ab7ab8d183</guid></item><item><title>Sudan&amp;apos;s Rapid Support Forces agrees to US-Arab humanitarian truce proposal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sudans-rapid-support-forces-agrees-to-us-arab-humanitarian-truce-proposal/2wdcv1w9l</link><description>Both the RSF and the Sudanese army have agreed to various ceasefire proposals during the two-and-a-half-year-old war, though none have succeeded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cbd5d954e5ecaafb046b10d530a87f6</guid></item><item><title>Sudan&amp;apos;s RSF agrees to a humanitarian ceasefire | Morning News Bulletin 7 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sudans-rsf-agrees-to-a-humanitarian-ceasefire-morning-news-bulletin-7-november-2025/y7f8ja43y</link><description>Sudan&amp;apos;s RSF agrees to a humanitarian ceasefire; Typhoon Kalmaegi slams into Vietnam after killing at least 114 people in the Philippines; And in sport, calls for moving the AFLW seasons back to summertime.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b780761fa73716220f0deb546e0826c</guid></item><item><title>Deadly Typhoon Kalmaegi ravages Vietnam after killing 188 in the Philippines</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/typhoon-kalmaegi-vietnam-killing-114-in-philippines1/izy3jypc0</link><description>The Vietnamese government has placed more than 268,000 soldiers on standby for search and rescue operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0ec36d9706cd4ba3a03927a7e6ae913</guid></item><item><title>Deadly Typhoon Kalmaegi ravages Vietnam after killing 188 in the Philippines</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/typhoon-kalmaegi-strikes-vietnam-after-killing-114-in-philippines1/izy3jypc0</link><description>The Vietnamese government has placed more than 268,000 soldiers on standby for search and rescue operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d44d0c0f50a2848a5448dd3b9dbd4b30</guid></item><item><title>Deadly Typhoon Kalmaegi ravages Vietnam after killing 188 in the Philippines</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/typhoon-kalmaegi-vietnam-philippines-cambodia-thailand/izy3jypc0</link><description>The Vietnamese government has placed more than 268,000 soldiers on standby for search and rescue operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a138c2b33e9baf53c7f43b362da8c01</guid></item><item><title>Deadly Typhoon Kalmaegi ravages Vietnam after killing 188 in the Philippines</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/typhoon-kalmaegi-strikes-vietnam-after-killing-114-in-philippines/izy3jypc0</link><description>The Vietnamese government has placed more than 268,000 soldiers on standby for search and rescue operations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3423e068ce908d90ebda7fcb132a75c6</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Sense of impending doom&amp;apos;: Should the Liberals and Nationals break up forever?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sense-of-impending-doom-should-the-liberals-and-nationals-break-up-forever/g7992uf1h</link><description>The Nationals have officially dumped their net zero policy - but does that mean the Liberals are going to dump them? This week, we speak to Jill Sheppard, a political scientist from the Australian National University, about what&amp;apos;s happening to the Coalition&amp;apos;s relationship and if they should break up. We also have news about a very spooky White House Halloween and - for some reason - horse racing commentary in the House of Representatives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8972f79a2c774c184b71248369cdaca</guid></item><item><title>South Lebanon villages face evacuation orders as Israel launches heavy airstrikes</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/south-lebanon-villages-face-evacuation-orders-as-israel-launches-heavy-airstrikes/vy16w33h7</link><description>The Israeli armed forces said armed group Hezbollah was trying to rebuild its military capabilities in southern Lebanon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a4f2d2b75bbb553bf282bc9c65b0117</guid></item><item><title>Why these US politicians want to speak with the former prince Andrew</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-democrats-summon-former-prince-andrew-over-epstein-claims/w83co6bbc</link><description>King Charles has also now formally stripped his brother of his royal titles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9a8a9fc56bcf590380a1ed23cdf790b</guid></item><item><title>Why these US politicians want to speak with the former prince Andrew</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-these-american-politicians-want-to-speak-with-former-prince-andrew/w83co6bbc</link><description>King Charles has also now formally stripped his brother of his royal titles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f8a91bad331eadc022a61afb3b89141</guid></item><item><title>Masculinity crisis deepens as half of Australian teen boys feel pressure to ‘be strong’</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/masculinity-crisis-deepens-as-half-of-australian-teen-boys-feel-pressure-to-be-strong/tjpn77mhu</link><description>A landmark report released this week has found Australian boys are feeling pressure to follow restrictive ideas about masculinity - and when they do - they are more likely to hurt themselves and others. Advocates have used a National Press Club address to call for urgent government reform, including a national action plan to improve young people&amp;apos;s wellbeing and reduce violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8caa4a2e3b3a6db08b7447fa9f63db6</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Ask her&amp;apos;: Sussan Ley fires back over colleague&amp;apos;s criticism of her leadership</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sussan-leys-liberal-colleague-thinks-her-leadership-is-in-need-of-a-miracle/zl47osmi5</link><description>Sarah Henderson, who was dumped by Sussan Ley from the frontbench earlier this year, says the party is in a &amp;quot;dire situation&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73c6905439703e5e4cbb66714e13f805</guid></item><item><title>Sudan officials outline conditions to agree to peace truce | Midday News Bulletin 7 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sudan-officials-outline-conditions-to-agree-to-peace-truce-midday-news-bulletin-7-november-2025/xs1oshnms</link><description>In this bulletin, Sudan officials outline the nation’s conditions to agree to a ceasefire deal, the Health Minister defends the public sectors&amp;apos; 250 billion-dollar annual wages bill. And in football, Maccabi Tel Aviv fans protest being blocked from the team&amp;apos;s match against Aston Villa, over concerns of violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b469d0aa2c3a5b5125142618c340af20</guid></item><item><title>Sudan&amp;apos;s RSF agrees to humanitarian truce: but will it ever happen?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sudans-rsf-agrees-to-humanitarian-truce-but-will-it-ever-happen/suq6eskul</link><description>Sudan’s paramilitary Rapid Support Forces, the RSF, has agreed to a humanitarian truce proposed by mediators, the first sign of possible peace after nearly three years of brutal conflict. The group says the pause is meant to allow aid to reach civilians, but the Sudanese Army has yet to accept the terms, insisting RSF fighters must first withdraw from populated areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">590613b5ee596d696d07285457c26315</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Deadly negligence&amp;apos;: Stern warning issued as COP30 climate summit opens in Brazil</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/deadly-negligence-stern-warning-issued-as-cop30-climate-summit-opens-in-brazil/sinu3z2fr</link><description>Leaders are gathering in Brazil for the UN COP30 Climate Summit as the United Nations declares the world will not meet the 1.5 degree warming limit set in 2015. With 2025 set to be one of the warmest years on record, the most vulnerable small island nations are pleading for stronger action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1aee7ed90084471d0b7bcdf92d9b90f</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 7 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-7-november-2025/wcuvkst6i</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18fbd1fd5e5f92df4353df29d27eed0c</guid></item><item><title>The risks and realities as talk of nuclear tests returns to the world stage</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nuclear-testing-risks-and-realities/yfj781d0t</link><description>Eighty years after the atomic bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, the shadow of nuclear weapons has re-emerged on the world stage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e25deaea36146067db1311155baa6225</guid></item><item><title>Elon Musk&amp;apos;s path to $1 trillion: These are the &amp;apos;aggressive goals&amp;apos; he must hit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/elon-musk-trillionaire-pay-package/uj2zmnioi</link><description>He&amp;apos;s already the world&amp;apos;s richest man by some estimates, and he could become richer — if he meets aggressive performance goals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4556ba619e1158c07d8f5a774b3fa9a7</guid></item><item><title>Australia negotiates COP31 host bid with Turkey | Evening News Bulletin 7 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australia-negotiates-cop31-host-bid-with-turkey-evening-news-bulletin-7-november-2025/pe2jiayvw</link><description>In this bulletin, the energy minister insists Australia has support to host COP31 as it negotiates an agreement with Turkiye, the UN lifts sanctions from Syria&amp;apos;s leader, ahead of his meeting with Donald Trump. And in NFL, the league courts the next generation of its fastest growing audience outside the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b43b52c446063a93d57315be3c3f4b42</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Deadly negligence&amp;apos;: Stern warning issued as COP30 climate summit opens in Brazil</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/deadly-negligence-stern-warning-issued-as-cop30-climate-summit-opens-in-brazil/o8mqqvndj</link><description>Leaders are gathering in Brazil for the UN COP30 Climate Summit as the United Nations declares the world will not meet the 1.5 degree warming limit set in 2015. With 2025 set to be one of the warmest years on record, the most vulnerable small island nations are pleading for stronger action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b65a3b0ea0b3cfbcbf4419bbf15f7b70</guid></item><item><title>Many Australians face &amp;apos;unsettled&amp;apos; weekend with severe storms and rain</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/weekend-weather-rain/atrmjisi9</link><description>A wet and stormy weekend is forecast for parts of the country, with giant hail and flash flooding possible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cd6833e5e9ccc84967f3b75b6984b1f</guid></item><item><title>Elon Musk’s trillion-dollar payday; uncertainty creeps back into markets</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/elon-musks-trillion-dollar-payday-uncertainty-creeps-back-into-markets/a9zn17411</link><description>Tesla shareholders have approved a US$1 trillion dollar compensation package for CEO Elon Musk, tying him to the electric vehicle maker for a decade. Plus, the Australian sharemarket has followed Wall Street on a downward tilt, thanks to concerns over tech stock valuations and economic uncertainty. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Heath Moss, Portfolio Manager at HLM Investments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">879a7da7416e7b527b35f8dfa3a19ab7</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Won&amp;apos;t make a lick of difference&amp;apos;: Why building apartments may not bring prices down</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/does-building-more-apartments-help-housing-affordability/0opkcmpj4</link><description>Allowing developers to build high-density housing doesn&amp;apos;t automatically make homes affordable. This is why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67d56819c2d2c19d7d40369b0bb3ee5b</guid></item><item><title>How an offer to carry a strange package to Australia almost turned Susi into a drug courier</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/susi-agreed-to-carry-a-package-to-australia-it-turned-out-to-have-a-20-million-street-value/1ik7l7bza</link><description>A Thai woman who regularly travels to Australia to visit family narrowly escaped becoming an unwitting drug courier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d720ab2f93e38d6a43a748868ea86288</guid></item><item><title>Morning News Bulletin 8 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/morning-news-bulletin-8-november-2025/s5w3e3os7</link><description>Drone strikes in Sudan, a day after the Rapid Support Forces agrees to a humanitarian truce; the Liberal Party yet to finalise their position on net zero policy; and in cricket, Nathan Ellis feels good about squad ahead of T20 World Cup next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ed85dc688e9f7123116c4462ffb5d7d</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Heartbreaking&amp;apos;: Experts argue egg donation rules could change to help Australia&amp;apos;s fertility issues</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/heartbreaking-experts-argue-egg-donation-rules-could-change-to-help-australias-fertility-issues/4cd5nz1zc</link><description>Demand for donated eggs is growing in Australia as more people face fertility challenges. But the demand for eggs far outstrips their supply and now, experts are arguing Australia should consider changing the rules around donation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e82b9f1811c5bd250c05e1269c36421</guid></item><item><title>Princess Anne will arrive in Australia days after Prince Andrew was stripped of his title</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/princess-anne-in-australia/7108p5ld3</link><description>While the controversy surrounding Prince Andrew will linger, one expert said the tour could take some heat off the royals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f98ddf2d2f1525d962c89350a8909469</guid></item><item><title>Just smile and wave? Not for increasing numbers of penguins as extreme weather advances</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/just-smile-and-wave-not-for-increasing-numbers-of-penguins-as-extreme-weather-advances/e0d9peck5</link><description>An international team of scientists has warned that the world’s penguins could be at risk from the combined effects of extreme weather. The new study suggests it’s not single events like heatwaves that pose the biggest danger, but their combined impact both on land and at sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b7c1b5b6f2570835ace2d9e2bcf2f8f</guid></item><item><title>At least 54 injured in blasts at high school mosque in Jakarta</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jakarta-mosque-school-bombing/5uv6rg5a7</link><description>A 17-year-old student has been identified as the suspected perpetrator of the attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ad2f1bcee1b8b5074910e5e544c1b88</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian militant group returns the body of Israeli hostage</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/islamic-jihad-hands-over-body-of-israeli-hostage/tlqnlxxd3</link><description>So far, the bodies of 22 hostages have been returned to Israel as part of a fragile ceasefire agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51b02b21cef0b463ca4c37513d06ac3d</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Please wake up&amp;apos;: Leaders and activists prepare for &amp;apos;make or break&amp;apos; COP30 in Brazil</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cop-30-brazil-belem/awobisgtu</link><description>COP30 is being hailed as the most significant climate summit since the Paris Agreement was signed ten years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08a851d16fe9de0a557fb8b8eff10ca2</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Unacceptable&amp;apos;: Hospitals are missing opportunity to vaccinate for whooping cough</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/whooping-cough-vaccine-rates/fdcd1iz7d</link><description>Immunisation Foundation founder Catherine Hughes, who lost her son to whooping cough, says Australia needs to boost vaccination rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96d59c368df4c78f8a1681aa0e51e86b</guid></item><item><title>Midday News Bulletin 8 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/midday-news-bulletin-8-november-2025/b2fprprhi</link><description>Indigenous activists from the Amazon, Mexico and Indonesia attend the UN climate summit in Brazil; Grammy nominations for Australian artists; and in cricket, the Melbourne Stars unveils the team&amp;apos;s new First Nations jersey.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">feb6c2810668bf7d79cb1528eba1fcdf</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The world is watching&amp;apos;: Denmark follows Australia&amp;apos;s youth social media ban</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/denmark-follows-youth-social-media-ban/lkxhu8y02</link><description>As the deadline looms for tech platforms to comply with Australia&amp;apos;s youth social media ban, Denmark has announced a similar policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7805e92c8b4e6996ceec06cf9f69d52f</guid></item><item><title>Evening News Bulletin 8 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/evening-news-bulletin-8-november-2025/glis363nf</link><description>A toddler hit by a train in western New South Wales; Denmark to ban social media for under 15s amid concern for youth mental health; The A-T-P tennis finals set to get underway in Turin from tomorrow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dff2f2391376bdfe175519bd771fae48</guid></item><item><title>Ukrainian-Australians call for further action on Russian &amp;apos;blood oil&amp;apos; entering the country</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ukrainian-australians-call-for-further-action-on-russian-blood-oil/5imqsjgdu</link><description>The Ukrainian-Australian community wants more government action to close a loophole allowing sanctioned Russian oil to enter the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02153feb1387254ccf0d0309ad90a1d8</guid></item><item><title>Police authorisation of Sydney neo-Nazi demonstration sparks calls for protest law review</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/minns-and-nsw-police-commissioner-call-for-legal-review-after-neo-nazi-protest/n3unuuvst</link><description>A neo-Nazi protest received NSW Police authorisation to go ahead outside NSW parliament on Saturday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a15ea1937cc716f523ab4b3c5ceae06c</guid></item><item><title>Police authorisation of Sydney neo-Nazi demonstration sparks calls for protest law review</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/minns-and-nsw-police-commissioner-call-for-legal-review-after-neo-nazi-protest1/n3unuuvst</link><description>A neo-Nazi protest received NSW Police authorisation to go ahead outside NSW parliament on Saturday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">149550e52f2da8c3d18259f958f63667</guid></item><item><title>Morning News Bulletin 9 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/morning-news-bulletin-9-november-2025/u32v3s2qv</link><description>Israel returns the bodies of 15 Palestinians under the Gaza ceasefire deal; The New South Wales Premier says actions will be taken after a neo-Nazi rally in Sydney; And in Rugby League, the Kangaroos achieve an Ashes clean sweep.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7460ba0902778c77e7cbff40c41fd9ab</guid></item><item><title>The first Miss Palestine hopes to make history in the &amp;apos;Olympics of women&amp;apos;s beauty&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/the-first-miss-palestine-hopes-to-make-history-in-the-olympics-of-womens-beauty/jtulqx3d4</link><description>This year&amp;apos;s Miss Universe will include Miss Palestine for the first time. But do beauty pageants have an impact outside of the arena?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">315719879d248b48c2f093b68b9ae102</guid></item><item><title>Naughty and downright bad: The First Nations characters Kodie wants to put on screen</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/reckless-the-first-nations-characters-kodie-bedford-wants-to-put-on-screen/lft0cvzd1</link><description>Australian writer Kodie Bedford wants to change the way we think about First Nations characters. The first step? Making them downright bad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a225e0e8773a11284d1c94f2efa89917</guid></item><item><title>The Alzheimer&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;imbalance&amp;apos; this Australian has under the microscope</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-alzheimers-imbalance-this-australian-has-under-the-microscope/janflm0p2</link><description>The researcher hopes to uncover clues to explain one group is particularly at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">032a7bc217999b7bc44e2b95dc175436</guid></item><item><title>Nuclear tensions rise as Trump floats cooperation with Russia and China</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nuclear-tensions-rise-as-trump-floats-cooperation-with-russia-and-china/aelg1mrao</link><description>Eighty years after the atomic bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, the shadow of nuclear weapons has re-emerged on the world stage. Once thought to be relics of a bygone era, they are again the subject of fierce rhetoric between Washington, Moscow and Beijing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0598cbb610a7cdc88099b31e105c5f59</guid></item><item><title>Calls for a better refugee response as Australia approaches one millionth visa milestone</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/calls-for-a-better-refugee-response-as-australia-approaches-one-millionth-visa-milestone/w4obit4j6</link><description>Australia is set to issue its one millionth permanent humanitarian visa since the end of World War II as early as the end of this year. The milestone has prompted celebration over the immense contribution refugees make to Australia&amp;apos;s national story. But refugee rights organisations say it&amp;apos;s a pertinent time to consider how Australia can improve its response to mass global displacement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f70cdc921b48f5be70f40616d36d57a</guid></item><item><title>Families await five more remains as Israel identifies latest hostage body</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/families-await-five-more-remains-as-israel-identifies-latest-hostage-body/2c5c3z26t</link><description>Five more bodies remain to be returned — three Israelis and one Thai national seized in the October 7 attack, and one Israeli officer who died in combat in 2014.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31809c9e6713e6044ac855f1bbb2c778</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Bruce Stillman on the life and legacy of DNA pioneer James Watson</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-bruce-stillman-on-the-life-and-legacy-of-dna-pioneer-james-watson/bp6n7fgvi</link><description>Australian scientist Bruce Stillman reflects on the complicated legacy of American biologist James Watson who has died at the age of 97. He co-discovered the double helix structure of the DNA molecule - but his remarks in later life have drawn criticism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c1bf6398627d1a846a49ef82f28e57b</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Fung-wong hits Philippines after forcing over a million to evacuate</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/typhoon-fung-wong-nears-super-typhoon-strength-as-it-approaches-philippines/dta1y5xvz</link><description>Fung-wong, expected to be a &amp;quot;super typhoon&amp;quot; before making landfall, bears a huge footprint, with a radius that could cover &amp;quot;almost the entire country&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8b12f425bfd3961bae752893e1b7f75</guid></item><item><title>Midday News Bulletin 9 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/midday-news-bulletin-9-november-2025/uttjljprl</link><description>New South Wales Police reviews the process that allowed a neo-Nazi rally outside state parliament; The United States says it will boycott the G20 summit in South Africa; And in tennis, Elena Rybakina wins the WTA Finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8357c0522201eafaf142736d78704481</guid></item><item><title>Russian drone attacks target nuclear substations, kill seven, Ukraine says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/russian-drone-attacks-target-nuclear-substations-kill-seven-ukraine-says/sv4bgrq0a</link><description>Several Ukrainian cities are using generators for power and water after Russia launched a barrage of drones and missiles, killing seven people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16420669433f80a4d5dde079146f8ddf</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;It&amp;apos;s ridiculous&amp;apos;: Liberal senator criticises calls to abandon net zero</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/andrew-bragg-blasts-calls-to-abandon-net-zero/tq4v7m007</link><description>As Opposition Leader Sussan Ley faces mounting pressure over net zero, one Liberal senator has urged the party to do a &amp;quot;better job&amp;quot; on reducing emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f2a97634f1f86c3c002355e7f66b381</guid></item><item><title>Report of single gunshot opens up a new line of inquiry in the search for Dezi Freeman</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dezi-freeman-manhunt-gunshot/41nl9vd88</link><description>Police are investigating reports of a gunshot heard in the vicinity moments after Dezi Freeman allegedly opened fire, killing two officers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c13ff67b69a356419f1100f4fe69c3e</guid></item><item><title>Evening News Bulletin 9 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/evening-news-bulletin-9-november-2025/hafho2euu</link><description>Hikers evacuated as crews battle an out of control bushfire in New Zealand&amp;apos;s north island; A groundbreaking report into women&amp;apos;s pain released in Victoria; The Wallabies record their second consecutive loss to Italy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a81fd70158958b0e1516a6820261197b</guid></item><item><title>Nearly one in 10 Australians believe violence can be justified by political causes, study finds</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-democracy-political-violence-survey/3n3e3g5pp</link><description>The new annual survey has been set up to measure Australia&amp;apos;s democratic health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fa6d7686652222699520fb6093d7f89</guid></item><item><title>One million permanent humanitarian visas: Calls for change as milestone nears</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-one-million-refugees/bhi7f43ml</link><description>While advocates celebrate Australia&amp;apos;s one millionth permanent humanitarian visa, experts also say Australia needs to reassess its approach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">091fd67b1f0afbc53afe1ee3d4688702</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We now have a group chat&amp;apos;: How five single mothers came together to reveal a love scam</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-five-single-mothers-came-together-to-reveal-a-love-scam/0flvkuhb3</link><description>A group of Chinese Australian single mothers were shocked to discover they&amp;apos;d all dated the same man — in some cases at the same time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb029ba90298fa29b20f9728177494a0</guid></item><item><title>I contracted a disease not officially transmitted in Australia. To save myself, I had to leave</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/i-contracted-a-disease-not-recognised-in-australia-to-save-myself-i-had-to-leave/v2xnwusmf</link><description>Lara Ryan says she contracted Lyme disease in Australia, most likely while camping. She had to travel overseas to receive the treatment she needed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb7443273b4ebe103bc50be64171ffc9</guid></item><item><title>BBC bosses resign over accusations of misleading Trump edit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bbc-bosses-resign-over-accusations-of-misleading-trump-edit/i4mb0zezl</link><description>The BBC has been embroiled in a spate of allegations that it had failed to maintain political neutrality in its reporting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b85e8c1a6156660a7dbc8798b4dbcc95</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds missing after boat carrying Rohingya migrants sinks off Malaysian coast</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hundreds-missing-after-boat-carrying-rohingya-migrants-sinks-off-malaysian-coast/3abjh2hkr</link><description>At least seven people have died and hundreds are missing after a boat carrying Rohingya migrants sank off the coast of Malaysia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02c3c5a4cb500cfad0746365d4182bdc</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Fung-wong hits the Philippines | Morning News Bulletin 10 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/super-typhoon-fung-wong-hits-the-philippines-morning-news-bulletin-10-november-2025/vn4vzu6tf</link><description>Super Typhoon Fung-wong makes landfall in the Philippines, Tributes for veteran talkback radio host John Laws, Manchester City defeat Premier League champions Liverpool in a three-nil home win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ea488bbff360278025e9f64338f21c5</guid></item><item><title>Israel confirms remains returned are soldier Hadar Goldin killed in Gaza in 2014</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-confirms-remains-returned-are-soldier-hadar-goldin-killed-in-gaza-in-2014/za51hibi9</link><description>Israeli authorities have received the remains of a hostage which Hamas says is the body of an Israeli soldier who was killed in 2014 and held for 11 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">374b1de25093f93b38e48459c43ed961</guid></item></channel></rss>