<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>SBS English News (Unofficial Aggregation)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 20:00:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>The US government has shut down. What happens now?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-to-know-about-the-us-government-shutdown/ipl8gg8s0</link><description>The US government has entered a shutdown, meaning thousands of federal employees are being placed on leave or asked to work without pay until the government reopens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3d73438cbd8bfd61429a238bb9c93d1</guid></item><item><title>SBS News In Easy English 1 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-1-october-2025/og0ij6kg9</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">634c7c07679bc14f068964ced9de631f</guid></item><item><title>Magnitude-6.9 earthquake kills more than 70 people in the Philippines</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/philippines-6-9-magniture-earthquake-kills-at-least-60/eexymigxd</link><description>The quake, which struck off the central island of Cebu, was the country&amp;apos;s deadliest in more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77b052b3a82d21bd7b5ba439b5f17230</guid></item><item><title>It happened &amp;apos;by accident&amp;apos;, but Mark is helping tackle a $2.7bn Australian problem</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-in-a-loneliness-crisis-research-suggests/ut4p7mu9o</link><description>Loneliness among men has been described as a &amp;quot;crisis&amp;quot; in Australia, and its estimated to cost the health system billions each year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edb259298a6eaedb69908518aa23d266</guid></item><item><title>BHP-China iron ore stand-off; house prices continue to rise</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/bhp-china-iron-ore-stand-off-house-prices-continue-to-rise/zflasuw75</link><description>The Australian sharemarket has fallen flat, as investors react to the US government shutdown and reports of China temporarily banning purchases of BHP’s iron ore. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Niv Dagan from Peak Asset Management. Plus, Australian house prices continue to rise, as the Albanese Government’s Home Guarantee scheme is expanded to all first home buyers. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Tim Lawless, Asia-Pacific research director at Cotality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70dcf961fdca3dd7adda15e950311621</guid></item><item><title>A new First Nations voice to guide Australia&amp;apos;s public health sector</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-new-first-nations-voice-to-guide-australias-public-health-sector/tqvwcecqm</link><description>The Public Health Association of Australia has announced they will be establishing an Aboriginal and Torres-Strait Islander voice to help guide their work after a near unanimous vote by their members. Nearly two years after the failed referendum saw a First Nations voice to parliament shot down, NGOs like the PHAA and state governments have chosen to follow the wishes of the majority of Indigenous communities in Australia who voted for this special representation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8949dfecda1f4bb674fc5069c318ac17</guid></item><item><title>Is your sunscreen safe? What to know amid Australia&amp;apos;s SPF ratings storm</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-sunscreen-tga-recall-explainer/rz9nt85bm</link><description>Eighteen sunscreens have either been recalled or had their sale paused in Australia. Here&amp;apos;s what you need to know as the weather gets warmer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39b79060ee7e02aaab39b3a367f61d50</guid></item><item><title>In a battle to build, these five charts show Labor&amp;apos;s housing headache</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-two-year-question-in-labors-housing-battle/ji1yydwv5</link><description>There are doubts major inroads into Australia&amp;apos;s housing supply problem can be made in a couple of years and questions over the government&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;ambitious&amp;quot; 2029 target. So, what can be done?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da71e36dd57187d50283b30ed59ba3a0</guid></item><item><title>Jane Goodall, pioneering scientist and conservationist, dies at 91</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jane-goodall-pioneering-scientist-activist-death/9q2d3od1b</link><description>The primatologist drew the public into the wild with her groundbreaking research, later shifting to climate advocacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f14e6e3cb3afec0f1aef8e03edd679b5</guid></item><item><title>Wildlife advocate and primate expert Jane Goodall dies at 91</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/wildlife-advocate-and-primate-expert-jane-goodall-dies-at-91/i6ec7swnj</link><description>The renowned conservationist, scientist, and global activist Jane Goodall has died at the age of 91. The Jane Goodall Institute announced the primatologist&amp;apos;s death of natural causes on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">543c18495ebcda15eb2c82d8aec941e4</guid></item><item><title>See the full list: The biggest Australian companies paying the least tax</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/see-the-full-list-the-biggest-australian-companies-paying-the-least-tax/kdgh1o7wg</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s largest companies paid $95.7 billion in taxes, with those paying zero dropping to an 11-year low.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fe1d3fada847653e05eca180847932d</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 2nd October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-2nd-october-2025/98pmdmae7</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2960dd08a4922185aa54540a6215bbed</guid></item><item><title>Albanese welcomes PNG&amp;apos;s decision to sign landmark defence pact</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-png-defence-pact-gets-green-light-following-cabinet-delay/nt085b3mc</link><description>The pact will elevate the Pacific partnership, ensuring an attack on one would be a &amp;quot;danger to the peace and security of both countries&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a92f04b61fa6d04c67d70b78d7e9ba4d</guid></item><item><title>Albanese welcomes PNG&amp;apos;s decision to sign landmark defence pact</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-welcomes-pngs-decision-to-sign-landmark-defence-pact/nt085b3mc</link><description>The pact will elevate the Pacific partnership, ensuring an attack on one would be a &amp;quot;danger to the peace and security of both countries&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d26cacb840ff16f519299547599c3165</guid></item><item><title>Animal shelter accused of having &amp;apos;blood on its hands&amp;apos; after euthanising 12-week-old puppy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/blood-on-their-hands-row-erupts-over-lost-dogs-homes-puppy-euthanasia-decision/x1ndqdphz</link><description>A couple who had fostered the dog, Murphy, had called Victoria&amp;apos;s Lost Dogs Home to ask how he was going, only to be told he would be put down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cae637382778e0ba4c6cc697d819a617</guid></item><item><title>Australian men face loneliness crisis: what’s driving it and how to fix it</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australian-men-face-loneliness-crisis-whats-driving-it-and-how-to-fix-it/k47gy4q99</link><description>Loneliness among men has been described as a &amp;quot;crisis&amp;quot; in Australia, and it appears to be on the rise. This social isolation can not only hurt mens mental health and overall wellbeing, it is also costing the Australian economy billions of dollars. A recent Australian study could hold the answer as to why men appear to be stuggling more with loneliness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2699cdf7843c4ff11fd65a92f917da1b</guid></item><item><title>Gaza peace plan, US shuts down &amp;amp; China combats whingers</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gaza-peace-plan-us-shuts-down-china-combats-whingers/sy8wo6r3a</link><description>A new 20-point plan for peace in Gaza gains support among the international community. Trump warns the US military of the enemy from within as Hegseth tells Generals to slim down for the war on woke. Plus, Democrats and Republicans point the finger at each other as the US government shuts down. Also, Moscow warns of a new red line in the war in Ukraine. And, China launches a campaign to stamp out online negativity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cae9b3556147066c2d14b3ea166cca48</guid></item><item><title>Nuclear energy sank the Coalition at the election — can it power their comeback?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nuclear-energy-sank-the-coalition-at-the-election-can-it-power-their-comeback/eqd6mzqsd</link><description>The coalition are revamping their proposal for nuclear energy, despite suffering an election loss with this policy. The details are yet to be confirmed, but the Opposition Energy Minister says they will adapt their plan to meet developments in the space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce95ff0c869a7707f7ba7c89bf33d0ea</guid></item><item><title>NIMBYs, YIMBYs — and BIMBYs: The new group in Australia&amp;apos;s housing stoush</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/yimbys-nimbys-and-bimbys-in-australias-housing-stoush/684pjcwmn</link><description>As state governments roll out plans to battle Australia&amp;apos;s housing crisis, community groups are mobilising to have a say in how their suburbs are — or are not — changed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac71bb540a7137e724f30e60564c8b9e</guid></item><item><title>ASX rallies despite US government shutdown</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asx-rallies-despite-us-government-shutdown/ln743tnhv</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Callam Pickering about the latest household spending data and what it means for interest rates, plus Henry Jennings from Marcus Today on the days market action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1c37f8b542f20920bc0294ef6e85ada</guid></item><item><title>Why experts are &amp;apos;rewriting&amp;apos; Australia&amp;apos;s bushfire risk this summer</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-experts-are-rewriting-australias-bushfire-risk-this-summer/cm2ns4rb1</link><description>Unusual weather patterns and climate change are raising concerns for parts of Australia, as well as popular travel destinations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74b84ba4c6053b03df899ae3bf840b38</guid></item><item><title>New trick Australians are using to &amp;apos;maximise&amp;apos; tax returns — but beware of the risks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-turning-to-ai-to-maximise-tax-returns-research-suggests/cxv17n2n4</link><description>It might be free to use and readily available, but it could also be giving incorrect advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18fb8425575513f0bd3949ff904ed080</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 3 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-3-october-2025/yloxqghu5</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">768b0278ce23523b8b3fabba58bc3ec3</guid></item><item><title>Footy, culture, and so much more: welcome to the Koori knockout</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/footy-culture-and-so-much-more-welcome-to-the-koori-knockout/ardx4qeqz</link><description>This weekend will see the largest annual gathering of Indigenous people in the country at the New South Wales Koori knockout rugby league tournament. It&amp;apos;s a sporting competition... but also, so much more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1aa459fcf3b03e862c3e2aed8b15fe8e</guid></item><item><title>Forwards or backwards? Daylight saving starts soon — here&amp;apos;s what to know</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/when-daylight-saving-time-starts-in-australia-in-2025/67t60uuqb</link><description>Here&amp;apos;s everything you need to know, including tips on how to adjust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f095370d70d3af25e324360142a0835</guid></item><item><title>When do the 2025 NRL and NRLW grand finals start? Here&amp;apos;s everything you need to know</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/when-do-the-2025-nrl-and-nrlw-grand-finals-start/fdj88sefp</link><description>It will be a busy day of footy on Sunday with both the NRL and NRLW grand finals taking place. Here&amp;apos;s what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46d15fe9fc47865d6df86970a318c2c9</guid></item><item><title>Oil prices tumble to 4 month low as ASX edges closer to record high</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/oil-prices-tumble-to-4-month-low-as-asx-edges-closer-to-record-high/ee4eoyhss</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Dianne Colledge from Morgans Financial Limited about the days sharemarket action including the opportunites for investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa53c66df7caad74aee6a6f6ac9017d0</guid></item><item><title>How the Dezi Freeman search could wind down — and how major Australian manhunts ended</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dezi-freeman-police-manhunt/h9o270lc9</link><description>While the operation to find Dezi Freeman is the biggest manhunt in Australia to date in terms of resources, it is far from the longest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3acb245cf6e9c9d2be5a7aeff339c82</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;No evidence&amp;apos; blueberries unsafe to eat, watchdogs say, after banned pesticide concerns</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/no-evidence-blueberries-unsafe-to-eat-watchdogs-say/39tc8g2za</link><description>The berry industry welcomed the finding, with a key figure saying it was &amp;quot;devastating&amp;quot; to have been &amp;quot;wrongfully targeted&amp;quot;. The researcher who raised the concerns says that wasn&amp;apos;t her intention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb95552da5a847a9c3d7b8e9a05dd541</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie quits Liberal front bench over immigration row</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/andrew-hastie-quits-liberal-front-bench-over-immigration-row/ykj28wrv4</link><description>His exit comes after he publicly pushed for net-zero emissions goals to be dropped and migration to be curbed, as well as touting himself as a future leadership aspirant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4a989416706104d091ce92b07ca3ad6</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The 99 per cent are not your enemy&amp;apos;: Genesis Owusu on power, politics and racism</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/some-things-need-to-be-said-genesis-owusu-on-speaking-truth-in-a-divided-world/vnmtwxihp</link><description>Genesis Owusu has battled racism, depression and industry pressures — but his third album is his most direct yet. He says it’s a blunt call for truth in an era of division.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d57c833150ae3b366294ff78e399fa4</guid></item><item><title>700 Australians were recruited for a yoga study. What researchers found surprised them</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/yoga-study-older-people-falls/s4gqz30zo</link><description>Many older Australians who practice yoga say it gives them strength and confidence, but a new study suggests one particular type of yoga could be associated with a higher risk of falls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">766326cb3fadeacdbd152085fa484ad8</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Could a First Nations voice help tackle stubborn public health challenges?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-could-a-first-nations-voice-help-tackle-stubborn-public-health-challenges/9o1r5o95q</link><description>Nearly two years after the failed referendum saw a First Nations voice to parliament shot down, some NGOs and state governments have been taking the initiative to follow the wishes of the majority of Indigenous communities in Australia who voted for this special representation. Australia&amp;apos;s principal non-government organisation for public health, the Public Health Association of Australia, has announced they will be instituting an Aboriginal and Torres-Strait Islander voice to help guide their work after a near unanimous vote by their members. SBS spoke to Dr Summer May Finlay, a Yorta Yorta woman, an Associate Professor at the University of Wollongong and the Vice President (Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander) of the Public Health Association about the importance of a First Nations voice in helping to Close the Gap on healthcare outcomes between Indigenous and non-Indigenous Australians</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b72abcb3c66a7c1aa036143c6a6ed3c</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Everyone loves a ghost train: but why do we love being scared?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-everyone-loves-a-ghost-train-but-why-do-we-love-being-scared/u32c8730l</link><description>Scary movies, haunted houses and trick or treating, October is the unofficial start to “spooky season” - at least, that&amp;apos;s what you would think judging by what&amp;apos;s on the shelves in our local shops. Sarah Kollat, teaching professor of psychology at Penn State University in the US, says there are lots of reasons people like to be scared. At a chemical level, our brains and bodies are reacting to the jump scares in a movie and “surviving” a haunted house. But psychologists also say getting scared in a safe environment prepares us for real danger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80dd3f386e756d22769ecab32573d2e2</guid></item><item><title>The major sticking points that could still upend the partially accepted Gaza peace deal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-major-sticking-points-that-could-still-upend-the-partially-accepted-gaza-peace-deal/r1v3u1nn3</link><description>One expert says a hostage-prisoner exchange between Israel and Hamas is &amp;quot;highly likely&amp;quot; to go ahead, but he and others remain wary about the prospects for other parts of a Gaza peace deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eafb2a9b36df924305576090a027935a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I passed out multiple times at work&amp;apos;: The health problem costing Australia billions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-health-problem-costing-australia-billions/g3usjolbe</link><description>Endometriosis affects one in seven Australian women, yet experts warn workplaces remain years behind in providing support for those living with this &amp;quot;invisible&amp;quot; condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6dcadce6efd2c049bdf54d58ac15c0d</guid></item><item><title>Why Joel spends his evenings being stabbed in the head with skewers — for fun</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-is-deathmatch-wrestling-and-why-is-it-controversial/nj1sz5e5z</link><description>Blood, thumbtacks, fire, cactus plants and even whipper snippers. Welcome to the world of Australian deathmatch wrestling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f61856630983c73041efd339266439b</guid></item><item><title>Yazidi refugees in Toowoomba find community through hockey</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/yazidi-refugees-in-toowoomba-find-community-through-hockey/j814wa3h1</link><description>The Queensland city of Toowoomba has become home to thousands of Yazidi refugees. A local hockey program is aiming to develop confidence and language skills for this community, with the help of retired locals on the field.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5f81e55f17530c791f21bcf7b4d475a</guid></item><item><title>Smooth Snake slithering its way back to life in the UK</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/smooth-snake-slithering-its-way-back-to-life-in-the-uk/epgsvimyj</link><description>Snakes may be ten a penny here in Australia but in the UK it&amp;apos;s a different story. Britain&amp;apos;s rarest reptile, known as the Smooth Snake, is thriving again after conservation efforts were introduced to save it in 2009. But monitoring exactly how many Smooth Snakes there are can be a challenge due to the reptile&amp;apos;s reclusive nature.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0577ac3c3db7bfe3fe5b9ffc9a5f20b</guid></item><item><title>Location-tracking apps: A harmful invasion of privacy or a great tool to keep loved ones safe?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/location-tracking-apps-a-great-tool-to-keep-loved-ones-safe-or-a-harmful-invasion-of-privacy/isma6nxvo</link><description>With consent, location-tracking can be immensely useful in some situations, experts say, but they warn that the technology is certainly not without potential harms and can lead to controlling and coercive behaviours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a5fa3dd319ea39f2d1f365c795522bf</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Determination and ingenuity&amp;apos;: Australia&amp;apos;s oldest man just turned 112</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australias-oldest-man-celebrates-life/p7v9yud7i</link><description>Ken Weeks was still walking into town for shopping after he turned 100 more than a decade ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bacbbd1941638773676ab40810dfdc13</guid></item><item><title>We now know when your HECS debt will be slashed, and by how much</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/millions-of-australians-to-see-their-student-debts-slashed-heres-what-you-need-to-know/jk27nb331</link><description>About three million Australians with a student debt will soon see their balance owed reduced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca91d2f5055b26f7ea83ab864b48208d</guid></item><item><title>Israelis like Michal and Yarden act as &amp;apos;human shields&amp;apos; in the West Bank. They&amp;apos;ve been called traitors</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/israelis-like-michal-and-yarden-act-as-human-shields-in-the-west-bank-theyve-been-called-traitors/il4m5r6gi</link><description>As the second anniversary of October 7 and Israel’s war in Gaza approaches, settler violence in the West Bank is steadily escalating. A small number of Israelis like Yarden want to end the &amp;apos;status quo&amp;apos; — and they&amp;apos;re willing to act as human shields to achieve it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">974283754e15dfcfaddb901970f9ce39</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We do not see any change&amp;apos;: Israel pounds Gaza despite Trump&amp;apos;s call for end to bombing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-says-gaza-deal-talks-to-go-on-couple-days-as-rubio-asks-israel-to-stop-bombing/kcyspcgfz</link><description>There was no let-up in Israeli attacks on Gaza over the weekend as planes and tanks pounded areas across the enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49494d7d2fb7fc0e2c5cb09883993f98</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy criticises world &amp;apos;silence&amp;apos; after yet another large-scale Russian attack</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/zelenskyy-criticises-world-silence-after-large-scale-russian-attacks-on-ukraine/0rwbgt2u2</link><description>Five people have died after the Russian military attacked Ukraine overnight with 53 missiles and several waves of drones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">606b8824cc69c840c6e7dcfe55b0aa92</guid></item><item><title>It&amp;apos;s on Australia&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;do not travel&amp;apos; list. But influencers are promoting it anyway</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/its-on-australias-do-not-travel-list-influencers-are-promoting-it-anyway/l6ladosss</link><description>A surge of travel vloggers is putting Afghanistan back on the tourism map, even as the Taliban tightens restrictions on women and security risks remain high.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9739ed1e9708b066c8679a8ce0741373</guid></item><item><title>The Australians who think it&amp;apos;s fine to steal, and those who disagree</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-retail-theft-survey/b1yrp6vki</link><description>A new survey found a generational divide when it comes to rationalising retail theft behaviours, including scanning items incorrectly at self-checkout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f73afe8aefb91168f2b15b3bcb87181</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 6 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-6-october-2025/22ssjf5lu</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">645ce9f66c6f1ad98a25360b9cd23743</guid></item><item><title>&amp;quot;Excitement, then everything changed&amp;quot;: survivors remember October 7 attack as calls grow for end to Gaza war</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/excitement-then-everything-changed-survivors-remember-october-7-attack-as-calls-grow-for-end-to-gaza-war/gcgwne2p3</link><description>Thousands of Australians are joining vigils across the nation to mark the second anniversary of the deadly Hamas attack on Israel. Around 1200 people were killed and 250 taken hostage during the designated terror group&amp;apos;s attack on October 7, 2023, which triggered a brutal military response from Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90e3b1dc68c0fb2458a0b763135949f9</guid></item><item><title>Australian claims dislocated arm from soldiers in prison called Israel&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;worst&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-prison-thunberg-australians-flotilla-ketziot-prison/4k67kxy2j</link><description>Ketziot prison was once called the &amp;quot;largest and the worst&amp;quot; of Israel&amp;apos;s prisons by Human Rights Watch. There are welfare concerns for Australians detained there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3479ab3351f4cc7f88d1ea8e3eb0dcfd</guid></item><item><title>Gold and copper prices surge and why you shouldn’t ignore your annual super statement</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gold-and-copper-prices-surge-and-why-you-shouldnt-ignore-your-annual-super-statement/ycyf7efc7</link><description>The ASX-200 has started the week in the red, as a tech sell-off offset strong gains by gold and copper miners. Plus, Japanese stocks have hit a record high just a day after the country’s ruling Liberal Democratic Party named Sanae Takaichi as its leader. For more, Rena Sarumpaet spoke with George Boubouras from K2 Asset Management. As annual superannuation statements start to arrive in the mail, Australians are being urged to not ignore them with research from Canstar showing about a fifth of respondents only check their super once every few years - or never. For more on how a financial health check could benefit your nest egg, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Canstar Data Insights Director Sally Tindall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf769f3e207d0282dbc7a810668680f0</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Fighting a war on two fronts&amp;apos;: Behind the rise of a new threat in Gaza</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hamas-influence-is-waning-in-gaza-palestinians-fear-armed-gangs-more/nz8wiwgfy</link><description>Newly released data shows a major spike in intra-Palestinian violent incidents this year, as well as a significant rise in stolen aid packages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e010bbb46bdb0e33ece03d84dbb1b80a</guid></item><item><title>The unseen impact of missing or damaged teeth — and the key to addressing it</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/unseen-impact-of-dental-issues/qxmy885wl</link><description>Why is it so shameful to have missing teeth or gum disease? And what can we do about it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5c6536419384386081ada9d87c84a61</guid></item><item><title>Australians from Gaza aid flotilla deported by Israel to Jordan following detention</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/thunberg-greeted-by-cheering-crowd-in-athens-after-israel-expels-flotilla-activists/mf2qe8dj9</link><description>Some of the Australian activists recently detained by Israel have alleged violence and mistreatment at the hands of soldiers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79606fccfeaecb0d2ba332a2ba68edc8</guid></item><item><title>Gaza peace talks to continue as October 7 anniversary marked by commemoration, protests</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gaza-peace-talks-begin-as-october-7-anniversary-marked-by-commemoration-protests/08rf6jaqb</link><description>As Gaza marks two years under devastating Israeli bombardment, commemorations of the October 7 attacks and demonstrations in support of Palestinians are planned around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0633872b0d7cba4a7204b1bbac0fc2b0</guid></item><item><title>University students panicked after fraudulent emails &amp;apos;revoked&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;disqualified&amp;apos; degrees</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/western-sydney-university-hacks-scams-fraudulent-emails/9qa23rd0r</link><description>Western Sydney University said the emails are &amp;quot;not legitimate&amp;quot; and have been reported to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52ce0f86abd8ab03886197cfd7efdcee</guid></item><item><title>Advocates alarmed as major change for autistic kids looms</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/advocates-alarmed-as-major-change-for-autistic-kids-looms/n2rj2ev77</link><description>There are fears that many children with autism or learning difficulties will fall between the cracks of a new support system that aims to limit access to the National Disability Insurance Scheme. The Thriving Kids initiative will be rolled out from the middle of next year, with a focus on providing support to children with so-called mild to moderate autism within community and mainstream settings. But disability advocates have told a parliamentary inquiry it is these children that are most often overlooked or misunderstood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbcbfc97c8481df7a17e0c2a379464dc</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 7 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-7-october-2025/pj6h2owkh</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76159309e4392687a2c1f21694cde629</guid></item><item><title>Federal government admits handballing truth-telling process as only &amp;apos;half a person&amp;apos; employed</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/federal-government-admits-handballing-truth-telling-process-as-only-half-a-person-employed/6yvl7nghg</link><description>The Greens have questioned what progress is being made on truth-telling and treaty at a federal level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c089253e246d0c2480ff6db83e911471</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The purpose of my voice is to teach history&amp;apos;: Survivor tells how a party turned to trauma</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jewish-community-groups-mark-7-october-but-remain-divided-over-israels-response/8wbljra59</link><description>Nova Festival attack survivor Natalie Sanandaji shares her ordeal escaping the massacre on 7 October 2023 in southern Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f54ac3b662d720cf0b52eb64f2f47c7</guid></item><item><title>GP snapshot reveals why the job has become more complicated</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gp-snapshot-reveals-why-the-job-has-become-more-complicated/qpql0lgde</link><description>A snapshot of Australian general practice has revealed that GPs are having to see patients for longer appointments to treat more complex medical needs. The Health of the Nation industry survey of almost 2,500 GPs also shows a growing number of general practitioners are managing patient conditions typically handled by specialists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c160cb3c86a6aded30a18e7d0e9289a</guid></item><item><title>ASIC approves ASX listing market competitor; is AI in a bubble? and gold approaches US$4,000</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asic-approves-asx-listing-market-competitor-is-ai-in-a-bubble-and-gold-approaches-us-4-000/15pn8lg7y</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Todd Hoare from LGT Wealth Management Australia Management about the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action, including ASIC&amp;apos;s approval of Cboe Australia&amp;apos;s listing market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a14fecba3f407f02c5f75ddaca796de3</guid></item><item><title>Government fast-tracks legislation to strengthen 000 call system</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/government-fast-tracks-legislation-to-strengthen-000-call-system/w83hkwzos</link><description>The government has fast-tracked legislation into parliament aimed at strengthening the 000 call system after failures by Optus to ensure access to emergency calls. As parliament resumed, the nation&amp;apos;s leaders made time to commemorate the second anniversary of the October 7 attack on Israel by Hamas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eae27ff927fc8446f700e60af6c28d2</guid></item><item><title>Minister urged to &amp;apos;come clean&amp;apos; on NDIS changes, as advocates fear &amp;apos;degrading&amp;apos; treatment</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/minister-urged-to-come-clean-on-upcoming-ndis-changes/6rtqr6kj3</link><description>Disability advocates are demanding clarity on upcoming NDIS changes, warning that the new system could be &amp;quot;traumatising&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35ef37fb66b60de2f07e0b9551334b12</guid></item><item><title>Trump threatens to invoke centuries-old anti-insurrection law to militarise US cities</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-threatens-to-invoke-insurrection-act-to-deploy-military-2/6g0b7x1n5</link><description>Donald Trump has said he would use the law to sidestep court rulings restricting orders to send National Guard troops into cities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72a0ed269fc7270b4c3aee326c3e94f9</guid></item><item><title>Trump threatens to invoke centuries-old anti-insurrection law to militarise US cities</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-threatens-to-invoke-insurrection-act-to-deploy-military/6g0b7x1n5</link><description>Donald Trump has said he would use the law to sidestep court rulings restricting orders to send National Guard troops into cities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2fd3ebac03c4a2285999cce9553fa08</guid></item><item><title>Kneecap member vows to fight and win again as prosecutors appeal terrorism charge</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/kneecap-vows-to-fight-and-win-uk-terrorism-charge-appeal/8d3xtw0yc</link><description>UK prosecutors will appeal a court&amp;apos;s decision to throw out a terrorism case against a member of the Irish rap trio.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38229a85ca8146e408f60d190f6a51bd</guid></item><item><title>Home Affairs knew for months &amp;apos;ISIS brides&amp;apos; were returning; granted children citizenship</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/government-reveals-it-knew-for-months-that-women-children-were-returning-from-syria/25rhks9h4</link><description>The federal government says the group, who arrived in Australia recently, are being monitored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7be85bee82432c5f464de873b190365f</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 8 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-8-october-2025/whwmm56t5</link><description>A daily news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2117dd9198b3e40c0ee5a7ff6776e2e4</guid></item><item><title>Australian flotilla activist accuses government of &amp;apos;shameful&amp;apos; Israel extraction effort</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-gaza-aid-flotilla-detained-israel-government-response/k0z6te9ta</link><description>Australians were detained at what has been called an &amp;quot;outrageous&amp;quot; prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1257d9945cbeacdd1dfcb0ead12bf2fb</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s cancer survival rates are improving — but there are also some &amp;apos;concerning&amp;apos; trends</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cancer-survival-rates-increasing-concerning-trends/2pv0jmxyg</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s latest snapshot of cancer incidence and deaths has been released.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">107c68cb639ee7a8a33619366761bd82</guid></item><item><title>Gold breaks US$4,000 &amp;amp; is NZ becoming a better value tourist destination?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gold-breaks-us-4-000-is-nz-becoming-a-better-value-tourist-destination/4wphc7m2n</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Armina Rosenberg from Minotaur Capital about the day&amp;apos;s market action, including gold&amp;apos;s new milestone and how her firm is using AI to invest; plus Nick Tuffley from ASB Bank goes through why the RBNZ cut interest rates more than expected and what it means for Australian travellers going to New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">075d064fad7859a126dc1ae41b3a59f0</guid></item><item><title>Communications minister accused of misleading parliament over Optus notification</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/communications-minister-accused-of-misleading-parliament-over-optus-notification/esnv5jsxx</link><description>The federal opposition has accused Communications Minister Anika Wells of misleading parliament over when her office was notified of the Optus Triple-Zero outage that has been linked to four deaths. It comes as emails that Optus sent to notify the government and the regulator of the outages, which ultimately affected more than 600 people last month, are scrutinised in Senate estimates. Meanwhile, legislation creating a triple-zero custodian has passed the lower house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7070d12aef1f94469b2c63613df90df</guid></item><item><title>There&amp;apos;s a difference between hot and cold sweat — and one tends to smell more distinctive</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hot-cold-sweat-whats-the-difference/zqv96pzqv</link><description>Cold sweat is known as psychological sweat, while hot sweat is often the body&amp;apos;s response to physical exertion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b581aa783d42878f5bfb52f06e2a6573</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Deeply harmful&amp;apos;: Autism advocates fear major change for some Australian children</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/kids-autism-program-challenged-during-inquiry/1ql3ja1au</link><description>The government is pushing ahead with a new program — and there are concerns it could leave some children falling between the cracks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f6ec8ef5e7935117bfb77b92878c052</guid></item><item><title>Prison guards thought TJ was &amp;apos;playing possum&amp;apos;. Hours later, he was dead</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/inquest-into-tian-jarrah-denniss-death-in-prison-custody/d1zj2u0aw</link><description>TJ&amp;apos;s death in custody prompted an apology by Corrective Services NSW. But did he ever stand a chance of leaving?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81fa8ce117eb05e7e0ae7de6f3e50dce</guid></item><item><title>Australian professor Richard Robson among Nobel Prize chemistry winners</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-professor-richard-robson-among-nobel-prize-chemistry-winners/glv6lyvry</link><description>The discovery for the Nobel chemistry prize has been likened to a Harry Potter enchanted handbag.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9daac0684ce9cf7602935db3d980fc48</guid></item><item><title>Senior US officials arrive in Egypt for Gaza peace talks as Israeli assault dials down</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-officials-gaza-peace-talks-in-egypt/ioj1mhemm</link><description>Donald Trump said a deal was &amp;quot;very close&amp;quot; and that he may travel to the Middle East this weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acf08b1fc5e9d0202db0f22b5875a723</guid></item><item><title>Could Donald Trump win the 2025 Nobel Peace Prize?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/can-donald-trump-win-2025-nobel-peace-prize/jd8qsc5o2</link><description>Leaders seeking to curry favour with Trump have been quick to talk up the US president&amp;apos;s chances, but experts aren&amp;apos;t so sure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0a4240ebbb17289ba0358cae532feac</guid></item><item><title>What we&amp;apos;ve learnt about the &amp;apos;ISIS brides&amp;apos;, as federal police anticipate more returns</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-weve-learnt-about-the-isis-brides-as-federal-police-anticipate-more-returns/azsbkp5dj</link><description>The Australian Federal Police said the group, which has returned from Syria, was being monitored as part of an ongoing operation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">095473ab291891ba39d99c9b49418bbc</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: What does the Middle East peace deal mean?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-what-does-the-middle-east-peace-deal-mean/kcb42zhl7</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Israel and Hamas have agreed on the first phase of a peace framework that will allow for the release of all hostages. In a post on social media, he said the release of hostages is imminent, adding that &amp;quot;All Parties will be treated fairly!&amp;quot;. The exchange of the remaining hostages held by Hamas for Palestinian prisoners could happen within 72 hours of the deal&amp;apos;s implementation. Dr Eyal Mayroz is a lecturer in Peace and Conflict Studies at the University of Sydney, and he gave SBS&amp;apos;s Cameron Carr his reaction to the agreement</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5e7f8c4f3c51e8fecc5c714da859ebf</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 9 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-9-october-2025/smjkdc3tt</link><description>A daily news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f36918c138d94a0d8745616a3fb46ba</guid></item><item><title>The Gaza peace deal&amp;apos;s first phase has been agreed to. But there are still many questions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-is-left-to-work-out-in-the-gaza-peace-plan/z86yn49de</link><description>Despite the hopes raised for ending the war, crucial details are yet to be spelled out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e0393a92f821e6c0dbee3b0dc02d076</guid></item><item><title>New workplace laws aim to remove extra pain burden on parents arising from stillbirth</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-workplace-laws-aim-to-remove-extra-pain-burden-on-parents-arising-from-stillbirth/yxxby73uk</link><description>Laws have been introduced into federal parliament to stop employers from scrapping leave entitlements when families face the tragedy of a stillbirth or death of their baby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e463603d4aa7c01baf13de3111cf7ff7</guid></item><item><title>The common mortgage feature that could be leaving you &amp;apos;worse off&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-common-mortgage-feature-that-could-be-leaving-you-worse-off/353pu5cpx</link><description>Mortgage offset accounts have helped many Australians wipe interest off their home loan. But they don&amp;apos;t always offer a benefit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee442e3b846b3c3009e9a69f6380e9a2</guid></item><item><title>Gaza peace deal market impacts &amp;amp; Gemini crypto exchange enters Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gaza-peace-deal-market-impacts-gemini-crypto-exchange-enters-australia/cn4wgwr7z</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Robert Talevski to see how the Gaza peace deal has impacted markets; and Ricardo takes a look at Australia&amp;apos;s crypto regulatory space with Gemini&amp;apos;s Saad Ahmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32dadee138ba4452c8f55df884a185c7</guid></item><item><title>Israel and Hamas have agreed on the first phase of a Gaza peace deal. Now what?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israel-and-hamas-have-agreed-on-the-first-phase-of-a-gaza-peace-deal-now-what/0q53t5h5m</link><description>Israel and Hamas have agreed to the first phase of United States President Donald Trump&amp;apos;s plan for Gaza. The ceasefire and hostage deal could be a first step toward ending a bloody two-year-old war that has roiled across the Middle East.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">365e8bc7ed55d46044888698306e272f</guid></item><item><title>A Gaza peace deal signed; au revoir to yet another French PM; &amp;amp; Australia&amp;apos;s new security alliance</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-gaza-peace-deal-signed-au-revoir-to-yet-another-french-pm-australias-new-security-alliance/qpvku4bvv</link><description>Hamas and Israel sign up for Phase One of Trump&amp;apos;s new 20-point plan for peace in Gaza. France&amp;apos;s revolving door on its prime ministerial office takes another spin. Plus Australia and PNG sign on to an expanded alliance for regional cooperation. And how desperate for $5,000 are you? Take a job at a haunted hotel desperate?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8242392b02a0cd65357a0346f8e7e0dc</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Palestinians and Israelis celebrate after news of ceasefire deal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/in-pictures-palestinians-and-israelis-celebrate-after-news-of-ceasefire-deal/2tn21mxlb</link><description>Israel and Hamas are expected to sign the agreement at the Egyptian beach resort of Sharm el-Sheikh on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57ba00d9399367bc75535899924611c2</guid></item><item><title>Fear drove Fouad to Australia. Even after a major milestone, his hopes are dim</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/syrians-in-australia-react-to-recent-elections/abrnu5ip9</link><description>Fouad Berzghal&amp;apos;s home country had its first election since the fall of its dictator. But there are questions over how much will change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27787313fa317cc17ce5162a28bb9d06</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;It felt like home&amp;apos;: Why generations of migrant Australians love the NPL</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-championship-2025-npl-clubs-vying-for-a-league/e8w984a52</link><description>Once the lifeblood of migrant communities, suburban football clubs are back on the national stage for the Australian Championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d609837651a1452d9f46ac7ed2f3256</guid></item><item><title>What’s the Senate actually estimating? Ft. David Pocock</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/whats-the-senate-actually-estimating-ft-david-pocock/mh2g41en3</link><description>The first senate estimates of the 48th Parliament have arrived – where the Albanese Labor Government and representatives from the Australian Public Service and government agencies are quizzed for up to 14 hours a day about pretty much anything. It’s tedious, it’s long, but it’s all about accountability, and Independent Senator for the ACT David Pocock takes us behind the scenes. Plus Bob Katter has a suggestion for the footy off-season, and Andrew Hastie has left the Coalition front bench.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf65a9ae21431245bb073149e8e14804</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Safe beds save lives&amp;apos;: Calls for urgent action to address rising number of homeless women</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/calls-for-urgent-action-to-address-rising-rates-of-homeless-women/guxjs58zb</link><description>Australians are being urged to recognise the link between domestic violence and homelessness, as more women face sleeping rough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4c2cda473f27360e0af7ffd236102d0</guid></item><item><title>Phase one of Gaza peace deal set to begin after approval by Israeli cabinet</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gaza-peace-deal-set-to-begin-after-approval-by-israeli-cabinet/cg3mvrghn</link><description>Despite celebrations in Israel and Gaza and a flood of messages from world leaders hailing the deal, numerous issues remain unsettled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">449af5463a6d312a1f266c15e3f5d7bd</guid></item><item><title>Are Syria’s first post-Assad elections strengthening or weakening democracy?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/are-syrias-first-post-assad-elections-strengthening-or-weakening-democracy/ba0rd6man</link><description>Syria&amp;apos;s first parliamentary elections since the fall of Bashar al-Assad have sparked criticism for how they were run. The election was seen as a key step in the shift away from the al-Assad regime, but one that has sparked concerns about inclusivity and fairness under the country&amp;apos;s new leaders. Syrians here in Australia say their relatives at home do not feel represented by the new Government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1324997c4daa234662dcdf368f87293c</guid></item><item><title>Pocock won&amp;apos;t rejoin parliamentary sports club despite ban reversal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/parliamentary-sports-club-drops-senator-over-cheap-shot-gambling-lobby-complaints/ni07m8rcy</link><description>The former Wallabies captain says he won’t take part in Parliament’s friendly sporting matches unless the club rethinks its corporate ties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d780167cc8bd777c6b16f620aa7162d</guid></item><item><title>Peace in the Middle East greeted with joy across the divide</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/peace-in-the-middle-east-greeted-with-joy-across-the-divide/f6r5yfx3w</link><description>After two years of devastating conflict, there are scenes of cautious celebration across the Middle East. A historic ceasefire deal between Israel and Hamas, brokered by US President Donald Trump, has been reached, in effect, marking what some are calling a new chapter of peace.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4091d5c843b7e47882f975b4d3b36f69</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 10 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-10-october-2025/ox4745edi</link><description>A daily news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">461f5ff0895d21df54b3565c645bef89</guid></item><item><title>Australian flotilla activist faces indefinite Israeli detention &amp;apos;threat&amp;apos;, as others return home</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/deported-australian-gaza-flotilla-activists-vow-to-return/r5ng7dpgj</link><description>The returned activists have concerns for Madeline Habib, who is said to be in &amp;quot;good health&amp;quot; while detained in Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">267ed924408cd9b6bd7f759e3a861ac5</guid></item><item><title>Tsunami threat passes after powerful earthquake strikes Philippines</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tsunami-warning-issued-after-magnitude-7-4-earthquake-strikes-philippines/rojk438gt</link><description>A tsunami alert for the Philippines, Palau and Indonesia has been lifted following a magnitude 7.4 earthquake south of the Philippines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eae9b3947c5305856ff6eafe0f99b2be</guid></item><item><title>How a &amp;apos;deeply-embedded&amp;apos; part of Australian culture could change forever</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-young-people-drinking-less/5evzgqh3h</link><description>Young Australians are leading this emerging generational shift, according to a new study.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37ff3efc37c81ed4a2b915dfbbae5f8c</guid></item><item><title>The looming Europe travel change that will affect Australians</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-looming-europe-travel-change-that-will-affect-australians/vcw4eeb3k</link><description>New personal data collection rules are about to come into effect in Europe&amp;apos;s Schengen area. Here&amp;apos;s what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8915e4cc6bb110563107cac201a2909</guid></item><item><title>Silver at highest since 1980 &amp;amp; how markets are reacting to Gaza peace deal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/silver-at-highest-since-1980-how-markets-are-reacting-to-gaza-peace-deal/629kn57mq</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Zoran Kresovic from Blueberry Markets about the day&amp;apos;s market action, including how investors are feeling following the potential Gaza peace deal, the future for gold and the outlook for silver, which hit a near 45 year high.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d1d05bfb6622d4a8698efb5d64f8f82</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan opposition figure María Corina Machado awarded Nobel Peace Prize</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/awarded-nobel-peace-prize-as-trump-misses-out/1mib232vu</link><description>Machado had been forced into hiding but remained in Venezuela, a choice that &amp;quot;inspired millions&amp;quot;, the Nobel Committee chair said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da4d3d7f412d47df82feb324ffda31e5</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan opposition figure María Corina Machado awarded Nobel Peace Prize</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/venezuelan-opposition-figure-maria-corina-machado-awarded-nobel-peace-prize/1mib232vu</link><description>Machado had been forced into hiding but remained in Venezuela, a choice that &amp;quot;inspired millions&amp;quot;, the Nobel Committee chair said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5e492e919ad601ea5669d16343048c1</guid></item><item><title>Displaced Gazans stream back to their destroyed homes after ceasefire comes into effect</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gaza-ceasefire-in-effect-gazans-return/47a4beep2</link><description>A massive column of displaced Gazans filed north through the dust towards Gaza City after the ceasefire came into effect at midday Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fa4b0c30e87f775a6a0bd207e3bf44c</guid></item><item><title>Saving money and packing &amp;apos;go bags&amp;apos;: How Australians in the US are preparing for the worst</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-living-in-america-anxiety/p88o60wos</link><description>With changes to visas and growing scrutiny of foreign nationals, Australians in the US say they feel uncertain about their futures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d92df2c543967f34a3a2a80e74842b9</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s potato capital is facing a threat never-before-seen in the country</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/potato-mop-top-virus-management/hsbsfzew1</link><description>With eradication off the table, Australia is looking to New Zealand for lessons on how to manage potato mop top virus as planting begins in Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c375078453cf75cec49b0f1ccf3cd88e</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan opposition leader awarded Nobel Peace Prize</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/venezuelan-opposition-leader-awarded-nobel-peace-prize/6wewdazz7</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8c0c33c9e965f0a57a9f2372ab9f4a4</guid></item><item><title>US aid cuts start to bite for Myanmar&amp;apos;s refugees</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-aid-cuts-start-to-bite-for-myanmars-refugees/jozn5d7v2</link><description>Earlier this year, US President Donald Trump ordered steep cuts to the US foreign aid budget, a move that sparked concerns it would cause widespread harm and even deaths for the millions that relied on the programs delivered or funded by the USAid office. Now, refugees and advocates say the cuts are starting to bite, with 85 per cent of residents in refugee camps along the Myanmar-Thai border living without USAid food rations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2a532cc132b4c5770d1b855534a7097</guid></item><item><title>Trump hikes tariffs on China by extra 100 per cent, threatens to cancel talks with Xi Jinping</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-threatens-to-cancel-talks-imposes-100-per-cent-tariffs-on-china/sxmr7930k</link><description>There was no immediate reaction from Beijing after Trump said China should not &amp;quot;be allowed to hold the world &amp;apos;captive&amp;apos;&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d401645600cd1cbcbc6079c8b41747c</guid></item><item><title>Trump hikes tariffs on China by extra 100 per cent, threatens to cancel talks with Xi Jinping</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-threatens-to-cancel-talks-impose-massive-tariffs-on-china/sxmr7930k</link><description>There was no immediate reaction from Beijing after Trump said China should not &amp;quot;be allowed to hold the world &amp;apos;captive&amp;apos;&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4aafafecdaf34fc1ca75d5263663b29e</guid></item><item><title>French president reappoints prime minister just days after he quit the job</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/french-president-reappoints-prime-minister-just-days-after-he-quit-the-job/rpa8d83zc</link><description>Newly reappointed French Prime Minister Sebastien Lecornu&amp;apos;s most pressing task will be to deliver a budget to parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">858c65f7f3f1fb0a683cc6367166a185</guid></item><item><title>French president reappoints prime minister just days after he quit the job</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/french-president-reappoints-prime-minister-just-days-after-he-quit-the-job-2/rpa8d83zc</link><description>Newly reappointed French Prime Minister Sebastien Lecornu&amp;apos;s most pressing task will be to deliver a budget to parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb612290ce62465ba2a75d1fdd89834a</guid></item><item><title>Hopes Gaza ceasefire will lead to drop in &amp;apos;dehumanisation and othering&amp;apos; in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hope-gaza-ceasefire-will-drop-dehumanisation-and-othering/ergaf1xko</link><description>The race discrimination commissioner hopes the Gaza ceasefire will lessen division at home but says &amp;quot;problems will remain&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79ef9413da5d1e22c283740b8f1a8ca0</guid></item><item><title>Three dead as light plane crashes just after take-off near Wollongong</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/three-dead-as-light-plane-crashes-just-after-take-off-near-wollongong/i2f2q6bfa</link><description>Three people have been killed in a light plane crash shortly after take-off, in what first responders have described as a &amp;quot;gruesome&amp;quot; scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">120b6304d5fde73aee6b4298f56982c6</guid></item><item><title>Russia sticks up for Venezuela against the US at the UN Security Council in drug boat row</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/russia-sticks-up-for-venezuela-against-the-us-at-the-un-security-council-in-drug-boat-row/0fox7uud4</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0000415bd3f2d3690947ed53131bb06a</guid></item><item><title>Clean-up begins in Philippines after at least eight killed in twin earthquakes</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/clean-up-begins-in-philippines-after-at-least-eight-killed-in-twin-earthquakes/hlog6tmyu</link><description>Some residents in Mindanao slept outdoors in fear of aftershocks after 7.4 and 6.7-magnitude earthquakes struck off the coast on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26a55f5ff6d8ae561174db3023b2e9f5</guid></item><item><title>North Korea shows off its &amp;apos;most powerful&amp;apos; missile at parade with Russian, Chinese top brass</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/north-korea-parades-its-most-powerful-missile-at-a-military-parade-attended-by-top-russian-and-china/22aulkt16</link><description>Kim Jong Un welcomed top Russian and Chinese officials to the event marking 80 years of North Korean rule under the Workers&amp;apos; Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8c3dcc4004306661593f57b1a5ce32c</guid></item><item><title>Casper takes a drug that helps him grow. But the treatment is controversial</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/casper-takes-a-drug-that-helps-him-grow-but-the-treatment-is-controversial/72242cs13</link><description>A controversial drug Australia had a key role in developing continues to bring hope - and frustration – for the short-statured community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f6752e3ad0558ffcc086d892ca1397b</guid></item><item><title>Not just magpies: The other birds swooping you this season — and why they do it</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/swooping-birds-magpies-spring/rjw9tyy7h</link><description>Magpies may have perfected the art of swooping, but they&amp;apos;re not the only Australian bird diving on unsuspecting humans this spring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac2a97d7785b3c241eafd24952f2dad4</guid></item><item><title>California sends ultraprocessed school meals to the sin bin</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/california-sends-ultraprocessed-school-meals-to-the-sin-bin/oqmx7iqdc</link><description>California is to phase out certain ultraprocessed foods from school meals over the next decade under a first-in-the-nation law signed by Governor Gavin Newsom. Schools will have to start removing those foods from their menus by July 2029, and districts will be barred from selling them for breakfast or lunch by July 2035.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e29626fd5f4127e4148022381379bafd</guid></item><item><title>Lostprophets singer Ian Watkins dies in prison attack</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lostprophets-singer-ian-watkins-dies-in-prison-stabbing-attack/zilz3kk5c</link><description>Lostprophets singer Ian Watkins was sentenced to 29 years in prison for child abuse in 2013.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bf9903b808391ca4c4d69a083b7cf25</guid></item><item><title>Diane Keaton, star of Annie Hall and The Godfather, dies at 79</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/oscar-winning-actress-diane-keaton-dies-at-79/c5xrom26x</link><description>Diane Keaton, the Oscar-winning star of Annie Hall, The Godfather films and Father of the Bride, has died at the age of 79.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f54b501fd3a6c497c0924eb42a6bd7d5</guid></item><item><title>Midday News Bulletin 12 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/midday-news-bulletin-12-october-2025/rn35t8w4z</link><description>Final preparations made for the exchange of hostages in Gaza for Palestinians held in Israeli prisons; rare earth minerals on the agenda when Anthony Albanese meets with Donald Trump; and in cricket, Australia to face India in a sold-out O-D-I World Cup blockbuster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba01124f30d3b3e8f547dfe6bee2a43f</guid></item><item><title>Families await hostage release as Palestinians return to &amp;apos;ghost town&amp;apos; during Gaza ceasefire</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/families-await-hostage-release-as-palestinians-return-to-ghost-town-during-gaza-ceasefire/q6o2ag6ps</link><description>The ceasefire between Israel and Hamas is in its second day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98d504f79bc84c9f7d023482bc16b8a9</guid></item><item><title>Made famous by Steve Irwin, this croc&amp;apos;s now been &amp;apos;wrongfully accused&amp;apos;, advocates say</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-theres-concern-over-iconic-crocodile-old-faithful-detention/b36fd948z</link><description>Old Faithful is being held in a government facility for displaying problematic behaviour towards humans, but environmental activists say it&amp;apos;s a case of mistaken identity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bed6c1b16fd51aef971771dd633ee04</guid></item><item><title>Evening News Bulletin 12 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/evening-news-bulletin-12-october-2025/g1demqpqz</link><description>Pro-Palestinian protests take place across the country, Human trafficking rates skyrocket in Australia, Portugal beats Ireland in stoppage time in their World Cup qualifier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbd44b6ef4136c594db2c6cc82bab8ed</guid></item><item><title>Who are the hostages Israel believes are still alive and when will they be released?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/who-are-the-hostages-israel-believes-are-still-alive-and-when-will-they-be-released/ywua8sqxi</link><description>A condition of the peace deal between Israel and Hamas is the return of 48 hostages held in Gaza, 20 of whom are believed to be alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">585053a1c521b656c9dfa58fbfaa7d21</guid></item><item><title>Why pro-Palestinian protesters say they will continue to march despite Gaza ceasefire</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-protesters-in-support-of-palestinians-say-theyll-continue-to-march-amid-a-gaza-ceasefire/irzowzg40</link><description>Dozens of rallies took place across the country on Sunday, with some protesters expressing concern the ceasefire would not hold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d12ea31494d7af73188787790b379c7</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Tip of the iceberg&amp;apos;: Human trafficking reports in Australia reach all-time high</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tip-of-the-iceberg-human-trafficking-reports-reach-all-time-high/6fgetvo7v</link><description>Police say the increase was likely the result of the community becoming better at recognising indicators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d917fab9081154253a02470d11373466</guid></item><item><title>Afghanistan says 58 Pakistani troops killed as border tensions erupt after airstrikes</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/afghanistan-says-58-pakistani-troops-killed-as-border-tensions-erupt-after-airstrikes/ez374mu6q</link><description>Pakistan closed several border crossings with Afghanistan after fierce overnight fighting left dozens dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3be84e506dab4d251f8787506dab489</guid></item><item><title>I asked a mortgage broker what median first home buyers can get with a 5% deposit (not much)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/i-asked-a-mortgage-broker-what-median-first-home-buyers-can-get-with-a-5-deposit-not-much/986cxo8k6</link><description>First home buyers can get into the housing market with a 5 per cent deposit - but are there hidden pitfalls they may not be aware of? We asked an expert to crunch the numbers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4ae1e8af7eaf6e3e9f25e9709f3e610</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I felt alone&amp;apos;: Inside the &amp;apos;invisible&amp;apos; loss one in three Australian women endure</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/i-felt-alone-inside-the-invisible-loss-one-in-three-australian-women-endure/d97d2me8d</link><description>Organisations that help women through miscarriages are looking forward to seeing a national pregnancy loss register to address what they say is an invisibility around the true scale of the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cc6a40abb4cdb96b172f7ec1cb137a5</guid></item><item><title>Gaza: Aid begins to roll in | Morning News Bulletin 13 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gaza-aid-begins-to-roll-in-morning-news-bulletin-13-october-2025/83js4v53r</link><description>Aid trucks enter Gaza as hostages expected to be freed under ceasefire deal; Taliban says 58 Pakistani soldiers killed in border clashes amid rising tensions; Socceroos eye 11-game unbeaten streak ahead of clash with United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3381331d8fee2219d39129220b32eaf5</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Gaza &amp;apos;war is over&amp;apos; as Israel awaits release of hostages amid ceasefire</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ceasefire-holds-in-gaza-ahead-of-hostage-release-and-trumps-visit-to-israel/7ts6fyvou</link><description>Israeli officials said they expect the hostage release to start around 2-3pm AEDT.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8c86e44218186db43d220557d42373f</guid></item><item><title>The miscarriage data gap and &amp;apos;invisible loss&amp;apos; leaving Australian women behind</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-miscarriage-data-gap-and-invisible-loss-leaving-australian-women-behind/y56quko28</link><description>A new report is calling for a national database on miscarriage to address ongoing invisibility around miscarriage and early pregnancy loss in Australia, particularly for First Nations women and in rural and regional communities. This comes as the government announced a $9.5 million funding package in May last year to improve awareness and support for early pregnancy loss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">012a9e93267514f189f40d33c4787b7d</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar president says coup attempt &amp;apos;underway&amp;apos; as protesters install new army chief</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/madagascar-president-says-coup-attempt-under-way-as-anti-government-protesters-install-new-army-chief/eq8vb1jxq</link><description>Anti-government demonstrations erupted in Madagascar on 25 September.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3beb9f07d7823eee92b18fd94768e67e</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump softens tone on China after tariff tensions flare</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/donald-trump-softens-tone-as-china-us-trade-tensions-flare/3mxy3fa5w</link><description>Trump has taken a less confrontational approach in his latest social media post on trade tensions with China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3b5920f3cfcf1b4d5b76ade1743c953</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;An all-time low&amp;apos;: Why are Afghanistan and Pakistan fighting along their border?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-are-afghanistan-and-pakistan-fighting-along-their-border/27ticq22j</link><description>Pakistan has accused Afghanistan of sheltering militants behind a surge in attacks on its soil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">626f88abf1ffbb3cc1e9f00578fef890</guid></item><item><title>Dozens killed as Pakistan–Afghanistan border clashes escalate</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/dozens-killed-as-pakistan-afghanistan-border-clashes-escalate/69n503u58</link><description>Dozens of fighters have been killed in overnight border clashes between Pakistan and Afghanistan in the most serious fighting between the neighbours since the Taliban came to power in Kabul. Tensions have risen after Pakistan demanded the Taliban take action against militants who have stepped up attacks in Pakistan, saying they operate from bases in Afghanistan. The Taliban denies that Pakistani militants are present on its soil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df5f32da0e0de3ed22cf86d0937051ce</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians return to Gaza as ceasefire holds, and Israel prepares for returning hostages</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/palestinians-return-to-gaza-as-ceasefire-holds-and-israel-prepares-for-returning-hostages/umghw6ry5</link><description>With the ceasefire in Gaza holding for a third day, tens of thousands of Palestinians are returning to rubble as Israel prepares for the release of hostages. United States President Donald Trump and Egyptian President Abdel Fattah al-Sisi are to co-host a Gaza peace summit in Egypt, where more than 20 world leaders are expected to back plans to achieve a lasting peace.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff2f94db9f99c40fd08a41c2163a6d99</guid></item><item><title>Trump en route to Middle East for historic deal | Midday News Bulletin 13 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trump-en-route-to-middle-east-for-historic-deal-midday-news-bulletin-13-october-2025/0b4337qd5</link><description>In this bulletin, US President departs for Middle East as hostage release imminent. Lidia Thorpe faces backlash over inflammatory comment at pro-Palestine rally. And in cricket, Pat Cummins doubtful for first Ashes Test, targets Gabba return after injury setback.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fb0b87096e49d8befcd787682001843</guid></item><item><title>Has your Qantas data been leaked? Here&amp;apos;s what you can do</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-to-do-if-your-qantas-data-was-leaked/vk1922mpe</link><description>A cybersecurity expert has warned scammers will employ both immediate and &amp;quot;long game&amp;quot; strategies to use the stolen data.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54a7898d0ee7ea167b5baaae9799ce52</guid></item><item><title>The changes to your superannuation in Treasurer Jim Chalmers&amp;apos; surprise announcement</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-six-superannuation-changes-in-treasurer-jim-chalmers-surprise-announcement/bz4k2c5zs</link><description>The government has responded to ongoing criticism, announcing half a dozen changes to the tax reforms they brought to the 2022 election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">970b3c637e63137bc62f109e447684d9</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 13 October</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-13-october/5rckfbih1</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b0c11b6796a5123e6f2b0956702444b</guid></item><item><title>Families wait for hostages to return within hours | Evening News Bulletin 13 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/families-wait-for-hostages-to-return-within-hours-evening-news-bulletin-13-october-2025/q06u0oicp</link><description>In this bulletin, families prepare for the imminent release of the last Israeli hostages, major changes announced to superannuation tax plans. And in cricket, Alyssa Healy reflects on Australia&amp;apos;s win against India at the Women&amp;apos;s World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02577b0c864f7284792a553d1ba5f77a</guid></item><item><title>New super changes for low income earners and high balances &amp;amp; how geopolitics is impacting markets</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-super-changes-for-low-income-earners-and-high-balances-how-geopolitics-is-impacting-markets/mb3ysbk81</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Goncalves speaks with Daniel Martin from Alvia Asset Partners about the day&amp;apos;s market news including the impact of geopolitics including the holding ceasefire in Gaza; plus hear from Treasurer Jim Chalmers as he addresses changes to superannuation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43aad4e296b0658e493b74a2dd371979</guid></item><item><title>Why doesn&amp;apos;t Australia have a national Human Rights Act?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/why-doesnt-australia-have-a-national-human-rights-act/rv6fkahti</link><description>Human right law experts are calling the federal government to take what they call a significant opportunity to establish a federal Human Rights Act. It comes as a new report analyses how attempts to create such an act in Australia over five decades has been met with political opposition and misinformation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59d41c6dac7295d94c943e5e8c06a3db</guid></item><item><title>AFP investigates Lidia Thorpe&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;burn down Parliament House&amp;apos; remarks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/afp-investigates-lidia-thorpes-burn-down-parliament-house-remarks/hgj9z28x9</link><description>Thorpe&amp;apos;s comments sparked a political firestorm, with Home Affairs Minister Tony Burke urging leaders to avoid inflaming community tensions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eac0beba72a04b656067de0ebf1b8706</guid></item><item><title>The common way Australians have their data stolen — and what it&amp;apos;s costing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-australians-unknowingly-hand-over-their-security-to-hackers/2l7tlnxdq</link><description>The average financial losses from cybercrimes, both for Australians and businesses, continue to rise annually.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a29622799582dc1d75a299590aef9681</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Eating mostly brown food&amp;apos;: The &amp;apos;devastating&amp;apos; juggle faced by a rising number of Australians</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/juggling-act-social-services-payments-rent-food/g4wjshlw9</link><description>With one in seven Australians living below the poverty line, researchers and advocates say that COVID-era universal income is the solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d960bd899656fec9831f257edb63d9b</guid></item><item><title>World leaders sign a historic Middle East peace deal | Morning Bulletin 14 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/world-leaders-sign-a-historic-middle-east-peace-deal-morning-bulletin-14-october-2025/nwktrhh4h</link><description>In this bulletin, World leaders sign a historic Middle East peace deal in Egypt; all surviving hostages freed from Gaza in exchange for thousands of Palestinians; and in football, A women&amp;apos;s Indigenous football team prepares to make history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d11ef1135f41699b194fe0e48e9a9a73</guid></item><item><title>‘Historic exchange’: all Israeli hostages freed as Gaza peace talks continue</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/historic-exchange-all-israeli-hostages-freed-as-gaza-peace-talks-continue/8afzwummn</link><description>All 20 surviving Israeli hostages have been released from Hamas captivity in Gaza in a historic exchange as part of the first phase of a Gaza peace plan. And nearly 2000 Palestinians have also been freed from Israeli prisons, with the majority headed back to the war-ravaged Palestinian enclave. United States President Donald Trump has claimed the Israel-Hamas war is over, but negotiations are set to continue in Egypt with long-term peace still far from secure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc266d227e42bc4c01add8dd56555570</guid></item><item><title>Trump hails &amp;apos;tremendous day for Middle East&amp;apos; as leaders sign Gaza declaration</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-hails-tremendous-day-for-middle-east-as-leaders-sign-gaza-declaration/exls08tjs</link><description>Trump told assembled leaders at a Gaza summit in Egypt that they had &amp;quot;achieved what everybody said was impossible&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">600da5ef52f715b166cee071281802c2</guid></item><item><title>The new threat to Australia&amp;apos;s potato industry - what is it and how can we deal with it?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-new-threat-to-australias-potato-industry-what-is-it-and-how-can-we-deal-with-it/l0arbsua4</link><description>Of all Australian states, Tasmania is the biggest producer of potatoes, and a lot of what&amp;apos;s grown here goes into potato products you would know well – hot chips, hash browns and wedges among them. But a new virus detected in recent months is causing concern. Growers are optimistic it can be managed, stressing it doesn&amp;apos;t pose a risk to human health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62d1ac1b34b4f270ce3471de7cdee3ef</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Freed Israeli hostages hug loved ones in tears of joy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/freed-israeli-hostages-hug-loved-ones-in-tears-of-joy/jxif449lm</link><description>Hundreds of people erupted in joy, tears and song on Tel Aviv&amp;apos;s Hostages Square on Monday as news of the releases broke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c5ea68d4d28bfd592eed440ad4b32d9</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Historic dawn&amp;apos;: Key takeaways from Trump&amp;apos;s speech at the Israeli parliament</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/key-takeaways-from-trumps-speech-at-the-israeli-parliament-knesset/pvop9ysoc</link><description>Trump announced a new era of peace, as Hamas freed the remaining hostages and Israel released nearly 2,000 prisoners and detainees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ce2f238668084b84f0275d06561d40a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The greatest joy&amp;apos;: Palestinians reunite with loved ones after Israeli imprisonment</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/palestinians-reunite-with-family-after-release-by-israel/91ul3ppe6</link><description>Deeply emotional scenes unfolded in Gaza and the West Bank as Palestinian prisoners and detainees returned after their release by Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eac2fe44e6429ce92c890c7279de0dd</guid></item><item><title>Marles, Wong praise Trump&amp;apos;s peace plan in Gaza as &amp;apos;enormous achievement&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/marles-praises-trumps-peace-plan-in-gaza-as-enormous-achievement/ya9qvbp5d</link><description>The government says US involvement in securing the release of Israeli hostages will be &amp;quot;remembered by history&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bae542074ee4be4f7dce350f37052f4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I don&amp;apos;t have words&amp;apos;: Cape Verde erupts in celebration after historic World Cup qualification</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cape-verde-historic-world-cup-qualification/kyjoflpjv</link><description>The island nation is set to become one of the smallest countries to participate in football&amp;apos;s showpiece event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8be5a9d7cf57dcbacb5825b90522517</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Concern&amp;apos; over prime minister and Opposition leader&amp;apos;s phone numbers being leaked</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/concern-over-prime-ministers-phone-being-leaked/rrh4ae0o5</link><description>Anthony Albanese and Sussan Ley are among dozens of high-profile Australians whose numbers have been leaked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0b5d82da36d30d788bd2759f48e969a</guid></item><item><title>Joyful reunions for families in Israel, Gaza | Midday News Bulletin 14 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/joyful-reunions-for-families-in-israel-gaza-midday-news-bulletin-14-october-2025/14t2cqou3</link><description>In this bulletin, scenes of jubilation as Israeli hostages and Palestinian prisoners return home, the United Nations urges leaders to use the momentum of the exchange to create peace in Gaza. And in football, Spain plans to continue its winning streak as it strives for World Cup qualification.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">21e16f73bac998d09dff41f8ec112ecd</guid></item><item><title>Climate tipping points being crossed, scientists warn</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/climate-tipping-points-being-crossed-scientists-warn/e2nzqakov</link><description>A large white coral reef containing important species and fossil traces has been discovered at a depth of more than 500 metres in the Gulf of Naples, in a rare discovery for the Mediterranean. But a new report suggests reefs like this might already be in danger, with global warming crossing dangerous thresholds sooner than expected and the world&amp;apos;s coral reefs now in an almost irreversible die-off. It marks what scientists are describing as the first tipping point in climate-driven ecosystem collapse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f92a62b5564c38dc6ba5020e6b6cf55b</guid></item><item><title>Middle East peace deal signed; so where to from here?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/middle-east-peace-deal-signed-so-where-to-from-here/mslljq4v8</link><description>World leaders have signed a historic Middle East deal at a summit in Egypt. It comes hours after Israel and Hamas exchanged detainees and hostages. Israel released nearly 2,000 Palestinians from Israeli prisons, and Gaza released the surviving Israeli hostages after two years in captivity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a960a0f7a7d519f4c0ffdf4d65709e6c</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 14 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-14-october-2025/07mga95db</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f0b6aaa279b497e596069263ec42745</guid></item><item><title>Aid organisations rush to Gaza in wake of deal | Evening News Bulletin 14 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/aid-organisations-rush-to-gaza-in-wake-of-deal-evening-news-bulletin-14-october-2025/zddv9awmd</link><description>In this bulletin, aid agencies call for greater access to the Gaza Strip to meet overwhelming demand, an advertising campaign targets teens ahead of an under-16 social media ban. And in football, Cape Verde qualifies for the World Cup for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">408073324f16b7ee81ecdc99a045def2</guid></item><item><title>Hamas&amp;apos; next move is unknown, but one person may &amp;apos;hold the key&amp;apos; to a lasting peace in Gaza</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gaza-peace-deal-what-happens-next/mxbnk7p2v</link><description>The first phase of a deeply complex peace process has begun. So what happens next?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5eb15f8b8a3f072b0df1e231020c4bd</guid></item><item><title>What are rare earths, and why are the share prices of companies mining them surging?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/what-are-rare-earths-and-why-are-the-share-prices-of-companies-mining-them-surging/ahkd2o2f8</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Kai Chen from MPC Markets about the rise on rare earths along with the rest of the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83036c7248750b5a662573a4fd77de29</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The hunt for the nearest mechanic&amp;apos;: NATO chief mocks &amp;apos;broken&amp;apos; Russian submarine</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nato-chief-mocks-broken-russian-submarine/xy1ynrhdh</link><description>Russia&amp;apos;s Black Sea Fleet rejected reports the diesel-powered submarine had suffered a serious malfunction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a6829e562fdc08a35cfd6712ba3af2e</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s Jewish and Palestinian communities celebrate the return of loved ones</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australias-jewish-and-palestinian-communities-celebrate-the-return-of-loved-ones/3y1ifgb3k</link><description>In Australia, Jewish and Palestinian communities have been celebrating the release of hostages and detainees as the fragile path to peace in Gaza continues. In Melbourne, Israeli hostage supporters took to the streets while there&amp;apos;s also been celebration among families of Palestinians set free.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">424fe4370713a45f7f10a0e28103f9f1</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Mystified&amp;apos;: Concern for thousands in Australia after Venezuela&amp;apos;s surprise move</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/venezuela-closes-embassy-australia-maduro-trump/mpgcbcetq</link><description>The closure of Venezuela&amp;apos;s embassy in Canberra follows the Nobel Peace Prize being awarded to Venezuela&amp;apos;s opposition leader over the weekend. But are the two related?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3d44e01ac6e1ec2e5d2181bc22bba7b</guid></item><item><title>I&amp;apos;m a mother of five and a world champion. I refuse to let trauma define me</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/im-a-mother-of-five-and-a-world-champion-i-refuse-to-let-trauma-define-me/xyr4caydj</link><description>Shantelle&amp;apos;s story is one of strength. The proud Barkindji and Ngiyampaa woman says some people prefer to see her as a victim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cc4efb77c24cd59b0db077fcfdbbfde</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Our shining star has dimmed&amp;apos;: Celebrated soul musician D&amp;apos;Angelo dies at 51</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/our-shining-star-has-dimmed-celebrated-soul-musician-dangelo-dies-at-51/7vo00osym</link><description>Acclaimed American soul musician D&amp;apos;Angelo has died at 51 after a &amp;quot;prolonged and courageous battle with cancer&amp;quot;, his family says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cf96ad8654d14a655e6368c6376edf8</guid></item><item><title>Warning Australia faces &amp;apos;looming period of risk&amp;apos; as it awaits nuclear submarines</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/warning-australia-facing-looming-period-of-risk-as-it-awaits-for-nuclear-submarines/tv9hb3orn</link><description>As Australia awaits nuclear-powered submarines, a strategic policy think tank warns we&amp;apos;re sitting vulnerable to potential threats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">def08fb9ad5ab463bf0d42db63e7ad60</guid></item><item><title>Israel and Hamas trade accusations, fragile ceasefire holds in Gaza | Morning Bulletin 15 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israel-and-hamas-trade-accusations-fragile-ceasefire-holds-in-gaza-morning-bulletin-15-october-2025/24mnxmijy</link><description>In this bulletin, Israel and Hamas trade accusations as the fragile ceasefire holds in Gaza; Victoria to reform its assisted dying laws; and in sport, South Sydney vows to take a strong stand against winger Tyrone Munro, who&amp;apos;s facing DV charges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae1bb9d6509c6b19651c99554902219d</guid></item><item><title>Israel says one of four bodies returned by Hamas does not match any of the hostages</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-delays-gaza-aid-as-hamas-reasserts-control-with-public-executions/m1gr6ipdw</link><description>The bodies were returned after Israel announced it would cut in half the number of humanitarian aid trucks allowed into Gaza in a move to punish Hamas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef6143ea93d1a034cb7422c416a76475</guid></item><item><title>Israel says one of four bodies returned by Hamas does not match any of the hostages</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/template/m1gr6ipdw</link><description>The bodies were returned after Israel announced it would cut in half the number of humanitarian aid trucks allowed into Gaza in a move to punish Hamas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99b13cf80cf1bb8238f1b17a3b32aced</guid></item><item><title>Israel says one of four bodies returned by Hamas does not match any of the hostages</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-says-one-of-four-bodies-returned-by-hamas-does-not-match-any-of-the-hostages/m1gr6ipdw</link><description>The bodies were returned after Israel announced it would cut in half the number of humanitarian aid trucks allowed into Gaza in a move to punish Hamas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0862f063fd2b57c23d80278cb539d32</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government debates ground-breaking Treaty Bill</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/victorian-government-debates-ground-breaking-treaty-bill/q2rsxdo7p</link><description>The Victorian Government is debating a historic Statewide Treaty Bill, establishing Australia&amp;apos;s first ever Treaty agreement between a state government and First Peoples in Victoria. If signed into law, the Treaty Bill will forge a path forward for First Peoples in Victoria to negotiate and influence the policy that affects community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dbd06e3145503ed0fadf3a971e18358</guid></item><item><title>Hamas hands over bodies of hostages to Red Cross | Midday News Bulletin 15 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/hamas-hands-over-bodies-of-hostages-to-red-cross-midday-news-bulletin-15-october-2025/vrpu153r2</link><description>Hamas hands over four bodies of hostages to the International Committee of the Red Cross; a grim milestone reached for Aboriginal deaths in custody in New South Wales; and Australia&amp;apos;s women&amp;apos;s cricket side prepares for their showdown with Bangladesh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d399ac2708ee83efe7c6be52393d4d98</guid></item><item><title>Military seizes power in Madagascar after president flees amid youth protests</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/military-seizes-power-in-madagascar-after-president-flees-amid-youth-protests/qvo024061</link><description>Gen Z-driven demonstrations erupted last month over water and power shortages, quickly escalating into an uprising over broader grievances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad47e15910b788f255e8c5db1df3857b</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 15 October</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-15-october/3nd3zru1t</link><description>A daily five-minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d9d2f9875051d46287880b7e9509db9</guid></item><item><title>Australian passport power revealed, as the US and UK hit record lows</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australias-passport-power-revealed-as-us-and-the-uk-hit-record-lows/1yssu9bu8</link><description>For the first time in 20 years, the United States&amp;apos; passport has fallen from the top ten most powerful in the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5913d8dc348b75c930086e886f61acc</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos&amp;apos; undefeated streak ends with loss to US</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/usa-vs-australia-socceroos-undefeated-streak-comes-to-end-with-loss-to-the-united-states/ekybucznm</link><description>The Socceroos have already qualified for the World Cup, with coach Tony Popovic hoping new players &amp;quot;surprise&amp;quot; him ahead of the finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42000ea24a0a0c3df9b2dd24f138c952</guid></item><item><title>US revokes visas of six foreigners over Charlie Kirk comments</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-revokes-visas-for-six-foreigners-over-charlie-kirk-comments-on-social-media/bccd5ohv8</link><description>According to the US state department, one foreigner whose visa was revoked accused Kirk of spreading &amp;quot;racist&amp;quot; rhetoric.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c61bfcbe91331a7578a56bd2365938d9</guid></item><item><title>US revokes visas of six foreigners over Charlie Kirk comments</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-revokes-visas-for-six-foreigners-over-charlie-kirk-comments/bccd5ohv8</link><description>According to the US state department, one foreigner whose visa was revoked accused Kirk of spreading &amp;quot;racist&amp;quot; rhetoric.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a80a43d1356dd046a2a1ffda6ff41f2b</guid></item><item><title>Israel and Hamas both accused of not keeping cease fire agreement</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israel-and-hamas-both-accused-of-not-keeping-cease-fire-agreement/o3uoxbnwq</link><description>Hamas has returned more bodies of Israeli hostages to the International Committee of the Red Cross in Gaza. Questions remain over sustainable peace in the Middle East, with uncertainty about how to resolve sticking points in Donald Trump&amp;apos;s 20-point plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">606cca32ae81250f8e0fe87566997c20</guid></item><item><title>These Sydneysiders watched as the hostage-detainee swap played out. Then came a call</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/those-watching-from-afar-as-the-gaza-ceasefire-plays-out-in-real-time/w3ip60rfg</link><description>Palestinian and Jewish Australians describe their emotional journey watching the first phase of the Gaza ceasefire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef864187adbe80a5f3efd531333779d0</guid></item><item><title>Kathryn lost her banking job to a chatbot. She just confronted her CBA bosses</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/kathryn-lost-her-banking-job-to-a-chatbot-she-just-confronted-her-cba-bosses/cgx8kmymj</link><description>Former Commonwealth Bank employee Kathryn Sullivan spent years teaching the bank&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;Bumblebee&amp;quot; chatbot how to respond to customers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">229c2ceb1c4b11d1ee4a3df1ccba43e5</guid></item><item><title>Concerns over fragile Gaza ceasefire | Evening News Bulletin 15 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/concerns-over-fragile-gaza-ceasefire-evening-news-bulletin-15-october-2025/gtg498al5</link><description>Australian Gaza aid flotilla activists urge the federal government to impose an arms embargo on Israel.; the Northern Territory Chief Minister defends a ban on transgender women being placed in female jails; and in football, the Socceroos unbeaten streak under Tony Popovic comes to an end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e3e339ba260c95d3c444a14953c7af7</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;La Crise&amp;apos;: French politics stumbles from crisis to crisis</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/la-crise-french-politics-stumbles-from-crisis-to-crisis/wyhuk8cc6</link><description>The Eurozone&amp;apos;s second-largest economy is battling a deep political crisis. It all started when French President Emmanuel Macron called snap elections last year in an attempt to consolidate his power. Instead, they resulted in a hung parliament and gains for the far right. Now, France’s sixth prime minister in under two years has been forced to abandon one of the president’s key achievements just to hold his government together.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">681e26464a74942865768e4235c9459f</guid></item><item><title>What record low fertility rates mean for our economy &amp;amp; gold hits another record</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/what-record-low-fertility-rates-mean-for-our-economy-gold-hits-another-record/ab79wv67m</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with McCrindle Social Researcher Ashley Fell about thegrowing trend for Australians to have fewer kids, and later in life; plus Luke Laretive from Seneca Financial Services looks through the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket moves including what he is telling his clients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">393550f2a88ab6ee9896470517c2cd65</guid></item><item><title>The &amp;apos;confluence of crises&amp;apos; driving Australia&amp;apos;s record-low fertility rate</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-confluence-of-crises-driving-australias-record-low-fertility-rate/9lh5pvz93</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s birth rate is declining — but researchers say it&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;not about selfishness&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef1723f1e0034dec133ef93803ce7c35</guid></item><item><title>Labor criticised over worker visa rule backflip that could affect thousands</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/labor-criticised-over-worker-visa-rule-backflip-that-could-affect-thousands/i08mdb5c4</link><description>Tens of thousands of people from the Pacific and East Timor currently work in Australia under the PALM scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb96a966de4ab0d3eef43c7085921580</guid></item><item><title>NSW hits &amp;apos;grim milestone&amp;apos; with First Nations deaths in custody reaching record levels</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nsw-hits-grim-milestone-with-first-nations-deaths-in-custody-reaching-record-levels/2fsnn2err</link><description>The New South Wales coroner says the state has hit a grim milestone with First Nations deaths in custody reaching record levels. 12 Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander people have died in custody in the state this year, the highest number ever recorded in a single year. The distressing figures have prompted the state coroner to issue a rare public statement, condemning the deaths and vowing to investigate each one independently and thoroughly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f262dfd27c59bfe3dabe5a590e28e054</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s rainforests are now adding to carbon emissions, scientists say</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rainforests-carbon-emissions-targets/vaghexnps</link><description>A new study has found Queensland&amp;apos;s tropical rainforests emit more carbon than they absorb, raising concerns for Australia&amp;apos;s climate targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad316dc2d21a9518f44c0f990e3178db</guid></item><item><title>Revealed: The generational divide over belonging in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-generational-divide-over-belonging-in-australia/pjnhensyl</link><description>Social isolation and economic disadvantage are partly responsible for declining rates in national belonging, a new study suggests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cfa26f0dae0c7c6911c060553577764</guid></item><item><title>Hamas returns two more bodies but says it has handed back all the hostage remains it can reach</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hamas-returns-hostages-bodies/0plf71soq</link><description>Earlier in the day, Israel returned the remains of 45 Palestinians to Gaza authorities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ac284148d23e1ac6920d8c05b113802</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan and Afghanistan agree on 48-hour temporary ceasefire | Morning News Bulletin 16 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pakistan-and-afghanistan-agree-on-48-hour-temporary-ceasefire-morning-news-bulletin-16-october-2025/699b4iygi</link><description>Pakistan and Afghanistan announce temporary ceasefire after fresh border clashes; First Nations deaths in custody reaching record levels in New South Wales; And in cricket, Pakistan go 1-0 up in the two-match Test series with South Africa.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28175e31d4808b2e0980063b945a6254</guid></item></channel></rss>