<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>SBS English News (Unofficial Aggregation)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 20:18:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>A surfer&amp;apos;s death in Sydney could stir up the shark net debate. So why are they so controversial?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sydney-surfer-shark-attack-death-shark-net-controversy/wv1hqtzrn</link><description>A fatal shark attack on Sydney&amp;apos;s Northern Beaches has come amid debates about the efficacy and environmental effects of shark nets. So do they actually protect swimmers, and what are the alternatives?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17612a2e8210fdd34cd3db530ec9abe3</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the Charlie Kirk shooting suspect</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-we-know-about-the-charlie-kirk-shooting-suspect/dqnakhike</link><description>More photos have been released of a &amp;quot;person of interest&amp;quot; in relation to the shooting of right-wing activist Charlie Kirk. There is still no suspect in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b355779fc318d8e1e4df044892a1f1eb</guid></item><item><title>Former Brazilian President jailed for 27 years | Midday News Bulletin 12 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/former-brazilian-president-jailed-for-27-years-midday-news-bulletin-12-september-2025/i92xlyog3</link><description>In this bulletin, Anthony Albanese is thankful for Pacific leaders support on Australia’s bid to host climate talks, a former Brazilian President is jailed for decades over an attempted election coup. And in sport, Greg Norman bows out of the LIV golf tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7249ed466b6ee80e5cae8f5e5c6e7e68</guid></item><item><title>Xi’s 'new world order', Indonesia unrest &amp; Thailand’s political plight</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/xis-new-world-order-indonesia-unrest-thailands-political-plight/gf52cf61m</link><description>In this episode: China’s military parade and its guests of honour the US media has dubbed ‘the Axis of Upheaval’, protesters mobilise across Indonesia as parliamentary allowances trigger mass unrest. Plus, Thailand faces yet another political crisis while environmental concerns escalate across the…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a301c53679e2f46c08e8310db39c9bd</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Cricketer Usman Khawaja on why he is calling on sporting bodies to consider banning Israel</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-cricketer-usman-khawaja-on-why-he-is-calling-on-sporting-bodies-to-consider-banning-israel/8q0qvuywq</link><description>Usman Khawaja says he raised the issue of imposing sanctions on Israel over its actions in Gaza during his meeting with Prime Minister Anthony Albanese.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">422348dd235b1a2ad21af885a71f1076</guid></item><item><title>Spring season property hotspots &amp; reporting season fallout</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/spring-season-property-hotspots-reporting-season-fallout/u6jn8r0fh</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Goncalves speaks with Tim Lawless from Cotality Australia about the direction for home prices as the Spring selling season begins and to find out where the property hotspots are, plus Mathan Somasundaram from Deep Data Analytics takes a look back at the reporting season…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">823ecf0ba615002992542f409f091c8b</guid></item><item><title>Matildas captain Steph Catley scores Ballon d&amp;apos;Or nomination</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/matilda-named-in-2025-balloon-dor-shortlist/ujyi1uiez</link><description>Steph Catley is the sole Australian nominee among the 30 finalists for the 2025 Ballon d&amp;apos;Or Féminin, marking a milestone in Australian football.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e7d4d595901d79ce913b63908facc60</guid></item><item><title>'I won't be silenced': Jacinta Price axed from Coalition frontbench in fallout over Indian migration remarks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/i-wont-be-silenced-jacinta-price-axed-from-coalition-frontbench-in-fallout-over-indian-migrantion-remarks/geqqnw8vj</link><description>Northern Territory Senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price has been removed from the Coalition frontbench, following fallout from remarks she made about Indian migrants. Sydney Lang takes a look at how the last week unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13bcf7a28a8f461d56412fee1914bde1</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Doesn&amp;apos;t cut the mustard&amp;apos;: Indian Australian community leaders demand Price apology</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-indian-community-leaders-demand-price-apology/3t2yqrt2p</link><description>While welcoming an apology from Opposition leader Sussan Ley, one Indian Australian community figure said &amp;quot;the Liberal Party has their work cut out to repair the damage&amp;quot; caused by senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price&amp;apos;s comments on Indian immigration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e627c942f9c9434aaec1553129c384be</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 3 Sep 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-3-sep-2025/rqbzuecm0</link><description>A daily 5-minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc1e50f5913792e815ab35e44f2d7890</guid></item><item><title>Sydney sets 146-year rainfall record as severe weather eases</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sydney-sets-146-year-rainfall-record-as-severe-weather-eases/1a8fcxhhy</link><description>Over the 24 hours to 9am on Thursday, Sydney received a total of 122mm of rain, marking its heaviest daily rainfall for September since 1879.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d1c543899ec6a382083579988d9ea50</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 2 Sep 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-2-sep-2025/nte6lpfva</link><description>A daily 5-minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89f4f62d7213f4dab0e96018aa0d25fb</guid></item><item><title>A man shot by police attending house fire in Queensland | Morning Bulletin 10 September</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-man-shot-by-police-attending-house-fire-in-queensland-morning-bulletin-10-september/nnox4yd2i</link><description>In this bulletin, A man shot by police in Queensland as they responded to a house fire; Israel launches a surprise attack on Hamas targets in Qatar; and in NRL, the Panthers lose a key player to injury ahead of their elimination finals clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3aee2f510c8ec59b2542d8a08e6988e</guid></item><item><title>I&amp;apos;m an Australian and wanted nothing to do with religion. Here&amp;apos;s what changed my mind</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/christianity-is-declining-in-australia-meet-the-gen-z-converts-bucking-the-trend/kpgccwiom</link><description>While latest Census data pointed to a significant downward trend in Australians identifying as Christian, there was an uptick in religious diversity. Some research suggests 38 per cent of gen Z identify as spiritual and there is an increase of gen Z men turning to religion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e17da9d041a976bbc9059bfd0dab3c4</guid></item><item><title>Radiotherapy could save your life: dispelling the misconceptions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/radiotherapy-could-save-your-life-dispelling-the-misconceptions/uno2r91al</link><description>Despite being a proven life-saving treatment, 1 in 5 Australians who need radiotherapy never receive it. This year, on September 7, the first-ever World Radiotherapy Awareness Day will be launched, and experts say it's an opportunity to dispel fears of the treatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2be2c9a4a00462aa89c636361cd468ff</guid></item><item><title>What this grieving daughter found online is helping thousands in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/what-this-grieving-daughter-found-online-is-helping-thousands-in-australia/1pz56yq42</link><description>More than 180,000 people in Australia confront death each year, yet few leave behind a will or clear end-of-life wishes. When Vibha&amp;apos;s mother died, she was overwhelmed by both grief and unanswered questions. But then, she found support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7ad10a285249611e8ce80abac9e68f8</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk shooting: More clues as search for shooter intensifies</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/charlie-kirk-shooting-more-clues-as-search-for-shooter-intensifies/t1xz9eoy5</link><description>The hunt for the killer of conservative activist Charlie Kirk continues, with US federal investigators pursuing new leads in Utah. The FBI has released images of the suspect and is offering a reward of up to A$150,000 (US$$100,000) for information.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1faa8d1a144aa699f9be42e7e44c86f9</guid></item><item><title>The PM in Vanuatu as part of Pacific trip | Evening News Bulletin 9 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-pm-in-vanuatu-as-part-of-pacific-trip-evening-news-bulletin-9-september-2025/wmvcxrcdx</link><description>The Prime Minister in Vanuatu meeting with Pacific leaders, The ANZ bank to cut jobs, Ange Postecoglou tipped to return to the English Premier League</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb521933a77083896d19e1e8d419f157</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 11 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-11-september-2025/cmk9s3xbb</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d85ecaf226af85d3584b0eef3f689ef0</guid></item><item><title>Your guide to the 2025 World Athletics Championships — and how to watch from Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/your-guide-to-2025-world-athletics-championships/p7wrafboj</link><description>Australia is gearing up for one of its biggest track and field campaigns in history, with a record number of athletes bound for Tokyo to contest the 2025 World Athletics Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6857921f0cef4d27931a5efa26154bbe</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk 'a man of deep faith' says Trump | Evening News Bulletin 11 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/charlie-kirk-a-man-of-deep-faith-says-trump-evening-news-bulletin-11-september-2025/a51l0n5o2</link><description>Donald Trump condemns the shooting of conservative influencer Charlie Kirk; Australia signs on to the Pacific Resilience Facility as it moves to bolster ties in the region; and in sport, "devastated" paddling champion Jess Fox will not compete at the Slalom World Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c90bd8e6919000758e2fd55c47a91d26</guid></item><item><title>Lifting caps from first home buyer scheme will help some but fuel wider price rise</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lifting-caps-from-first-home-buyer-scheme-will-help-some-but-fuel-wider-price-rise/qufj0whee</link><description>The federal government will expand its Home Guarantee Scheme in October, lifting income and property caps to give first-time buyers greater access, but it will also fast-track price rises, a new analysis has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71f1d32104dd7cab1f85b9385a5703e4</guid></item><item><title>Federal government approves Woodside gas project extension, with some conditions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/federal-government-approves-woodside-gas-project-extension-with-some-conditions/goc08nvfr</link><description>The country&amp;apos;s largest gas project&amp;apos;s potential operating life has been extended to 2070.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a12ecbec94d2b938be29e759dfc967ac</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 12 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-12-september-2025/la1ex1kfj</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6152830b72d22eecc9fd00ff5b880c68</guid></item><item><title>Qatar says &amp;apos;regional response under way&amp;apos; after Israeli strike on Doha</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/qatar-says-regional-response-under-way-after-israeli-strike-on-doha/4zl864b98</link><description>Gulf leaders have rallied in solidarity with Qatar as global condemnation over the strikes grows.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8255137c41c0a31613dc27dc03babd23</guid></item><item><title>Why the final approval for North West Shelf gas plant has Indigenous groups and environmentalists worried</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/why-the-final-approval-for-north-west-shelf-gas-plant-has-indigenous-groups-and-environmentalists-worried/v12sc9i5e</link><description>The federal government has given the final approval for the Woodside North West Shelf gas project with a series of conditions. The approval comes ahead of the Albanese government's announcement of a 2035 emissions reduction target, and after Australia emphasised its commitment to tackling climate…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0996f56dc4418abd3998966386a8cca9</guid></item><item><title>ASX 200’s worst day since April; Australian economy grows faster than expected</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asx-200s-worst-day-since-april-australian-economy-grows-faster-than-expected/xkhcq18co</link><description>The Australian sharemarket has experienced its worst single-day drop since April, with all 11 sectors finishing in the red. For more, Rena Sarumpaet spoke with Perpetual’s Head of Investment Strategy, Matt Sherwood. Plus, Australia’s GDP expanded by a larger-than-expected 0.6% in the June quarter.…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76b3432d097b0c048c854c1813b1b733</guid></item><item><title>Bali floods leave at least 19 people dead and five missing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bali-floods-leave-15-people-dead-and-10-missing/05funve0t</link><description>Floodwaters rose to over 2.5 metres in some areas, with more than 800 people forced into temporary shelters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ade30020ec35fafac954ba6dfcbdbe8e</guid></item><item><title>"Terrifying reality" Islamophobia envoy calls for urgent action | Evening News Bulletin</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/terrifying-reality-islamophobia-envoy-calls-for-urgent-action-evening-news-bulletin/nhetlxwy2</link><description>In this bulletin, the Federal Government is handed dozens of recommendations to combat Islamophobia, the environment minister says final approval of the extension of a gas project is subject to conditions. And in tennis, Australia eyes a top 8 qualifying spot in the Davis Cup, playing Belgium this…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52878b3d2b7f48a88655bba7ad178c50</guid></item><item><title>Israel strikes Qatar, why it's been a bad week to be a PM &amp; the real 'Succession' finale</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israel-strikes-qatar-why-its-been-a-bad-week-to-be-a-pm-the-real-succession-finale/v3tnyfj2b</link><description>Israel's strike on Qatar blows up ceasefire talks, the prime ministers of Nepal, Japan and France depart in a hurry, and Albanese battles for influence in the Pacific, while Moldova battles to stop Putin’s influence ahead of elections. Plus, the Murdoch succession is finally settled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7e0eaabc8585d03e4f518e25a324473</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 5 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-5-september-2025/dn8y3bjig</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09f805b8314d81e4ff90e19d59400831</guid></item><item><title>Is Victoria Australia's crime state and what does it mean for insurance premiums?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/is-victoria-australias-crime-state-and-what-does-it-mean-for-insurance-premiums/iqp477ah1</link><description>Car theft claims rose to a record $233m in Victoria last financial year, but fell in every other state so Stephanie Youssef speaks with Insuance Council of Australia CEO Andrew Hall to find out what can be done about it and what it means for premiums, plus SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves takes…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5522aef409671e89a18893236459103b</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 9 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-9-september-2025/7pl65i7q0</link><description>A Five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">645638e8c6be4a78aaa6378a1dca6105</guid></item><item><title>A generation to lose it, three to restore it: One man&amp;apos;s quest to revive a language at risk</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/a-generation-to-lose-it-three-to-restore-it-one-mans-quest-to-revive-a-language-at-risk/9vo5uavn8</link><description>Once punished for speaking, now celebrated in song — te reo Māori is finding new life. For Marlon Williams, music has become both a personal reckoning and a powerful tool for revival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b3898f7eed595f5272fcb0165d193ad</guid></item><item><title>I went to search a car for drugs while on duty. What happened next made me re-evaluate my life</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/greg-was-run-over-while-on-duty-it-made-the-police-detective-re-evaluate-his-life/n45nsyhh9</link><description>Police recruitment drives in response to chronic shortages have led to more people applying to join their local force. But what were the factors that led to the shortages in the first place?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9049ee608eae75f0ac91bb2c95569d0a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Like the Castle&amp;apos;: The Australian families who could lose farms in Trump&amp;apos;s rare earths push</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-families-who-could-lose-farms-in-rare-earths-minerals-push/o3shp981l</link><description>In north-west Victoria, a David and Goliath battle is playing out between farmers and the rare earths mining industry which has been backed by state and federal governments as the world scrambles to extract key minerals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9724dc5ede0aef6038ef0e9aebce6151</guid></item><item><title>Scottish brothers reach Cairns after record-breaking row across the Pacific Ocean</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lachlan-jamie-ewan-maclean-scottish-brothers-cairns-rowing-pacific-ocean/4qgv8mys7</link><description>After more than four months at sea, the brothers reunited with loved ones — along with pizza and beer — as they reached their final destination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53880f8926f2556582b6c95c8afaf9f1</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Girt by sea&amp;apos; explained: National anthem now in 60+ languages</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/girt-by-sea-explained-national-anthem-now-in-60-languages/z1ycvk2zl</link><description>Ever wondered what &amp;quot;girt by sea&amp;quot; means, especially if your first language isn&amp;apos;t English? SBS Audio has brought Australia’s national anthem to life in more than 60 languages, so everyone can understand the words behind the music.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04079c2c5f6e829b610f96ef72903390</guid></item><item><title>US Conservative activist Charlie Kirk shot and killed</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-conservative-activist-charlie-kirk-shot-and-killed/t8muabr16</link><description>One of President Donald Trump's key allies has been shot and killed during a public event at a university in Utah.Charlie Kirk co-founded the Turning Point USA organisation in 2012 to drive conservative viewpoints among young people, and then became the go-to spokesman on television networks and at…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d48f01cd23bf9e9cd238d03f6a3aecf</guid></item><item><title>US stocks benefit from Oracle surge; home ownership dream slipping</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-stocks-benefit-from-oracle-surge-home-ownership-dream-slipping/lva29gz3x</link><description>The ASX 200 has closed 0.3% lower with healthcare stocks dragging the index down, despite gains by gold miners. That’s almost despite Oracle’s shares soaring almost 40% in its best one-day performance since 1992, lifting the S&amp;P 500 and other global markets to record highs. For more, Stephanie…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09067c9fdf20c9801c040532d3c16c92</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;When I wear the clothes... I feel proud&amp;apos;: How these women fleeing conflict find strength</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/karen-women-fleeing-myanmar-find-strength-weaving-western-australia/tlol975h4</link><description>Karen women in Australia use weaving to preserve culture and heal from trauma. However, recent international aid cuts raise fears for more than 100,000 displaced Karen still stuck in refugee camps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c17959a19232c1709745ea92d7da110f</guid></item><item><title>Ireland says it will boycott Eurovision 2026 if Israel is allowed to participate</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ireland-israel-eurovision-2026-participation-gaza/yf4scypng</link><description>Irish broadcaster RTE said it would be &amp;quot;unconscionable&amp;quot; to take part in the contest alongside Israel, given its ongoing assault on Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62cffd1bb18419483053a0ea72f1e5f3</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 10 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-10-september-2025/hh3zlp7ve</link><description>A daily 5-minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41a086b5616544320d925dff8713e1aa</guid></item><item><title>Bali floods leave at least 19 people dead and five missing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bali-floods-leave-19-people-dead-and-five-missing/05funve0t</link><description>Floodwaters rose to over 2.5 metres in some areas, with more than 800 people forced into temporary shelters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86c7ef56559860dfa062ba2b88867059</guid></item><item><title>Brazil's former President Bolsonaro sentenced to jail</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/brazils-former-president-bolsonaro-sentenced-to-jail/v1s50igk9</link><description>Brazil's former President, Jair Bolsonaro has been sentenced to prison after being convicted of plotting a coup to remain in power after losing the 2022 election. Mr Bolsonaro, who has denied any wrongdoing, has not attended the court and has only sent his lawyers.He is the first former president…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d59efe136133d39a3417df21ab88006</guid></item><item><title>How much you need for a comfortable retirement? | NAB latest to cut jobs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/how-much-you-need-for-a-comfortable-retirement-nab-latest-to-cut-jobs/lvwy0rsjq</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Marcus Bogdan from Blackmore Capital about the day's market action including why banks seem to be on a job cutting cycle, plus Stephnie Youssef speaks with ASFA CEO Mary Delahunty to find out how much money is needed in super to fund a comfortable…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89a3a01df5e55e9682b60616942b381f</guid></item><item><title>Ley apologises to Indian Australians, says Price remains &amp;apos;valued&amp;apos; party member after sacking</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ley-apologises-to-indian-australians-says-price-remains-valued-party-member/li9efqs2v</link><description>Sussan Ley&amp;apos;s apology come after she dumped Jacinta Nampijinpa Price from the Opposition frontbench over the senator&amp;apos;s remarks about Indian migrants and her refusal to endorse her leadership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">247454894dec2d9a59ae4e4275dc557c</guid></item><item><title>Former Virgin CEO’s $50m payday; &amp; is a US rate cut locked in?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/former-virgin-ceos-50m-payday-is-a-us-rate-cut-locked-in/l8f9hkzjz</link><description>Former Virgin Australia CEO Jayne Hrdlicka is collecting a $49.9 million pay packet, which includes 10 million shares, as revealed in the company’s annual report. For more on this and the ASX-200’s performance this week, Stephanie Youssef spoke with IG Markets analyst Tony Sycamore. Plus, US…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">926fab565460dcb2749e5787e0bab9e0</guid></item><item><title>Refugees, foreign students and 'boat people': What it's really like to migrate to Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sbs50-stories-of-migration-since-1975/w4o7q8wg5</link><description>As SBS celebrates 50 years of storytelling, we share the stories of those who made the at times perilous journey across the seas in search of freedom, safety and a sense of home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bae5ca5a05eba4b134ba244c5b95381</guid></item><item><title>Australians on Gaza flotilla say they remain &amp;apos;steadfast&amp;apos; after alleged drone attacks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-on-gaza-flotilla-steadfast-after-alleged-drone-attacks/ybr5gq8x0</link><description>There are believed to be about 10 Australians involved in the Global Sumud Flotilla, which is attempting to break Israel&amp;apos;s naval blockade of Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ee2e658fa589e3c6d2762554aa8e9b1</guid></item></channel></rss>