<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>SBS English News (Unofficial Aggregation)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 15:11:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>PM travels to Indonesia to sign security treaty | SBS News In Easy English 6 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pm-travels-to-indonesia-to-sign-security-treaty-sbs-news-in-easy-english-6-february-2026/ify7k0di8</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">928ab6f5719dc1f8f621c0984105c4d9</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Impossible choices&amp;apos;: The data that proves living costs are rising for Australians</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/impossible-choices-the-data-that-proves-living-costs-are-rising-for-australians/smm4voks8</link><description>Living costs rose across all households over the past year, with those on government payments facing the steepest increases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad6539bb0afbbd98f74519598553aed5</guid></item><item><title>ASX200&amp;apos;s worst day since April 2025 as technology rout continues</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asx200s-worst-day-since-april-2025-as-technology-rout-continues/53xb4haxx</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Lochlan Halloway from Morningstar to go through all the factors that has triggered a sell-off on the sharemarket, including an ongoing technology sector rout, along with a look at the local reporting season; plus Peter McGuire from Trading.com looks at Bitcoin&amp;apos;s sliding value.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bdf2e7773186383ee114e6a8b9607c8</guid></item><item><title>Do you earn more or less than others working in the same job?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-does-where-you-live-in-australia-affect-your-income/zc6kzm5iq</link><description>New figures show where the highest-paid Australian workers live and what jobs they are doing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cd3355efaee3d0af689fd5f9489b0d2</guid></item><item><title>Tutorials, work and fears their loved ones are dead: The uni students facing unique stress</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/no-sleep-for-weeks-the-students-facing-an-anxious-start-to-the-academic-year/fxdivmn8n</link><description>&amp;apos;Aida&amp;apos; is among university students from Iran battling financial stress and emotional trauma, following the recent violent crackdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">865f16bffecd48837fe0a24f26a35dea</guid></item><item><title>‘Are our loved ones alive or not?’ A distressing start to the academic year for these international students</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/are-our-loved-ones-alive-or-not-a-distressing-start-to-the-academic-year-for-these-international-students/odjxp3hg0</link><description>University students in Australia, including more than 800,000 from overseas, are preparing for a new academic year. However, many from Iran are facing financial hardship while also grieving lives lost during recent protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d0d5f167dcd76adb1323b112dd4b83a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Blatantly racist&amp;apos;: Trump deletes social media video depicting Obamas as apes after backlash</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/blatantly-racist-trump-deletes-social-media-video-depicting-obamas-as-apes-after-backlash/buk0jk1mt</link><description>The White House initially described the negative reaction as &amp;quot;fake outrage&amp;quot; before deleting the post 12 hours later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d71ee25c6c92b45f209fab2c8872ccd3</guid></item><item><title>Russian general under US sanctions shot several times in Moscow</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/russian-general-shot-several-times-in-moscow/dh4ve1d2v</link><description>Investigators said lieutenant general Vladimir Alexeyev was critically injured after he was shot by an unidentified gunman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f790b2f1eefac1a03da8264dcd76544e</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: SBS talks to Mildura&amp;apos;s mayor on managing heatwaves, and overcoming climate change scepticism</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-sbs-talks-to-milduras-mayor-on-managing-heatwaves-and-overcoming-climate-change-scepticism/2f65oth3c</link><description>The far northwestern city of Mildura is used to hot summers. But in January, the city and surrounds sweltered through an unusual heatwave, with temperatures breaking records throughout the region. SBS&amp;apos; Deborah Groarke spoke with the mayor of Mildura, Ali Cupper, on how the Council deals with hot weather, and its concerns around how worsening climate change patterns might affect its residents and agricultural economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20c0522744be7c04ef9d20bba5684446</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;You cannot escape diversity&amp;apos;: The controversial housing laws trying to &amp;apos;integrate&amp;apos; immigrants</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/you-cannot-escape-diversity-the-controversial-housing-laws-trying-to-integrate-immigrants/9jrnb72bf</link><description>Denmark&amp;apos;s once-termed &amp;quot;ghetto laws&amp;quot; were designed to &amp;quot;integrate&amp;quot; immigrants but the European Court of Justice has deemed them potentially unlawful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdc75762c6c38a08317f358ddda855c7</guid></item><item><title>The fight over voting: can the US electoral system be altered to favour one party?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-fight-over-voting-can-the-us-electoral-system-be-altered-to-favour-one-party/ldijy7alc</link><description>With the midterm elections due at the end of this year in the United States, Republicans and Democrats in some states are scrambling for an advantage. Republican President Donald Trump had hoped re-districting could help House Republicans hold on to their slim majority. But there are moves to introduce legislation that could also give the party an advantage, laws that the Democrats say are designed to shut out minority voters. And there are still election battles to be won in Texas - and Georgia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3b1a47ddb4897665e3e08f0f8cd9732</guid></item><item><title>US pushing for June deadline to end Russia-Ukraine war, Zelenskyy says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-pressing-ukraine-and-russia-to-end-war-by-june-zelenskyy-says/zps8n57kj</link><description>The US has given Ukraine and Russia a June deadline to reach a deal to end the nearly four‑year war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55f3050ac14e125170ed05daf6c99281</guid></item><item><title>Residents told &amp;apos;too late to leave&amp;apos; as Tropical Cyclone Mitchell nears WA coast</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cyclone-mitchell-fears-as-storm-closes-in/mz5ou8z8d</link><description>Locals are waiting to count their losses after being hit by severe tropical Cyclone Mitchell, with the worst yet to come.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5312fb5f3d0985a7e6b2c245271a65b2</guid></item><item><title>Queensland plans laws with two-year jail terms for &amp;apos;from the river to the sea&amp;apos; slogan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/queensland-set-to-impose-two-year-jail-terms-for-from-the-river-to-the-sea-slogan/h3851dtd5</link><description>Pro-Palestinian slogans would be outlawed in Queensland under sweeping legislation to crack down on hate speech and antisemitism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16098c1a3dd0a89ac8ecc7128e8daec4</guid></item><item><title>Sydney pro-Palestinian protest group to launch legal challenge to Herzog visit police powers</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sydney-pro-palestinian-protest-group-to-launch-legal-challenge-to-herzog-visit-police-powers/bsr6ddv7h</link><description>The decision to grant police extra powers during the Israeli president&amp;apos;s visit will face a legal challenge in the NSW Supreme Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f561ae933b4a5311238ca4f544429767</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Beyond a nuisance&amp;apos;: Why the government is being urged to tackle sovereign citizens online</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/beyond-a-nuisance-why-the-government-is-being-urged-to-tackle-sovereign-citizens-online/iz4rf7xu0</link><description>The sovereign citizen movement has become a serious security threat, and governments need to treat it as such, a new report argues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ad897ccb43db7ece8913bdbd39cb569</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Easy and cheaper&amp;apos;: Why a growing number of Australians are adopting this niche lifestyle</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/is-living-off-grid-actually-cheaper/659x148w4</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s off-grid communities used to be seen by some as hippy communes. These days, they&amp;apos;re more high-tech — and a more affordable housing option.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91df205e1406621d52cd1f6aa0600b62</guid></item><item><title>WA communities &amp;apos;dodge a bullet&amp;apos; after Cyclone Mitchell weakens as it nears coast</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cyclone-mitchell-downgraded-but-continues-to-pummel-west-australias-coast/xzlcxq7rb</link><description>WA Premier Roger Cook said it was &amp;quot;good news&amp;quot; the system had been downgraded to a category one, but urged locals to be vigilant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37f10261a77407eeda6659d3d745a9ea</guid></item><item><title>Australian researchers on a mission to save millions of lives from antibiotic resistance</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australian-researchers-on-a-mission-to-save-millions-of-lives-from-antibiotic-resistance/ur9klrb22</link><description>The rise of antibiotic resistance is threatening millions of lives worldwide, but “unconventional” Australian research could make obsolete medications effective again. Data released by the World Health Organization (WHO) has found that some of the most common illnesses in the world are becoming more resistant to treatment every year. Dr Maud Eijkenboom says the current approach of developing new antibiotics is losing the battle against ever-evolving viruses and bacteria. After her son struggled with a resistant disease, Dr Eijkenboom set on her own path to discover a better way eradicate the rising wave of lethal pathogens. In 2021, she founded Lixa, a Perth-based biotech company receiving international support for its “game-changing” research. In this edition of Weekend One on One, she speaks with SBS&amp;apos;s Cameron Carr about the impact of her research, and started by explaining what Lixa is all about.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddacb0ccac6e8eba690382971431687b</guid></item><item><title>Minneapolis Indigenous leaders, community, hold memorial service as US Senate debates ICE funding</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/minneapolis-indigenous-leaders-community-hold-memorial-service-as-us-senate-debates-ice-funding/22n0ihvc4</link><description>Indigenous leaders and community members in Minneapolis have held a memorial honouring two people shot dead by immigration officers last month. As protests against the widespread immigration crackdown continue, Republicans and Democrats remain locked in a standoff over reforms to Immigration and Customs Enforcement. The debate in the Senate continues as the deadline for reaching a funding agreement for the Department of Homeland Security looms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ded7b6b993927478a882474d14285633</guid></item><item><title>Australian food causes a stir at university canteen in Germany</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-food-causes-a-stir-at-university-canteen-in-germany/pusyh6g0i</link><description>Students in Germany were taken aback when an unexpected dish with a decidedly Australian flavour appeared on the menu in their canteen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5da371d5aa45ece583ea7f3d7845b1c0</guid></item><item><title>Call for calm over Herzog visit | SBS News In Easy English 9 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/call-for-calm-over-herzog-visit-sbs-news-in-easy-english-9-february-2026/ues26pex4</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ae404a3d7da7e77a625bb358f67c78</guid></item><item><title>Senate estimates wrap: AFP Herzog advice, minister&amp;apos;s $30K phone discount and condoms</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/30k-ministers-phone-bill-condoms-labor-grilled-in-senate-estimates/jedyb5wva</link><description>A minister&amp;apos;s $30,000 phone bill discount has been scrutinised as Labor faces another Senate estimates week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c743d3575b9b841a81f1bb4e046e6b3</guid></item><item><title>ASX has best day since Donald Trump&amp;apos;s Liberation Day</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asx-has-best-day-since-donald-trumps-liberation-day/w2jrhqh7n</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with George Boubouras from K2 Asset Management to find out why the market has been so volatile of late as he takes a closer look at how investors will be analysing AI investments during the upcoming reporting season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38ee44694ea4b2132970caafae55be80</guid></item><item><title>The world is running out of antibiotics. New research could make old ones work again</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-research-combatting-antibiotic-resistance/6s3a7lbvu</link><description>Australian research could be key to combating the rising threat of antibiotic resistance and saving millions of lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eb0080b414afd1d16b5c5178910dc25</guid></item><item><title>Tensions linger as protesters gather outside Sydney police station</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/police-clash-with-protesters-as-thousands-rally-against-president-herzogs-visit/ysljl9ehd</link><description>Demonstrators gathered outside Surry Hills Police Station on Tuesday, a day after clashes with officers at Sydney&amp;apos;s Town Hall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">079a59378101fce626d25b89d3b4811a</guid></item><item><title>Australia opposes Israel&amp;apos;s plan to expand control in West Bank, government says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/international-condemnation-of-new-israeli-settlement-measures-in-west-bank-grows/qp1uyfvw2</link><description>Israeli government minister Bezalel Smotrich said the changes were aimed at &amp;quot;burying the idea of a Palestinian state&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1800a5986b494c6f049820d83fd7184a</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Feyza Tuncay on helping children learn about ethics</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-feyza-tuncay-on-helping-children-learn-about-ethics/xclgycqpn</link><description>Primary Ethics is an independent, not-for-profit organisation and provides ethics classes for school students across New South Wales. Classes are impartially run by volunteers and the program has been implemented in hundreds of schools. Facilitator Feyza Tuncay became involved with Primary Ethics when she started volunteering as an ethics teacher at her son&amp;apos;s school. She&amp;apos;s speaking here to SBS News&amp;apos; Jennifer Scherer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">268724697e16b201da31d7cc619f1c60</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I won&amp;apos;t walk away&amp;apos;: Starmer stands firm amid ongoing Epstein scandal in UK</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/i-wont-walk-away-starmer-stands-firm-amid-ongoing-epstein-scandal-in-uk/ftvek3byi</link><description>The Jeffrey Epstein saga has continued to make headlines. UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer has come under new pressure to resign, amid an expanding scandal over his appointment of Peter Mandelson as ambassador to the US despite ties to Epstein. The latest tranche of files relating to the convicted sex offender have also brought new scrutiny to former prince Andrew, with UK police assessing reports he sent sensitive information to Epstein. Epstein associate Ghislaine Maxwell has refused to testify before a US congressional committee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95f3ff7b23d907e0946bb8b32df8f0e5</guid></item><item><title>Premier Minns defends police response to rally against Herzog visit | SBS News In Easy English 10 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/premier-minns-defends-police-response-to-rally-against-herzog-visit-sbs-news-in-easy-english-10-february-2026/2wbakjozd</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c427b94df7646ffd126727af34311448</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Speaks of colonialism&amp;apos;: Why Bad Bunny&amp;apos;s performance resonated around the world</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bad-bunny-performance-symbolism/ohcs33wc9</link><description>Riddled with easter eggs, the show brought Puerto Rican history and culture to one of the biggest platforms on the planet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d33e9956f6b300d662f0ccf9cb0a3039</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Lopsided&amp;apos; foreign worker scheme under fire as most of the money stays in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lopsided-foreign-worker-scheme-where-most-of-the-money-stays-in-australia-under-fire/9q6geobwm</link><description>The PALM labour scheme is under renewed scrutiny after new analysis warned the program carries modern slavery risks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17bec57c73eed7f29b93f7a215309b0b</guid></item><item><title>Government unveils policy to end violence against First Nations women and children</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/government-unveils-policy-to-end-violence-against-first-nations-women-and-children/ehc1ne8tx</link><description>The Federal Government has launched a landmark $218 million national plan to end violence against First Nations women and children. It marks the first long-term strategy designed and led entirely by Indigenous communities. While the policy targets specialised healing and emergency services in remote areas, community leaders warn that real change also requires confronting the systemic racism and high rates of violence perpetrated by non-Indigenous men.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a337e7cf92c43daa725c347b739bb17c</guid></item><item><title>AI industry risks and the Australian dollar nears US$0.71</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ai-industry-risks-and-the-australian-dollar-nears-us-0-71/e0v4hjw1g</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Todd Hoare from LGT Wealth Management about the day&amp;apos;s market moves including the increasing risks AI poses to certain industries, what&amp;apos;s driving the Australian dollar, and the opportunities for investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcfb280b8a7410191b5c512619b6629a</guid></item><item><title>What we know about Israel&amp;apos;s damage to Gaza cemetery housing Australian war graves</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-war-graves-destroyed-israel-gaza/rmimxni60</link><description>The graves include those of Australian Light Horse troops, a World War One force known for their role in the Battle of Beersheba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1f855981e68ab0d9caecb14bcadee69</guid></item><item><title>Albanese says he raised criminal charges over Zomi Frankcom&amp;apos;s killing with Isaac Herzog</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/zomi-frankcoms-brother-seeks-answers-from-israels-president-over-her-death-in-gaza/qglvohe2h</link><description>The prime minister said he raised Zomi Frankcom&amp;apos;s killing in an Israeli air strike directly with the Israeli president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31022be5beaad8bb6a5deb0ecbadcf5f</guid></item><item><title>Israeli minister urges protesters not to &amp;apos;import conflict&amp;apos;, defending Herzog visit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-minister-urges-protesters-not-to-import-conflict-defending-herzog-visit/br7wgmmsh</link><description>Israel&amp;apos;s deputy foreign minister has spoken out against the &amp;quot;absolutely heartbreaking&amp;quot; violence during protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">481eecaea0eaaff536eaffc476f1174e</guid></item><item><title>US Congress criticises ICE enforcement as &amp;apos;reckless and creating chaos&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-congress-criticises-ice-enforcement-as-reckless-and-creating-chaos/n2e1srdag</link><description>A contentious hearing of the US House Committee on Homeland Security has exposed deep divisions over immigration enforcement following the death of two American citizens at the hands of Immigration and Customs Enforcrment, better known as ICE. While ICE officials framed the deaths as a result of officers facing increasing threats of harm, the argument was rejected with those holding the agency accountable, calling its tactics Gestapo-like.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd108b2fcc1be75f6a31a8c58e67b79e</guid></item><item><title>PM thanks Israeli president for providing &amp;apos;comfort&amp;apos;; Herzog describes &amp;apos;emotional&amp;apos; visit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-thanks-herzog-for-providing-comfort-during-emotional-visit/zy5r6eei0</link><description>Anthony Albanese has praised the Israeli president and first lady for providing comfort to Jewish Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47951a8c67905d972255474f475a96dc</guid></item><item><title>Famine levels reached in two more regions of Sudan&amp;apos;s North Darfur, UN says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/famine-levels-reached-in-two-more-regions-of-sudans-north-darfur-un-says/s3trt0ypk</link><description>Acute malnutrition has now reached famine levels in two more regions of North Darfur in Sudan, according to a new report from a UN-backed global hunger monitor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cea59ac3308487846ffe05ecc6840f81</guid></item><item><title>Eight people killed after woman opens fire at high school in Canada, suspect found dead</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/british-columbia-shooting/ca2agz7xd</link><description>Police said the suspected shooter has also been found dead with &amp;quot;what appears to be a self‑inflicted injury&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a518c78cfa7b5e707fea61b781eaa79d</guid></item><item><title>Call for transparent investigation into police actions at Sydney rally | SBS News In Easy English 11 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/call-for-transparent-investigation-into-police-actions-at-sydney-rally-sbs-news-in-easy-english-11-february-2026/njfvkswi7</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a2da90cc1014340d0c4a24622d9935c</guid></item><item><title>Muslim worshippers say NSW police &amp;apos;came in like a wrecking ball&amp;apos; at Sydney protest</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/muslim-worshippers-say-nsw-police-came-in-like-a-wrecking-ball-at-sydney-protest/oqfxv0wte</link><description>Muslim worshippers who were praying at a Sydney protest say police intervened during a vulnerable moment of prayer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd1091ceba6ed356a5da3580c922dd5a</guid></item><item><title>Review launched into the plan for Australia&amp;apos;s largest river ecosystem</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/review-launched-into-the-plan-for-australias-largest-river-ecosystem/vjp4kwsra</link><description>Public consultation has opened on a review into the management plan for the Murray–Darling Basin, Australia&amp;apos;s largest river system. The announcement has come weeks after Environment Minister Murray Watt listed the lower Murray River region as critically endangered. Conservation groups have reacted cautiously, saying they hope the review leads to decisive action for a Basin that underpins public health, regional livelihoods, and cultural connection for millions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73a39ed49e1eab014fe6a7416b4cb2d0</guid></item><item><title>ASIO and AFP face Senate questions about the Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asio-and-afp-face-senate-questions-about-the-bondi-terror-attack/qxc80pxqw</link><description>The Australian Security Intelligence Organisation and Australian Federal Police have been questioned about their actions before and after the Bondi terror attack, with Australia&amp;apos;s top spy agency defending its failure to prevent it. During a senate estimates hearing late on Tuesday night, the AFP also warned it will take a more aggressive approach to tackling hate and extremism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f891c0eb9dc9fc7365d5ea2803c9f082</guid></item><item><title>Israel&amp;apos;s President Herzog given official welcome in Canberra</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israels-president-herzog-given-official-welcome-in-canberra/5z8guuc6f</link><description>Israeli President Isaac Herzog has enjoyed a ceremonial welcome and a lunch with Prime Minister Anthony Albanese in Canberra. President Herzog and his wife, Michal, were given a ceremonial 21-gun salute by the Federation Guard before attending a garden function at the Israeli embassy. His visit has been dogged by protests, with demonstrators saying he should not have been invited in the first place,</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8486bb78f042e1cd2ca25590ef07797</guid></item><item><title>Trump allegedly said Ghislaine Maxwell is &amp;apos;evil&amp;apos;: What do we know about their relationship?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-called-maxwell-evil-in-resurfaced-interview-as-she-refuses-to-answer-questions-from-us-congress/rhjmukkc0</link><description>Ghislaine Maxwell&amp;apos;s attorney says she&amp;apos;s prepared to speak publicly if granted clemency by the US president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14c06cf670fff5242b674cc87b1badbe</guid></item><item><title>CBA&amp;apos;s Matt Comyn on why the disruptive potential of AI should not be underestimated</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/cbas-matt-comyn-on-why-the-disruptive-potential-of-ai-should-not-be-underestimated/uijydybwb</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Commonwealth Bank CEO Matt Comyn following the groups $5.45bn half- year cash profit announcement, including a deep dive into artificial technology and productivity; plus Luke Laretive from Seneca Financial Solutions takes a look at the day&amp;apos;s market action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acd93d068da2a996a59df085ba0f38ff</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Completely over the top&amp;apos;: How tensions built towards NSW police tactics at Sydney protest</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/protest-footage-raises-excessive-force-militarisation-questions-of-nsw-police/ib31jv0tv</link><description>Experts have pointed to new laws and increased police militarisation as factors leading to clashes in Sydney on Monday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5b81920bd4c359307f3e84e7c06dd72</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Left our nation in shock&amp;apos;: Canada in mourning after mass shooting</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/left-our-nation-in-shock-canada-in-mourning-after-mass-shooting/b6vig9bxq</link><description>Canadians are grappling with the deaths of at least nine people, including the suspect, after a mass school shooting in a remote town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c27da64b0b1c0e2f96f18d1e90eb5e95</guid></item><item><title>Australia to send envoy to Laos over methanol poisoning deaths, Wong announces</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-special-envoy-laos-methanol-poisoning/8vatb6stq</link><description>Australians Holly Morton-Bowles and Bianca Jones died from methanol poisoning while drinking at a backpackers&amp;apos; hostel in Vang Vieng.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a2aa974bf69c413163d00885a0fa56e</guid></item><item><title>US Attorney General under pressure over handling of Epstein files</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-attorney-general-under-pressure-over-handling-of-epstein-files/xgr1yl81r</link><description>The US Attorney-General has faced an onslaught of questions into the Department of Justice&amp;apos;s handling of the more than 3 million files released related to late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein. Survivors and critics are demanding transparency and justice for the more than one thousand victims identified, as Pam Bondi faced a Senate congressional hearing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91fcb4171efba3be6a85dda7e4b7c7a7</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor says he plans to challenge Sussan Ley for Liberal leadership | SBS News In Easy English 12 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/angus-taylor-says-he-plans-to-challenge-sussan-ley-for-liberal-leadership-sbs-news-in-easy-english-12-february-2026/6nlz1p8sc</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa78612651e78f73fb524c0908db8ccb</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Smartest policy brain&amp;apos; or controversial deal-maker: Who is the real Angus Taylor?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/who-is-angus-taylor-the-man-taking-on-sussan-ley-ahead-of-liberal-leadership-showdown/pqndd5kxm</link><description>From water dealings to questionable economic credentials — who is the new Liberal Party leader?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e2d2ac43407a6aeda53b0bf0f2d0cad</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor launches leadership bid</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/angus-taylor-launches-leadership-bid/iby8avx5a</link><description>Former Shadow Minister for Defence Angus Taylor has triggered a formal leadership challenge against Sussan Ley, prompting a wave of coordinated frontbench resignations. The coalition is reeling from historic polling lows. While Mr Taylor campaigns for a &amp;quot;decisive&amp;quot; reset of the party’s values, a loyal faction of Liberals is fighting to protect Ms Ley’s position, arguing she deserves more time to stabilise the party room before Friday’s high-stakes ballot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6663f889a7b951b5853df975838f58b8</guid></item><item><title>Latest report on Closing the Gap targets not a story of &amp;apos;failure&amp;apos;, says PM</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/latest-report-on-closing-the-gap-targets-not-a-story-of-failure-says-pm/jfrqxb8d9</link><description>The federal government has released its latest report card on its Closing the Gap targets, which are meant to improve the lives of Indigenous Australians. The data shows just four of the 19 targets are on track. Anthony Albanese has used his annual closing the gap speech on Thursday to announce a $144 million boost to Indigenous health to upgrade more than 100 services in cities and regional areas. But some - like the incarceration rates of First Nations people - continue to worsen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb69c377e3fd9af092593e6527c39643</guid></item><item><title>AMP CEO Alexis George on results, super changes and female leadership</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/amp-ceo-alexis-george-on-results-super-changes-and-female-leadership/1shzygtje</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with AMP CEO Alexis George following the financial services company&amp;apos;s full-year results as she prepares to step down, including her advice to aspiring female leaders; plus Stephanie Youssef discusses the day&amp;apos;s market action with market analyst Evan Lucas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">393aa8543e743b5fc2cbfe992d0d404c</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Lai’s ‘death’ sentence, Japan’s Takaichi takes on China &amp;amp; the bulging Olympic controversy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/jimmy-lais-death-sentence-japans-takaichi-takes-on-china-the-bulging-olympic-controversy/ceaay1r0d</link><description>A massive win for Japan’s hawkish first female PM worries China, conservatives reclaim Thailand and Jimmy Lai, Hong Kong’s most high-profile casualty of draconian security laws gets a ‘death sentence’. Plus, trouble growing at the winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cfcdaa439d7c09f39d3553ae35be0cf</guid></item><item><title>The results of recent Liberal spills show a clear trend. What does it mean for Angus Taylor?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-results-of-recent-liberal-spills-show-a-clear-trend-what-does-it-mean-for-angus-taylor/opcjunzhe</link><description>Sussan Ley is fighting to defy the odds when it comes to leadership challenges in her party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e61f8955a6619005782d2d3f629d222</guid></item><item><title>Israeli president wraps up visit feeling &amp;apos;hope in the air&amp;apos; — and with a message to protesters</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-president-wraps-up-visit-with-hope-and-message-to-protesters/xmzgcecv2</link><description>Isaac Herzog&amp;apos;s trip has sparked controversy and national protests, including a Sydney rally that descended into violence on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df0e2da92f5efdfa7f65dcc584d66467</guid></item><item><title>Pat is living in a &amp;apos;dangerous&amp;apos; and run-down home. They&amp;apos;ve been hit with a rent increase</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/pat-is-living-in-a-dangerous-and-run-down-home-then-their-rent-went-up/etu3vn4b8</link><description>Across Australia, rents are climbing far faster than wages and many can&amp;apos;t keep up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e542281b234a532d16472815ae553bc0</guid></item><item><title>Immigration crackdown in Minnesota to end, US border chief announces</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/immigration-crackdown-in-minnesota-to-conclude-trumps-border-chief-says/d9yfzizwu</link><description>Border tsar Tom Homan said Donald Trump had agreed to end the operation, which saw 3,000 armed immigration agents deployed to the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a582dad7d892bf79c5e8c9f2525647a3</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor has outlined his priorities after ousting Sussan Ley as Liberal leader</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/angus-taylor-ousts-sussan-ley-as-liberal-party-leader/kg601fr3i</link><description>A new Liberal Party duo has emerged, with Angus Taylor becoming its 17th leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b458b8df596d0335fba7a7117ff3119</guid></item><item><title>ICE&amp;apos;s controversial surge force to quit Minnesota</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ices-controversial-surge-force-to-quit-minnesota/kdmfi1l2y</link><description>The United States&amp;apos; border chief has announced ICE agents will withdraw from Minnesota. This ends a two-month surge operation which resulted in two US citizens being killed by federal agents, and thousands of arrests. It follows mass protests in the state and across the country, as well as condemnation by Democratic Senators over the violent immigration crackdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e2f0e8f4b3a5d9f89b20116336940d5</guid></item><item><title>NSW police to be investigated over protest, as witness shares new account of &amp;apos;dark moment&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/police-watchdog-to-investigate-officers-conduct-a-anti-herzog-rally-in-sydney/pclf5ii03</link><description>The Law Enforcement Conduct Commission said it had received a &amp;quot;significant number of complaints&amp;quot; about police conduct at Monday&amp;apos;s rally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b673b19ca4e37356dc172928c5c753f0</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor elected new Liberal Party leader | SBS News In Easy English 13 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/angus-taylor-elected-new-liberal-party-leader-sbs-news-in-easy-english-13-february-2026/aajopb466</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99cb7c464f39b31ac65e0a2d5041b57c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;quot;There&amp;apos;s not a lot left to burn&amp;quot;: Coalition launches new bid for unity and support under Angus Taylor</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/theres-not-a-lot-left-to-burn-coalition-launches-new-bid-for-unity-and-support-under-angus-taylor/7fiv18n4l</link><description>Angus Taylor has seized the Liberal Party leadership in a decisive party room vote - 34 to 17 - ending Sussan Ley’s nine-month tenure as the party’s first female leader. Backed by new deputy Jane Hume, the Rhodes scholar and former Shadow Treasurer now faces the challenge of rebuilding a fractured base while navigating a political history marked by significant past controversies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d65e7bf19d62ca8bf8f0a60cbcf32771</guid></item><item><title>Lunar New Year 2026: What to know about the &amp;apos;very special&amp;apos; Year of the Fire Horse</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lunar-new-year-2026-fire-horse-what-to-know/mj0anue2q</link><description>The fire horse, which occurs once every 60 years, is considered to be like &amp;quot;double fire&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19ecbf28a347a5a6b7cb272d013e45e7</guid></item><item><title>ANZ says AUD heading for US $0.73 as Cochlear warns of currency impacts</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/anz-says-aud-heading-for-us-0-73-as-cochlear-warns-of-currency-impacts/wsgwt9wkq</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Cochlear CEO Dig Howett about the hearing implant maker&amp;apos;s latest results, the link between hearing loss and dementia and the impact the higher Australian dollar will have on its earnings. Plus Mahjabeen Zaman from ANZ looks at the drivers of the surging currency and market implications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42f8e2c561a9ae5cf39a98c24d17d495</guid></item><item><title>SBS NITV Radio talks to Charles Pakana about World Radio Day</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-nitv-radio-talks-to-charles-pakana-about-world-radio-day/cqpfy3ovn</link><description>13 February is celebrated as World Radio Day. The day is designed to honour radio as a trusted and powerful form of communication. Today is also the 18th anniversary of the National Apology to the Stolen Generations. SBS NITV Radio&amp;apos;s Kerri-Lee Barry has spoken to Charles Pakana from Victorian Aboriginal News, who says radio is a way to connect with each other as we share our histories and truth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b1abea6e18155d6164f28bfd37caa3f</guid></item><item><title>Australians&amp;apos; personal data could soon be accessible by US agencies. Here&amp;apos;s why</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trumps-america-wants-access-to-australian-biometric-data/ftomgcy5j</link><description>Speculation over a proposal to hand Australians&amp;apos; biometric data to the US is raising concerns among privacy experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">987aeea1bfcfee4bb17c2ec2db139020</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Not a Ley problem&amp;apos;: The long-standing Liberal issues that may haunt Angus Taylor</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ley-not-the-problem-former-leaders-issues-may-haunt-taylor/yvh6dcl7c</link><description>Among several issues that plagued Sussan Ley, one broke &amp;quot;the camel&amp;apos;s back&amp;quot;, turning voters to One Nation, a polling expert says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3167745dcad5eb3e67851712ae3e3a76</guid></item><item><title>The Lunar New Year DIY dumpling event putting a new spin on a centuries-old tradition</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-lunar-new-year-diy-dumpling-event-putting-a-new-spin-on-a-centuries-old-tradition/9v84r6nfv</link><description>Dumplings are popular dish for families celebrating Lunar New Year. In Melbourne, one restaurant is challenging tradition, with a make-your-own approach and a range of exotic flavours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eedc6ad00fdae68b5bc59e344ab07f51</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane lion dancers master their skills to welcome the Year of the Horse</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/brisbane-lion-dancers-master-their-skills-to-welcome-the-year-of-the-horse/k1ak1v0ut</link><description>Millions of people around the world will soon welcome in the Year of the Horse. A key part of Lunar New Year celebrations for many communities is lion dancing, which is said to bring good luck and prosperity into the new year. But it takes discipline to master the skill, as one group of dancers in Brisbane hopes to continue the traditional performance</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a540ce475a5944729ed51035a1fc3ac</guid></item><item><title>The introduction of decimal currency, 60 years on</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-introduction-of-decimal-currency-60-years-on/hvtgyzcll</link><description>Today marks a major milestone in Australia’s financial history – the 60th anniversary of decimal currency. It’s been decades since Australians ditched pounds, shillings and pence for dollars and cents – in one of the largest transitions in the nation’s history. And while the way we pay for things continues to change, the legacy of that moment endures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fa024643a55de94851085d2061333f5</guid></item><item><title>Bondi attack stories and memories to be preserved in new digital project</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/remembering-bondi-project-sydney-jewish-museum/6ca0trpar</link><description>The Sydney Jewish Museum has asked people to share memories through an online tool, and hoped the project would &amp;quot;amplify healing&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">309ce5a1ce58ace56ac8362bde45b98c</guid></item><item><title>Gary wasn&amp;apos;t impressed by Australia&amp;apos;s dumpling scene. Now he&amp;apos;s selling thousands a day</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/gary-wasnt-impressed-by-australias-dumpling-scene-now-hes-selling-thousands-a-day/6cqp6gbvw</link><description>Dumplings are a popular dish for Lunar New Year celebrations. However, one Australian restaurant is bringing a twist to the tradition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb7b517bfea453ff19d2afdbddc7b828</guid></item><item><title>PM calls for &amp;apos;full explanation&amp;apos; after Muslim prayer disrupted by police at Sydney protest</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/pm-calls-for-full-explanation-after-muslim-worshippers-dragged-from-sydney-protest/93gy77pgq</link><description>Anthony Albanese said the Muslim community was feeling a &amp;quot;great deal of hurt&amp;quot; after officers manhandled several worshippers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec8ddc7b0a701d1e2d1a01a193e9091b</guid></item><item><title>Mariam&amp;apos;s story of survival amid a &amp;apos;war on women&amp;apos; in Sudan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sudan-gender-based-violence-crisis/pq1retgcu</link><description>Nearly three years into a civil war, Sudan is facing a hunger crisis. It&amp;apos;s also facing a crisis of violence against women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b43f4f5700f9567aeaa6bd8cc8cc4164</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Can a souffle rise once?&amp;apos;: Albanese takes first swipe at new Opposition leaders</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anthony-albanese-angus-taylor-criticism/0nhyfq7cc</link><description>The prime minister has made his first comments about the ouster of Sussan Ley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6e3b267d66d4b53d17f4a08e214f20c</guid></item><item><title>Bangladesh&amp;apos;s Tarique Rahman poised to be PM as Islamists concede in &amp;apos;credible&amp;apos; elections</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bangladeshs-tarique-rahman-poised-to-be-pm/62nelflyq</link><description>Nearly 60 per cent turned up to vote in what the Bangladesh Electoral Commission called &amp;quot;by far, the best election&amp;quot; in the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1355e2db4d03cd52aa94978e154eff5d</guid></item><item><title>Bangladesh&amp;apos;s Tarique Rahman poised to be PM as Islamists concede in &amp;apos;credible&amp;apos; elections</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bangladeshs-tarique-rahman-poised-to-be-pm-as-islamists-concede-in-credible-elections/62nelflyq</link><description>Nearly 60 per cent turned up to vote in what the Bangladesh Electoral Commission called &amp;quot;by far, the best election&amp;quot; in the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f704d8f6da902b9d76c24711b8ed4cba</guid></item><item><title>With their first female leader gone, can the Liberals shake their &amp;apos;women problem&amp;apos;?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/liberals-women-problem-after-sussan-ley-dumped-as-first-female-leader/bamdvwqf3</link><description>Senior Liberals say Sussan Ley&amp;apos;s removal was about polling, not gender. But experts warn it may reinforce doubts about the party&amp;apos;s appeal to women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d355396c4df18a1ae16f181a7a00f27c</guid></item><item><title>How to set boundaries and manage family expectations during Lunar New Year</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lunar-new-year-mental-health-expert-tips/45biogco0</link><description>From dinner-table arguments to loneliness, experts weigh in on some of the challenges families can face during the Lunar New Year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b36098699b3f77bb70bad7d6ed060f00</guid></item><item><title>The &amp;apos;transactional&amp;apos; experience that prompted Jay to campaign against surrogacy laws</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/how-a-hair-stylists-client-list-became-a-campaign-to-change-surrogacy-laws/68mzq9pv6</link><description>Jay always wanted to be a dad, but WA&amp;apos;s surrogacy laws meant significant barriers. So he became the face of a campaign to change them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53732ac447f6e05155105724ced5769a</guid></item><item><title>Mariam&amp;apos;s story of survival amid a &amp;apos;war on women&amp;apos; in Sudan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/mariams-story-of-survival-amid-a-war-on-women-in-sudan/559hvyz8u</link><description>Women and girls are bearing the brunt of Sudan’s nearly three-year-old civil war, facing widespread gender-based violence, displacement and deepening hunger as the conflict intensifies. 18-year-old Mariam, a survivor of sexual violence has had to flee escalating violence to an under-resourced displacement camp where food and medicine is in limited supply. With famine spreading and humanitarian access shrinking, organisations like Plan International warn the needs of survivors far exceed the support available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccb165ec3003c083b17779b613cc8301</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: What needs to happen to bring the Murray Darling Basin back to health?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-what-needs-to-happen-to-bring-the-murray-darling-basin-back-to-health/flm7l3sho</link><description>The Murray Darling Basin management plan is currently under review. Public submissions on a discussion paper [[see it here: https://www.mdba.gov.au/publications-and-data/publications/2026-basin-plan-review-discussion-paper]] are being accepted until 1 May 2026, as authorities determine their next steps in managing Australia&amp;apos;s biggest river ecosystem. SBS has spoken with the national director of the Murray Darling Conservation Alliance, Craig Wilkins, about what those next steps should be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">107ced71972b7468aa2d561b3496af10</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Unprecedented times&amp;apos;: Jakara Anthony&amp;apos;s Winter Olympic gold secures record medal haul for Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jakara-anthony-winter-olympics-gold-medal/dbfe6nwgy</link><description>The 27-year-old skier has become Australia&amp;apos;s first ever two-time Winter Olympic gold medallist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e192cf53d0b05c84d9e8b1713d704f8</guid></item><item><title>Which states get an Anzac Day public holiday this year?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anzac-day-public-holiday-which-states/0nax12a1k</link><description>With Anzac Day falling on a weekend this year, an extra public holiday has been announced for the people of NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">936e15ece260f9f695fc5dad08385b7d</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Standards too low, numbers too high&amp;apos;: Refreshed Liberal Party poised for immigration cuts</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/angus-taylor-anti-immigration-stance/t40pzjmu2</link><description>Angus Taylor called to &amp;quot;shut the door on people who reject our way of life, who don&amp;apos;t believe in our core values&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b46f3e0cce6920d8716dbdc0eb70b962</guid></item><item><title>Weet-bix kimchi: Glynn&amp;apos;s experiment with Australian and Korean favourites may be a hit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/weet-bix-fermented-australian-kimchi-from-regional-tasmania/a2mc6iuwy</link><description>Through Weet-Bix kimchi, Sue Glynn is connecting Australia and Korea in regional Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ec4b8c1f091ad0d6e73233d81175b3d</guid></item><item><title>James was tackled by officers at an anti-Herzog protest. He says he&amp;apos;s lucky to be alive</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/not-changing-what-ive-said-chris-minns-firm-on-sydney-protest-amid-investigation/aid614hmc</link><description>James Ricketson says he is exploring legal options after police tackled him to the ground at a protest against the Israeli president&amp;apos;s visit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25dca6bf101b6c6a42762769145f2605</guid></item><item><title>A major trade deal with the EU may be closer than ever. Here&amp;apos;s how Australians stand to benefit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-eu-trade-deal/9yiyz75cl</link><description>Australians could see more competitive prices for European products under a deal that could give the economy a billion-dollar boost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">896259c36d2e465690b7f0a7a9b5da61</guid></item><item><title>Darren&amp;apos;s hunted zebras and bears overseas. Now a &amp;apos;trophy&amp;apos; ban is in Australia&amp;apos;s sights</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/killing-or-conservation-inside-australias-trophy-hunting-fight/gwb6i8s0o</link><description>Supporters say trophy hunting is misunderstood. But critics call it cruelty dressed up as conservation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28ca3e1d648592f5b5689d3046457eb0</guid></item><item><title>What fasting for Ramadan is like for a sailor, a midwife and a miner</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-ramadan-fasting-is-like-in-australian-workplaces/afrnkk8oh</link><description>Australians in high-stakes workplaces — from ships to hospitals to mine sites — reveal the realities of observing Ramadan while on the job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c1bbaf3d65d4ea06f7ee15a701863a9</guid></item><item><title>Israel&amp;apos;s approval of West Bank land registration condemned as &amp;apos;de facto annexation&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/de-facto-annexation-israel-approves-proposal-to-register-land-in-west-bank-as-state-property/rregk7fxr</link><description>The land registration adds to a series of measures taken earlier this ⁠month to expand control.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">477e43337d5c4334ee3182e76cb3db93</guid></item><item><title>Immigration and taxes: Angus Taylor outlines agenda ahead of frontbench announcement</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/immigration-taxes-and-housing-taylor-outlines-agenda-ahead-of-front-bench-announcement/412y425cu</link><description>Angus Taylor is expected to announce a new frontbench in the coming days in a bid to move on from weeks of party infighting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">454a24f822d8b2a14a3d54d34088878e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Not fair dinkum&amp;apos;: ACCC rejects Coles&amp;apos; arguments in landmark &amp;apos;illusory&amp;apos; discounts legal case</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/accc-coles-misleading-discounts-allegations-federal-court-case/92p7elywx</link><description>The consumer watchdog&amp;apos;s barrister said increased costs are irrelevant to whether products are promoted to customers as genuine discounts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90cb79de359ce0e690dcb4531d1e24e4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Iran is my home as well&amp;apos;: Worldwide turnout of hundreds of thousands in solidarity with Iranian protesters</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/iran-is-my-home-as-well-worldwide-turnout-of-hundreds-of-thousands-in-solidarity-with-iranian-protesters/4wlnbwj7e</link><description>From Munich to Melbourne, hundreds of thousands have turned out to oppose Iran&amp;apos;s clerical leadership in the wake of a brutal crackdown on protesters inside the country. While opinions differ over who should take over the current regime, protesters all voiced their desire for an Iran free from oppression.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acab2944d9da356f03fbe9dad0de4b16</guid></item><item><title>Court appearance for alleged Bondi shooter | SBS News In Easy English 16 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/court-appearance-for-alleged-bondi-shooter-sbs-news-in-easy-english-16-february-2026/b9qdml1j4</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d542eef3447d36c32b21b79b6eb568</guid></item><item><title>Opposition was preparing widespread immigration bans under Sussan Ley&amp;apos;s leadership</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/opposition-was-preparing-widespread-immigration-bans-before-liberal-leadership-spill/z89xa831g</link><description>The Opposition&amp;apos;s immigration spokesperson under Ley has said he never proposed nor agreed to the policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75fc8909326c7874899db49ff85e3b52</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians look to salvage Gaza&amp;apos;s history from the ruins of war</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/palestinians-look-to-salvage-gazas-history-from-the-ruins-of-war/fsx3yp0sc</link><description>.The Gaza Strip is home to some extraordinary remnants of human history, dating from the Bronze Age through to the Ottoman and British empires.Many historic sites suffered from neglect before the war - but the United Nations cultural agency, UNESCO, says it has verified damage to at least 150 historic heritage sites since the start of the Israel-Hamas conflict. Palestinians in the Gaza Strip are reckoning with how to save their historical monuments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60ffd6545c3d500ffc25cd320e0fadbe</guid></item><item><title>Tech stocks recover and IMF warns Australian states on spending</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/tech-stocks-recover-and-imf-warns-australian-states-on-spending/0s02gxzdv</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Alex Pikoulas from Munjarra Capital about the day&amp;apos;s market action including the latest profit results and the turn around in the tech sector; plus Anthony Walker from SP Global Ratings after the IMF warned Australian states to reign in spending.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43b0fbadbee53b48850dfbcc9b34ad5a</guid></item><item><title>ACCC alleges Coles claimed to cut prices - but didn&amp;apos;t</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/accc-alleges-coles-claimed-to-cut-prices-but-didnt/l8005aeup</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s competition watchdog is suing supermarket chain Coles in the Federal Court. The ACCC alleges Coles deceived shoppers about discounts on a range of goods. It&amp;apos;s a case that could have wide-ranging implications for consumer law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f04aab88d64e1fb41869591235d5c403</guid></item><item><title>Australians sent back to Syrian camp holding suspected IS families after being released</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-released-from-syrias-roj-camp-of-is-affiliated-families/1rgyuwnlg</link><description>The women and children had been released from Roj camp in Syria for repatriation to Australia but were then forced to turn back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26322fb548e3176acc02e121375f569a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I want to taste everything&amp;apos;: Why millions of people make this annual pilgrimage</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lunar-new-year-2026-asian-australian-pilgrimage-to-asia/zvkose308</link><description>As many Asians living in Australia return to their ancestral homes for Lunar New Year, what awaits them can be surprising.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3ee4356f8a27e52978c2ac52cefcc3e</guid></item><item><title>Kath hosted her late partner Nigel&amp;apos;s wake while he was still alive</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/living-funerals-living-wakes-australia/9pst1yh9d</link><description>Living funerals are an emerging practice in Australia, allowing people to say goodbye to loved ones before they die.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fecd296f29f559aafdc724b93616899a</guid></item><item><title>The Godfather and Apocalypse Now star Robert Duvall dies aged 95</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/robert-duvall-dies-aged-95/yk6ca6al2</link><description>The Oscar-winning American actor died peacefully at his home after a career spanning more than six decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae79e9d53e5a5881942b0fe9a9cb9a66</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Very rare&amp;apos;: Israeli prosecutors to charge West Bank settler over killing of Palestinian activist</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-prosecutors-west-bank-settler-palestinian-activist-killing/gjsv4v806</link><description>The decision is an uncommon legal step amid mounting criticism over accountability for violence in the occupied territories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c918705833496bb27912438ce6db9d46</guid></item><item><title>Who are the Australians with alleged IS links seeking to return from a Syrian camp?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/who-are-the-australians-with-is-links-seeking-to-return-from-a-syrian-displacement-camp/kteqt8i8c</link><description>The government says it won&amp;apos;t help repatriate a group of Australian women and children with links to the self-proclaimed Islamic State group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d56243d1db928e888eafea40e2204ee1</guid></item><item><title>Protest restrictions eased in Sydney after nearly two months</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/protest-restrictions-eased-sydney-after-nearly-two-months/dxgzax77y</link><description>The restrictions were rushed through NSW parliament after the Bondi terror attack in December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f704a31ecfe8e3085c759370a6358abc</guid></item><item><title>The Year of the Horse welcomed around the world</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-year-of-the-horse-welcomed-around-the-world/3lq7ejito</link><description>The Lunar New Year has begun with vibrant celebrations welcoming the Year of the Horse, from fireworks in Vietnam and bustling Hong Kong markets to festive streets in Malaysia and Peru. Families gather for symbolic meals, travellers embrace cultural traditions, and global leaders send messages of unity, marking a holiday that connects communities across Asia and around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ba4953eddbb2b1db8473ffe2f3cc2b2</guid></item><item><title>How the tale of one possum reveals threats to thousands of Aussie species</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/how-the-tale-of-one-possum-reveals-threats-to-thousands-of-aussie-species/udv2e0mic</link><description>Australia’s unique wildlife is facing an escalating extinction crisis, driven primarily by climate change and compounded by habitat loss. 34 new species of plants and animals have been added to the government&amp;apos;s threatened species list this February, including the lemuroid ringtail possum - native to north Queensland&amp;apos;s Wet Tropics region. Researchers say urgent climate action and stronger environmental protections are critical to prevent further irreversible loss of Australia&amp;apos;s signature biodiversity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">722b1ba0b95aff16d1dbd79f09844c98</guid></item><item><title>Landmark study finds &amp;apos;systemic&amp;apos; racism in Australian universities</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-human-rights-commission-report-finds-racism-in-australian-universities/htf3u3rbi</link><description>The survey of more than 76,000 students and staff found Jewish and Palestinian students experienced the highest level of discrimination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5be2df23403b6745f15959e3e8b10fdf</guid></item><item><title>PM rules out repatriation for Australians with alleged IS links in Syria | SBS News In Easy English 17 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pm-rules-out-repatriation-for-australians-with-alleged-is-links-in-syria-sbs-news-in-easy-english-17-february-2026/bmscm041v</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da9a73967005936c2a608aaffb513308</guid></item><item><title>See the full list: Opposition leader Angus Taylor unveils fresh shadow ministry</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/opposition-leader-angus-taylor-unveils-fresh-shadow-ministry/411rnsatg</link><description>The Opposition has unveiled its shadow ministry, with a mix of new and old faces taking up frontbench positions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30c8a6673f858a86346eda8d60d5c4d6</guid></item><item><title>Do migrants feel they belong in Australia? The answer is complicated</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/do-new-migrants-feel-they-belong-to-australia-the-answer-is-complicated-study-shows/x8hre58vx</link><description>Interviews with migrants from Australia&amp;apos;s fastest growing communities show only 32 per cent feel a great sense of belonging.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a0880652b41e2492d333b9fd92a951b</guid></item><item><title>BHP CFO on copper growth opportunties, iron ore future and growing dividends</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/bhp-cfo-on-copper-growth-opportunties-iron-ore-future-and-growing-dividends/02zrgxnfj</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with BHP CFO Vandita Pant following the miner&amp;apos;s US$5.6bn half-year profit to find out more about its growing copper business and future dividend policy; plus Jonathan Shead from State Street Investment Management on the investment environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2824a48dbba0de5f40c6e4e216eaeaea</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;A true giant&amp;apos;: US civil rights leader Jesse Jackson dies aged 84</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-civil-rights-icon-jesse-jackson-dies-aged-84/z5haz42pi</link><description>Jesse Jackson cast himself as a barrier-breaker for people of colour, the impoverished and the powerless.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c7dadd06a3d2fae55656d367b47bb8e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;It was a no-brainer&amp;apos;: The baby boomer retirement myth being upended</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/no-brainer-why-more-young-people-like-zoe-are-rethinking-their-australian-dream/4mdmrz8w2</link><description>You might think it&amp;apos;s boomers and empty nesters moving to these parts of Australia, according to an expert. New data tells a different story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62fd14a4e7eefeaebde2c93bd0fd52d4</guid></item><item><title>Sabina quit snacking after monitoring her sugar levels. Is the data that simple?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/sabina-quit-snacking-when-she-started-monitoring-her-sugar-levels-but-is-the-data-that-simple/pbtwrxi7s</link><description>Continuous glucose monitors provide live data for blood sugar levels. But is access to this health data a good thing for non-diabetics?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9949b35d971804969c78494c20b22ba6</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor reveals new-look shadow cabinet | Morning News Bulletin 18 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/angus-taylor-reveals-new-look-shadow-cabinet-morning-news-bulletin-18-february-2026/1bbbxir8u</link><description>Liberal leader Angus Taylor unveils his new shadow frontbench; U-S civil rights leader Reverend Jesse Jackson dies in the US at the age of 84; Cronulla prop Addin Fonua-Blake sets his sights on the State of Origin series.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">065747a59e266deab2adb8e23c17457e</guid></item><item><title>Iran and US agree on &amp;apos;guiding principles&amp;apos; in nuclear talks, but deal far from imminent</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-iran-nuclear-talks-guiding-principles-agreed-but-deal-not-imminent/w5appewuv</link><description>Iran&amp;apos;s foreign minister said there was still much work to be done after talks with the US in Geneva ended.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a846c471efd8949b781a80658fbea682</guid></item><item><title>Government stands firm on not assisting or repatriating IS families in Syria</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/government-stands-firm-on-not-assisting-or-repatriating-is-families-in-syria/wpbepaasa</link><description>The last remaining Australian women and children with links to the IS Group have been sent back to a Syrian camp after attempting to repatriate themselves home. The group of 34 left al-Roj in the country&amp;apos;s northeast overnight - but a communications issue with Damascus forced their return to the camp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e9e14d59c3df3ef6949b17a1d9b7674</guid></item><item><title>Tilda Swinton, Javier Bardem and others criticise Berlin Film Festival&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;silence&amp;apos; on Gaza</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dozens-condemn-berlin-film-festival-silence-on-gaza/zojo9eirv</link><description>An open letter signed by film industry figures condemned the Berlin Film Festival&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;neutral stance&amp;quot; on Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc759321283e6cb70c28b7731efe316c</guid></item><item><title>Randa Abdel-Fattah to headline Sydney Writers&amp;apos; Festival in May</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/randa-abdel-fattah-sydney-writers-festival/bjn6v696b</link><description>The Palestinian Australian author has been announced as part of the line-up for the country&amp;apos;s largest literary festival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e8dc8a54b8d320c5a2a2f816fab574e</guid></item><item><title>Mayor responds to Hanson&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;unwelcoming&amp;apos; western Sydney suburb claim</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/aftab-malik-pauline-hanson-invitation-itfar-ramadan/rzxy7cjtx</link><description>It comes as Pauline Hanson faces a backlash over anti-Muslim remarks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb1c7ea938aff755aecf9427f05fb04b</guid></item><item><title>Concerns over direction of Australia&amp;apos;s immigration debate | Midday News Bulletin 18 Febuary 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/concerns-over-direction-of-australias-immigration-debate-midday-news-bulletin-18-febuary-2026/to0ybtsbt</link><description>Concerns over an immigration debate as the Liberals mull a new policy, Eleven killed in new US strikes on alleged drug smuggling boats, Australia to play Mexico in May ahead of the football World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47c93d562dda0b17dbab0535e30a9cd2</guid></item><item><title>&amp;quot;True giant&amp;quot;: Jesse Jackson, influential US civil rights leader, dies at age 84</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/true-giant-jesse-jackson-influential-us-civil-rights-leader-dies-at-age-84/2x7gkk6fo</link><description>Influential civil rights leader Reverend Jesse Jackson has died at the age of 84. Devoting six decades of his life to political and civil rights activism, Jesse Jackson is being remembered for his charisma and conviction till the very end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48755665f04d38da188096d9576266e6</guid></item><item><title>Man with shot gun arrested in Capitol Hill | SBS News in Easy English 18 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/man-with-shot-gun-arrested-in-capitol-hill-sbs-news-in-easy-english-18-february-2026/ksyu4ody4</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English Language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f849dc5eb6244900f98042f437307a52</guid></item><item><title>Government bans woman with alleged IS links from returning to Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/government-bans-woman-with-alleged-is-links-from-returning-to-australia/2tt852ezp</link><description>Human rights advocates say the move could render the Australian &amp;quot;stateless&amp;quot;, stressing the government&amp;apos;s duty under international law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba7219fc6a23c8927aaaa3908ee5b737</guid></item><item><title>Pauline Hanson offers partial apology for anti-Muslim remarks | Evening News Bulletin 18 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pauline-hanson-offers-partial-apology-for-anti-muslim-remarks-evening-news-bulletin-18-february-2026/fx69e9uyq</link><description>Pauline Hanson offers a partial apology for her anti-Muslim remarks, Wages not keeping pace with Australia&amp;apos;s inflation rate, And in AFL, Hawthorn has confirmed it has re-signed Josh Weddle to a four-year contract.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab997f422e62b34dea99db68745059e8</guid></item><item><title>No, not even water: A guide to Ramadan for non-Muslims</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ramadan-guide-for-non-muslims/54526knpd</link><description>Wonder what Ramadan is all about? Here&amp;apos;s why many Muslims fast during the holy month, and how to best support your practising friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">008bc76385c6c58b7e095e90dbcc82a6</guid></item><item><title>No, not even water: A guide to Ramadan for non-Muslims</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/no-not-even-water-a-guide-to-ramadan-for-non-muslims/tnccci4jz</link><description>Wonder what Ramadan is all about? Here&amp;apos;s why many Muslims fast during the holy month, and how to best support your practising friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ea3cf88301b12b1bfbbbb35758ee3ad</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine, Russia peace talks begin</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ukraine-russia-peace-talks-begin/xnc2au9ga</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c92ccbf4259dcff57ad8a49d6b3548b</guid></item><item><title>Muslim leaders&amp;apos; three requests as Australia&amp;apos;s largest mosque receives new threatening letter</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ramadan-islamophobia-concerns-australia-lakemba-mosque/pacrzf7gp</link><description>It comes amid unease and safety concerns in Muslim communities across the country ahead of Ramadan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df5d22a74566b2b2d3754aab27911afa</guid></item><item><title>Racism revealed to be widespread and systemic in Australian universities</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/racism-revealed-to-be-widespread-and-systemic-in-australian-universities/fwtgzu973</link><description>The first national report on racism at universities in Australia has found it is a problem that is widespread and systemic. The report found 70 per cent of students and staff from 42 universities had witnessed racism. Levels of racism were higher among Indigenous, Chinese, African, Jewish and Middle Eastern students and staff; with only six per cent of those who experienced racism making a complaint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">102a45d8a073aa7a6d8fcded2bf39b88</guid></item><item><title>Inflation eats into wages as cost of living worsens</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/inflation-eats-into-wages-as-cost-of-living-worsens/wwh0xx8vk</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Devika Shivadear from RSM Australia about the latest Wage Price Index which shows real wages has gone backwards; plus a look at the day on the sharemarket with Jun Bei Lui from Ten Cap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8cf63144fa527125134c8d48ec0ae0c</guid></item><item><title>Pauline Hanson faces storm over anti-Muslim comments</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pauline-hanson-faces-storm-over-anti-muslim-comments/dk1qkv6cw</link><description>One Nation leader Pauline Hanson has partially walked back anti-Muslim comments she made earlier this week, but has refused to offer a full apology. The backlash against Senator Hanson&amp;apos;s comments continues from all sides of politics, with Labor and Coalition politicians condemning the remarks. Australia&amp;apos;s Islamophobia envoy has invited Senator Hanson to an Iftar dinner during the holy month of Ramadan, where he encourages her to ask questions directly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2eda9cc7305ee2e9d5ff401dc084d21</guid></item><item><title>NSW Parliament tackles &amp;apos;a deeply concerning convergence of extremism&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nsw-parliament-tackles-a-deeply-concerning-convergence-of-extremism/k9dt4gnbt</link><description>Religious leaders and academic experts have faced a New South Wales parliamentary inquiry into a proposed law to combat right wing extremism. This, as the state government introduced the crime amendment bill following a neo-nazi protest outside state Parliament in November last year. The Law and Safety committee have been investigating the risks posed by certain groups, and are looking into the best ways to counter it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0f0ca9bb330b122ddc1f802598e4493</guid></item><item><title>The road toll is rising; &amp;apos;we need to do more of everything&amp;apos; say the safety experts</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-road-toll-is-rising-we-need-to-do-more-of-everything-say-the-safety-experts/fp7c4egx1</link><description>Australia’s road toll is rising, and new warnings suggest the country is drifting away from its goal of halving deaths by 2030. More than thirteen hundred people were killed on Australian roads last year, with early 2026 figures showing little sign of improvement. Industry leaders and victim advocates are calling for urgent action, from safer street design to changes in driver behaviour, as families continue to live with the consequences of road trauma every day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">372c1c8217064f68dfe105d667d912e9</guid></item><item><title>What we know so far about the abduction and search for Nancy Guthrie</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nancy-guthrie-disappearance-search-latest/o300vluwt</link><description>From eerie doorbell footage to a DNA setback, here&amp;apos;s how the Nancy Guthrie abduction has unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd3233f47a7276db6de24d1ac05e6fb5</guid></item><item><title>What makes people proud to be Australian? The answer might surprise you</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-national-pride-pew-report/0nv0le4l0</link><description>These are the factors that influence Australians&amp;apos; sense of pride in their country — and those that don&amp;apos;t, according to a new report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eed3ed5fe8f7c27b6189a11768778941</guid></item><item><title>I became paralysed and almost died doing an extreme sport. I don&amp;apos;t regret any of it</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/a-motocross-accident-left-me-paralysed-unfazed-i-turned-to-another-extreme-sport/9k2fcimtf</link><description>After an accident in 2018 left Christina Vithoulkas paralysed from the chest down, she became Australia&amp;apos;s first female para-drifter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3f5b943561888a4cbef93d2b7a7a078</guid></item><item><title>A woman is banned from returning to Australia from Syria | Morning News Bulletin 19 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-woman-is-banned-from-returning-to-australia-from-syria-morning-news-bulletin-19-february-2026/2bp1olc5t</link><description>The federal government bans a woman with alleged links to the IS group from returning to Australia; Ukrainian President Zelenskyy says limited progress made in Geneva peace talks; And in sport, a silver medal for Australia in the women&amp;apos;s aerials at the Milano-Cortina Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">daf0402a1c218970ce4bbc2d2a53f495</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Means everything&amp;apos;: Australian Danielle Scott claims aerial skiing silver at the Olympics</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/aussie-danielle-scott-claims-aerial-skiing-silver-at-the-olympics/gmb3ohoav</link><description>Freestyle skier Danielle Scott is officially an Olympic medallist, breaking through to win silver in the aerials in her fourth Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2117ad285a4427987359e3f96bdfbf2c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Means everything&amp;apos;: Australian Danielle Scott claims aerial skiing silver at the Olympics</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-danielle-scott-claims-aerial-skiing-silver-at-the-olympics/gmb3ohoav</link><description>Freestyle skier Danielle Scott is officially an Olympic medallist, breaking through to win silver in the aerials in her fourth Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edd808832cf6c806fdb57e97bded519e</guid></item><item><title>The super mistake that could cost you more than $120,000 at retirement</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-not-checking-your-super-could-cost-you-over-120-000-at-retirement/pnthrysuz</link><description>One in four Australians couldn&amp;apos;t answer a key question about their super, a new survey found, prompting a warning from a peak body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c2cbb25ea15d4fc5be17bfee32b7415</guid></item><item><title>Eight skiers found dead after California avalanche, one still missing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/california-avalanche-skiers-found-dead/q7villp8m</link><description>Rescuers had earlier reached six survivors in &amp;quot;extreme&amp;quot; conditions near Lake Tahoe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72c5ca3a4fa51756bcac700262330541</guid></item><item><title>How Palestinians in Gaza are marking their first Ramadan since fragile truce took hold</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/first-ramadan-after-israel-truce-gaza/gf29g2o4e</link><description>Amid the devastation, some in Gaza City are working to revive Ramadan festivities as Palestinian Muslims celebrate the holy month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c4961f773fd6e01153ce818fa021e04</guid></item><item><title>Local dog goes for gold as he gatecrashes Olympic sprint</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dog-winter-olympics/llc8znnnb</link><description>The unexpected competitor, a &amp;quot;stubborn, but very sweet&amp;quot; resident of a nearby bed-and-breakfast, joined skiers down the home stretch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8d82bece2ee1785100b99c7809eab33</guid></item><item><title>Zuckerberg on the stand: Why this new social media trial could be a turning point</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/mark-zuckerberg-on-the-stand-why-this-new-social-media-trial-can-be-a-turning-point/te9xkchob</link><description>It&amp;apos;s the first time Mark Zuckerberg has addressed child safety on his platforms before a jury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2184b06c5ed621e76c003020623d848</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s debt levels at their highest since the WWII | Midday News Bulletin 19 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australias-debt-levels-at-their-highest-since-the-wwi-midday-news-bulletin-19-february-2026/hxb71iib8</link><description>A new report showing Australia&amp;apos;s debt levels at their highest since the Second World War, Regret from Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg over Instagram&amp;apos;s slow progress in detecting underage users, An upset for Arsenal in the Premier League.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d32ea9e217d73343e6dcd3f340c6fff</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Outrageous decision&amp;apos;: Why are Ukrainian officials boycotting the Paralympics?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ukraine-officials-boycott-russia-competing-in-paralympics/ri4di1uft</link><description>Paralympians from Russia and Belarus have been given the green light to compete — and not as neutral individuals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba50d0ec60fa8cc4d3315a1ffa2193e3</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Need to do more of everything&amp;apos;: Australia&amp;apos;s 2030 goal that&amp;apos;s at risk</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australias-2030-goal-thats-at-risk/i1kn803tk</link><description>The figures are heading in the wrong direction — but some believe simple changes could make a difference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7305d7db5413037867e238b7819dc3b2</guid></item><item><title>Eight skiers die California avalanche |SBS News in Easy English 19 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/eight-skiers-die-california-avalanche-sbs-news-in-easy-english-19-february-2026/9hywmdxd9</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28f9ca11622df7f0d0a45d4b55e7c3bb</guid></item><item><title>Criticism over passports issued to IS linked women and children | Evening News Bulletin 19 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/opposition-criticises-passports-issued-to-women-and-children-with-links-to-i-s-fighters-evening-news-bulletin-19-february-2026/mklahwopa</link><description>The Federal Opposition says passports should not have been issued to women and children with links to IS fighters, Australia&amp;apos;s unemployment rate remains stable, Mary Fowler named in the Matildas squad for next month&amp;apos;s Asian Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">470602fc142b302d604cedc7910f29a5</guid></item><item><title>Is Australia facing an economic reality not seen since World War Two?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-government-debt-analysis/b7ibrbt13</link><description>As debt climbs, some economists warn Australia may face difficult choices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06199b7b66ecd598be892af76a920d60</guid></item><item><title>Latest labour data increases chance of a rate rise, experts warn</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/labour-data-rate-rise-rba/if516z32w</link><description>A historically strong jobs market has raised the chances of another rate rise in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2d56251cd2d54094dad9985d944d963</guid></item><item><title>Is the US approach to Europe softening? Israel moves in the West Bank and, well, cocaine sharks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/is-the-us-approach-to-europe-softening-israel-moves-in-the-west-bank-and-well-cocaine-sharks/eedp75dnt</link><description>Marco Rubio sends mixed messages to Europe, Israel starts registration of large areas of the occupied West Bank and how new is Bangladesh’s new government? Plus, Chinoys celebrate lunar new year in the Philippines and Cocaine Sharks coming to waters near you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eedbad5d2a38d20b772a580700fdb5a9</guid></item><item><title>Muslim faithful mark the start of Ramadan in Australia and around the world</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/muslim-faithful-mark-the-start-of-ramadan-in-australia-and-around-the-world/9pqy6rkv9</link><description>The holy month of Ramadan is underway, with Muslims around the world marking Iftar - the first day of the fasting period. In Australia, venues are catering to the growing number of observers, opening their doors until long after sunset and into the early hours of the morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99da299f262385d2c6b17980878b9220</guid></item><item><title>Government blocks return of Australian woman from Syrian refugee camp for IS Group families</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/government-blocks-return-of-australian-woman-from-syrian-refugee-camp-for-is-group-families/ajfnnky6u</link><description>Home Affairs Minister Tony Burke has blocked the immediate return of an Australian woman from Syria via a temporary exclusion order. It follows what the government is calling its no assistance policy for 34 citizens recently turned back by Syrian authorities. While the Prime Minister insists those who joined the IS Group must live with their choices, legal and human rights experts argue that abandoning children and coerced women in detention camps poses a greater long-term radicalisation risk than bringing them home to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3c7d83f825ac86c4f3bcad4447fa48a</guid></item><item><title>Jobless rate stays at 4.1% and ASX hits another record</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/jobless-rate-stays-at-4-1-and-asx-hits-another-record/novh8uo7s</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Hugh Lam, CFA from Betashares for his take on the markets as the ASX200 hits another record high, the jobless rate remains at 4.1% and takes a look at the latest company profit reports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7f72580089b8a17545290d15b3f2f46</guid></item><item><title>They&amp;apos;re &amp;apos;devastated&amp;apos;: Fresh plea for Australian children in Syrian detention camps</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fresh-plea-for-australian-children-in-syrian-detention-camps/qb9z6g3xw</link><description>Child welfare advocates are calling for the return of Australians from a detention camp in Syria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6de4d7e72a9be526b4f3ca30a9a13cc1</guid></item><item><title>Calls for major change after deadly mental health escapes in Sydney</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/calls-for-major-change-after-deadly-mental-health-escapes-in-sydney/ta8d6md7r</link><description>A WARNING THAT THIS STORY MAY BE DISTRESSING FOR SOME LISTENERS The New South Wales government is investigating the circumstances surrounding the escape of two patients from the same hospital, who days later were allegedly involved in separate incidents where three people died. Mental health professionals say it&amp;apos;s again thrown the state&amp;apos;s mental health care crisis into the spotlight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94250522597c5c31ef86bfbb52a828e3</guid></item><item><title>Former prince Andrew released from police custody after arrest</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/prince-andrew-arrest/zo7uja2z5</link><description>King Charles has responded. Here&amp;apos;s what we know so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">846210384241532e281af1c8e8146305</guid></item><item><title>See the full list: Private insurer price hikes — and how to save cash</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/private-health-price-hikes-list/4y8b9j6s8</link><description>The 4.41 per cent increase announced this week is an industry average, and some insurers will raise premiums by more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f65163aacd735aac03c65c61161e7e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Canary in the coal mine&amp;apos;: The possum on the frontline of Australia&amp;apos;s extinction crisis</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/possum-threatened-species-australia/mar3m3qe5</link><description>The lemuroid ringtail possum is one of 34 species that have just been added to Australia&amp;apos;s threatened species list.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">419030bdf41553d86ad5248dc27e49c8</guid></item><item><title>Police arrest the King&amp;apos;s brother, Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor | Morning News Bulletin 20 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/police-arrest-the-kings-brother-andrew-mountbatten-windsor-morning-news-bulletin-20-february-2026/5o7avdbex</link><description>Police arrest the King&amp;apos;s brother, Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor; Man charged in Sydney with possessing violent extremist material; And in football, Postecoglou rules out return to managing Celtic.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfd24b424deee272050be992e2e5655f</guid></item><item><title>Trump&amp;apos;s Board of Peace flags billions in Gaza aid, as he gives Iran 10-day threat</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-launches-board-of-peace-with-gaza-aid-promise/p22ck786f</link><description>The first meeting of Trump&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;Board of Peace&amp;apos; has heard pledges of cash and troops to rebuild Gaza and maintain order there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6af8be042223fac434557ea3f30bc67</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Hallmarks of genocide&amp;apos; found in Sudan, UN says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sudan-civil-war-genocide-united-nations/9ci878kco</link><description>A UN fact-finding mission concluded that the RSF paramilitary group had acted &amp;quot;with genocidal intent&amp;quot; during the seizure of Al-Fasher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e1b4ca051ed27b50ee05ddef3b60928</guid></item><item><title>Monarchists, anti-monarchists and prime minister react to former prince Andrew&amp;apos;s arrest</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/world-reacts-to-former-prince-andrews-arrest/rcgv754de</link><description>Australia and the world have been quick to react to the news of former prince Andrew&amp;apos;s arrest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b79e65029b44cae2cc97144c5da96a6</guid></item><item><title>Former Prince Andrew released after arrest | Midday News Bulletin 20 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/former-prince-andrew-released-after-arrest-midday-news-bulletin-20-february-2026/ks1ea3ck0</link><description>In this bulletin, Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor released after 12 hours in police custody, Donald Trump gives Iran 10 days to reach a deal, threatening more strikes And in sport, Australia&amp;apos;s Indra Brown scores a place at the Milano Cortina Olympic halfpipe finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adb4050ccc3eb079bcbc5d13daa3a31a</guid></item><item><title>How former prince Andrew went from pilot to fallen figure</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/prince-andrew-arrested-after-decades-controversies-epstein/9okjjpkjc</link><description>Former prince Andrew has left the police station after 10 hours of questioning by UK Police for alleged misconduct in public office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c7dbdc38ac27aea868883da9adb3335</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 20 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-20-february-2026/7a0chyaxj</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38c904a9171b7a08a6f889f720a2501e</guid></item><item><title>Former Prince Andrew becomes first senior British royal to be arrested in almost 400 years</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/former-prince-andrew-becomes-first-senior-british-royal-to-be-arrested-in-almost-400-years/lqevb0t3d</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor has become the first senior British royal in modern times to be arrested. The 66-year-old was arrested by police on suspicion of misconduct in public office, after it was alleged he sent confidential government documents to late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0221416d437bc113041c3827145c424a</guid></item><item><title>Trump&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;Board of Peace&amp;apos; flags billions in Gaza aid, US issues fresh threats against Iran</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trumps-board-of-peace-flags-billions-in-gaza-aid-us-issues-fresh-threats-against-iran/61ija714i</link><description>United States President Donald Trump has held the inaugural meeting of his so-called &amp;quot;Board of Peace&amp;quot;, pledging AU$14.2 billion for the reconstruction of Gaza. Boasting his role as a peacemaker while leveling fresh threats against Iran, Donald Trump says the board will help achieve peace in the Middle East.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f393c32b05fef7a8e3c624c14447a91d</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Extremely interesting&amp;apos;: Trump says he&amp;apos;ll release files on aliens and UFOs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-announces-hell-release-files-on-aliens-and-ufos-after-obama-comments/bmdifsivy</link><description>The decision comes following Barack Obama&amp;apos;s comment that aliens &amp;quot;are real&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a2ca6b435b0ae7629751f28d9703320</guid></item><item><title>Two mental health facility escapes ended in tragedy. Now, a push for &amp;apos;urgent&amp;apos; change</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/calls-for-major-change-after-deadly-mental-health-escapes-in-sydney/yjzdwp98q</link><description>Two men escaped the nation&amp;apos;s largest mental health facility and were allegedly involved in separate incidents killing three people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c95e47a403357456d72ce3a8bcfd89f</guid></item><item><title>Australian Federal Police says reports of crime received over Pauline Hanson&amp;apos;s remarks on Muslims</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australian-federal-police-says-reports-of-crime-received-over-pauline-hansons-remarks-on-muslims/gu8yllg4m</link><description>The fallout continues after One Nation leader Pauline Hanson suggested earlier this week that there are no &amp;quot;good&amp;quot; Muslims. The Australian Federal Police says it has received reports of a crime in relation to comments made by Ms Hanson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8af3d4854dd2454e826f3cfc83a7b91c</guid></item><item><title>UN says siege at el-Fasher shows evidence of genocide</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/un-says-siege-at-el-fasher-shows-evidence-of-genocide/dn8pk0jel</link><description>A United Nations fact-finding mission in Sudan has found the 18-month long siege and subsequent capture of El-Fasher in the Darfur region, last October, bears evidence of genocide. The United States, in response, has imposed sanctions on paramilitary commanders. But experts are calling for far stronger global response, to stop the violence from continuing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67b44c87ccd5592d6997297d773fd5d8</guid></item><item><title>Virginia Giuffre&amp;apos;s family welcomes royal arrest | Evening News Bulletin 20 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/virginia-giuffres-family-welcomes-royal-arrest-evening-news-bulletin-20-february-2026/rf4xu1cdr</link><description>In this bulletin, Virginia Giuffre&amp;apos;s family reacts to Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor&amp;apos;s arrest, an appeal court increases the sentence of a man convicted over a fatal hit-and-run-crash in Darwin. And in AFL, a growing injury toll for the Greater Western Sydney Giants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d47fdc6641dae8a778a78fa902f859e</guid></item><item><title>NT hit-and-run driver avoids jail again after prosecutors appeal &amp;apos;inadequate&amp;apos; sentence</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nt-hit-and-run-driver-avoids-jail-again-after-prosecutors-appeal-inadequate-sentence/mtgb0de4d</link><description>A five-month home detention term for a fatal hit-and-run driver has been overturned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14d930b8c32078d5df3a78598b3795c2</guid></item><item><title>US goods deficit widens despite tariffs and market reacts to QBE and Rio results</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-goods-deficit-widens-despite-tariffs-and-market-reacts-to-qbe-and-rio-results/hw7rv3gfm</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Marcus Bogdan from Blackmore Capital on the day&amp;apos;s market action, including a wrap of the major profits and a look at the latest US trade figures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">580e857a3f35ad08877c8838004e7915</guid></item><item><title>Dreams of being a ballerina: Hopes of Australian child in Syrian camp for IS-linked families</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/dreams-of-being-a-ballerina-hopes-of-australian-child-in-syrian-camp-for-is-linked-families/cirb1lqi9</link><description>An Australian child in a camp for families with links to IS fighters says she wants to come to Australia, a family member told SBS.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39a2a8627a39f3a12dbf41b107665041</guid></item><item><title>Is there a &amp;apos;sweet spot&amp;apos;? These five charts are key to the migration debate</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/migration-sweet-spot-these-five-charts-are-key-to-the-migration-debate/69sydxzau</link><description>The government&amp;apos;s opponents have fuelled debate over Australia&amp;apos;s migration numbers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">497fbfd7c4bac40ce6fd64181e9e7f19</guid></item><item><title>US Supreme Court strikes down Trump tariffs | Morning News Bulletin 21 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-supreme-court-strikes-down-trump-tariffs-morning-news-bulletin-21-february-2026/ya2pxqtrb</link><description>The US Supreme Court strikes down Donald Trump&amp;apos;s global tariffs, Federal Police say they&amp;apos;ve received reports of a crime after Pauline Hanson&amp;apos;s anti-Muslim comments, Clayton Oliver impresses the GWS Giants in his first match with the club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adc4e5b8bddfbcf9bdb4ff3ae122539a</guid></item><item><title>Cafes and restaurants are closing in record numbers. This couple is bucking the trend</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/cafes-and-restaurants-are-closing-in-record-numbers-this-couple-is-bucking-the-trend/idmdixlzv</link><description>Australian restaurants and cafes are in crisis, according to a new report. Rising costs and falling revenue have forced one in ten food service outlets to close over the past year. However, one Australian couple has found ways to survive and thrive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a756f557c58c219c62ff4af75d746bf0</guid></item><item><title>It scares me all the time&amp;apos;: Exploring new ways to improve water safety</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/it-scares-me-all-the-time-exploring-new-ways-to-improve-water-safety/tv4tmgse9</link><description>Australian and Indian drowning prevention experts have come together for a two-day workshop to explore new ways to reduce drowning deaths in both countries. Drowning causes tens of thousands of deaths a year in India, and in Australia, experts say the Indian diaspora is among groups that are worryingly over-represented in the country&amp;apos;s drowning fatalities. Through exchanging ideas and building stronger cultural knowledge, workshop participants have explored new, sustainable ways to improve water safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f549fe883614f2768571cddb913e4298</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump imposes 10 per cent global levy after US Supreme Court strikes down tariffs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-supreme-court-donald-trump-tariffs/7utfupgbg</link><description>The US president has announced a 10 per cent global tariff for 150 days under a different legal authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e4e468b955e1aaaa2658dbfc50edc71</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: New project explores power of language and shared histories</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-new-project-explores-power-of-language-and-shared-histories/1049wei0n</link><description>The Acknowledgement of Country has been translated into 40 languages as part of a project led by Dr Elaine Laforteza. She explains how it started and the vision for what comes next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5753be9e2251151328da43f539855b9d</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: How students are combating racism at Australian universities</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-how-students-are-combating-racism-at-australian-universities/k7nspp61k</link><description>The University of Melbourne Student Union is preparing to release the findings of its fourth report on racism on campus. The union&amp;apos;s president, Lushy Chinganya, explains what it found and how it connects with the latest Human Rights Commission report on the same issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c5f20cdcd4f55b023a69a7b832ab919</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We nearly gave up&amp;apos;: These pizza chefs bought their first home. It hasn&amp;apos;t been easy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/we-nearly-gave-up-these-pizza-chefs-bought-their-first-home-it-hasnt-been-easy/ksabcq74o</link><description>Australian restaurants and cafes are in crisis, according to a new report. One Melbourne couple has found ways to survive and thrive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ecdd8b9f5ae06d381bd74defdd7d84d</guid></item><item><title>Trump reinstates 10 per cent global tariffs | Midday News Bulletin 21 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trump-reinstates-10-per-cent-global-tariffs-midday-news-bulletin-21-february-2026/12nz08yfd</link><description>Donald Trump signs new order to reinstate global 10 per cent tariffs after Supreme Court ruled earlier tariffs illegal, More arrests over the Sydney shooting of former NRL star, Australia finishes a disappointing T20 campaign with a bang.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d43abfc04f8cd0d67ed9019dfe1affb</guid></item><item><title>Daylight upon the magic: How former prince Andrew&amp;apos;s arrest could impact the royal family</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/daylight-on-the-magic-how-former-prince-andrews-arrest-can-impact-the-royal-family/chs8quqrz</link><description>The last time a British royal was arrested, it led to the fall of the crown. Could it happen again?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d74a4ba28cf2fe646313cecb9f3b6318</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Attack on all of us&amp;apos;: Jewish leader condemns alleged Brisbane synagogue ramming</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/man-charged-with-hate-crime-over-alleged-brisbane-synagogue-ramming/dluo4w8v1</link><description>It comes after a man allegedly rammed the gates of a Brisbane synagogue with his ute on Friday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2366c8ee482c18330e7af3c6ac3c95b</guid></item><item><title>Major synagogue attacked in Brisbane | Evening News Bulletin 21 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/major-synagogue-attacked-in-brisbane-evening-news-bulletin-21-february-2026/xwvtirf6t</link><description>A car rams into the gates of a major Brisbane synagogue; The US carries out another deadly raid on an alleged drug boat; Matilda&amp;apos;s goalkeeper Teagan Micah forced to withdraw from Australia&amp;apos;s Asian Cup side.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4fd06c9f7054fd29bc7f84f3a681acb</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Green light to violence&amp;apos;: Anti-racism commissioner denounces Hanson&amp;apos;s remarks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/race-discrimination-commissioner-condemns-pauline-hansons-remarks-on-muslims/a49gig1xd</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s race discrimination commissioner says he was deeply concerned by Hanson&amp;apos;s comments that there were &amp;quot;no good Muslims&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1475292907d0c7e36c7afb6e66761c2</guid></item><item><title>Anna dePeyster, former wife of media mogul Rupert Murdoch, dies aged 81</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anne-de-peyster-former-wife-of-media-mogul-rupert-murdoch-dies-aged-81/aetmewc79</link><description>Anna dePeyster, who served on the News Corporation board, was married to Rupert Murdoch for more than 30 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e60b3d02601aa6823e47d8639f9d9829</guid></item><item><title>Anna dePeyster, former wife of media mogul Rupert Murdoch, dies aged 81</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anna-de-peyster-former-wife-of-media-mogul-rupert-murdoch-dies-aged-81/aetmewc79</link><description>Anna dePeyster, who served on the News Corporation board, was married to Rupert Murdoch for more than 30 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b9b18353326789eab3c95086d906366</guid></item></channel></rss>