<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>SBS English News (Unofficial Aggregation)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Feb 2026 23:20:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Iran has its &amp;apos;finger on the trigger&amp;apos;. But is it at its &amp;apos;weakest&amp;apos; as US tensions soar?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/iran-us-tensions-regime-weakness-military-threats/kxciuuyla</link><description>Tensions between the US and Iran are increasing, while reports indicate that the US is bolstering its military presence in the region.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0708af7bdc4eb4f9416eaff2974444a</guid></item><item><title>Could a bubble be about to burst? What to know as gold and silver prices surge</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gold-and-silver-investing-explained/b5mtxf4nf</link><description>As prices soar amid global uncertainty, experts weigh in on whether the rally will last.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b9e4031602e8d287bad46cf108dde2d</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Immensely harmful&amp;apos;: Greenlandic mayor issues warning after US flag stunt</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/greenland-mayor-warning-us-flag-nuuk/7qwriuc1c</link><description>The official, whose district includes the capital, said the people of Greenland were already worried and afraid amid recent developments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">250de36e556015ee7c678875ab49363a</guid></item><item><title>Trump claims Putin will halt strikes for one week as Ukraine faces extreme cold</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-says-putin-will-halt-strikes-on-kyiv-for-one-week-amid-freezing-temperatures/ppq0bbuis</link><description>Ukraine&amp;apos;s state weather agency has forecast a drastic dip in temperatures to as low as minus 30C in coming days</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9750e8278df3ea4341e345b844f95882</guid></item><item><title>Nearly 50C: More temperature records smashed as &amp;apos;heat dome&amp;apos; persists</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/heatwave-australia-temperatures/6zd0omzpq</link><description>Australia claimed all of the top 15 hottest spots in the world over the 24 hours to 8am on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be9f87cb49fefc640dbaca932c6a8c80</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Americans will be &amp;apos;safe&amp;apos; in Venezuela as he opens up travel route</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-orders-reopening-of-us-venezuela-airspace-after-years-of-flight-bans/2v6uu75ks</link><description>The airspace decision reflects broader efforts by the Trump administration to restore diplomatic engagement with Venezuela.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f01a3f5acb7b641f9d97dc67cc576b48</guid></item><item><title>EU designates Iran&amp;apos;s Revolutionary Guard Corps as terrorist organisation</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/eu-designates-irans-revolutionary-guard-corps-as-terrorist-organisation/ryw8fpw10</link><description>The EU has formally designated Iran’s Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps a terrorist organisation, aligning it with groups such as Islamic State and al-Qaida. Tensions between Tehran and Washington are escalating amid one of the deadliest protest crackdowns in Iran’s recent history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f12be94ae18051b8caf2b1b4e00ef28a</guid></item><item><title>Older Australians waiting longer to access home support services | SBS News In Easy English 30 January 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/older-australians-waiting-longer-to-access-home-support-services-sbs-news-in-easy-english-30-january-2026/h55f369r1</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3cb607271fbc498532e0e35b83744ab</guid></item><item><title>Drowning victims&amp;apos; families &amp;apos;in shock&amp;apos; but grateful after $150k raised in support</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/community-shows-support-after-nsw-river-tragedy/07f7v62mx</link><description>Over $150,000 has been raised to support the families of two men who drowned in NSW, as their communities grapple with loss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a793dcdf7466e07bc99275948fd66def</guid></item><item><title>Hastie says he won&amp;apos;t challenge for leadership as Ley gives Nationals one-week ultimatum</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hastie-says-he-wont-challenge-for-leadership-as-ley-gives-nationals-one-week-ultimatum/j3ageb006</link><description>One of Liberal Party leader Sussan Ley&amp;apos;s potential challengers has ducked out of the running, saying he doesn&amp;apos;t have enough support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83fb101816f98f6050fe1d1327738953</guid></item><item><title>Hastie says he won&amp;apos;t challenge for leadership as Ley gives Nationals one-week ultimatum</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hastie-says-he-wont-challenge-for-leadership-after-ley-gives-nationals-one-week-ultimatum/j3ageb006</link><description>One of Liberal Party leader Sussan Ley&amp;apos;s potential challengers has ducked out of the running, saying he doesn&amp;apos;t have enough support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ffaf0d4c734834640b1429372ea371e</guid></item><item><title>Is it too late to fix your mortgage interest rate? &amp;amp; Trump ready to announce Fed Chair pick</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/is-it-too-late-to-fix-your-mortgage-interest-rate-trump-ready-to-announce-fed-chair-pick/l5yu505me</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Canstar&amp;apos;s Sally Tindall to find out if it is too late to fix your home loan interest rate ahead of what&amp;apos;s expected to be a rise in official interest rates next week; plus Dianne Colledge from Morgans goes through the day&amp;apos;s share market action including a preview of Donald Trump&amp;apos;s pick of US Federal Reserve governor which is expected to be made at the weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13db2a889e97c472daa42080df4ed55d</guid></item><item><title>Leader in dementia research shares four ways you can reduce your risk</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/leader-in-dementia-research-shares-four-ways-you-can-reduce-your-risk/z65n663g7</link><description>Henry Brodaty is a world-recognised dementia researcher. Here, he shares ways you can seek to reduce your risk of developing the disease.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0df4b06a0cdf3b4e5976d145813d4604</guid></item><item><title>First cohort of migrants under Tuvalu deal arrive in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/first-cohort-of-migrants-under-tuvulu-deal-arrive-in-australia/f7r88618d</link><description>The Falepili Union treaty between Australia and Tuvalu was hailed as a global first-of-its kind, with one provision of the agreement allowing up to 280 Tuvaluans to relocate to Australia each year as rising seas threaten their homeland. The first cohort of migrants under the deal are now arriving in Australia. But with just a small Tuvaluan diaspora here, they&amp;apos;re facing a challenge to settle in to their new home, while maintaining a connection to community and culture.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef5dd1fe4b64674b58e1d10ce7339b3a</guid></item><item><title>Australian beef farmers scramble to find new markets as a billion-dollar export hit looms</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australian-beef-farmers-scramble-to-find-new-markets-as-a-billion-dollar-export-hit-looms/vhw14vxqb</link><description>New tariffs on Australian beef may cut exports to China by 30 per cent cut this year, according to industry experts. Among those affected is a fifth-generation cattle farmer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84ae6ff2324d446cca698a42e4cb9121</guid></item><item><title>Fresh Epstein files reference Trump, Gates, Musk, former prince Andrew and Lutnick</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-justice-department-releases-millions-of-new-epstein-files/0uovgs6m4</link><description>The latest cache related to the late convicted sex offender includes more than three million pages, 180,000 images and 2,000 videos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f037408c91b08979502910690a3b5aa</guid></item><item><title>Israel announces Gaza&amp;apos;s Rafah border crossing with Egypt to reopen</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-announces-rafah-border-crossing-into-gaza-to-reopen/z6d3fixwa</link><description>Reopening of the crossing was one of the requirements under a US-brokered ceasefire agreed in October between Israel and Hamas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5deb17a5cb54e03a9109018e73fe0af7</guid></item><item><title>The $1 billion problem facing Aussie farmers like Robert</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/the-1-billion-problem-facing-aussie-farmers-like-robert/kuobylh9v</link><description>A fifth-generation NSW farmer is among those &amp;apos;shocked and disappointed&amp;apos; over new China tariffs on Australian beef.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304031faf4dc1f5b3f529c29168f37e8</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Protect every solitary moment&amp;apos;: The viral app that asks users if they&amp;apos;re still alive</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/protect-every-solitary-moment-the-viral-app-that-asks-users-if-theyre-still-alive/ldab9huwu</link><description>A popular Chinese app aims to address the issue of &amp;apos;empty nesters&amp;apos; who die and are only found days, weeks, or even months later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2075188bbce3dcefc6a0f686872c00d2</guid></item><item><title>Thousands applied for this world-first visa. Now the first have arrived in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/first-tuvaluans-arrive-in-australia-under-the-new-falepili-treaty/fzy0g06j7</link><description>Nearly 300 Tuvaluans can relocate to Australia each year under a new treaty, which was partially designed to assist those affected by climate change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a63b7c4a187c18f8b5060d51a0df6acd</guid></item><item><title>Big, thirsty, and &amp;apos;willing to do anything&amp;apos; for water: Australia&amp;apos;s camel chaos</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/big-thirsty-and-willing-to-do-anything-for-water-australias-camel-chaos/z2m228vl8</link><description>A joint task force has been set up in central Australia to manage feral camels wrecking &amp;apos;havoc&amp;apos; in remote communities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7600c50a9d0862a0c3bc2faf066ca1a6</guid></item><item><title>Working no longer &amp;apos;number one&amp;apos;: How this country is trying to break its overwork habit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/japan-work-culture-sanae-takaichi/1a9ts1qxt</link><description>While working hours have fallen and reforms are in place, Japan is still wrestling with a deep-rooted culture of overwork.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b88fdee5e67bd64e40e864e1274df77</guid></item><item><title>Exhibition described as a milestone for inclusion and representation</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/exhibition-described-as-a-milestone-for-inclusion-and-representation/sf6aazuh0</link><description>A powerful exhibition featuring photographs and stories of Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander people with disability has been called a milestone for inclusion and representation. First exhibited at the United Nations in Geneva more than a decade ago, it&amp;apos;s now being shown again on home soil in its most accessible format.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab324c1e591e9510d1ebf88581991d0b</guid></item><item><title>Second woman claims Epstein sent her to the UK for sex with former prince Andrew</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/epstein-files-former-prince-andrew/n7vrx0utt</link><description>The claims have emerged after newly-released Epstein files include images of the former prince crouching over an unidentified woman lying on the floor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1ac9f7540a6cedd916b83797ec338180</guid></item><item><title>Abuse survivors led the push for this law reform — now NSW could be the first to act</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nsw-moves-to-abolish-good-character-references-in-criminal-court-proceedings/ap3z65rwc</link><description>NSW could be the first state to abolish &amp;quot;good character&amp;quot; references in court proceedings when laws are introduced next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fddbe409075ae861c5bc1090c8ab0ce4</guid></item><item><title>New seating, leadership drama and key bills — what to expect in parliament’s first week back</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-to-expect-on-parliaments-first-week-back-after-summer-break/1hes8454c</link><description>Leadership threats hang over two major parties as politicians head back to Canberra next week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be65e3a3809732cb132640aea9c4ff3b</guid></item><item><title>Reyna and her family are facing deportation from Australia. Her community is fighting back</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/reyna-and-her-family-are-facing-deportation-from-australia-her-community-is-fighting-back/3yn3td8ht</link><description>A Queensland family, who have lived in Toowoomba for 14 years, are facing possible deportation from Australia — a visa battle that&amp;apos;s caught the attention of their community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca7bcb25c8b161cb336d2519dd00cb88</guid></item><item><title>My daughter might have hundreds of half-siblings. For this, I feel immense guilt</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/my-daughter-might-have-hundreds-of-half-siblings/7bh9zg9yq</link><description>Carol&amp;apos;s two children were conceived with donor sperm in the late 90s. Decades later, she and her family found out the whole truth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69115dd013b8362cc8b232e67115d88f</guid></item><item><title>Reopening of Gaza&amp;apos;s Rafah border crossing expected on Monday, Israel says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-reopening-rafah-crossing-gaza/wmzsgzmv1</link><description>Preparations are underway to open the crossing between Egypt and the Palestinian territory, which was closed in May 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cd861160e927c138620e0641768259f</guid></item><item><title>Grammys 2026: Bad Bunny makes history, Tame Impala secures sole Australian win</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/when-and-where-you-can-watch-the-grammy-awards/48br2i1jx</link><description>Several artists used their acceptance speeches to speak out against US President Donald Trump&amp;apos;s immigration crackdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08308f124a6cc306d62184b9d8be36bc</guid></item><item><title>Ayatollah Khamenei warns Trump of broader conflict as the US amasses forces in the region</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ayatollah-khamenei-warns-trump-of-broader-conflict-as-the-us-amasses-forces-in-the-region/87dpoe8h1</link><description>Iran&amp;apos;s Supreme Leader is warning the United States that any attack on Iran could trigger regional conflict, as US naval presence in the region strengthens. As tensions mount over Iran&amp;apos;s protest crackdown and a possible nuclear deal, the United States President says his plans hinge on the success or failure of a deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a306e3b284742ec31296fb532626c497</guid></item><item><title>Australia confirms closure of Afghan embassy amid Taliban pressure</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australia-confirms-closure-of-afghan-embassy-amid-taliban-pressure/ute0yp0dz</link><description>The Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade has confirmed plans to close the Afghan Embassy in Australia, leaving many members of Australia&amp;apos;s Afghan community on edge. Experts say the decision follows a demand from the Taliban that all embassies under the control of an anti-Taliban ambassador be closed. While some members of the Afghan diaspora in Australia say they expect the closure to have little impact, for others, it&amp;apos;s a deeply concerning development.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8158d9ef21b5a6af822f0fd7b91c33d</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s top political spenders revealed | SBS News In Easy English 2 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australias-top-political-spenders-revealed-sbs-news-in-easy-english-2-february-2026/zbu1u7q7m</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c2289c1d5c05a93b57c2a48da966af80</guid></item><item><title>Littleproud and Ley have &amp;apos;constructive&amp;apos; discussion after failed Nationals spill</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/david-littleproud-remains-nationals-leader-after-spill-motion-fails/f2wz5mdi6</link><description>A second Nationals party room meeting in as many days will take place on Tuesday before the resumption of parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c575f3e21d89fbd7f614d497e7b44d49</guid></item><item><title>What is behind the surge in support for Pauline Hanson and One Nation?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/what-is-behind-the-surge-in-support-for-pauline-hanson-and-one-nation/5yd76alwo</link><description>Support for One Nation has spiked on the back of Pauline Hanson&amp;apos;s anti-immigration stance. But experts say while they have reached an unprecedented 26 per cent in primary support, it is the growing hunger for anti-establishment politics that could be reshaping the Australian landscape.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">060e77741f67166c1c853914412542e0</guid></item><item><title>Politicians&amp;apos; kids, billionaires and delivery giants: Australia&amp;apos;s political donors revealed</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/political-donations-2025-federal-election-leadup/pi0lbzm5h</link><description>Here&amp;apos;s who donated the most in the lead-up to the 2025 federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac225faa3cc0a2715f84acae50ef02e8</guid></item><item><title>Property values accelerate ahead of RBA meeting &amp;amp; gold and silver prices smashed</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/property-values-accelerate-ahead-of-rba-meeting-gold-and-silver-prices-smashed/5b7iiniov</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Tim Lawless from Cotality Australia about the future for property prices amid expectations of a rise in interest rates; Phil O&amp;apos;Donaghoe from Deutsche Bank explains why a rate rise tomorrow isn&amp;apos;t a done deal; plus Raymond Chan from Morgans Financial Limited looks at the day&amp;apos;s market action including a spectacular fall in the price of precious metals like gold and silver.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4a42386f362d5bbe6a79444f4992e1a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Lifeline&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;poisoned chalice&amp;apos;? What the reopening of Gaza&amp;apos;s Rafah crossing means</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-the-reopening-of-the-rafah-crossing-means-for-gaza/doxcsin6w</link><description>The &amp;quot;key transit route&amp;quot; has partially reopened after almost two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f12c001cb030d1ea7e464105c6b3af4</guid></item><item><title>What could disappear if rates rise today — and how much a hike would cost you</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rba-rate-decision-mortgage-impact/jtp5wbh8s</link><description>You won&amp;apos;t find this home loan rate if the RBA hikes, a finance expert says. But some economists believe a hold is still possible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adb62989b1515969350c68c97b74a3ff</guid></item><item><title>Trump says the US has struck a trade deal with India, will slash tariffs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/donald-trump-us-india-trade-deal-narendra-modi/tviinj94m</link><description>The US president said Indian Prime Minister Narendra Modi had agreed to stop buying Russian oil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41db363b79596e51f045fdd218272114</guid></item><item><title>The Rafah crossing reopens, but with limited numbers</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-rafah-crossing-reopens-but-with-limited-numbers/t8lpu7wht</link><description>The Rafah border crossing between Gaza and Egypt has been reopened. Movement will be limited, but for Palestinians needing medical treatment it offers a critical lifeline. The border has been largely shut since May 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7d9e06915d19060926c9ccce07a1956</guid></item><item><title>First Palestinians leave Gaza for medical treatment after Rafah crossing partially reopens</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rafah-crossing-reopens-gazans-travel-egypt/nw9xywulg</link><description>About 150 people were due to leave Gaza on the first day of the reopening, Egyptian officials said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4c0f880bf9d2c21776f585cef8c9d0d0</guid></item><item><title>Police suspect mother of top US news anchor was &amp;apos;abducted&amp;apos; from home</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/savannah-guthrie-mum-missing/u2x7vokrh</link><description>Police are searching for Nancy Guthrie, the mother of Melbourne-born media personality Savannah Guthrie.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a27c71cd5110bfe4bef06087b5890799</guid></item><item><title>Royals, power and public trust: the Epstein files continue to rock the Establishment</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/royals-power-and-public-trust-the-epstein-files-continue-to-rock-the-establishment/nsqfzlw5r</link><description>From London to Oslo, institutions built on tradition and public trust are being tested by demands for transparency, accountability and justice. In Britain, both a former prince and a senior political figure are being urged to answer questions about their past associations with Jeffrey Epstein. While in Norway, a criminal trial involving the Crown Princess’s son is unfolding under intense public scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beeb370ab5eb42a0b8af3c52ddc0867a</guid></item><item><title>Police search for Dezi Freeman: &amp;apos;the largest manhunt we have seen in Victoria&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/police-search-for-dezi-freeman-the-largest-manhunt-we-have-seen-in-victoria/3spa4jf4i</link><description>A fresh search in Victoria&amp;apos;s High Country has begun for accused police killer Dezi Freeman, with detectives now believing the 56-year-old is most likely dead. Mr Freeman is accused of killing two police officers and severely injuring a third after they executed a search warrant on a rural property near the Victorian town of Porepunkah last year. Police are now focusing on a new search area in the vast Mount Buffalo National Park.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddbe55b15c60320ef2d64ad150a1b4fd</guid></item><item><title>Wong condemns &amp;apos;horrific use of violence&amp;apos; as Australia imposes fresh sanctions on Iran</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-slaps-fresh-sanctions-on-iran-over-violent-repression-and-irgc-linked-abuses/6cfs3xym4</link><description>Australia has imposed new sanctions on 20 Iranian individuals and three entities, citing repression and human rights abuses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91f12d231c833b343b0dcf32927a7be7</guid></item><item><title>School staff face termination under new hate speech rules | SBS News In Easy English 3 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/school-staff-face-termination-under-new-hate-speech-rules-sbs-news-in-easy-english-3-february-2026/ghzttaslg</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46b0a777df2265fe9cebbc4f80c29807</guid></item><item><title>Ley avoids Liberal leadership spill as Nationals consider Coalition &amp;apos;reset&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ley-avoids-liberal-leadership-spill-as-nationals-consider-coalition-reset/3t93o86ea</link><description>The Nationals want to get the Coalition &amp;quot;settings right&amp;quot; as Ley lays out a pathway forward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">361d9e9406b2784859c87067a798e5e5</guid></item><item><title>Pro-Palestinian protests planned despite extended restrictions ahead of Herzog visit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/extension-to-protest-restrictions-announced-in-nsw-in-the-lead-up-to-isaac-herzog-visit-to-australia/n3a69evvk</link><description>Demonstrators have criticised the extension of protest restrictions, while NSW Police say the measures are about ensuring community safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef43d219dc4ab28f1b9e385d3aeb7521</guid></item><item><title>Interest rate rise ends two-year pause</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interest-rate-rise-ends-two-year-pause/iqjmz8d1s</link><description>The Reserve Bank of Australia has ended a two-year hiatus by raising interest rates to 15 per cent, sparking a fierce political debate over whether government spending or private demand is fuelling persistent inflation. While the Treasurer defends the budget and points to external pressures, the Opposition and the Greens argue that current policy settings are punishing everyday Australians and ignoring alternative economic levers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d2f41cc85cf2d336bd2083d21cc53a0</guid></item><item><title>The key to a long life? One factor may matter more than we thought</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/new-study-genetics-play-a-key-role-in-human-longevity/s1lpsa5sm</link><description>Some say the study&amp;apos;s findings have &amp;quot;important consequences for ageing research&amp;quot;, while others believe they are &amp;quot;not too surprising&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06bd41d82da962b0058c1ef02313390f</guid></item><item><title>RBA pulls the trigger on rates; gold and silver rebound</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/rba-pulls-the-trigger-on-rates-gold-and-silver-rebound/4ok7lrcvh</link><description>The Reserve Bank of Australia has increased interest rates for the first time since November 2023, hiking the official cash rate to 3.85%. It says it now expects inflation to remain well above its 2-3% target for longer, leaving the door open for further rate increases. For more on this, Stephanie Youssef spoke with HSBC chief economist Paul Bloxham. Despite the decision, the Australian share market finished the session strong, amid a strong global stocks rebound that included a gold and silver price recovery. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Mark Gardner, CEO at MPC Markets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60803d08903426b9c5c0fcdadc1b0aec</guid></item><item><title>RBA governor&amp;apos;s four reasons for rate hike as major banks react to increase</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rba-governors-four-reasons-for-rate-hike-as-materially-higher-inflation-predicted/tw8nsbl5f</link><description>The Reserve Bank has hiked the cash rate to 3.85 per cent, with one of the major banks saying it&amp;apos;s unlikely to be a &amp;quot;one-and-done&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e484c2021f0272a734ac35a477a1fd8e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The digital Wild West&amp;apos;: Spain planning to ban social media for under-16s</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-digital-wild-west-spain-planning-to-ban-social-media-for-under-16s/bkomqip4t</link><description>Australia became the first country in the world to ban social media for under-16s last year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">466cdfcfcdbe374642e288369d680da5</guid></item><item><title>The Australians competing in skimo, a new Olympic sport so steep athletes get &amp;apos;delirious&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-australians-competing-in-skimo-a-new-olympic-sport-so-steep-athletes-get-delirious/ny3ysml8r</link><description>Two Australians will represent the country in the new sport at the Milano Cortina Winter Olympic Games 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f8038a4671e68743fbd3cd788f067ef</guid></item><item><title>Musk says raid on French X offices as part of deepfake probe a &amp;apos;political attack&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/x-offices-raided-in-france-amid-investigation-into-sexual-deepfakes-and-political-interference/hs1damycj</link><description>The billionaire owner of the social media platform has also been summoned for a &amp;quot;voluntary interview&amp;quot; as part of the investigation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e6de3b6c1dcbd2adc58c23fe9f0b00e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Left out&amp;apos;: How hate laws leave LGBTIQ+ workers vulnerable</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/left-out-how-hate-laws-leave-lgbtiq-workers-vulnerable/dcbwzf1ze</link><description>Nearly half of Australia&amp;apos;s LGBTIQ+ workers say they have faced discrimination and harassment in the past year. With hate speech rising in Australia, rights groups say stronger laws and greater legal representation are needed to protect the LGBTIQ+ community from greater harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2b6b8da2e1b5984a2f256f6108561f7</guid></item><item><title>Nearly nine billion a year: The &amp;apos;particularly nasty&amp;apos; litter polluting Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cigarette-butts-most-littered-item-in-australia/1o7c3ktf0</link><description>Clean Up Australia&amp;apos;s annual survey revealed this pervasive source of waste unseated soft plastics as the most prevalent item tossed on the ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4464ad9d1f1f054670946b2058c3b1d</guid></item><item><title>Historic defence properties earmarked for sale in bid to raise nearly $2 billion</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/historic-defence-properties-to-be-sold-off-in-bid-to-raise-nearly-2-billion-government-announces/bw9li4svu</link><description>Defence Minister Richard Marles said the sites eyed for sale were &amp;quot;vacant, decaying, under-utilised and costing millions of dollars to retain&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbdae1764715167d0019819497d35d23</guid></item><item><title>Safety arrangements ahead of Herzog visit | SBS News In Easy English 4 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/safety-arrangements-ahead-of-herzog-visit-sbs-news-in-easy-english-4-february-2026/k1z48vi8x</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9908545ae1c58e6165f2125c3810af17</guid></item><item><title>Billionaire Clive Palmer to challenge electoral donations cap in High Court</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/clive-palmer-political-donations-cap/sjtbvhp7y</link><description>Palmer&amp;apos;s mining company, Mineralogy, funnelled more than $52 million into his party ahead of the federal election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a7e0aa6754f22525ad69a2b264c4d36</guid></item><item><title>Capital Gains Tax again under the spotlight following latest rate rise</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/capital-gains-tax-again-under-the-spotlight-following-latest-rate-rise/snj6ul0z6</link><description>Following the latest interest rate rise, the Federal Government is facing renewed pressure from unions and economists to reform the 50 per cent Capital Gains Tax ((CGT)) discount, which critics label a &amp;quot;tax avoidance scheme&amp;quot; favouring the wealthiest Australians. While the Treasurer maintains a focus on housing supply, proponents of the reform argue that winding back these concessions could reclaim $20 billion in annual revenue and ease the cost-of-living crisis for the nation’s workforce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4edf2b9d7067a4077b82684edf30c640</guid></item><item><title>Kids in jail, rising racism: Australia&amp;apos;s 2026 human rights report card</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australias-human-rights-report-card/v5qltzf2m</link><description>Human Rights Watch has released its annual report for 2026, highlighting several issues it says have tarred Australia&amp;apos;s reputation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8624b3ff1aa9c53b97c20129de4d167b</guid></item><item><title>Kids in jail, rising racism: Australia&amp;apos;s 2026 human rights report card</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/kids-in-detention-rising-racism-and-refugee-abuse-australias-human-rights-report-card/v5qltzf2m</link><description>Human Rights Watch has released its annual report for 2026, highlighting several issues it says have tarred Australia&amp;apos;s reputation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5b935818eb1d32e7ef3c32e116de1ef</guid></item><item><title>Mapped: The $3 billion in defence sites the government wants to offload</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/mapped-the-3-billion-in-defence-sites-the-government-wants-to-offload/l1mth8du1</link><description>The Opposition has accused the government of selling the &amp;quot;heart and soul&amp;quot; of Australia&amp;apos;s defence force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e29e10fb2b8701c4dca9d0eedb80952c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Absolutely abhorrent&amp;apos;: Posters of accused Bondi shooter appear in Melbourne</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/absolutely-abhorrent-posters-of-accused-bondi-shooter-appear-in-melbourne/xstp1bb1o</link><description>Victoria Police are investigating the display of posters across Melbourne that depict the alleged Bondi gunman Naveed Akram. About 40 have appeared. featuring the image of the accused shooter and the word Aussie beneath his face. They were put together in the style of artist Peter Drew&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;Aussie&amp;apos; series of street art.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c2e224b6bf33d8823534e89ae6e28f8</guid></item><item><title>What&amp;apos;s really driving inflation — and why software shares are getting crushed</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/what-is-really-driving-inflation-software-shares-smashed/9z0yzrjig</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Shane Oliver from AMP to figure out the real drivers of inflation; plus Damien Boey from Wilson Asset Management about the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action including a software shares sell-off.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03c1f7294126e0baa92e0d1360890938</guid></item><item><title>Who is Isaac Herzog, and why is his imminent Australian visit controversial?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/isaac-herzog-australia-visit-controversy-explained/8rsgnrmic</link><description>Israel&amp;apos;s president is set to arrive in Australia soon for a visit hailed by some as &amp;quot;deeply significant&amp;quot;, and criticised by others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2d8f9f6f07eee97a17dc2c4c941d5f3e</guid></item><item><title>Many Aussies live in multi-generational homes. How is living with parents in your 40s?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/multigenerational-living-housing/od3sc7lpx</link><description>While multi-generational living can come with a lot of benefits, others say most of our houses simply aren&amp;apos;t designed for it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28b0339b01c947251011ca6147c4db9d</guid></item><item><title>Your Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics guide: Aussie athletes and how to watch</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/milano-cortina-2026-winter-olympic-games-guide/4wlvbbu3m</link><description>Thirty Australian athletes will make their debut at the Milano Cortina 2026 Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5310955c627ef066cd6d358189f9b9f0</guid></item><item><title>What&amp;apos;s behind Australia&amp;apos;s inflation problem — and can you do anything about it?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-is-inflation-and-what-can-you-do-about-it/o3dhilgt3</link><description>Inflation is back in the spotlight after the Reserve Bank hiked rates for the first time in more than two years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">001d7cfcd27e969677c9947cabdbe98f</guid></item><item><title>Trump administration to remove 700 immigration officers from Minnesota</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-administration-to-remove-700-immigration-officers-from-minnesota/533mt73ol</link><description>Minneapolis has become a major flashpoint in Trump&amp;apos;s immigration crackdown after two fatal shootings in the city by federal agents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d1846d67fe9165debfbf2b59840578a</guid></item><item><title>Mildura has already broken heatwave records. As climate change advances, what comes next?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/mildura-has-already-broken-heatwave-records-as-climate-change-advances-what-comes-next/s262bycuh</link><description>For many in Australia&amp;apos;s south-east, the day after Australia Day brought sweltering conditions and record temperatures. In Mildura, in Victoria&amp;apos;s far northwest, the mercury hit 48.6 Celsius. And when coastal areas enjoyed a reprieve, the inland still had to cope with an extended heatwave that lasted a week. Experts say these kinds of phenomena are going to intensify over time because of the impacts of climate change - but while there has been plenty of coverage of how that impacts on urban centres, regional Australia has not received the same attention. SBS visited Mildura to see how the region felt the heat, and what they&amp;apos;re doing to cope with climate change at a local level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e530a064349eb49a4668efe5fd936f34</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Bloodbath&amp;apos;: Mass layoffs at Jeff Bezos-owned Washington Post</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/washington-post-layoffs/y2dd49wsv</link><description>The shrinking of the prominent masthead comes as major media outlets in the US face intense pressure from Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a84e5765efdb90a112b2f37ac6da267</guid></item><item><title>Bondi stabbings: &amp;apos;Major failing&amp;apos; in mental health care of killer, inquest finds</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bondi-stabbing-inquest-findings-handed-down/yxmsv2val</link><description>The coroner said Joel Cauchi&amp;apos;s psychiatrist failed to act on warning signs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38552da847896d1b07ff110f49867aa2</guid></item><item><title>Alleged Invasion Day rally attacker ‘self-radicalised’, WA Police say, declaring terror act</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/perth-bombing-declared-terrorism-event/iwsn67pat</link><description>WA&amp;apos;s first terrorism charge has been laid against the man accused of the alleged Invasion Day rally attack in Perth&amp;apos;s CBD on 26 January.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8baf20379fd8be43489e680ae2cda8b</guid></item><item><title>Coroner hands down inquest findings into Bondi mass stabbing | SBS News In Easy English 5 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/coroner-hands-down-inquest-findings-into-bondi-mass-stabbing-sbs-news-in-easy-english-5-february-2026/pwuk6gacb</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c538d4213fcbd73fce0d7993e7e80b38</guid></item><item><title>Trump v Iran, the huge Epstein dump and Melania’s hundred-million-dollar doco bomb</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trump-v-iran-the-huge-epstein-dump-and-melanias-hundred-million-dollar-doco-bomb/igeaxz98s</link><description>The US and Iran tussle over talks to stave off more strikes, millions more Epstein documents touch the rich and powerful the world over from Elon Musk to the Norwegian princess-royal and more trilateral talks in Abu Dhabi don’t stop the destruction across Ukraine. Plus, US democracy in danger and what we learned when Melania Trump’s doco hit the cinemas…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6edf15bd82b440f056dba78a7f51dc9</guid></item><item><title>Who&amp;apos;s using the capital gains tax discount, and how much does it cost the budget?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/whos-using-the-capital-gains-tax-discount-and-how-much-does-it-cost-the-budget/rmli0xslw</link><description>A rise in the cash rate due to stubborn inflation has cast a spotlight on making housing more affordable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">186f63ce24f25ff67674dc553cf4bdea</guid></item><item><title>The cost of cancer: new research highlights the financial toll of treatment</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-cost-of-cancer-new-research-highlights-the-financial-toll-of-treatment/lun0qpo6x</link><description>Almost 99 per cent of Australians diagnosed with cancer incur out-of-pocket expenses, even when accessing public care. That&amp;apos;s the shocking finding from the Cancer Council Australia’s latest national survey, which suggests the financial burden arises from both direct medical costs and indirect expenses at every stage of the cancer journey. The cost of accessing care and treatment hits First Nations communities especially hard, with Indigenous Australians ultimately facing a higher mortality rate for blood cancer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">deb22260f1510372cca3cbf1f5214ff9</guid></item><item><title>Democracy is under threat warns Human Rights Watch, set back to the 1980s</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/democracy-is-under-threat-warns-human-rights-watch-set-back-to-the-1980s/m1qp10l6t</link><description>Democracy and the rules-based international order are under threat, according to the latest annual report by Human Rights Watch. There&amp;apos;s a particular focus on the United States and what the international body describes as its erosion of human rights, but there is also a spotlight on Australia. Australia&amp;apos;s immigration and youth detention policies are listed as &amp;apos;significant failings&amp;apos;, cited as the only Western democracy without a national human rights act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12fea713fb412e6b7f7762a601d062d4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Might be how I die&amp;apos;: Nick nearly didn&amp;apos;t survive a Japan ski trip. He&amp;apos;s now warning travellers</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-deaths-at-japanese-ski-resorts-prompt-warnings-from-authorities/l27exiaxg</link><description>An Australian who had a near-fatal ski accident in Japan has urged holidaymakers to be aware of risks, following recent deaths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07a4eb792ba028e6a650ab8100c40157</guid></item><item><title>Coroner identifies major failings by psychiatrist who treated Bondi Junction attacker</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/coroner-identifies-major-failings-by-psychiatrist-who-treated-bondi-junction-attacker/4tpkye4zr</link><description>A psychiatrist who treated the Westfield Bondi Junction attacker has been referred for review by the coroner investigating the mass killing in 2024. New South Wales State Coroner Teresa O&amp;apos;Sullivan criticised the care of Joel Cauchi&amp;apos;s former psychiatrist for failing to adequately respond to a schizophrenia relapse in the years before the mass stabbing, which saw six people killed and 10 injured. She has made 23 recommendations, including a call for the Health Ombudsman of Queensland to review the psychiatrist&amp;apos;s care and treatment of Joel Cauchi.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb735555d32f93669af86e516836c610</guid></item><item><title>Software sell-off continues and bitcoin tumbles</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/software-sell-off-continues-bitcoin-tumbles/5wo6glp9s</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Ben Clark from TMS Private Wealth about the day&amp;apos;s market action including a software sell-off in the US which is trickling to Australia, plus what the fall in the bitcoin price says about the economic and investment environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a38f8fc84ed9cc20ae740f5902428444</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Dangerous, sick and hopeless situation&amp;apos;: Fears after US-Russia nuclear control deal expires</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/a-fundamental-us-russia-nuclear-deal-is-dead-does-the-world-risk-armaggedon/cvkptsvz3</link><description>Experts say the expiry of an arms control treaty between the US and Russia is &amp;quot;the end of an era&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf6ef77070060c00770cc1b45e6af45a</guid></item><item><title>Russia and Ukraine conduct first prisoner swap in months amid peace talks in Abu Dhabi</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/russia-ukraine-pow-exchange/67egi7e3c</link><description>The countries swapped 157 captured soldiers and civilians each after US-mediated peace talks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6691d94f1ce6bdb4d1861b1e4c299ce</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I am sorry&amp;apos;: UK prime minister apologises to Epstein victims for appointing former US envoy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/keir-starmer-apologises-epstein-victims-peter-mandelson/0wln3onqz</link><description>Keir Starmer is battling for his political future as fallout grows in the wake of the latest Epstein files release.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7545efcb51c4b67a9aa952fe2bef6ef3</guid></item><item><title>Albanese hails Australia-Indonesia relationship after signing major security treaty</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-and-indonesia-to-sign-major-security-treaty/zykt3chwg</link><description>&amp;quot;Australia and Indonesia&amp;apos;s relationship is stronger than it has ever been,&amp;quot; Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33651a182167c708fae105b5babe18db</guid></item><item><title>Nationals offer to spend two weeks off frontbench as deadline for Coalition reunion expires</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/liberals-prepared-to-go-it-alone-as-key-moment-for-nationals-make-up-arrives/fm96rymz0</link><description>It comes as Liberal senator Jane Hume maintained the Liberals were prepared to stand on their own two feet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35207633306c531b49eba120e138ca6d</guid></item><item><title>Prisoners of war exchanged, with hope of further Russia-Ukraine peace talks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/prisoners-of-war-exchanged-with-hope-of-further-russia-ukraine-peace-talks/no91bckto</link><description>A second round of talks in Abu Dhabi between Ukraine, Russia and the United States have concluded without a peace deal, despite delegates citing progress towards reaching an end to the four-year war. Ukraine and Russia did exchange 310 prisoners of war in total, as Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy signalled further meetings were being planned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">119bb2d77cdec7c0d8d44839142b0ced</guid></item><item><title>Turf war: Why this median strip conflict is being compared to the division of Korea</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/melbourne-median-strip-grass-dispute/i77zne9ot</link><description>An inner-city median strip has become the centre of a row a mayor likened to a geopolitical standoff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e2f82e3791f47e5aff63eae7bb69020</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Great concern&amp;apos; about escalation: What to know ahead of US-Iran meeting</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/talks-between-us-and-iran-in-oman-on-nuclear-issues/5gn3h3ah2</link><description>The talks come at a time of heightened tension between the two countries, with leaders from both sides trading threats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d3c4421cade93ee801ece13898c6bca</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Life goes on&amp;apos;: Underworld figure Tony Mokbel reveals plans as a free man</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tony-mokbel-case-abandoned/sbpyrtme6</link><description>Tony Mokbel spoke outside court after prosecutors said they would drop a retrial of a drug trafficking case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49f5d8dc0d9ce8acb68952988c7ba9e1</guid></item><item><title>PM travels to Indonesia to sign security treaty | SBS News In Easy English 6 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pm-travels-to-indonesia-to-sign-security-treaty-sbs-news-in-easy-english-6-february-2026/ify7k0di8</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">928ab6f5719dc1f8f621c0984105c4d9</guid></item><item><title>Pressure mounts on Keir Starmer to resign over Epstein scandal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pressure-mounts-on-keir-starmer-to-resign-over-epstein-scandal/4b8ujahuh</link><description>The UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer is under mounting pressure, following scrutiny over his decision to appoint friend of Jeffrey Epstein Peter Mandelson as the UK&amp;apos;s US ambassador in 2024. The files released last week included emails appearing to show a close relationship between the former ambassador and Epstein, and suggested Mr Mandelson had shared government documents with Epstein while serving as a Cabinet Minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00056be6c547af4500f934827beef928</guid></item><item><title>Demonstrators and police still in deadlock over Israeli president protest plans</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/demonstrators-and-police-still-in-deadlock-over-planned-israeli-president-protests/bxnnbi4r8</link><description>The protesters&amp;apos; planned route &amp;quot;may and potentially will result in arrests&amp;quot;, a senior NSW Police official has warned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62f8ab8c1867e344f4f52e2d447dd7a4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Impossible choices&amp;apos;: The data that proves living costs are rising for Australians</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/impossible-choices-the-data-that-proves-living-costs-are-rising-for-australians/smm4voks8</link><description>Living costs rose across all households over the past year, with those on government payments facing the steepest increases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad6539bb0afbbd98f74519598553aed5</guid></item><item><title>Family &amp;apos;devastated&amp;apos;: A timeline of Gus Lamont&amp;apos;s disappearance and major crime investigation</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gus-lamonts-grandparents-devastated-major-crime-declared-what-we-know-so-far/aslwtmox5</link><description>Police recently revealed they had identified a suspect who was living at the remote property at the time Gus vanished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">961be7d2a4488a300064f8b50d16b8bc</guid></item><item><title>ASX200&amp;apos;s worst day since April 2025 as technology rout continues</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asx200s-worst-day-since-april-2025-as-technology-rout-continues/53xb4haxx</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Lochlan Halloway from Morningstar to go through all the factors that has triggered a sell-off on the sharemarket, including an ongoing technology sector rout, along with a look at the local reporting season; plus Peter McGuire from Trading.com looks at Bitcoin&amp;apos;s sliding value.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bdf2e7773186383ee114e6a8b9607c8</guid></item><item><title>Australia and Indonesia sign security pact</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australia-and-indonesia-sign-security-pact/ddx81vzh9</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has hailed a new security pact with Indonesia as a significant shift toward a closer defence partnership between the two countries. However, analysts warn the treaty may come at a high cost, potentially ignoring ongoing human rights issues in West Papua and concerns about the Indonesian government&amp;apos;s future political direction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0333e9b7a9073e098dbe5ba581d3285b</guid></item><item><title>Do you earn more or less than others working in the same job?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-does-where-you-live-in-australia-affect-your-income/zc6kzm5iq</link><description>New figures show where the highest-paid Australian workers live and what jobs they are doing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cd3355efaee3d0af689fd5f9489b0d2</guid></item><item><title>Tutorials, work and fears their loved ones are dead: The uni students facing unique stress</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/no-sleep-for-weeks-the-students-facing-an-anxious-start-to-the-academic-year/fxdivmn8n</link><description>&amp;apos;Aida&amp;apos; is among university students from Iran battling financial stress and emotional trauma, following the recent violent crackdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">865f16bffecd48837fe0a24f26a35dea</guid></item><item><title>‘Are our loved ones alive or not?’ A distressing start to the academic year for these international students</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/are-our-loved-ones-alive-or-not-a-distressing-start-to-the-academic-year-for-these-international-students/odjxp3hg0</link><description>University students in Australia, including more than 800,000 from overseas, are preparing for a new academic year. However, many from Iran are facing financial hardship while also grieving lives lost during recent protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d0d5f167dcd76adb1323b112dd4b83a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Blatantly racist&amp;apos;: Trump deletes social media video depicting Obamas as apes after backlash</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/blatantly-racist-trump-deletes-social-media-video-depicting-obamas-as-apes-after-backlash/buk0jk1mt</link><description>The White House initially described the negative reaction as &amp;quot;fake outrage&amp;quot; before deleting the post 12 hours later.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d71ee25c6c92b45f209fab2c8872ccd3</guid></item><item><title>More Australians in jail at a higher cost; is the system working?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/more-australians-in-jail-at-a-higher-cost-is-the-system-working/3een20nxa</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s average daily prison population is at its highest level in eight years. New data from the Productivity Commission has found more on average, around 45,000 people were locked up each day in the 2024-2025 financial year. Experts say the figures are a clear indication the system is failing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">087adb3459113c3ff97f25ab2993c75c</guid></item><item><title>Russian general under US sanctions shot several times in Moscow</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/russian-general-shot-several-times-in-moscow/dh4ve1d2v</link><description>Investigators said lieutenant general Vladimir Alexeyev was critically injured after he was shot by an unidentified gunman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f790b2f1eefac1a03da8264dcd76544e</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: SBS talks to Mildura&amp;apos;s mayor on managing heatwaves, and overcoming climate change scepticism</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-sbs-talks-to-milduras-mayor-on-managing-heatwaves-and-overcoming-climate-change-scepticism/2f65oth3c</link><description>The far northwestern city of Mildura is used to hot summers. But in January, the city and surrounds sweltered through an unusual heatwave, with temperatures breaking records throughout the region. SBS&amp;apos; Deborah Groarke spoke with the mayor of Mildura, Ali Cupper, on how the Council deals with hot weather, and its concerns around how worsening climate change patterns might affect its residents and agricultural economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20c0522744be7c04ef9d20bba5684446</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Twin flames and message of unity open Milano Cortina Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/in-pictures-milan-cortina-2026-winter-olympics-opening-ceremony/2tl518ldk</link><description>Mariah Carey, Milan-born rapper Ghali and Italian pop star Laura Pausini were among the headline performers at Milan&amp;apos;s San Siro stadium.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0f19a2b6d8a96fca603d77d7a8c1a18</guid></item><item><title>Minns invokes special powers, urges calm ahead of Israeli president&amp;apos;s visit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/special-police-powers-in-effect-on-monday-as-nsw-declares-israeli-presidents-visit-a-major-event/e3gcrw17h</link><description>The NSW premier said special provisions invoked for Isaac Herzog&amp;apos;s visit were about public safety and not a ban on lawful protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44041621e2345da1e05fb251c2b3e31d</guid></item><item><title>Iran says US nuclear talks off to &amp;apos;good start&amp;apos; but draws line at missile, proxy issues</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/iran-says-us-nuclear-talks-off-to-good-start-but-draws-line-at-missile-proxy-issues/hkypxkf3e</link><description>Iran&amp;apos;s top diplomat struck an optimistic note after talks on its nuclear program, despite US pressure to broaden the agenda.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6b95ac153d7740dcb029344836271eb</guid></item><item><title>From SoundCloud to the Super Bowl — Bad Bunny set to make halftime history</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bad-bunny-to-make-history-at-super-bowl-sunday/u8z8cqbs2</link><description>The Puerto Rican star will be the first Latin artist to perform solo at America&amp;apos;s most-viewed concert.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc128f8f089165b894d27e77ec8ae5ce</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;You cannot escape diversity&amp;apos;: The controversial housing laws trying to &amp;apos;integrate&amp;apos; immigrants</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/you-cannot-escape-diversity-the-controversial-housing-laws-trying-to-integrate-immigrants/9jrnb72bf</link><description>Denmark&amp;apos;s once-termed &amp;quot;ghetto laws&amp;quot; were designed to &amp;quot;integrate&amp;quot; immigrants but the European Court of Justice has deemed them potentially unlawful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fdc75762c6c38a08317f358ddda855c7</guid></item><item><title>The Trump effect and 90s nostalgia: What&amp;apos;s behind the rise in &amp;apos;Chinamaxxing&amp;apos;?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/chinamaxxing-trend-and-why-everyone-want-to-be-chinese-now/n2607p6zg</link><description>A Chinamaxxing trend has emerged on social media with creators posting about being in a &amp;quot;very Chinese time of my life&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01630aace4c2fed33903937f173099be</guid></item><item><title>The fight over voting: can the US electoral system be altered to favour one party?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-fight-over-voting-can-the-us-electoral-system-be-altered-to-favour-one-party/ldijy7alc</link><description>With the midterm elections due at the end of this year in the United States, Republicans and Democrats in some states are scrambling for an advantage. Republican President Donald Trump had hoped re-districting could help House Republicans hold on to their slim majority. But there are moves to introduce legislation that could also give the party an advantage, laws that the Democrats say are designed to shut out minority voters. And there are still election battles to be won in Texas - and Georgia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3b1a47ddb4897665e3e08f0f8cd9732</guid></item><item><title>Trump&amp;apos;s America wants more access to your personal data. Could the Australian Government hand it over?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trumps-america-wants-more-access-to-your-personal-data-could-the-australian-government-hand-it-over/nw9s5x3cp</link><description>Growing speculation over a proposal to hand Australians&amp;apos; personal and biometric data to the United States is raising alarm among privacy and security experts. As other countries with visa-free arrangements with the U-S consider proposals to expand their data-sharing agreements, the Australian Government is yet to clarify if they&amp;apos;re considering the move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07147186f129729269b00cf923d983b6</guid></item><item><title>US pushing for June deadline to end Russia-Ukraine war, Zelenskyy says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-pressing-ukraine-and-russia-to-end-war-by-june-zelenskyy-says/zps8n57kj</link><description>The US has given Ukraine and Russia a June deadline to reach a deal to end the nearly four‑year war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55f3050ac14e125170ed05daf6c99281</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Twisted wreck&amp;apos;: Fresh warnings to e-bike riders found breaking rules in NSW</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/twisted-wreck-fresh-warnings-to-e-bike-riders-found-breaking-rules-in-nsw/t3p5kq0m4</link><description>After a video showing e-bike riders speeding across the Sydney Harbour Bridge, police will have more powers to destroy illegal devices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">422b4a965bdaa6dd4191753d8f9fdf05</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Spreads like wildfire&amp;apos;: Why measles cases are on the rise and what we should do about it</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-measles-cases-are-on-the-rise/sxtbm9vr7</link><description>Rising international travel and vaccine fatigue are among the factors behind rising measles infection rates, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67985d26e7cee4c4e8545265edce4612</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We trust each other&amp;apos;: Coalition reunited after Ley, Littleproud strike fresh deal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/off-again-on-again-coalition-reunites-after-almost-month-long-split/qhy1jiqg0</link><description>The leaders of the Nationals and Liberals say the current Coalition team will go to the next election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4a414dabeb0654035131b5fc6fa8e4a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We trust each other&amp;apos;: Coalition reunited after Ley, Littleproud strike fresh deal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/off-again-on-again-coalition-set-to-reunite-after-almost-month-long-split/qhy1jiqg0</link><description>The leaders of the Nationals and Liberals say the current Coalition team will go to the next election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffa561113448d5dc513b2984096333bc</guid></item><item><title>Anger builds ahead of the Israeli president&amp;apos;s arrival | Midday News Bulletin 8 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/anger-builds-ahead-of-the-israeli-presidents-arrival-midday-news-bulletin-8-february-2026/wgaq3i5j0</link><description>Anger builds ahead of the Israeli president&amp;apos;s arrival; reports the coalition is poised to reunite; Australia&amp;apos;s first medal hope dashed at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">deb3cd0c9d8c1757d506495a8fe00d5f</guid></item><item><title>Residents told &amp;apos;too late to leave&amp;apos; as Tropical Cyclone Mitchell nears WA coast</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cyclone-mitchell-fears-as-storm-closes-in/mz5ou8z8d</link><description>Locals are waiting to count their losses after being hit by severe tropical Cyclone Mitchell, with the worst yet to come.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5312fb5f3d0985a7e6b2c245271a65b2</guid></item><item><title>A deal to reunify the Liberals and Nationals | Evening News Bulletin 8 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-deal-to-reunify-the-liberals-and-nationals-evening-news-bulletin-8-february-2026/s690rgblg</link><description>A deal to reunify the Liberals and Nationals, A heavy police presence for the Israeli President&amp;apos;s visit, And in golf, Elvis Smylie makes a dazzling debut on the Saudi-backed LIV Golf tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f1fa2ad38150e79aad6353b8f125ad6</guid></item><item><title>Queensland plans laws with two-year jail terms for &amp;apos;from the river to the sea&amp;apos; slogan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/queensland-set-to-impose-two-year-jail-terms-for-from-the-river-to-the-sea-slogan/h3851dtd5</link><description>Pro-Palestinian slogans would be outlawed in Queensland under sweeping legislation to crack down on hate speech and antisemitism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16098c1a3dd0a89ac8ecc7128e8daec4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We will pay&amp;apos;: US TV host Savannah Guthrie&amp;apos;s plea for missing mother&amp;apos;s safe return</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/savannah-guthries-plea-for-missing-mother/zv9oa5dgm</link><description>Savannah Guthrie has told her mother&amp;apos;s kidnappers the family is prepared to pay for her safe return of the 84-year-old.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e71fdefc2633ca0f864f6c4a5326ab8a</guid></item><item><title>Sydney pro-Palestinian protest group to launch legal challenge to Herzog visit police powers</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sydney-pro-palestinian-protest-group-to-launch-legal-challenge-to-herzog-visit-police-powers/bsr6ddv7h</link><description>The decision to grant police extra powers during the Israeli president&amp;apos;s visit will face a legal challenge in the NSW Supreme Court.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f561ae933b4a5311238ca4f544429767</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Beyond a nuisance&amp;apos;: Why the government is being urged to tackle sovereign citizens online</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/beyond-a-nuisance-why-the-government-is-being-urged-to-tackle-sovereign-citizens-online/iz4rf7xu0</link><description>The sovereign citizen movement has become a serious security threat, and governments need to treat it as such, a new report argues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ad897ccb43db7ece8913bdbd39cb569</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Easy and cheaper&amp;apos;: Why a growing number of Australians are adopting this niche lifestyle</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/is-living-off-grid-actually-cheaper/659x148w4</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s off-grid communities used to be seen by some as hippy communes. These days, they&amp;apos;re more high-tech — and a more affordable housing option.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91df205e1406621d52cd1f6aa0600b62</guid></item><item><title>Legal fight ahead of Israeli president visit | Morning News Bulletin 9 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/legal-fight-ahead-of-israeli-president-visit-morning-news-bulletin-9-february-2026/rttt2q0lp</link><description>Legal challenge targets extra police powers for the Israeli president&amp;apos;s visit to Australia; the Christchurch Mosque gunman&amp;apos;s appeal hearing is set to begin; Gout Gout will skip this year&amp;apos;s Commonwealth Games to focus on the world under-20s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ea64215db448d98772f2516701921cd</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Something has to happen&amp;apos;: Pressure on Taylor to challenge Ley after Coalition reunion</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/pressure-angus-taylor-sussan-ley-coalition-reunion/ovdzpg740</link><description>A senior Liberal says the party is &amp;quot;now at irrelevance&amp;quot; after dire opinion polling, stoking fears of a leadership spill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fe85e31c11b7dbb4304639a63efa6a6</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Something has to happen&amp;apos;: Pressure on Taylor to challenge Ley after Coalition reunion</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/something-has-to-happen-pressure-on-taylor-to-challenge-ley-after-coalition-reunion/ovdzpg740</link><description>A senior Liberal says the party is &amp;quot;now at irrelevance&amp;quot; after dire opinion polling, stoking fears of a leadership spill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4881d01fa0ba1574acce7eb6928a6c8a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Something has to happen&amp;apos;: Pressure on Taylor to challenge Ley after Coalition reunion</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/coalition-is-restored-but-liberals-stare-down-next-crisis-as-support-for-one-nation-surges/ovdzpg740</link><description>A senior Liberal says the party is &amp;quot;now at irrelevance&amp;quot; after dire opinion polling, stoking fears of a leadership spill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4b0084f799728020031c554c415e0b1</guid></item><item><title>WA communities &amp;apos;dodge a bullet&amp;apos; after Cyclone Mitchell weakens as it nears coast</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cyclone-mitchell-downgraded-but-continues-to-pummel-west-australias-coast/xzlcxq7rb</link><description>WA Premier Roger Cook said it was &amp;quot;good news&amp;quot; the system had been downgraded to a category one, but urged locals to be vigilant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37f10261a77407eeda6659d3d745a9ea</guid></item><item><title>Japan&amp;apos;s Sanae Takaichi rides youth-led frenzy towards super majority after election win</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/japanese-pm-sanae-takaichi-set-to-win-supermajority-in-snap-election/jmyhsm2ra</link><description>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi&amp;apos;s governing coalition has won more than two-thirds of the lower house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62574bb338cb22bf2348fe79577e121e</guid></item><item><title>Japan&amp;apos;s Sanae Takaichi rides youth-led frenzy towards super majority after election win</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/japanese-pm-sanae-takaichi-set-to-win-super-majority-in-snap-election/jmyhsm2ra</link><description>Japanese Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi&amp;apos;s governing coalition has won more than two-thirds of the lower house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a04434700daa7998c16ba8948055de35</guid></item><item><title>Israeli President Isaac Herzog arrives in Australia to welcome embrace and rally rage</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-president-arrives-court-decision-on-protest-expected-soon/wcr3lu11s</link><description>NSW Premier Chris Minns declared Herzog&amp;apos;s visit as a major event — granting police extra powers to block movement in Sydney&amp;apos;s city centre.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e769af49dab6f58638ecd7b83b36c2ee</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;A guilty plea under duress&amp;apos;: Jailed Christchurch massacre shooter to appeal conviction</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jailed-christchurch-massacre-shooter-to-appeal-conviction/g8wl4a15z</link><description>An Australian man killed 51 Muslim worshippers and injured dozens in the worst mass shooting in New Zealand&amp;apos;s history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1580f129b0137e8a2e16e77799be4699</guid></item><item><title>Who is Michael Dickson, the Australian who just claimed Super Bowl glory?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/who-is-michael-dickson-the-australian-vying-for-super-bowl-glory/f6xzz3df5</link><description>Overlooked by the AFL, Dickson has become just the second Australian to play in and win one of the world&amp;apos;s biggest sports events.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a21d4aa7191da073808fc84b070b1c0e</guid></item><item><title>Australian researchers on a mission to save millions of lives from antibiotic resistance</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australian-researchers-on-a-mission-to-save-millions-of-lives-from-antibiotic-resistance/ur9klrb22</link><description>The rise of antibiotic resistance is threatening millions of lives worldwide, but “unconventional” Australian research could make obsolete medications effective again. Data released by the World Health Organization (WHO) has found that some of the most common illnesses in the world are becoming more resistant to treatment every year. Dr Maud Eijkenboom says the current approach of developing new antibiotics is losing the battle against ever-evolving viruses and bacteria. After her son struggled with a resistant disease, Dr Eijkenboom set on her own path to discover a better way eradicate the rising wave of lethal pathogens. In 2021, she founded Lixa, a Perth-based biotech company receiving international support for its “game-changing” research. In this edition of Weekend One on One, she speaks with SBS&amp;apos;s Cameron Carr about the impact of her research, and started by explaining what Lixa is all about.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddacb0ccac6e8eba690382971431687b</guid></item><item><title>Japan&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;Iron Lady&amp;quot; Takaichi secures sweeping mandate for conservative agenda in landslide election</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/japans-iron-lady-takaichi-secures-sweeping-mandate-for-conservative-agenda-in-landslide-election/zldf0e2it</link><description>Japan&amp;apos;s Prime Minister Sanae Takaichi has won the country&amp;apos;s election In a landslide victory, with her party expected to secure a more than two-thirds majority in the powerful lower house. Takaichi&amp;apos;s government will push for greater defence spending, tougher immigration policies, and a stronger economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">212a978e969cbfc9a11ac837509eb8e7</guid></item><item><title>Premier Minns urges calm over protest against Herzog visit | Midday News Bulletin 9 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/premier-minns-urges-calm-over-protest-against-herzog-visit-midday-news-bulletin-9-february-2026/94n57vl2b</link><description>The New South Wales Premier urges calm in the face of protests over the Israeli President&amp;apos;s Sydney visit; Sussan Ley denies speculation she will be removed as Opposition leader, as the Coalition reunites; and in sport, American skiing legend Lindsey Vonn has surgery after a crash at the Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50d7aa6a5c8f053d7f3212a4d1a08a51</guid></item><item><title>Minneapolis Indigenous leaders, community, hold memorial service as US Senate debates ICE funding</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/minneapolis-indigenous-leaders-community-hold-memorial-service-as-us-senate-debates-ice-funding/22n0ihvc4</link><description>Indigenous leaders and community members in Minneapolis have held a memorial honouring two people shot dead by immigration officers last month. As protests against the widespread immigration crackdown continue, Republicans and Democrats remain locked in a standoff over reforms to Immigration and Customs Enforcement. The debate in the Senate continues as the deadline for reaching a funding agreement for the Department of Homeland Security looms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ded7b6b993927478a882474d14285633</guid></item><item><title>Australian food causes a stir at university canteen in Germany</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-food-causes-a-stir-at-university-canteen-in-germany/pusyh6g0i</link><description>Students in Germany were taken aback when an unexpected dish with a decidedly Australian flavour appeared on the menu in their canteen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5da371d5aa45ece583ea7f3d7845b1c0</guid></item><item><title>Call for calm over Herzog visit | SBS News In Easy English 9 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/call-for-calm-over-herzog-visit-sbs-news-in-easy-english-9-february-2026/ues26pex4</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0ae404a3d7da7e77a625bb358f67c78</guid></item><item><title>Danish apps help grocery shoppers boycott US goods</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/danish-apps-help-grocery-shoppers-boycott-us-goods/cs1any2ud</link><description>A Danish app born out of Donald Trump’s Greenland rhetoric is turning everyday grocery shopping into a quiet act of protest. As shoppers scan products to see where their money really goes, technology, politics and consumer choice collide, revealing how global tensions can play out not in parliaments or protests, but in supermarket aisles.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4df67e9aaeee3e1e096675f95ec9b310</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Effectively a death sentence&amp;apos;: Rights groups condemn Jimmy Lai&amp;apos;s 20-year prison term</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/effectively-a-death-sentence-rights-groups-condemn-jimmy-lais-20-year-prison-term/wxpdjblqt</link><description>The Hong Kong pro-democracy media mogul had been found guilty on two counts of foreign collusion, to which he pleaded not guilty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">607b88b10d36ee0c9a7601b7397ef014</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We will be wiped out&amp;apos;: Support for Coalition at record low</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/we-will-be-wiped-out-support-for-coalition-at-record-low/u4jgulinv</link><description>A new opinion poll has support for the Coalition at a record low with Opposition Leader Sussan Ley the least popular leader in 23 years. The poll comes a day after she and Nationals leader David Littleproud brokered a deal to reunite the Liberal and National parties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf8aa506f7eae21869ecbd2caffdd36e</guid></item><item><title>Controversy continues over the Israeli president&amp;apos;s visit | Evening News Bulletin 9 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/controversy-continues-over-the-israeli-presidents-visit-evening-news-bulletin-9-february-2026/p5tbp39ly</link><description>Controversy continues over the Israeli President&amp;apos;s visit; Hong Kong democracy activist Jimmy Lai sentenced to 20 years in jail; and in sport, Seattle Seahawks win a second Super Bowl title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">413abc36a67b85f61e8f8754da004759</guid></item><item><title>Extra police powers for Israeli president&amp;apos;s visit withstand legal challenge</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nsw-police-powers-israel-president-isaac-herzog-visit-result/c1ny4n1fq</link><description>Protest organisers Palestine Action Group launched legal action after Isaac Herzog&amp;apos;s visit was declared a major event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b13abc0779c76980b72c59b33790cd8</guid></item><item><title>Senate estimates wrap: AFP Herzog advice, minister&amp;apos;s $30K phone discount and condoms</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/30k-ministers-phone-bill-condoms-labor-grilled-in-senate-estimates/jedyb5wva</link><description>A minister&amp;apos;s $30,000 phone bill discount has been scrutinised as Labor faces another Senate estimates week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c743d3575b9b841a81f1bb4e046e6b3</guid></item><item><title>ASX has best day since Donald Trump&amp;apos;s Liberation Day</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asx-has-best-day-since-donald-trumps-liberation-day/w2jrhqh7n</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with George Boubouras from K2 Asset Management to find out why the market has been so volatile of late as he takes a closer look at how investors will be analysing AI investments during the upcoming reporting season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38ee44694ea4b2132970caafae55be80</guid></item><item><title>The world is running out of antibiotics. New research could make old ones work again</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-research-combatting-antibiotic-resistance/6s3a7lbvu</link><description>Australian research could be key to combating the rising threat of antibiotic resistance and saving millions of lives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eb0080b414afd1d16b5c5178910dc25</guid></item><item><title>Police pepper spray, arrest Herzog demonstrators at Sydney Town Hall | Morning News Bulletin 10 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/police-pepper-spray-arrest-herzog-demonstrators-at-sydney-town-hall-morning-news-bulletin-10-february-2026/p356owis4</link><description>Protesters and police clash in demonstrations against Israeli president&amp;apos;s visit to Australia; Hong Kong authorities defend the jailing of pro-democracy activist Jimmy Lai; and in sport, the Seattle Seahawks win the US Super Bowl.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0d71dc2275ad5ef19b081f317161f72</guid></item><item><title>Tensions linger as protesters gather outside Sydney police station</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/police-clash-with-protesters-as-thousands-rally-against-president-herzogs-visit/ysljl9ehd</link><description>Demonstrators gathered outside Surry Hills Police Station on Tuesday, a day after clashes with officers at Sydney&amp;apos;s Town Hall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">079a59378101fce626d25b89d3b4811a</guid></item><item><title>Australia opposes Israel&amp;apos;s plan to expand control in West Bank, government says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/international-condemnation-of-new-israeli-settlement-measures-in-west-bank-grows/qp1uyfvw2</link><description>Israeli government minister Bezalel Smotrich said the changes were aimed at &amp;quot;burying the idea of a Palestinian state&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1800a5986b494c6f049820d83fd7184a</guid></item><item><title>Roblox put on notice over &amp;apos;disturbing&amp;apos; child grooming reports</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/roblox-put-on-notice-over-disturbing-child-grooming-reports/op1usxr7v</link><description>The eSafety Commissioner has told the gaming platform it needs to take action after reports of children being targeted by predators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2334b61ff97d7cd1278ed87b9a877e62</guid></item><item><title>Arrests made as protests against Israeli President&amp;apos;s visit turn chaotic</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/arrests-made-as-protests-against-israeli-presidents-visit-turn-chaotic/xer5cm9cd</link><description>Dozens of people have been arrested after a demonstration against Israel&amp;apos;s visiting president descended into chaos. New South Wales Police say 10 of the 27 people arrested on Monday night were taken into custody for assaulting police, while witnesses have alleged that some officers were seen beating and deploying pepper spray at attendees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fce4e8af6789d7ce161b01125f9ad721</guid></item><item><title>Islamophobia envoy calls for apology over Sydney prayer incident; Minns defends police</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/completely-unacceptable-muslim-groups-condemn-police-over-sydney-protest-incident/dg2f2fh2z</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s Islamophobia envoy has issued a strong rebuke after NSW police officers confronted a group of men praying at a protest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76101097b03376ba5589a4cc1f056afd</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Feyza Tuncay on helping children learn about ethics</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-feyza-tuncay-on-helping-children-learn-about-ethics/xclgycqpn</link><description>Primary Ethics is an independent, not-for-profit organisation and provides ethics classes for school students across New South Wales. Classes are impartially run by volunteers and the program has been implemented in hundreds of schools. Facilitator Feyza Tuncay became involved with Primary Ethics when she started volunteering as an ethics teacher at her son&amp;apos;s school. She&amp;apos;s speaking here to SBS News&amp;apos; Jennifer Scherer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">268724697e16b201da31d7cc619f1c60</guid></item><item><title>NSW Premier defends police actions at Herzog protest | Midday News Bulletin 10 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nsw-premier-defends-police-actions-at-herzog-protest-midday-news-bulletin-10-february-2026/58ohy4gpx</link><description>New South Wales Premier defends police response at Sydney protest against Israeli president&amp;apos;s visit; Members of the crossbench call for policy to repair social media algorithms; And in sport, Snowboarding history made as two Australian women finish in top 10 for the first time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f731c8e0d4af1a4899d76cd389e8b391</guid></item><item><title>King Charles ready to help police with inquiries into brother Andrew, palace says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/buckingham-palace-ready-to-assist-with-uk-police-inquiries-into-king-charless-brother-andrew/q8hlp0jnp</link><description>Former prince Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor has faced ongoing scrutiny over his relationship with Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2767d357f2fea9160752948bab689875</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong defends 20 year sentence against China critic Jimmy Lai</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/hong-kong-defends-20-year-sentence-against-china-critic-jimmy-lai/t29mlq4wh</link><description>Hong Kong&amp;apos;s most vocal China critic, media tycoon Jimmy Lai, has been sentenced to 20 years in prison, ending the city&amp;apos;s largest national security case. Mr Lai&amp;apos;s sentence on two counts of conspiracy to collude with foreign forces and one for publishing seditious materials ends a legal saga that has lasted nearly five years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29d25dad253cc77ccc8e595e73be3093</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I won&amp;apos;t walk away&amp;apos;: Starmer stands firm amid ongoing Epstein scandal in UK</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/i-wont-walk-away-starmer-stands-firm-amid-ongoing-epstein-scandal-in-uk/ftvek3byi</link><description>The Jeffrey Epstein saga has continued to make headlines. UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer has come under new pressure to resign, amid an expanding scandal over his appointment of Peter Mandelson as ambassador to the US despite ties to Epstein. The latest tranche of files relating to the convicted sex offender have also brought new scrutiny to former prince Andrew, with UK police assessing reports he sent sensitive information to Epstein. Epstein associate Ghislaine Maxwell has refused to testify before a US congressional committee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95f3ff7b23d907e0946bb8b32df8f0e5</guid></item><item><title>Premier Minns defends police response to rally against Herzog visit | SBS News In Easy English 10 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/premier-minns-defends-police-response-to-rally-against-herzog-visit-sbs-news-in-easy-english-10-february-2026/2wbakjozd</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c427b94df7646ffd126727af34311448</guid></item><item><title>DFAT admits it &amp;apos;fell short&amp;apos; after Laos methanol poisoning victims&amp;apos; families left in the dark</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dfat-apologises-to-families-of-australian-methanol-poisoning-victims-in-laos/5232sikwp</link><description>The apology comes after the families of the victims revealed they learned of a related court case from another victim&amp;apos;s family.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6189744cd7cdcf749b06b0725bdde69</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Speaks of colonialism&amp;apos;: Why Bad Bunny&amp;apos;s performance resonated around the world</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bad-bunny-performance-symbolism/ohcs33wc9</link><description>Riddled with easter eggs, the show brought Puerto Rican history and culture to one of the biggest platforms on the planet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d33e9956f6b300d662f0ccf9cb0a3039</guid></item><item><title>PM defends President Herzog’s visit as he issues call for calm | Evening News Bulletin 10 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pm-defends-president-herzogs-visit-as-he-issues-call-for-calm-evening-news-bulletin-10-february-2026/ov50bfhvb</link><description>Anthony Albanese defends President Isaac Herzog&amp;apos;s visit as he issues call for calm; government unveils policy to end violence against First Nations women and children; and in cricket, Pakistan reverses its boycott and agrees to play against India in the T20 World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45bdcf74719b15338c48180a2d8cb177</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Lopsided&amp;apos; foreign worker scheme under fire as most of the money stays in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lopsided-foreign-worker-scheme-where-most-of-the-money-stays-in-australia-under-fire/9q6geobwm</link><description>The PALM labour scheme is under renewed scrutiny after new analysis warned the program carries modern slavery risks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17bec57c73eed7f29b93f7a215309b0b</guid></item><item><title>Government unveils policy to end violence against First Nations women and children</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/government-unveils-policy-to-end-violence-against-first-nations-women-and-children/ehc1ne8tx</link><description>The Federal Government has launched a landmark $218 million national plan to end violence against First Nations women and children. It marks the first long-term strategy designed and led entirely by Indigenous communities. While the policy targets specialised healing and emergency services in remote areas, community leaders warn that real change also requires confronting the systemic racism and high rates of violence perpetrated by non-Indigenous men.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a337e7cf92c43daa725c347b739bb17c</guid></item><item><title>AI industry risks and the Australian dollar nears US$0.71</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ai-industry-risks-and-the-australian-dollar-nears-us-0-71/e0v4hjw1g</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Todd Hoare from LGT Wealth Management about the day&amp;apos;s market moves including the increasing risks AI poses to certain industries, what&amp;apos;s driving the Australian dollar, and the opportunities for investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcfb280b8a7410191b5c512619b6629a</guid></item><item><title>What we know about Israel&amp;apos;s damage to Gaza cemetery housing Australian war graves</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-war-graves-destroyed-israel-gaza/rmimxni60</link><description>The graves include those of Australian Light Horse troops, a World War One force known for their role in the Battle of Beersheba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1f855981e68ab0d9caecb14bcadee69</guid></item><item><title>I was violently attacked on a busy street. Ashamed, I kept it a secret for almost 20 years</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/i-was-attacked-on-a-busy-street-i-kept-it-a-secret-for-almost-20-years/qqt73a9jw</link><description>Emmanuella Grace felt invincible living and working in London. This changed one night when two seemingly friendly men approached her.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ea966289dd3a80c387509bb91e0f668</guid></item><item><title>Protest held at Surry Hills police station over officers&amp;apos; tactics | Morning News Bulletin 11 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/protest-held-at-surry-hills-police-station-over-officers-tactics-morning-news-bulletin-11-february-2026/rw05bcanq</link><description>Protesters demand the release of several people arrested during a pro-Palestinian rally in Sydney; Epstein survivors unveil a bill to end statute of limitations on sex trafficking cases; and in sport, the Bangladesh Cricket Board urges Pakistan to withdraw its decision on Sunday&amp;apos;s match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2fb6e28b70060652f4acab83e61cb909</guid></item><item><title>Suspect detained in the disappearance of Nancy Guthrie, police say</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fbi-releases-footage-of-masked-intruder-at-nancie-guthries-home/f3spyvf13</link><description>Nancy Guthrie is the mother of Melbourne-born US TV host Savannah Guthrie, and has been missing for more than a week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94c56d2bd93917ac3f0f8e8702cc9b5a</guid></item><item><title>Could Keir Starmer become the first world leader to lose his job over the Epstein files?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/could-keir-starmer-lose-his-job-over-the-epstein-files/wn6nt2vuo</link><description>The UK prime minister is under pressure over hiring Jeffrey Epstein associate Peter Mandelson as the UK&amp;apos;s ambassador to the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7802a883425ab5f76b4fb5616d6d9328</guid></item><item><title>Albanese says he raised criminal charges over Zomi Frankcom&amp;apos;s killing with Isaac Herzog</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/zomi-frankcoms-brother-seeks-answers-from-israels-president-over-her-death-in-gaza/qglvohe2h</link><description>The prime minister said he raised Zomi Frankcom&amp;apos;s killing in an Israeli air strike directly with the Israeli president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31022be5beaad8bb6a5deb0ecbadcf5f</guid></item><item><title>Israeli minister urges protesters not to &amp;apos;import conflict&amp;apos;, defending Herzog visit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-minister-urges-protestors-not-to-import-conflict-defending-herzog-visit/br7wgmmsh</link><description>Israel&amp;apos;s deputy foreign minister has spoken out against the &amp;quot;absolutely heartbreaking&amp;quot; violence during protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69757c4fbb4dfd334d7a10840e0ac691</guid></item><item><title>Israeli minister urges protesters not to &amp;apos;import conflict&amp;apos;, defending Herzog visit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-minister-urges-protesters-not-to-import-conflict-defending-herzog-visit/br7wgmmsh</link><description>Israel&amp;apos;s deputy foreign minister has spoken out against the &amp;quot;absolutely heartbreaking&amp;quot; violence during protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">481eecaea0eaaff536eaffc476f1174e</guid></item><item><title>Grand Mufti calls for transparent investigation of police conduct at Sydney rally | Midday News Bulletin 11 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/grand-mufti-calls-for-transparent-investigation-of-police-conduct-at-sydney-rally-midday-news-bulletin-11-february-2026/6ww6rvzp1</link><description>The Grand Mufti of Australia calls for a transparent investigation of police conduct at a Sydney rally; the heads of America&amp;apos;s immigration agencies questioned at a hearing in Washington; and in sport, a Ukrainian athlete defies an Olympic ban on his helmet showing war victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa3edcc4b1fa245988f9cc3f34262d89</guid></item><item><title>US Congress criticises ICE enforcement as &amp;apos;reckless and creating chaos&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-congress-criticises-ice-enforcement-as-reckless-and-creating-chaos/n2e1srdag</link><description>A contentious hearing of the US House Committee on Homeland Security has exposed deep divisions over immigration enforcement following the death of two American citizens at the hands of Immigration and Customs Enforcrment, better known as ICE. While ICE officials framed the deaths as a result of officers facing increasing threats of harm, the argument was rejected with those holding the agency accountable, calling its tactics Gestapo-like.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd108b2fcc1be75f6a31a8c58e67b79e</guid></item><item><title>PM thanks Israeli president for providing &amp;apos;comfort&amp;apos;; Herzog describes &amp;apos;emotional&amp;apos; visit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/herzog-stresses-unity-in-fighting-antisemitism-as-pocock-joins-canberra-protests/zy5r6eei0</link><description>Anthony Albanese has praised the Israeli president and first lady for providing comfort to Jewish Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e801c74bb7d308cf1f515eebb817f7d</guid></item><item><title>PM thanks Israeli president for providing &amp;apos;comfort&amp;apos;; Herzog describes &amp;apos;emotional&amp;apos; visit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-thanks-herzog-for-providing-comfort-during-emotional-visit/zy5r6eei0</link><description>Anthony Albanese has praised the Israeli president and first lady for providing comfort to Jewish Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47951a8c67905d972255474f475a96dc</guid></item><item><title>Famine levels reached in two more regions of Sudan&amp;apos;s North Darfur, UN says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/famine-levels-reached-in-two-more-regions-of-sudans-north-darfur-un-says/s3trt0ypk</link><description>Acute malnutrition has now reached famine levels in two more regions of North Darfur in Sudan, according to a new report from a UN-backed global hunger monitor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cea59ac3308487846ffe05ecc6840f81</guid></item><item><title>Eight people killed after woman opens fire at high school in Canada, suspect found dead</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/british-columbia-shooting/ca2agz7xd</link><description>Police said the suspected shooter has also been found dead with &amp;quot;what appears to be a self‑inflicted injury&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a518c78cfa7b5e707fea61b781eaa79d</guid></item><item><title>Call for transparent investigation into police actions at Sydney rally | SBS News In Easy English 11 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/call-for-transparent-investigation-into-police-actions-at-sydney-rally-sbs-news-in-easy-english-11-february-2026/njfvkswi7</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a2da90cc1014340d0c4a24622d9935c</guid></item><item><title>Muslim worshippers say NSW police &amp;apos;came in like a wrecking ball&amp;apos; at Sydney protest</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/muslim-worshipperssay-nsw-police-came-in-like-a-wrecking-ball-at-sydney-protest/oqfxv0wte</link><description>Muslim worshippers who were praying at a Sydney protest say police intervened during a vulnerable moment of prayer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99064e255a4ed19217035e613249d91e</guid></item><item><title>Muslim worshippers say NSW police &amp;apos;came in like a wrecking ball&amp;apos; at Sydney protest</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/muslim-worshippers-say-nsw-police-came-in-like-a-wrecking-ball-at-sydney-protest/oqfxv0wte</link><description>Muslim worshippers who were praying at a Sydney protest say police intervened during a vulnerable moment of prayer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd1091ceba6ed356a5da3580c922dd5a</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police granted extra powers ahead of Herzog visit | Evening News Bulletin 11 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/victoria-police-granted-extra-powers-ahead-of-herzog-visit-evening-news-bulletin-11-february-2026/9pkn3gu77</link><description>Police granted extra powers ahead of the Israeli president&amp;apos;s visit to Melbourne; Ukraine&amp;apos;s ambassador to Australia calls for more support, as the country enters a fifth year of war.; and in football, Socceroo Mohammed Toure scores a hat-trick in his first start for Norwich City.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d83bd71911834f4c3cbf2cc46df6b581</guid></item><item><title>Review launched into the plan for Australia&amp;apos;s largest river ecosystem</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/review-launched-into-the-plan-for-australias-largest-river-ecosystem/vjp4kwsra</link><description>Public consultation has opened on a review into the management plan for the Murray–Darling Basin, Australia&amp;apos;s largest river system. The announcement has come weeks after Environment Minister Murray Watt listed the lower Murray River region as critically endangered. Conservation groups have reacted cautiously, saying they hope the review leads to decisive action for a Basin that underpins public health, regional livelihoods, and cultural connection for millions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73a39ed49e1eab014fe6a7416b4cb2d0</guid></item><item><title>ASIO and AFP face Senate questions about the Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asio-and-afp-face-senate-questions-about-the-bondi-terror-attack/qxc80pxqw</link><description>The Australian Security Intelligence Organisation and Australian Federal Police have been questioned about their actions before and after the Bondi terror attack, with Australia&amp;apos;s top spy agency defending its failure to prevent it. During a senate estimates hearing late on Tuesday night, the AFP also warned it will take a more aggressive approach to tackling hate and extremism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f891c0eb9dc9fc7365d5ea2803c9f082</guid></item><item><title>Israel&amp;apos;s President Herzog given official welcome in Canberra</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israels-president-herzog-given-official-welcome-in-canberra/5z8guuc6f</link><description>Israeli President Isaac Herzog has enjoyed a ceremonial welcome and a lunch with Prime Minister Anthony Albanese in Canberra. President Herzog and his wife, Michal, were given a ceremonial 21-gun salute by the Federation Guard before attending a garden function at the Israeli embassy. His visit has been dogged by protests, with demonstrators saying he should not have been invited in the first place,</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8486bb78f042e1cd2ca25590ef07797</guid></item><item><title>Trump allegedly said Ghislaine Maxwell is &amp;apos;evil&amp;apos;: What do we know about their relationship?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-called-maxwell-evil-in-resurfaced-interview-as-she-refuses-to-answer-questions-from-us-congress/rhjmukkc0</link><description>Ghislaine Maxwell&amp;apos;s attorney says she&amp;apos;s prepared to speak publicly if granted clemency by the US president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14c06cf670fff5242b674cc87b1badbe</guid></item><item><title>CBA&amp;apos;s Matt Comyn on why the disruptive potential of AI should not be underestimated</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/cbas-matt-comyn-on-why-the-disruptive-potential-of-ai-should-not-be-underestimated/uijydybwb</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Commonwealth Bank CEO Matt Comyn following the groups $5.45bn half- year cash profit announcement, including a deep dive into artificial technology and productivity; plus Luke Laretive from Seneca Financial Solutions takes a look at the day&amp;apos;s market action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acd93d068da2a996a59df085ba0f38ff</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor steps down ahead of expected Liberal leadership spill</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/angus-taylor-steps-down-ahead-of-sussan-ley-leadership-spill/vxzco24d8</link><description>Sussan Ley&amp;apos;s factional rival Angus Taylor has stepped down from the frontbench, but stopped short of declaring a Liberal Party spill.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c04745e3497bbb0a8ac9bad5da4f513e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Completely over the top&amp;apos;: How tensions built towards NSW police tactics at Sydney protest</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/protest-footage-raises-excessive-force-militarisation-questions-of-nsw-police/ib31jv0tv</link><description>Experts have pointed to new laws and increased police militarisation as factors leading to clashes in Sydney on Monday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5b81920bd4c359307f3e84e7c06dd72</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor resigns ahead of an expected Liberal leadership spill | Morning News Bulletin 12 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/angus-taylor-resigns-ahead-of-an-expected-liberal-leadership-spill-morning-news-bulletin-12-february-2026/prg2bra8y</link><description>Angus Taylor resigns ahead of an expected Liberal leadership spill; Millions of voters in Bangladesh prepare to go to the polls; And in football, Tottenham Hotspur sacks manager Thomas Frank after a poor Premier League run.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6eed8a9483c7f74092e9141e548ea3a5</guid></item><item><title>Instagram CEO defends platform against addiction claims in social media trial</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/instagram-ceo-defends-platform-against-addiction-claims-in-social-media-trial/tz3gq9tad</link><description>The landmark trial could set a legal precedent regarding whether social media giants deliberately designed platforms to be addictive to children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1de255b92f436be32c919317573b150</guid></item><item><title>James Van Der Beek, Dawson&amp;apos;s Creek star, dies aged 48</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dawsons-creek-star-james-van-der-beek/vggo9supc</link><description>The American actor&amp;apos;s family said he &amp;quot;passed peacefully&amp;quot; following a battle with cancer he disclosed in 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d35fc981fdcfc40b9aa325edcd1ea05</guid></item><item><title>Landmark European space launch aims to begin to challenge Elon Musk&amp;apos;s SpaceX</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/landmark-european-space-launch-aims-to-begin-to-challenge-elon-musks-spacex/nq0y12no8</link><description>On Thursday, the four-booster Ariane 64 is scheduled to lift off from French Guiana on its maiden flight. This powerful version of the Ariane 6 rocket will carry 32 satellites for Amazon Leo’s broadband constellation. At a time when the United States is seen as a potentially unreliable partner, this is a key milestone in Europe’s effort to secure independent access to space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5e7aa4e41d5b6b39518860db1678ba4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Left our nation in shock&amp;apos;: Canada in mourning after mass shooting</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/left-our-nation-in-shock-canada-in-mourning-after-mass-shooting/b6vig9bxq</link><description>Canadians are grappling with the deaths of at least nine people, including the suspect, after a mass school shooting in a remote town.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c27da64b0b1c0e2f96f18d1e90eb5e95</guid></item></channel></rss>