<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>SBS English News (Unofficial Aggregation)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 14:12:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 6 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-6-october-2025/22ssjf5lu</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">645ce9f66c6f1ad98a25360b9cd23743</guid></item><item><title>Australian claims dislocated arm from soldiers in prison called Israel&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;worst&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-prison-thunberg-australians-flotilla-ketziot-prison/4k67kxy2j</link><description>Ketziot prison was once called the &amp;quot;largest and the worst&amp;quot; of Israel&amp;apos;s prisons by Human Rights Watch. There are welfare concerns for Australians detained there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3479ab3351f4cc7f88d1ea8e3eb0dcfd</guid></item><item><title>Gold and copper prices surge and why you shouldn’t ignore your annual super statement</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gold-and-copper-prices-surge-and-why-you-shouldnt-ignore-your-annual-super-statement/ycyf7efc7</link><description>The ASX-200 has started the week in the red, as a tech sell-off offset strong gains by gold and copper miners. Plus, Japanese stocks have hit a record high just a day after the country’s ruling Liberal Democratic Party named Sanae Takaichi as its leader. For more, Rena Sarumpaet spoke with George Boubouras from K2 Asset Management. As annual superannuation statements start to arrive in the mail, Australians are being urged to not ignore them with research from Canstar showing about a fifth of respondents only check their super once every few years - or never. For more on how a financial health check could benefit your nest egg, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Canstar Data Insights Director Sally Tindall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf769f3e207d0282dbc7a810668680f0</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Fighting a war on two fronts&amp;apos;: Behind the rise of a new threat in Gaza</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hamas-influence-is-waning-in-gaza-palestinians-fear-armed-gangs-more/nz8wiwgfy</link><description>Newly released data shows a major spike in intra-Palestinian violent incidents this year, as well as a significant rise in stolen aid packages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e010bbb46bdb0e33ece03d84dbb1b80a</guid></item><item><title>The unseen impact of missing or damaged teeth — and the key to addressing it</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/unseen-impact-of-dental-issues/qxmy885wl</link><description>Why is it so shameful to have missing teeth or gum disease? And what can we do about it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5c6536419384386081ada9d87c84a61</guid></item><item><title>University students panicked after fraudulent emails &amp;apos;revoked&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;disqualified&amp;apos; degrees</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/western-sydney-university-hacks-scams-fraudulent-emails/9qa23rd0r</link><description>Western Sydney University said the emails are &amp;quot;not legitimate&amp;quot; and have been reported to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52ce0f86abd8ab03886197cfd7efdcee</guid></item><item><title>Advocates alarmed as major change for autistic kids looms</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/advocates-alarmed-as-major-change-for-autistic-kids-looms/n2rj2ev77</link><description>There are fears that many children with autism or learning difficulties will fall between the cracks of a new support system that aims to limit access to the National Disability Insurance Scheme. The Thriving Kids initiative will be rolled out from the middle of next year, with a focus on providing support to children with so-called mild to moderate autism within community and mainstream settings. But disability advocates have told a parliamentary inquiry it is these children that are most often overlooked or misunderstood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbcbfc97c8481df7a17e0c2a379464dc</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 7 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-7-october-2025/pj6h2owkh</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76159309e4392687a2c1f21694cde629</guid></item><item><title>GP snapshot reveals why the job has become more complicated</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gp-snapshot-reveals-why-the-job-has-become-more-complicated/qpql0lgde</link><description>A snapshot of Australian general practice has revealed that GPs are having to see patients for longer appointments to treat more complex medical needs. The Health of the Nation industry survey of almost 2,500 GPs also shows a growing number of general practitioners are managing patient conditions typically handled by specialists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c160cb3c86a6aded30a18e7d0e9289a</guid></item><item><title>ASIC approves ASX listing market competitor; is AI in a bubble? and gold approaches US$4,000</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asic-approves-asx-listing-market-competitor-is-ai-in-a-bubble-and-gold-approaches-us-4-000/15pn8lg7y</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Todd Hoare from LGT Wealth Management Australia Management about the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action, including ASIC&amp;apos;s approval of Cboe Australia&amp;apos;s listing market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a14fecba3f407f02c5f75ddaca796de3</guid></item><item><title>Government fast-tracks legislation to strengthen 000 call system</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/government-fast-tracks-legislation-to-strengthen-000-call-system/w83hkwzos</link><description>The government has fast-tracked legislation into parliament aimed at strengthening the 000 call system after failures by Optus to ensure access to emergency calls. As parliament resumed, the nation&amp;apos;s leaders made time to commemorate the second anniversary of the October 7 attack on Israel by Hamas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eae27ff927fc8446f700e60af6c28d2</guid></item><item><title>Minister urged to &amp;apos;come clean&amp;apos; on NDIS changes, as advocates fear &amp;apos;degrading&amp;apos; treatment</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/minister-urged-to-come-clean-on-upcoming-ndis-changes/6rtqr6kj3</link><description>Disability advocates are demanding clarity on upcoming NDIS changes, warning that the new system could be &amp;quot;traumatising&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35ef37fb66b60de2f07e0b9551334b12</guid></item><item><title>Home Affairs knew for months &amp;apos;ISIS brides&amp;apos; were returning; granted children citizenship</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/government-reveals-it-knew-for-months-that-women-children-were-returning-from-syria/25rhks9h4</link><description>The federal government says the group, who arrived in Australia recently, are being monitored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7be85bee82432c5f464de873b190365f</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 8 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-8-october-2025/whwmm56t5</link><description>A daily news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2117dd9198b3e40c0ee5a7ff6776e2e4</guid></item><item><title>Australian flotilla activist accuses government of &amp;apos;shameful&amp;apos; Israel extraction effort</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-gaza-aid-flotilla-detained-israel-government-response/k0z6te9ta</link><description>Australians were detained at what has been called an &amp;quot;outrageous&amp;quot; prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1257d9945cbeacdd1dfcb0ead12bf2fb</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s cancer survival rates are improving — but there are also some &amp;apos;concerning&amp;apos; trends</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cancer-survival-rates-increasing-concerning-trends/2pv0jmxyg</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s latest snapshot of cancer incidence and deaths has been released.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">107c68cb639ee7a8a33619366761bd82</guid></item><item><title>Gold breaks US$4,000 &amp;amp; is NZ becoming a better value tourist destination?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gold-breaks-us-4-000-is-nz-becoming-a-better-value-tourist-destination/4wphc7m2n</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Armina Rosenberg from Minotaur Capital about the day&amp;apos;s market action, including gold&amp;apos;s new milestone and how her firm is using AI to invest; plus Nick Tuffley from ASB Bank goes through why the RBNZ cut interest rates more than expected and what it means for Australian travellers going to New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">075d064fad7859a126dc1ae41b3a59f0</guid></item><item><title>Communications minister accused of misleading parliament over Optus notification</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/communications-minister-accused-of-misleading-parliament-over-optus-notification/esnv5jsxx</link><description>The federal opposition has accused Communications Minister Anika Wells of misleading parliament over when her office was notified of the Optus Triple-Zero outage that has been linked to four deaths. It comes as emails that Optus sent to notify the government and the regulator of the outages, which ultimately affected more than 600 people last month, are scrutinised in Senate estimates. Meanwhile, legislation creating a triple-zero custodian has passed the lower house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7070d12aef1f94469b2c63613df90df</guid></item><item><title>There&amp;apos;s a difference between hot and cold sweat — and one tends to smell more distinctive</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hot-cold-sweat-whats-the-difference/zqv96pzqv</link><description>Cold sweat is known as psychological sweat, while hot sweat is often the body&amp;apos;s response to physical exertion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b581aa783d42878f5bfb52f06e2a6573</guid></item><item><title>Could Donald Trump win the 2025 Nobel Peace Prize?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/can-donald-trump-win-2025-nobel-peace-prize/jd8qsc5o2</link><description>Leaders seeking to curry favour with Trump have been quick to talk up the US president&amp;apos;s chances, but experts aren&amp;apos;t so sure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0a4240ebbb17289ba0358cae532feac</guid></item><item><title>What we&amp;apos;ve learnt about the &amp;apos;ISIS brides&amp;apos;, as federal police anticipate more returns</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-weve-learnt-about-the-isis-brides-as-federal-police-anticipate-more-returns/azsbkp5dj</link><description>The Australian Federal Police said the group, which has returned from Syria, was being monitored as part of an ongoing operation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">095473ab291891ba39d99c9b49418bbc</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 9 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-9-october-2025/smjkdc3tt</link><description>A daily news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f36918c138d94a0d8745616a3fb46ba</guid></item><item><title>New workplace laws aim to remove extra pain burden on parents arising from stillbirth</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-workplace-laws-aim-to-remove-extra-pain-burden-on-parents-arising-from-stillbirth/yxxby73uk</link><description>Laws have been introduced into federal parliament to stop employers from scrapping leave entitlements when families face the tragedy of a stillbirth or death of their baby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e463603d4aa7c01baf13de3111cf7ff7</guid></item><item><title>The common mortgage feature that could be leaving you &amp;apos;worse off&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-common-mortgage-feature-that-could-be-leaving-you-worse-off/353pu5cpx</link><description>Mortgage offset accounts have helped many Australians wipe interest off their home loan. But they don&amp;apos;t always offer a benefit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee442e3b846b3c3009e9a69f6380e9a2</guid></item><item><title>Gaza peace deal market impacts &amp;amp; Gemini crypto exchange enters Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gaza-peace-deal-market-impacts-gemini-crypto-exchange-enters-australia/cn4wgwr7z</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Robert Talevski to see how the Gaza peace deal has impacted markets; and Ricardo takes a look at Australia&amp;apos;s crypto regulatory space with Gemini&amp;apos;s Saad Ahmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32dadee138ba4452c8f55df884a185c7</guid></item><item><title>A Gaza peace deal signed; au revoir to yet another French PM; &amp;amp; Australia&amp;apos;s new security alliance</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-gaza-peace-deal-signed-au-revoir-to-yet-another-french-pm-australias-new-security-alliance/qpvku4bvv</link><description>Hamas and Israel sign up for Phase One of Trump&amp;apos;s new 20-point plan for peace in Gaza. France&amp;apos;s revolving door on its prime ministerial office takes another spin. Plus Australia and PNG sign on to an expanded alliance for regional cooperation. And how desperate for $5,000 are you? Take a job at a haunted hotel desperate?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8242392b02a0cd65357a0346f8e7e0dc</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;It felt like home&amp;apos;: Why generations of migrant Australians love the NPL</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-championship-2025-npl-clubs-vying-for-a-league/e8w984a52</link><description>Once the lifeblood of migrant communities, suburban football clubs are back on the national stage for the Australian Championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d609837651a1452d9f46ac7ed2f3256</guid></item><item><title>What’s the Senate actually estimating? Ft. David Pocock</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/whats-the-senate-actually-estimating-ft-david-pocock/mh2g41en3</link><description>The first senate estimates of the 48th Parliament have arrived – where the Albanese Labor Government and representatives from the Australian Public Service and government agencies are quizzed for up to 14 hours a day about pretty much anything. It’s tedious, it’s long, but it’s all about accountability, and Independent Senator for the ACT David Pocock takes us behind the scenes. Plus Bob Katter has a suggestion for the footy off-season, and Andrew Hastie has left the Coalition front bench.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf65a9ae21431245bb073149e8e14804</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Safe beds save lives&amp;apos;: Calls for urgent action to address rising number of homeless women</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/calls-for-urgent-action-to-address-rising-rates-of-homeless-women/guxjs58zb</link><description>Australians are being urged to recognise the link between domestic violence and homelessness, as more women face sleeping rough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4c2cda473f27360e0af7ffd236102d0</guid></item><item><title>Are Syria’s first post-Assad elections strengthening or weakening democracy?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/are-syrias-first-post-assad-elections-strengthening-or-weakening-democracy/ba0rd6man</link><description>Syria&amp;apos;s first parliamentary elections since the fall of Bashar al-Assad have sparked criticism for how they were run. The election was seen as a key step in the shift away from the al-Assad regime, but one that has sparked concerns about inclusivity and fairness under the country&amp;apos;s new leaders. Syrians here in Australia say their relatives at home do not feel represented by the new Government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1324997c4daa234662dcdf368f87293c</guid></item><item><title>Peace in the Middle East greeted with joy across the divide</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/peace-in-the-middle-east-greeted-with-joy-across-the-divide/f6r5yfx3w</link><description>After two years of devastating conflict, there are scenes of cautious celebration across the Middle East. A historic ceasefire deal between Israel and Hamas, brokered by US President Donald Trump, has been reached, in effect, marking what some are calling a new chapter of peace.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4091d5c843b7e47882f975b4d3b36f69</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 10 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-10-october-2025/ox4745edi</link><description>A daily news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">461f5ff0895d21df54b3565c645bef89</guid></item><item><title>Tsunami threat passes after powerful earthquake strikes Philippines</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tsunami-warning-issued-after-magnitude-7-4-earthquake-strikes-philippines/rojk438gt</link><description>A tsunami alert for the Philippines, Palau and Indonesia has been lifted following a magnitude 7.4 earthquake south of the Philippines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eae9b3947c5305856ff6eafe0f99b2be</guid></item><item><title>How a &amp;apos;deeply-embedded&amp;apos; part of Australian culture could change forever</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-young-people-drinking-less/5evzgqh3h</link><description>Young Australians are leading this emerging generational shift, according to a new study.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37ff3efc37c81ed4a2b915dfbbae5f8c</guid></item><item><title>The looming Europe travel change that will affect Australians</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-looming-europe-travel-change-that-will-affect-australians/vcw4eeb3k</link><description>New personal data collection rules are about to come into effect in Europe&amp;apos;s Schengen area. Here&amp;apos;s what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8915e4cc6bb110563107cac201a2909</guid></item><item><title>Silver at highest since 1980 &amp;amp; how markets are reacting to Gaza peace deal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/silver-at-highest-since-1980-how-markets-are-reacting-to-gaza-peace-deal/629kn57mq</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Zoran Kresovic from Blueberry Markets about the day&amp;apos;s market action, including how investors are feeling following the potential Gaza peace deal, the future for gold and the outlook for silver, which hit a near 45 year high.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d1d05bfb6622d4a8698efb5d64f8f82</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan opposition figure María Corina Machado awarded Nobel Peace Prize</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/venezuelan-opposition-figure-maria-corina-machado-awarded-nobel-peace-prize/1mib232vu</link><description>Machado had been forced into hiding but remained in Venezuela, a choice that &amp;quot;inspired millions&amp;quot;, the Nobel Committee chair said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5e492e919ad601ea5669d16343048c1</guid></item><item><title>Displaced Gazans stream back to their destroyed homes after ceasefire comes into effect</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gaza-ceasefire-in-effect-gazans-return/47a4beep2</link><description>A massive column of displaced Gazans filed north through the dust towards Gaza City after the ceasefire came into effect at midday Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fa4b0c30e87f775a6a0bd207e3bf44c</guid></item><item><title>Saving money and packing &amp;apos;go bags&amp;apos;: How Australians in the US are preparing for the worst</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-living-in-america-anxiety/p88o60wos</link><description>With changes to visas and growing scrutiny of foreign nationals, Australians in the US say they feel uncertain about their futures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d92df2c543967f34a3a2a80e74842b9</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s potato capital is facing a threat never-before-seen in the country</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/potato-mop-top-virus-management/hsbsfzew1</link><description>With eradication off the table, Australia is looking to New Zealand for lessons on how to manage potato mop top virus as planting begins in Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c375078453cf75cec49b0f1ccf3cd88e</guid></item><item><title>Hopes Gaza ceasefire will lead to drop in &amp;apos;dehumanisation and othering&amp;apos; in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hope-gaza-ceasefire-will-drop-dehumanisation-and-othering/ergaf1xko</link><description>The race discrimination commissioner hopes the Gaza ceasefire will lessen division at home but says &amp;quot;problems will remain&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79ef9413da5d1e22c283740b8f1a8ca0</guid></item><item><title>Clean-up begins in Philippines after at least eight killed in twin earthquakes</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/clean-up-begins-in-philippines-after-at-least-eight-killed-in-twin-earthquakes/hlog6tmyu</link><description>Some residents in Mindanao slept outdoors in fear of aftershocks after 7.4 and 6.7-magnitude earthquakes struck off the coast on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26a55f5ff6d8ae561174db3023b2e9f5</guid></item><item><title>North Korea shows off its &amp;apos;most powerful&amp;apos; missile at parade with Russian, Chinese top brass</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/north-korea-parades-its-most-powerful-missile-at-a-military-parade-attended-by-top-russian-and-china/22aulkt16</link><description>Kim Jong Un welcomed top Russian and Chinese officials to the event marking 80 years of North Korean rule under the Workers&amp;apos; Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8c3dcc4004306661593f57b1a5ce32c</guid></item><item><title>Casper takes a drug that helps him grow. But the treatment is controversial</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/casper-takes-a-drug-that-helps-him-grow-but-the-treatment-is-controversial/72242cs13</link><description>A controversial drug Australia had a key role in developing continues to bring hope - and frustration – for the short-statured community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f6752e3ad0558ffcc086d892ca1397b</guid></item><item><title>Not just magpies: The other birds swooping you this season — and why they do it</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/swooping-birds-magpies-spring/rjw9tyy7h</link><description>Magpies may have perfected the art of swooping, but they&amp;apos;re not the only Australian bird diving on unsuspecting humans this spring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac2a97d7785b3c241eafd24952f2dad4</guid></item><item><title>California sends ultraprocessed school meals to the sin bin</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/california-sends-ultraprocessed-school-meals-to-the-sin-bin/oqmx7iqdc</link><description>California is to phase out certain ultraprocessed foods from school meals over the next decade under a first-in-the-nation law signed by Governor Gavin Newsom. Schools will have to start removing those foods from their menus by July 2029, and districts will be barred from selling them for breakfast or lunch by July 2035.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e29626fd5f4127e4148022381379bafd</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;All over the place&amp;apos;: Concerns over Qantas hacked data access as airline investigates</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/its-all-over-the-place-qantas-customer-data-leaked/yfa1yeucc</link><description>One cybersecurity expert says the stolen data might be available not just on the dark web, but also on the clear web.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e041d61ae2264ebcb23c839e668acd6c</guid></item><item><title>Why pro-Palestinian protesters say they will continue to march despite Gaza ceasefire</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-protesters-in-support-of-palestinians-say-theyll-continue-to-march-amid-a-gaza-ceasefire/irzowzg40</link><description>Dozens of rallies took place across the country on Sunday, with some protesters expressing concern the ceasefire would not hold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d12ea31494d7af73188787790b379c7</guid></item><item><title>I asked a mortgage broker what median first home buyers can get with a 5% deposit (not much)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/i-asked-a-mortgage-broker-what-median-first-home-buyers-can-get-with-a-5-deposit-not-much/986cxo8k6</link><description>First home buyers can get into the housing market with a 5 per cent deposit - but are there hidden pitfalls they may not be aware of? We asked an expert to crunch the numbers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4ae1e8af7eaf6e3e9f25e9709f3e610</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I felt alone&amp;apos;: Inside the &amp;apos;invisible&amp;apos; loss one in three Australian women endure</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/i-felt-alone-inside-the-invisible-loss-one-in-three-australian-women-endure/d97d2me8d</link><description>Organisations that help women through miscarriages are looking forward to seeing a national pregnancy loss register to address what they say is an invisibility around the true scale of the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cc6a40abb4cdb96b172f7ec1cb137a5</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Gaza &amp;apos;war is over&amp;apos; as Israel awaits release of hostages amid ceasefire</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ceasefire-holds-in-gaza-ahead-of-hostage-release-and-trumps-visit-to-israel/7ts6fyvou</link><description>Israeli officials said they expect the hostage release to start around 2-3pm AEDT.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8c86e44218186db43d220557d42373f</guid></item><item><title>The miscarriage data gap and &amp;apos;invisible loss&amp;apos; leaving Australian women behind</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-miscarriage-data-gap-and-invisible-loss-leaving-australian-women-behind/y56quko28</link><description>A new report is calling for a national database on miscarriage to address ongoing invisibility around miscarriage and early pregnancy loss in Australia, particularly for First Nations women and in rural and regional communities. This comes as the government announced a $9.5 million funding package in May last year to improve awareness and support for early pregnancy loss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">012a9e93267514f189f40d33c4787b7d</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump softens tone on China after tariff tensions flare</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/donald-trump-softens-tone-as-china-us-trade-tensions-flare/3mxy3fa5w</link><description>Trump has taken a less confrontational approach in his latest social media post on trade tensions with China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3b5920f3cfcf1b4d5b76ade1743c953</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;An all-time low&amp;apos;: Why are Afghanistan and Pakistan fighting along their border?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-are-afghanistan-and-pakistan-fighting-along-their-border/27ticq22j</link><description>Pakistan has accused Afghanistan of sheltering militants behind a surge in attacks on its soil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">626f88abf1ffbb3cc1e9f00578fef890</guid></item><item><title>Dozens killed as Pakistan–Afghanistan border clashes escalate</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/dozens-killed-as-pakistan-afghanistan-border-clashes-escalate/69n503u58</link><description>Dozens of fighters have been killed in overnight border clashes between Pakistan and Afghanistan in the most serious fighting between the neighbours since the Taliban came to power in Kabul. Tensions have risen after Pakistan demanded the Taliban take action against militants who have stepped up attacks in Pakistan, saying they operate from bases in Afghanistan. The Taliban denies that Pakistani militants are present on its soil.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df5f32da0e0de3ed22cf86d0937051ce</guid></item><item><title>Has your Qantas data been leaked? Here&amp;apos;s what you can do</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-to-do-if-your-qantas-data-was-leaked/vk1922mpe</link><description>A cybersecurity expert has warned scammers will employ both immediate and &amp;quot;long game&amp;quot; strategies to use the stolen data.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54a7898d0ee7ea167b5baaae9799ce52</guid></item><item><title>The changes to your superannuation in Treasurer Jim Chalmers&amp;apos; surprise announcement</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-six-superannuation-changes-in-treasurer-jim-chalmers-surprise-announcement/bz4k2c5zs</link><description>The government has responded to ongoing criticism, announcing half a dozen changes to the tax reforms they brought to the 2022 election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">970b3c637e63137bc62f109e447684d9</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 13 October</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-13-october/5rckfbih1</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b0c11b6796a5123e6f2b0956702444b</guid></item><item><title>New super changes for low income earners and high balances &amp;amp; how geopolitics is impacting markets</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-super-changes-for-low-income-earners-and-high-balances-how-geopolitics-is-impacting-markets/mb3ysbk81</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Goncalves speaks with Daniel Martin from Alvia Asset Partners about the day&amp;apos;s market news including the impact of geopolitics including the holding ceasefire in Gaza; plus hear from Treasurer Jim Chalmers as he addresses changes to superannuation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43aad4e296b0658e493b74a2dd371979</guid></item><item><title>Why doesn&amp;apos;t Australia have a national Human Rights Act?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/why-doesnt-australia-have-a-national-human-rights-act/rv6fkahti</link><description>Human right law experts are calling the federal government to take what they call a significant opportunity to establish a federal Human Rights Act. It comes as a new report analyses how attempts to create such an act in Australia over five decades has been met with political opposition and misinformation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59d41c6dac7295d94c943e5e8c06a3db</guid></item><item><title>The common way Australians have their data stolen — and what it&amp;apos;s costing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-australians-unknowingly-hand-over-their-security-to-hackers/2l7tlnxdq</link><description>The average financial losses from cybercrimes, both for Australians and businesses, continue to rise annually.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a29622799582dc1d75a299590aef9681</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Eating mostly brown food&amp;apos;: The &amp;apos;devastating&amp;apos; juggle faced by a rising number of Australians</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/juggling-act-social-services-payments-rent-food/g4wjshlw9</link><description>With one in seven Australians living below the poverty line, researchers and advocates say that COVID-era universal income is the solution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d960bd899656fec9831f257edb63d9b</guid></item><item><title>‘Historic exchange’: all Israeli hostages freed as Gaza peace talks continue</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/historic-exchange-all-israeli-hostages-freed-as-gaza-peace-talks-continue/8afzwummn</link><description>All 20 surviving Israeli hostages have been released from Hamas captivity in Gaza in a historic exchange as part of the first phase of a Gaza peace plan. And nearly 2000 Palestinians have also been freed from Israeli prisons, with the majority headed back to the war-ravaged Palestinian enclave. United States President Donald Trump has claimed the Israel-Hamas war is over, but negotiations are set to continue in Egypt with long-term peace still far from secure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc266d227e42bc4c01add8dd56555570</guid></item><item><title>The new threat to Australia&amp;apos;s potato industry - what is it and how can we deal with it?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-new-threat-to-australias-potato-industry-what-is-it-and-how-can-we-deal-with-it/l0arbsua4</link><description>Of all Australian states, Tasmania is the biggest producer of potatoes, and a lot of what&amp;apos;s grown here goes into potato products you would know well – hot chips, hash browns and wedges among them. But a new virus detected in recent months is causing concern. Growers are optimistic it can be managed, stressing it doesn&amp;apos;t pose a risk to human health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62d1ac1b34b4f270ce3471de7cdee3ef</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Freed Israeli hostages hug loved ones in tears of joy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/freed-israeli-hostages-hug-loved-ones-in-tears-of-joy/jxif449lm</link><description>Hundreds of people erupted in joy, tears and song on Tel Aviv&amp;apos;s Hostages Square on Monday as news of the releases broke.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c5ea68d4d28bfd592eed440ad4b32d9</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The greatest joy&amp;apos;: Palestinians reunite with loved ones after Israeli imprisonment</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/palestinians-reunite-with-family-after-release-by-israel/91ul3ppe6</link><description>Deeply emotional scenes unfolded in Gaza and the West Bank as Palestinian prisoners and detainees returned after their release by Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eac2fe44e6429ce92c890c7279de0dd</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I don&amp;apos;t have words&amp;apos;: Cape Verde erupts in celebration after historic World Cup qualification</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cape-verde-historic-world-cup-qualification/kyjoflpjv</link><description>The island nation is set to become one of the smallest countries to participate in football&amp;apos;s showpiece event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8be5a9d7cf57dcbacb5825b90522517</guid></item><item><title>Climate tipping points being crossed, scientists warn</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/climate-tipping-points-being-crossed-scientists-warn/e2nzqakov</link><description>A large white coral reef containing important species and fossil traces has been discovered at a depth of more than 500 metres in the Gulf of Naples, in a rare discovery for the Mediterranean. But a new report suggests reefs like this might already be in danger, with global warming crossing dangerous thresholds sooner than expected and the world&amp;apos;s coral reefs now in an almost irreversible die-off. It marks what scientists are describing as the first tipping point in climate-driven ecosystem collapse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f92a62b5564c38dc6ba5020e6b6cf55b</guid></item><item><title>Middle East peace deal signed; so where to from here?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/middle-east-peace-deal-signed-so-where-to-from-here/mslljq4v8</link><description>World leaders have signed a historic Middle East deal at a summit in Egypt. It comes hours after Israel and Hamas exchanged detainees and hostages. Israel released nearly 2,000 Palestinians from Israeli prisons, and Gaza released the surviving Israeli hostages after two years in captivity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a960a0f7a7d519f4c0ffdf4d65709e6c</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 14 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-14-october-2025/07mga95db</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f0b6aaa279b497e596069263ec42745</guid></item><item><title>Hamas&amp;apos; next move is unknown, but one person may &amp;apos;hold the key&amp;apos; to a lasting peace in Gaza</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gaza-peace-deal-what-happens-next/mxbnk7p2v</link><description>The first phase of a deeply complex peace process has begun. So what happens next?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5eb15f8b8a3f072b0df1e231020c4bd</guid></item><item><title>What are rare earths, and why are the share prices of companies mining them surging?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/what-are-rare-earths-and-why-are-the-share-prices-of-companies-mining-them-surging/ahkd2o2f8</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Kai Chen from MPC Markets about the rise on rare earths along with the rest of the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83036c7248750b5a662573a4fd77de29</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The hunt for the nearest mechanic&amp;apos;: NATO chief mocks &amp;apos;broken&amp;apos; Russian submarine</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nato-chief-mocks-broken-russian-submarine/xy1ynrhdh</link><description>Russia&amp;apos;s Black Sea Fleet rejected reports the diesel-powered submarine had suffered a serious malfunction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a6829e562fdc08a35cfd6712ba3af2e</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s Jewish and Palestinian communities celebrate the return of loved ones</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australias-jewish-and-palestinian-communities-celebrate-the-return-of-loved-ones/3y1ifgb3k</link><description>In Australia, Jewish and Palestinian communities have been celebrating the release of hostages and detainees as the fragile path to peace in Gaza continues. In Melbourne, Israeli hostage supporters took to the streets while there&amp;apos;s also been celebration among families of Palestinians set free.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">424fe4370713a45f7f10a0e28103f9f1</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Mystified&amp;apos;: Concern for thousands in Australia after Venezuela&amp;apos;s surprise move</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/venezuela-closes-embassy-australia-maduro-trump/mpgcbcetq</link><description>The closure of Venezuela&amp;apos;s embassy in Canberra follows the Nobel Peace Prize being awarded to Venezuela&amp;apos;s opposition leader over the weekend. But are the two related?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3d44e01ac6e1ec2e5d2181bc22bba7b</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Our shining star has dimmed&amp;apos;: Celebrated soul musician D&amp;apos;Angelo dies at 51</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/our-shining-star-has-dimmed-celebrated-soul-musician-dangelo-dies-at-51/7vo00osym</link><description>Acclaimed American soul musician D&amp;apos;Angelo has died at 51 after a &amp;quot;prolonged and courageous battle with cancer&amp;quot;, his family says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cf96ad8654d14a655e6368c6376edf8</guid></item><item><title>Warning Australia faces &amp;apos;looming period of risk&amp;apos; as it awaits nuclear submarines</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/warning-australia-facing-looming-period-of-risk-as-it-awaits-for-nuclear-submarines/tv9hb3orn</link><description>As Australia awaits nuclear-powered submarines, a strategic policy think tank warns we&amp;apos;re sitting vulnerable to potential threats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">def08fb9ad5ab463bf0d42db63e7ad60</guid></item><item><title>Victorian government debates ground-breaking Treaty Bill</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/victorian-government-debates-ground-breaking-treaty-bill/q2rsxdo7p</link><description>The Victorian Government is debating a historic Statewide Treaty Bill, establishing Australia&amp;apos;s first ever Treaty agreement between a state government and First Peoples in Victoria. If signed into law, the Treaty Bill will forge a path forward for First Peoples in Victoria to negotiate and influence the policy that affects community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dbd06e3145503ed0fadf3a971e18358</guid></item><item><title>Military seizes power in Madagascar after president flees amid youth protests</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/military-seizes-power-in-madagascar-after-president-flees-amid-youth-protests/qvo024061</link><description>Gen Z-driven demonstrations erupted last month over water and power shortages, quickly escalating into an uprising over broader grievances.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad47e15910b788f255e8c5db1df3857b</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 15 October</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-15-october/3nd3zru1t</link><description>A daily five-minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d9d2f9875051d46287880b7e9509db9</guid></item><item><title>Australian passport power revealed, as the US and UK hit record lows</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australias-passport-power-revealed-as-us-and-the-uk-hit-record-lows/1yssu9bu8</link><description>For the first time in 20 years, the United States&amp;apos; passport has fallen from the top ten most powerful in the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5913d8dc348b75c930086e886f61acc</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos&amp;apos; undefeated streak ends with loss to US</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/usa-vs-australia-socceroos-undefeated-streak-comes-to-end-with-loss-to-the-united-states/ekybucznm</link><description>The Socceroos have already qualified for the World Cup, with coach Tony Popovic hoping new players &amp;quot;surprise&amp;quot; him ahead of the finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42000ea24a0a0c3df9b2dd24f138c952</guid></item><item><title>Israel and Hamas both accused of not keeping cease fire agreement</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israel-and-hamas-both-accused-of-not-keeping-cease-fire-agreement/o3uoxbnwq</link><description>Hamas has returned more bodies of Israeli hostages to the International Committee of the Red Cross in Gaza. Questions remain over sustainable peace in the Middle East, with uncertainty about how to resolve sticking points in Donald Trump&amp;apos;s 20-point plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">606cca32ae81250f8e0fe87566997c20</guid></item><item><title>These Sydneysiders watched as the hostage-detainee swap played out. Then came a call</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/those-watching-from-afar-as-the-gaza-ceasefire-plays-out-in-real-time/w3ip60rfg</link><description>Palestinian and Jewish Australians describe their emotional journey watching the first phase of the Gaza ceasefire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef864187adbe80a5f3efd531333779d0</guid></item><item><title>Kathryn lost her banking job to a chatbot. She just confronted her CBA bosses</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/kathryn-lost-her-banking-job-to-a-chatbot-she-just-confronted-her-cba-bosses/cgx8kmymj</link><description>Former Commonwealth Bank employee Kathryn Sullivan spent years teaching the bank&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;Bumblebee&amp;quot; chatbot how to respond to customers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">229c2ceb1c4b11d1ee4a3df1ccba43e5</guid></item><item><title>What record low fertility rates mean for our economy &amp;amp; gold hits another record</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/what-record-low-fertility-rates-mean-for-our-economy-gold-hits-another-record/ab79wv67m</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with McCrindle Social Researcher Ashley Fell about thegrowing trend for Australians to have fewer kids, and later in life; plus Luke Laretive from Seneca Financial Services looks through the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket moves including what he is telling his clients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">393550f2a88ab6ee9896470517c2cd65</guid></item><item><title>The &amp;apos;confluence of crises&amp;apos; driving Australia&amp;apos;s record-low fertility rate</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-confluence-of-crises-driving-australias-record-low-fertility-rate/9lh5pvz93</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s birth rate is declining — but researchers say it&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;not about selfishness&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef1723f1e0034dec133ef93803ce7c35</guid></item><item><title>Labor criticised over worker visa rule backflip that could affect thousands</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/labor-criticised-over-worker-visa-rule-backflip-that-could-affect-thousands/i08mdb5c4</link><description>Tens of thousands of people from the Pacific and East Timor currently work in Australia under the PALM scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb96a966de4ab0d3eef43c7085921580</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s rainforests are now adding to carbon emissions, scientists say</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rainforests-carbon-emissions-targets/vaghexnps</link><description>A new study has found Queensland&amp;apos;s tropical rainforests emit more carbon than they absorb, raising concerns for Australia&amp;apos;s climate targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad316dc2d21a9518f44c0f990e3178db</guid></item><item><title>Young people feel much more disconnected than boomers in Australia. Why?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-generational-divide-over-belonging-in-australia/pjnhensyl</link><description>Social isolation and economic disadvantage are partly responsible for declining rates in national belonging, a new study suggests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3cfa26f0dae0c7c6911c060553577764</guid></item><item><title>Hamas says it can&amp;apos;t retrieve more bodies, as first hostage funerals start in Israel</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hamas-returns-hostages-bodies/0plf71soq</link><description>Israel confirmed it had received the coffins of two more deceased hostages and was transporting them to a facility for identification.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ac284148d23e1ac6920d8c05b113802</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar braces for military rule as coup leader prepares to be sworn in</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/template/urqjyxbr8</link><description>The African Union said it was suspending Madagascar after a coup ousted President Andry Rajoelina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19012ff1570ecd784880a83242599d0c</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar braces for military rule as coup leader prepares to be sworn in</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/madagascar-military-coup-leader-prepares-to-be-sworn-in/urqjyxbr8</link><description>The African Union said it was suspending Madagascar after a coup ousted President Andry Rajoelina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f0efd57fa8c7d9982c1f7f7d6f077af</guid></item><item><title>Is your job burning you out? Experts say better boundaries and workplace connections can help</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/is-your-job-burning-you-out-experts-say-better-boundaries-and-workplace-connections-can-help/c00bsgb5r</link><description>Despite a growing awareness around mental health, research shows burnout in the workplace is still a major challenge. Experts say without proper training and healthy boundaries in the workplace, more and more Australians will consider leaving their jobs in the next year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf0ea677b196500cdeb94117b3fde252</guid></item><item><title>Afghanistan and Pakistan announce temporary ceasefire following border clashes</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/afghanistan-pakistan-ceasefire/odtxselwu</link><description>The truce follows accusations of cross-border attacks and civilian casualties, which have strained relations between the two neighbours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6bfef285b317b3c02581f45e8cd0bdd0</guid></item><item><title>Afghanistan and Pakistan announce temporary ceasefire following border clashes</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/template/odtxselwu</link><description>The truce follows accusations of cross-border attacks and civilian casualties, which have strained relations between the two neighbours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0352f1be111698365091e7490a68e535</guid></item><item><title>Trump confirms he authorised covert CIA operations in Venezuela</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-venezuela-cia-operations/oknxuv9vy</link><description>Donald Trump said he was &amp;quot;looking at land now&amp;quot; after recently targeting alleged drug smuggling boats from Venezuela by sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5ae3bdaec1094c947d1b23677e47b0c</guid></item><item><title>Hamas-Israel ceasefire holds - but only just</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/hamas-israel-ceasefire-holds-but-only-just/3lbupapyq</link><description>Two more bodies of deceased hostages have been handed over to the Red Cross by Hamas, following Israel&amp;apos;s accusation that the militant group were failing to abide by the terms of the ceasefire deal. Aid is continuing to roll into Gaza despite threats from Israel that they would cut supplies and close border crossings. But there are heightened concerns for the fragile ceasefire, amid reports US President Donald Trump is considering allowing Israel to resume its military activities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bcc996311d8b3686920c6f4f58e6d65</guid></item><item><title>Germany, NATO pledge billions in new Ukraine aid as Russia reels from fuel strikes</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/germany-nato-pledge-billions-in-new-ukraine-aid-as-russia-reels-from-fuel-strikes/p48lq50cj</link><description>Germany and NATO allies have pledged billions in new aid to Ukraine as the war nears its fourth winter, with Kyiv urging urgent air-defence support amid a sharp drop in foreign assistance. Meanwhile, Russia is grappling with fuel shortages following Ukrainian strikes, as President Donald Trump renews his criticism of Vladimir Putin over the prolonged conflict and Russia’s faltering economy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b14d8cf379889a65e7f5b3010fab0541</guid></item><item><title>NSW premier says court ruling striking out anti-protest laws &amp;apos;disappointing&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/protest-laws-nsw-court-palestine-action-group/l9i8imjjw</link><description>Critics said the police powers, implemented in February after alleged antisemitic attacks, were unconstitutional and too broad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae531e7e586a5d2b02846a0fb86445da</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 16 October</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-16-october/6rzmbvr3m</link><description>A daily five-minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c09914d46463f7985a985ae45417dde7</guid></item><item><title>Government could make offshore skills change to solve &amp;apos;wicked&amp;apos; problem</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/government-considering-offshore-recognition-of-skills-to-solve-wicked-shortage/4b3nhd2pl</link><description>Proposed tweaks to the skilled migration pathway could ensure migrants arrive job-ready.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">887aa6e5204dc3d719d429d57bb0fbc8</guid></item><item><title>Yeah, nah: Australians report a drop in their sense of belonging</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/yeah-nah-australians-report-a-drop-in-their-sense-of-belonging/nimqd7gxk</link><description>Australians&amp;apos; sense of belonging has been declining over time. That&amp;apos;s the major finding from this year&amp;apos;s social cohesion report, from the Scanlon Foundation Research Institute. But while the report suggests there is ongoing strain in peoples&amp;apos; sense of belonging, trust, and identity, the Foundation remains optimistic, saying most Australians still report happiness and a strong sense of community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">911dd4df5f2a602ccc4a600189eacc37</guid></item><item><title>ASX hits record as jobless rate rises to 4.5%</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asx-hits-record-as-jobless-rate-rises-to-4-5/yfl4iry0i</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Chris Brycki from Stockspot while Stephanie Youseff talks with Alex Joiner from IFM Investors about the rise in the unemployment rate to a near four year high, what it means for interest rates and why the sharemarket hit a record as a result.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7a8b4835b481cd9289d5818cb22e0a3</guid></item><item><title>The great divide: Australians reach a &amp;apos;difficult&amp;apos; new high</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-reach-a-difficult-new-high/4i8lrqqes</link><description>Some say the numbers show life is getting harder, while others argue the picture isn’t as &amp;quot;dire&amp;quot; as it seems.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46b3a48f4083ea4e50ae7de2ffda47ff</guid></item><item><title>SPECIAL EPISODE: Inside the Gaza ceasefire: hostages, prisoners &amp;amp; a negotiator</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/special-episode-inside-the-gaza-ceasefire-hostages-prisoners-a-negotiator/p3ustu2tm</link><description>Israeli hostages have been released and Palestinians prisoners freed, but is the Trump-brokered truce a turning point or just a timeout? This in-depth episode explores the deal, the delivery of aid, and the future of Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72d19b90f5678e3aebf3b54eeae887cd</guid></item><item><title>Israel delays reopening of crucial Gaza border, rules out aid transfers</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-delays-reopening-of-crucial-gaza-border-rules-out-aid-transfers/al67io3uh</link><description>A key border crossing between Gaza and Egypt will remain closed, dashing hopes it would quickly open under a ceasefire deal between Israel and Hamas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f88c73323c9bc5ce56f317e88ae5291</guid></item><item><title>Melbourne’s weekly pro-Palestinian protests to pause after Gaza ceasefire</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/melbournes-weekly-pro-palestinian-protests-to-pause-after-gaza-ceasefire/9zqoj10s5</link><description>Organisers say Sunday rallies outside the state library will be halted, a move which was reportedly welcomed by Melbourne&amp;apos;s lord mayor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adcfcfb52a10ca9ff43f562edf24fee9</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Bombs have stopped, but threats remain&amp;apos;: The &amp;apos;absolute catastrophe&amp;apos; inside Gaza</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gaza-aid-ceasefire-rebuilding/rwrmct7lq</link><description>Humanitarian groups call for all Gaza crossings to open so more aid can enter, warning efforts depend on sustaining the fragile ceasefire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b8c6f33ad3aa6d02059babd50d1f681</guid></item><item><title>Australia’s rental affordability &amp;apos;myth&amp;apos; that doesn’t match reality</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-rental-affordability-myth-that-doesnt-match-reality/8pc3nse4m</link><description>Workers in critical sectors are frequently locked out of affordable housing — and not just in capital cities, a new report says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbbde9304229d83536d06090e7d6e862</guid></item><item><title>Australia’s rental affordability &amp;apos;myth&amp;apos; that doesn’t match reality</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australias-rental-affordability-myth-that-doesnt-match-reality/8pc3nse4m</link><description>Workers in critical sectors are frequently locked out of affordable housing — and not just in capital cities, a new report says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">322d4d2d2eef363a717b7645ced8969d</guid></item><item><title>Trump says he will meet Putin to discuss Ukraine war after &amp;apos;great progress&amp;apos; in call</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-putin-budapest-meeting-phone-call/n5c7a9idr</link><description>Donald Trump said he and Vladimir Putin would meet to discuss if they can bring the &amp;quot;inglorious&amp;quot; war to an end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f38113a0db106cfeda77f07ff981930</guid></item><item><title>Government considering offshore recognition of migrant skills</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/government-considering-offshore-recognition-of-migrant-skills/oyoypsu23</link><description>Home Affairs Minister Tony Burke says the government is working on the possibility of an offshore recognition of skills. He says this will help save time and money for skilled migrants looking to move to Australia. In his address the Press Club in Canberra Mr Burke also flagged changes to inactive bank accounts to combat money laundering.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9059fdc6bf0805753e63fc1e8b8ed206</guid></item><item><title>What this week&amp;apos;s surprise unemployment data could mean for your mortgage repayments</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-this-weeks-surprise-unemployment-data-could-mean-for-your-mortgage-repayments/1qcd4db63</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s jobless rate has hit a near four-year high, raising speculation it could trigger another rate cut by the Reserve Bank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c32a7d00b620ec2136c639b246b46f54</guid></item><item><title>Vatican report says clergy sex abuse victims need reparations and tangible sanctions to heal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/vatican-report-says-clergy-sex-abuse-victims-need-reparations-and-tangible-sanctions-to-heal/2nr10q7oq</link><description>An internal Vatican report has delivered scathing criticism of the Catholic Church&amp;apos;s handling of decades of allegations of sexual abuse from around the world. It&amp;apos;s calling for financial reparations and sanctions for abusers and their enablers. AND A WARNING THAT THE CONTENT OF THIS STORY MAY BE DISTRESSING FOR SOME LISTENERS</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f745e484d8333a0cf9d9fd06b5b40c75</guid></item><item><title>Hundreds of claims a day: Are these Australia&amp;apos;s most dangerous jobs?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/worker-compensation-australia-claims-report-2025/wwqkll5l9</link><description>More than 180 workers died from traumatic injuries while working in Australia last year, according to Safe Work Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c97ab2d072e2c6af2fb58c87b7a9668f</guid></item><item><title>Australian military &amp;apos;contingency planning&amp;apos; for possible Gaza troop deployment</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-troops-gaza-deployment-plans/barxp3cbw</link><description>A temporary international stabilisation force is a vital element of Donald Trump&amp;apos;s 20-point peace plan for Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63ccc2105104ff5ef4d5ba8d0743804f</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 17 October</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-17-october/1dpep5sms</link><description>A daily five-minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2206e9d7d229f72c778f504bba5b573</guid></item><item><title>Fears grow over truce&amp;apos;s fragility amid concerns around hostages bodies, aid</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/fears-grow-over-truces-fragility-amid-concerns-around-hostages-bodies-aid/2ft7m68pm</link><description>Israel is pressing Hamas to honour the ceasefire agreement and return the bodies of hostages still held in Gaza. This comes as satellite images show limited aid convoys entering the enclave through Kerem Shalom, while displaced Palestinians in Khan Younis endure worsening living conditions amid shortages of food, fuel, and clean water. With more than 67,900 Palestinians killed since 2023 and uncertainty over Rafah’s reopening, fears are growing that the fragile truce could collapse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1b9946a7f8bc0adecb0f2ed12a12a40</guid></item><item><title>KISS founding member and lead guitarist Ace Frehley dies at 74</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ace-frehley-of-kiss-dies-at-74/ex1w3teta</link><description>Ace Frehley, founding member of the glam rock band KISS, has died at 74 after complications following a recent fall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db73e8919bd765f7fe4ebb41b2683420</guid></item><item><title>The quiet creep that&amp;apos;s making Australian banking less &amp;apos;inclusive and accessible&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/is-australian-banking-becoming-less-inclusive-and-accessible/w2hi2lrci</link><description>A decline in face-to-face banking services and cash facilities is harming some Australians more than others, advocates say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2caf29b5a0a995074fb9a5bcf5f13c8d</guid></item><item><title>Gold price warning as some traditional buyers tap out at record levels</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gold-price-warning-as-some-traditional-buyers-tap-out-at-record-levels/pdtyehkrm</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Oreana Private Wealth Chief Investment Officer Isaac Poole in Asia, who says some traditional gold buyers are tapping out of the market at current record levels, plus a look at the day&amp;apos;s market action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32a7c7ea0795ab6b966ced5a3e96ae8a</guid></item><item><title>Morning News Bulletin 18 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/morning-news-bulletin-18-october-2025/hpdeb2fy6</link><description>Hamas political representative fails to confirm whether Hamas will disarm; the search for a missing toddler in South Australia comes to an end; Cameron Green remains on track for the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2798898284934e637ffcb2cb3fe23020</guid></item><item><title>How Donald Trump became a hero in Israel</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-donald-trump-is-being-hailed-as-a-hero-in-israel/uo2ew5l26</link><description>The release of Israeli hostages saw Donald Trump hailed as a hero to the Jewish people this week. This is why he&amp;apos;s getting all the credit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58574d4d5fe3f4f000951ad26474585c</guid></item><item><title>Champion of champions: Remembering Dr Charles Perkins 25 years after his death</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/champion-of-champions-remembering-dr-charles-perkins-25-years-after-his-death/hfxjo6lph</link><description>This weekend marks 25 years since the passing of Arrernte and Kalkadoon leader Dr Charles Perkins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5727c97114627c523581ac0d5fd6aa26</guid></item><item><title>Long-lost diary tells a personal story of China&amp;apos;s involvement in D-Day</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/long-lost-diary-tells-a-personal-story-of-chinas-involvement-in-d-day/5z0ky5cix</link><description>A long-lost diary from a Chinese war veteran has been discovered, detailing the participation of China&amp;apos;s participation in D-Day. The 80-page diary was discovered in an abandoned Hong Kong flat, and details Lam Ping Yu&amp;apos;s brush with death during the world&amp;apos;s largest-ever sea, land and air armada on D Day during World War Two.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9eae7a45a44e90fb60ee5bd2bb30a265</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew renounces title amid renewed scrutiny over Epstein ties</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/prince-andrew-renounces-title-amid-renewed-scrutiny-over-epstein-ties/u2may3k29</link><description>The move comes after new claims surfaced in Virginia Giuffre’s posthumous memoir detailing Andrew&amp;apos;s alleged involvement with Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50af7a1739745a46753e2e521827517d</guid></item><item><title>Prince Andrew renounces title amid renewed scrutiny over Epstein ties</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/template/u2may3k29</link><description>The move comes after new claims surfaced in Virginia Giuffre’s posthumous memoir detailing Andrew&amp;apos;s alleged involvement with Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1195910d7ab892d8cff8f8840f74906a</guid></item><item><title>Barking bad: The ruff road to recovery</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/barking-bad-the-ruff-road-to-recovery/3rsd9rhvm</link><description>Dogs can become so attached to particular toys that they display behaviour that would be associated with addiction in humans. Researchers say when the dogs were deprived of their toys in the study, they became so fixated on what they&amp;apos;d lost that their blood pressure increased and they ignored everything else.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a129e3eb6cbf58d0540e0b746c032c4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Get the war over&amp;apos;: Trump backs away from giving long-range missiles to Ukraine</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-warns-zelenskyy-tomahawks-missiles-could-result-in-big-escalation-in-ukraine-war/2q3ba6ch3</link><description>Zelenskyy came to Washington after weeks of calls for Tomahawk missiles, hoping to capitalise on Trump&amp;apos;s growing frustration with Putin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6308ca3729378d8148778b45781c3db3</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Get the war over&amp;apos;: Trump backs away from giving long-range missiles to Ukraine</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-warns-zelenskyy-tomahawk-missiles-could-result-in-big-escalation-in-ukraine-war/2q3ba6ch3</link><description>Zelenskyy came to Washington after weeks of calls for Tomahawk missiles, hoping to capitalise on Trump&amp;apos;s growing frustration with Putin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0c176215d257343558dbe06c50b7371</guid></item><item><title>Remains of another Israeli hostage in Gaza handed over by Hamas</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/remains-of-another-israeli-hostage-in-gaza-handed-over-by-hamas/wqn3i72f0</link><description>Israel says it has received nine of 28 bodies held in Gaza, with Hamas saying it needed heavy machinery and excavating equipment to speed up the process.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d5504091c935dece725c01f74302262</guid></item><item><title>Midday News Bulletin 18 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/midday-news-bulletin-18-october-2025/knmeaqsib</link><description>Hamas transfers another hostage body to Israel; Albanese government investing $10 million in anti-bullying review; Max Verstappen to start first in the sprint race at the Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec0f0ec2f39d09c40a824707277c0e2a</guid></item><item><title>Albanese will finally meet Trump. Here’s how it went for other leaders</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-is-set-to-meet-trump-heres-how-its-gone-for-others/vyr86pbeh</link><description>Since Trump&amp;apos;s return to the presidency, over 270 days have passed without an official meeting between Albanese and Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">244dd9735b0039556c2ebbbde6dcfe1f</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Irreparably broken&amp;apos;: Barnaby Joyce to quit Nationals, won&amp;apos;t contest seat at next election</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/barnaby-joyce-to-quit-nationals-wont-contest-seat-at-next-election/d2d1yuxic</link><description>Reports the firebrand MP plans to defect to One Nation are not yet confirmed, but his options have been kept open.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adb0b11a736988e54c625d2cf6c0b7d3</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Approach with caution&amp;apos;: A warning to the public as gold and silver prices skyrocket</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/a-warning-to-the-public-as-gold-and-silver-prices-skyrocket/4mlde8xtc</link><description>While the price of gold has kept skyrocketing, prices &amp;quot;can go down and stay down for a very long period of time&amp;quot;, an expert warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f9a10ed6b0c9e80a85f6ac22fbaa234</guid></item><item><title>Evening News Bulletin 18 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/evening-news-bulletin-18-october-2025/alqa2eegi</link><description>Donald Trump pressures Ukraine&amp;apos;s Volodymyr Zelenskyy to strike a deal with Russia, Former deputy prime minister Barnaby Joyce will not contest his seat at the next election, Tasmania claim three-run victory over Western Australia in Sheffield Shield clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e7ad498ba0b0d4bfdef5742c68dfdc4</guid></item><item><title>AI &amp;apos;supercharging&amp;apos; bullying, minister warns, as $10 million tipped into new school plan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ai-bullying-fears-raised-as-10-million-tipped-into-new-school-plan/mjli4ehx3</link><description>Artificial intelligence has led to a &amp;quot;terrifying&amp;quot; new type of bullying, the education minister has warned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2daa42141753c3ebb3795311f53d794c</guid></item><item><title>Morning News Bulletin 19 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/morning-news-bulletin-19-october-2025/asrfsz2ra</link><description>Israel reportedly kills 11 members of one family in airstrike on Gaza city; fallout after Barnaby Joyce quits the Nationals; Ange Postecoglou sacked as Nottingham Forest manager.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">848e92084007e9cdbd0081aa9371b411</guid></item><item><title>Could your dog be an addict? Scientists think so</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/could-your-dog-be-an-addict-scientists-think-so/c1ttw1h88</link><description>Does your dog seem to really, really love playing with a certain toy? It may be something more than harmless fun.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">357ead34b7929960767362cdd318d950</guid></item><item><title>How &amp;apos;anti-foreign worker sentiment&amp;apos; is snuffing out the dreams of Australians in the US</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/study-plans-america-broken-trump-visa/lvcdvkeom</link><description>Rapid political change has shattered the dreams of some Australians who were looking to work or study in the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5e79a7e4e303d78595ead245495bb96</guid></item><item><title>When is Diwali and what does the festival celebrate?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/when-is-diwali-and-what-does-the-festival-celebrate/aaditlj2j</link><description>The global festival of lights lasts five days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dc912c48c15c618bebc72dfe08e3f10</guid></item><item><title>How caring in language can prevent elderly falls</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/how-caring-in-language-can-prevent-elderly-falls/u7o69l9uf</link><description>In Australia, around one in four people aged over 65 experiences at least one fall each year and it is the leading cause of injury, hospitalisation, and death among older Australians. Preventing falls isn’t simple, especially when language stands in the way of awareness. But in Perth, two Chinese university students are turning that challenge into change, using their culture and compassion to protect some of those most vulnerable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ccabdcec1759c997df9967f7d6645ff</guid></item><item><title>A rich cultural heritage celebrated in lights: Diwali</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-rich-cultural-heritage-celebrated-in-lights-diwali/i9liz6aaz</link><description>Diwali is the biggest festival in India and many South Asian countries, marking the victory of good over evil and the triumph of light over darkness. It is celebrated by more than a billion people around the world, including diaspora communities in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5af6aa457edd09b9a75480df6631b9b3</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: No Kings protests against Trump draw huge crowds across US</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/no-kings-anti-trump-rallies-draw-crowds-across-us/uraw80jq8</link><description>Organisers said seven million Americans attended the rallies against political developments during Donald Trump&amp;apos;s second term.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0daa2b540cb870d3749b501106452564</guid></item><item><title>Two more hostage bodies handed over as Netanyahu says war not over until Hamas disarms</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/netanyahu-says-gaza-war-not-over-until-hamas-disarms/0wp83yx8m</link><description>Israel says the Rafah border crossing will remain closed as Hamas has been too slow to hand over the bodies of deceased hostages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c909604f8855c1cc54309ece30715e5</guid></item><item><title>Nationals leader says he&amp;apos;d like Barnaby Joyce to stay with the party</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/barnaby-joyce-urged-to-stick-with-nationals-david-littleproud/4lag6ompr</link><description>Joyce has signalled his intention to leave the National Party, and the move has prompted speculation he could defect to One Nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0420d5fcd5041adb5d7b801e46e638c</guid></item><item><title>An &amp;apos;entirely unpredictable&amp;apos; Albanese-Trump meeting wouldn&amp;apos;t harm relations, minister says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-trump-meeting-wouldnt-harm-australia-us-ties-minister/l30969g36</link><description>A minister has downplayed the risk of Donald Trump dressing down Anthony Albanese when the two leaders come face-to-face.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce0399884f21af1949e87eec98e623cc</guid></item><item><title>Midday News Bulletin 19 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/midday-news-bulletin-19-october-2025/cjrbke99r</link><description>The Nationals leader urges Barnaby Joyce to stay with the party; the UN aid chief says mobilising aid in Gaza is a massive task; Australian Jack Miller set to compete in the Australian Motorcycle Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da26702b02b0a5cc3c7ef46527b50372</guid></item><item><title>Minister &amp;apos;concerned&amp;apos; at setting migration targets as protesters march across the country</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/minister-concerned-at-setting-migration-targets-as-anti-immigration-and-counter-protesters-on-the-march/fzghrf7mm</link><description>In Melbourne, police used pepper spray and flash distraction devices as they sought to keep the rival rallies separated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44c30b290f12436d0a56bbcb0471a74f</guid></item><item><title>Evening News Bulletin 19 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/evening-news-bulletin-19-october-2025/ltkejt2t6</link><description>Clashes in Melbourne as competing protests face off across the country again, No Kings&amp;apos; demonstrations draw large crowds across the US, Mollie O&amp;apos;Callaghan sets a swimming world record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb4319d57824e31e7b6e53548cc8f74e</guid></item><item><title>Is the government&amp;apos;s new plan to combat bullying fair, and what&amp;apos;s missing from it?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/antibullying-convo-article/uqgjdjnev</link><description>Amid ongoing community concerns about the devastating impacts of bullying, how does the government&amp;apos;s new plan stack up?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c416cb4103f37e89fd5b6f6645b0db6a</guid></item><item><title>Is the government&amp;apos;s new plan to combat bullying fair, and what&amp;apos;s missing from it?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-does-the-governments-new-plan-to-combat-bullying-stack-up/uqgjdjnev</link><description>Amid ongoing community concerns about the devastating impacts of bullying, how does the government&amp;apos;s new plan stack up?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7be452c98b97e72894aa1424c0c6e638</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We matter, we belong&amp;apos;: This year Diwali carries new meaning for Indian Australians</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/diwali-2025-indian-australians-push-back-against-anti-immigration/wihyrhoz0</link><description>Amid political tension, Diwali offers Indian Australians a moment to celebrate — and quietly affirm they belong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2be269b9d04aa02bf7bfbe27dcf743f8</guid></item><item><title>Are you experiencing burnout? Here are the signs — and what can be done</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/are-you-experiencing-burnout-here-are-the-signs-and-what-can-be-done/nvm4b0kc4</link><description>Despite growing awareness around mental health in the workplace, research suggests burnout is getting worse in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">224212f58bec5b01724d8a7feeefbd54</guid></item><item><title>I had anti-women views as a teenager. Now I cringe at the words we used</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/losing-the-anti-women-views-i-learned-in-online-spaces/hk82mrcv7</link><description>Jamie&amp;apos;s changed now, but as a teen he had problematic views largely informed by early YouTube videos and online gaming, he says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6375961a4e4bcf114d735e29c8ddec9</guid></item><item><title>What to expect from Albanese&amp;apos;s meeting with Trump, as he arrives in the US</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-to-expect-from-albaneses-imminent-meeting-with-trump/0861ikjml</link><description>Only time will tell if these two very different personalities from opposite sides of the political spectrum will be able to gel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cab08d9d6fbefe82d9414bcea379035f</guid></item><item><title>Gaza ceasefire to resume after Israeli strikes kill at least 26</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-says-it-has-resumed-enforcement-of-ceasefire-after-conducting-strikes-on-gaza/y9o72sdvm</link><description>Israel said it carried out the strikes after an earlier attack killed two of its soldiers, in what is the most serious test yet of the US-brokered truce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87fd37bf0d07a6dc28c2c27385364241</guid></item><item><title>Gaza ceasefire to resume after Israeli strikes kill at least 26</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-launches-strikes-on-gaza-after-accusing-hamas-of-breaching-ceasefire/y9o72sdvm</link><description>Israel said it carried out the strikes after an earlier attack killed two of its soldiers, in what is the most serious test yet of the US-brokered truce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37b707d258a0bd1876ce522d0064bb2f</guid></item><item><title>Israel strikes Gaza in major test of ceasefire | Morning News Bulletin 20 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israel-strikes-gaza-in-major-test-of-ceasefire-morning-news-bulletin-20-october-2025/g436lsisl</link><description>Israel says air strikes and artillery fire in southern Gaza are in response to Hamas violations of the ceasefire; Victoria Police says it expects to make more arrests over weekend protests; and in sport, Australia&amp;apos;s triathlete Matt Hauser wins a world triathlon title in Wollongong.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42c37fcdf17d7bc962055aaccf0fdced</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;No violence, very professional&amp;apos;: What we know about the Louvre jewellery heist</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/manhunt-continues-for-thieves-after-jewels-stolen-in-heist-at-the-louvre-museum-in-paris/lmbqqvmw5</link><description>Masked robbers broke into the Paris museum using a crane and angle grinders to steal French crown jewels worth tens of millions of dollars.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a9adf824849cedfcd8675fd5cff78a6</guid></item><item><title>Barnaby Joyce reveals he spoke with Pauline Hanson amid National Party split plans</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/barnaby-joyce-reveals-he-spoke-with-pauline-hanson-amid-national-party-split-plans/6u73puepd</link><description>The Nationals MP confirmed he had briefly spoken with One Nation leader Pauline Hanson, but didn&amp;apos;t detail the conversation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbf7f7d002dbdbd8f8fd0af353ef005e</guid></item><item><title>Trump says he hopes to resolve trade tensions with China</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trump-says-he-hopes-to-resolve-trade-tensions-with-china/j2e05akdd</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23069fa47011183f93f2c3fef32d2097</guid></item><item><title>Record flu cases this year prompt vaccination warning</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/record-flu-cases-this-year-prompt-vaccination-warning/nj0yf7wso</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f8d278f045075d4cb9c3c4952f4e14cd</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley announces plan to give Australians income tax cuts, without details or costings</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sussan-ley-announces-new-economic-policy-and-reform/ez8ftktc8</link><description>The Coalition is planning tax cuts and policy reform in the lead-up to the next election, but details are scarce.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">237d01f47e5820c0fb951107786d808a</guid></item><item><title>Trump, Albanese to meet in coming hours | Midday News Bulletin 20 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trump-albanese-to-meet-in-coming-hours-midday-news-bulletin-20-october-2025/ub5olej0e</link><description>In this bulletin, Anthony Albanese to meet with Donald Trump over AUKUS and trade, the Puk Puk defence treaty with PNG is a step closer to being implemented. And in Formula One, Max Verstappen wins the US Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18f269a36c6c711142491f5d16ba5608</guid></item><item><title>Police union boss likens Melbourne protest to Northern Ireland in the 1970s</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/had-a-gutful-victoria-police-blame-left-wing-groups-over-violent-protests-in-melbourne/7n4t7nirx</link><description>Premier Jacinta Allan blamed a &amp;quot;very small number&amp;quot; of counter-protesters for the violence and said they deserved to face &amp;quot;serious consequences&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">234d9d68c474cbce07720129846cecd6</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;How&amp;apos; not &amp;apos;who&amp;apos; the question after Louvre crown jewels smash and grab</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/how-not-who-the-question-after-louvre-crown-jewels-smash-and-grab/rssu948vk</link><description>French President Emmanuel Macron says everything is being done to catch the people behind a spectacular jewel heist at the Louvre, the latest in a series of museum robberies. After the brazen theft of some of France&amp;apos;s crown jewels in broad daylight, staff and union representatives say not enough has been done to guard the objects and people at one of the world&amp;apos;s most famous galleries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6668f792bc55ee76bea2f821038512fe</guid></item><item><title>Two people dead after plane slides off runway and into sea in Hong Kong</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hong-kong-plane-crash-kills-two/a6i8y8adh</link><description>The aircraft deviated from the north runway and slid into the sea, Hong Kong&amp;apos;s Civil Aviation Department said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6d86780c366f781ed78de1f20ecd200</guid></item><item><title>Big bills, no seat: Some of the federal election&amp;apos;s big spenders didn&amp;apos;t actually win</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nearly-2-million-and-no-seat-see-what-independents-spent-for-the-2025-federal-election/krs38smhx</link><description>Independent candidates received and spent hundreds of thousands of dollars to get elected to federal parliament — some unsuccessfully.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2bb78bf9759f7ce7f9fa448d7003d2a</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 20 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-20-october-2025/h27gjkbih</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">534a413ea8870ed3e00ef8ec42d0e3d2</guid></item><item><title>Promising signs for AUKUS ahead of meeting | Evening News Bulletin 20 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/promising-signs-for-aukus-ahead-of-meeting-evening-news-bulletin-20-october-2025/58rei37ww</link><description>In this bulletin, signs AUKUS is assured, hours before the Prime Minister meets with Donald Trump, dozens of deaths reported in Israeli strikes on Gaza, with allegations of ceasefire breaches on both sides. And in sport, India backs Kohli to bounce back from poor performance in the last ODI.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d8f5c54cd39731165f3439a9e3a2cf8</guid></item><item><title>Diwali shines a light on culture for Australian family in Gujarat</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/diwali-shines-a-light-on-culture-for-australian-family-in-gujurat/omihf47u7</link><description>This week, more than a billion people around the world are celebrating Diwali, the religious festival celebrating the victory of light over darkness. It&amp;apos;s an important time for Australia’s South Asian communities. But one family is going a step further, travelling to India for the occasion. SBS caught up with them in Gujarat, on India’s west coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58e299b08f1b12b88e126a4ee1c2f3df</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Concerning&amp;apos; or a sign of &amp;apos;good things&amp;apos;? What Australia&amp;apos;s flu record means</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-recorded-more-flu-cases-than-ever-this-year-is-it-the-worst-year-on-record/me2opicyw</link><description>There&amp;apos;s been a 10 per cent increase in flu rates compared to last year, with doctors sounding the alarm over vaccine hesitancy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">686166dd3b448554f908f50d9eec07f6</guid></item><item><title>What are rare earth minerals and why is Donald Trump interested in Australia&amp;apos;s supply?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-are-rare-earth-minerals-and-why-is-trump-interested-in-australias-supply/mfxgjcwhy</link><description>They&amp;apos;re used in electric vehicles, weapons and green energy, but what actually are rare earths?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6714023469024d5f61e14a3477cdee97</guid></item><item><title>PM&amp;apos;s balancing act ahead of US talks as China&amp;apos;s economy expands by 4.8%</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pms-balancing-act-ahead-of-us-talks-as-chinas-economy-expands-by-4-8/ne7mekta7</link><description>Australian Prime Minister Anthony Albanese is in the US meeting President Donald Trump but has a delicate balancing act considering how important China is to Australia. SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Shane Oliver from AMP and David Scutt from Forex.com to find out what it means for Australia and the market reaction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79759bde1dc0b60944603fa196cbb21b</guid></item><item><title>More arrests likely after Melbourne immigration protests turn violent</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/more-arrests-likely-after-melbourne-immigration-protests-turn-violent/uwdtila1e</link><description>Safety on the streets of Melbourne has been brought into question after protesters pelted police with rocks and bottles filled with broken glass at a weekend protest. Victoria Police expect to make more arrests after two officers were injured during the demonstrations on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f618969e71071f1afc61c10813201c8e</guid></item><item><title>As an ex-Olympian, I felt embarrassed about my body. Here&amp;apos;s how I regained my pride</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/they-assume-you-have-it-figured-out-as-an-ex-olympian-i-felt-ashamed-about-my-weight/gmrcu5yfp</link><description>For years, Olympic swimmer Joanna Fargus tried to hide her success as an athlete because she felt embarrassed about her body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56a68d69893f664597bce82001ed047d</guid></item><item><title>Global Amazon outage affects hundreds of platforms | Morning News Bulletin 21 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/global-amazon-outage-affects-hundreds-of-platforms-morning-news-bulletin-21-october-2025/g8y6nyv8g</link><description>A major global outage affects Amazon, disrupting hundreds of platforms; Donald Trump and Anthony Albanese meet at the White House and sign a deal on critical minerals; and in football, a first World Cup win for Morocco.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7665657aaecfe97ff5d0c4f0368eba91</guid></item><item><title>Here&amp;apos;s what we know so far about Trump and Albanese&amp;apos;s $13 billion rare earths deal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-and-albanese-have-signed-a-rare-earth-minerals-deal-what-we-know-so-far/5ws9qzbf0</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese signed a rare earth minerals deal in Washington, stating it goes beyond &amp;quot;just digging things up&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbab98614f7970acfe6cd4bb4849d06a</guid></item><item><title>Amazon says AWS cloud services back to normal after massive outage</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/amazons-aws-struggles-to-recover-after-outage-disrupts-apps-and-services-worldwide/ydottqgy7</link><description>The disruption affected streaming platforms including Amazon&amp;apos;s Prime Video and Disney+, as well as apps Airbnb, Snapchat and Duolingo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">655c4a4ab5715eb11c7d6ffa5ab05c5d</guid></item><item><title>Amazon says AWS cloud services back to normal after massive outage</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/amazon-says-aws-cloud-services-back-to-normal-after-massive-outage/ydottqgy7</link><description>The disruption affected streaming platforms including Amazon&amp;apos;s Prime Video and Disney+, as well as apps Airbnb, Snapchat and Duolingo.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4e183069577a6580cd9eb38b82b9208</guid></item><item><title>Hamas warned &amp;apos;to behave&amp;apos;, as remains of another returned Israeli hostage identified</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/template/gdvsji676</link><description>US President Donald Trump has sent a warning to Hamas, after the group handed over the remains of one more Israeli hostage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4213979510262b9f5b41193131e14153</guid></item><item><title>Hamas warned &amp;apos;to behave&amp;apos;, as remains of another returned Israeli hostage identified</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hamas-hands-over-body-of-another-israeli-hostage/gdvsji676</link><description>US President Donald Trump has sent a warning to Hamas, after the group handed over the remains of one more Israeli hostage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">773cba63118f851346afac521b38cf83</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Friends&amp;apos;, but with tariffs: Five key things to know from the Trump-Albanese meeting</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/five-key-things-to-know-from-the-trump-albanese-meeting/rgfdjrzum</link><description>An awkward moment between Donald Trump and Kevin Rudd failed to derail the US president&amp;apos;s first meeting with &amp;quot;friend&amp;quot; Anthony Albanese.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e606783fd3c6c9bdc1ebd9da02e138d4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Very popular&amp;apos;: Albanese&amp;apos;s glow sends an important message to China</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/with-a-glowing-meeting-in-trumpland-albanese-sends-an-important-message-to-china/izwe9iyei</link><description>Donald Trump&amp;apos;s meeting with Anthony Albanese comes ahead of a hotly anticipated one-on-one with Xi Jinping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4222c5c36fc8401cbc8b95e47b88acc7</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Back him or sack him&amp;apos;: Ley takes aim at Rudd, criticises PM&amp;apos;s Trump tariff &amp;apos;failure&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/back-him-or-sack-him-ley-takes-aim-at-rudd-criticises-pms-trump-tarrif-failure/zf6lyin9i</link><description>Sussan Ley has doubled down on calls to dismiss ambassador Kevin Rudd, despite reports Donald Trump has accepted his apology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81d5511b9ceb7305ce42e1590965de26</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Back him or sack him&amp;apos;: Ley takes aim at Rudd, criticises PM&amp;apos;s Trump tariff &amp;apos;failure&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sussan-ley-anthony-albanese-donald-trump-tariffs/zf6lyin9i</link><description>Sussan Ley has doubled down on calls to dismiss ambassador Kevin Rudd, despite reports Donald Trump has accepted his apology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16e0f32f43541bf38d05966ab82dd7c6</guid></item><item><title>US envoys arrive in Israel to shore up ceasefire | Midday News Bulletin 21 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-envoys-arrive-in-israel-to-shore-up-ceasefire-midday-news-bulletin-21-october-2025/11e7vl8u2</link><description>The US sends its advisers to Israel as Gaza ceasefire threatened; Opposition leader Sussan Ley calls on Kevin Rudd to resign; And in sport, a joint bid to host the 2031 Women&amp;apos;s World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">548e6db7f74ac9f9884d9616af19ee63</guid></item><item><title>Your viewing guide to the Orionids meteor shower as it reaches its peak</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/your-viewing-guide-to-tonights-orionids-meteor-shower/p502zzfn8</link><description>Australia will witness its &amp;quot;fourth best&amp;quot; meteor shower of the year on Wednesday morning. Here&amp;apos;s what you can expect.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c9030be744dd54f2407669177009d75</guid></item><item><title>More sunscreens have been recalled. Is yours among them?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/more-sunscreens-have-been-recalled-is-yours-among-them/kf8cxj1sd</link><description>Two more sunscreens are off the shelves, as parts of Australia brace for a week of hot temperatures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">efa62031d8c0cd48393271fa82220b4b</guid></item><item><title>SBS News In Easy English 21 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-21-october-2025/essu4bpsz</link><description>A daily 5 minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf23b67c4dd7abaa807731e2a3ab2d41</guid></item><item><title>Australia and China trade accusations after South China Sea flare incident</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-and-china-trade-accusations-after-south-china-sea-flare-incident1/ut069y68e</link><description>The potential consequences of a flare striking a plane are severe, an expert has said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64093cbfa5902131dadeffe7f781339e</guid></item><item><title>US officials work to preserve Gaza ceasefire</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-officials-work-to-preserve-gaza-ceasefire/s0anhwigi</link><description>Diplomatic efforts have intensified in the Middle East as the United States works to preserve the fragile Gaza ceasefire following a weekend of renewed violence. The truce, part of US President Donald Trump’s multi-phase Gaza plan, was shaken after a Palestinian attack killed two Israeli soldiers, triggering Israeli airstrikes that left dozens dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de86e745be573827d92cdb4e644fe35c</guid></item><item><title>The growing number of Australians adopting this risky travel trend</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-growing-number-of-australians-adopting-this-risky-travel-trend/byentmbqe</link><description>The government places this &amp;quot;expectation&amp;quot; on all Australians travelling overseas, yet a growing number aren&amp;apos;t heeding the advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd4defc6be3ebb44979ae3ecfcd4d8a8</guid></item><item><title>Japan set to welcome first female PM following coalition deal | Evening News Bulletin 21 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/japan-set-to-welcome-first-female-pm-following-coalition-deal-evening-news-bulletin-21-october-2025/u37eraw7d</link><description>Japan set to welcome first female PM following coalition deal; Defence Minister says jobs expected to flow from AUKUS defence agreement; And in AFL, coaches named ahead of first State of Origin game in almost 27 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c09e6f0ed0ad9cb8a782bfa1b3d3e8c4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Broke half the internet&amp;apos;: Amazon cloud outage lasts 15 hours, triggering global chaos</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/broke-half-the-internet-amazon-cloud-outage-lasts-15-hours-triggering-global-chaos/uvo81bq38</link><description>A massive internet outage has taken out thousands of websites, apps and services globally. The technical fault originated with U-S data centres operated by Amazon Web Services, which controls 30 per cent of the world&amp;apos;s cloud computing market that underpins web-based services like apps and websites.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb36cafd14857ab02521790de98268a9</guid></item><item><title>Deals signed as Trump and Albanese meet; but what are the wider implications?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/deals-signed-as-trump-and-albanese-meet-but-what-are-the-wider-implications/zrzqbx2un</link><description>In a historic meeting between Donald Trump and Anthony Albanese, the AUKUS agreement remained unchanged as the two leaders unveiled a multi-billion-dollar critical minerals deal to secure supply chains and reduce reliance on China. The agreement involves major US investment in Australian mining and processing projects, but has sparked criticism over fears it could give the US too much control over Australia’s resources and sovereignty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e8b365db8103ff1247fcee61de0d45e</guid></item><item><title>Rare earths deal boosts some mining shares as ASX hits record</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/rare-earths-deal-boosts-some-mining-shares-as-asx-hits-record/2eyin84df</link><description>The Australian sharemarket hit a record high for a second time in a week as the US and Australia strike a rare earths supply deal, but it was BHP that was a real stand out today. SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Catherine Allfrey from Wavestone Capital to find out if the sector is worth the hype and what else is driving investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cceda0c8400d76095027f505b6133927</guid></item><item><title>Rare earth minerals deal declared &amp;apos;a triumph&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/rare-earth-minerals-deal-declared-a-triumph/jabta9o0w</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s newly sealed critical minerals deal with the United States has sent the share market skyrocketing. The industry and investors are responding to billions of dollars in new investment aimed at disrupting China&amp;apos;s dominance over global rare earths supply chains.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a4c1d7bfac0d86a89f1a2f2e648157cb</guid></item></channel></rss>