<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>SBS English News (Unofficial Aggregation)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2025 21:02:34 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Arab leaders urge international community to stop applying &amp;apos;double standards&amp;apos; to Israel</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/arab-leaders-urge-international-community-to-stop-applying-double-standards-to-israel/usbjwt647</link><description>An Israeli strike on Doha last week has set off a wave of condemnation, with Arab and Islamic leaders gathering in Qatar to arrive at a united response. Israel, meanwhile, is standing firm, deepening its alliance with Washington as the war in Gaza rages on.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3653d263be203116438f7672fa22bbe</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 15th September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-15th-september-2025/sbnl9okv6</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d11c5dbd624e4b995766a4d36eb1d63f</guid></item><item><title>Adolescence star Owen Cooper becomes youngest male actor to win an Emmy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/adolescence-star-owen-cooper-youngest-male-actor-emmy-award/bs6xak09v</link><description>The four-part series he starred in recorded 140 million views in its first three months on Netflix, and drew rave reviews.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88b9cdd5a554d3787a15cef54e87bbb4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;No Australian spared&amp;apos;: National Climate Risk Assessment delivers dire warning</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/no-australian-spared-national-climate-risk-assessment-delivers-dire-warning/dv11b9bvw</link><description>Coastal hazards driven by climate change could put three million people at risk by 2090 if Australia warms by 3 degrees, according to a major body of new climate research released by the federal government. The National Climate Risk Assessment has been released, as the government prepares the ground to announce its carbon emissions reduction target for 2035.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f97c0aa4761f1a3ffcd5412c41816d0</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We take it very seriously&amp;apos;: Queenslander charged over Nazi salute at AFL game</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/we-take-it-very-seriously-queenslander-charged-over-nazi-salute-at-afl-game/yl67p2juy</link><description>A spectator has received a lifetime AFL ban after being accused of performing a Nazi salute at a major finals clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5914a8ddfe870a62368edabcf5190c91</guid></item><item><title>ANZ cops $240m fine for widespread misconduct</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/anz-cops-240m-fine-for-widespread-misconduct/bmgq0k3yc</link><description>The Australian share market has begun the week lower, despite optimism ahead of the US Federal Reserve’s expected interest rate cut this week. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Macquarie Private Bank Division Director Martin Lakos. Plus, ANZ has been fined $240 million for what ASIC has called widespread misconduct, including allegations of failing to respond to customer hardship notices and failing to refund fees charged to thousands of dead customers. For more, Asha Abdi spoke with Professor Allan Fels from the University of Melbourne.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5d13edf20e0ec5fc15dd1f0095cd1c1</guid></item><item><title>How much money do you really need to be happy? Here&amp;apos;s what the research says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-much-money-do-you-need-to-be-happy/4wiladly5</link><description>Recent data shows that economic inequality in Australia is increasing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4088fd69be648f99c3bda2c7527648cd</guid></item><item><title>Inside the &amp;apos;hyper-connected&amp;apos; nationalist groups fuelling protests in Australia and the UK</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/far-right-movements-australia-uk/qg4lpzb6n</link><description>There is a complex picture behind the recent mobilisation of the far-right across Australia and the UK. But experts say it&amp;apos;s happened before.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9daae4521c2c5f20a914b428a4563f2b</guid></item><item><title>Kurtis Marschall takes pole vault bronze for Australia at World Athletics Championships 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/kurtis-marschall-takes-pole-vault-bronze-for-australia-at-world-athletics-championships-2025/04sycae6g</link><description>Pole vaulter Kurtis Marschall has won Australia&amp;apos;s first medal of the Tokyo world championships and Mondo Duplantis has broken his own world record in the event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e6d4e4819da4612df4aec0b6e792707</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout is through to his World Athletics Championships semi-final. Here&amp;apos;s how to watch</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/when-gout-gout-is-running-at-the-world-athletics-championships-and-how-to-watch/wxcgdxhi1</link><description>The Australian sprinting sensation is making his senior international debut in Tokyo. Here&amp;apos;s what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f827afa27127359f3e334562ecad2985</guid></item><item><title>Liberal senator warns of &amp;apos;mass exodus&amp;apos; from Coalition frontbench over net zero</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/liberal-mp-warns-of-mass-exodus-from-coalition-frontbench-over-net-zero/bdze7eboy</link><description>The Liberal party is once again at loggerheads over the party&amp;apos;s stance on net zero, with another frontbencher warning against adopting a policy &amp;quot;at any cost&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">128743e323d67bc42866ac5b3b5aebf9</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Israel is fighting a war of slavery&amp;apos;: Strong criticism from emergency summit in Qatar</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israel-is-fighting-a-war-of-slavery-strong-criticism-from-emergency-summit-in-qatar/3h32qdqlj</link><description>Arab and Islamic leaders have met in Doha following Israel’s strike that killed Hamas officials and a Qatari security officer. Qatar’s Emir accused Israel of seeking dominance, while Iran, Turkey and Egypt called for sanctions, isolation and regional defence coordination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de90d414b7efa5a9f88bf3f078625899</guid></item><item><title>What social media platforms will — and won&amp;apos;t — have to do under Australia&amp;apos;s under-16s ban</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/social-media-ban-guidelines-for-platforms/py4ll7x14</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s eSafety commissioner has unveiled guidelines for social media companies to comply with age restriction laws that will come into effect on 10 December. Here&amp;apos;s what we know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b879f0b6c80c03ba96e0dde6e7570be</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 16 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-16-september-2025/31fthx5k3</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ab9a66db86207a08fe5b80ad88d414a</guid></item><item><title>Cash-for-votes, deepfakes and propaganda: Russia&amp;apos;s latest bid for influence</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cash-for-votes-deepfakes-and-propaganda-russias-latest-bid-for-influence/xmp4569qg</link><description>As Russia&amp;apos;s neighbour prepares to head to the polls, a pro-Russian alliance appears to be on the rise thanks, in part, to a disinformation and propaganda campaign some believe is backed by the Kremlin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4aa7ab05869477868278a2d54ed7348</guid></item><item><title>Australian dollar hits a 10 month high against the US</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australian-dollar-hits-a-10-month-high-against-the-us/a3vmn3yt3</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves takes a look at the driving forces in the currency markets with Chris Weston from Pepperstone and previews the US Federal Reserve&amp;apos;s Thursday morning interest rate decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8f4e843fec3119fba965a843fc9c962</guid></item><item><title>Israel has committed genocide against Palestinians in Gaza, UN inquiry finds</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-has-committed-genocide-in-gaza-un-inquiry-finds/vuen505p5</link><description>The UN commission of inquiry concluded that Israeli authorities and forces had, since October 2023, committed &amp;quot;four of the five genocidal acts&amp;quot; listed in the 1948 Genocide Convention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd9543e763cd97308302a62d53ddc57a</guid></item><item><title>Deep rifts widen further within Coalition under climate change pressure</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/deep-rifts-widen-further-within-coalition-under-climate-change-pressure/1zvkaao65</link><description>Liberal senator Jonathan Duniam has warned the Coalition will face a &amp;quot;mass exodus&amp;quot; from its frontbench if it adopts a net zero policy without caveats, handing Opposition leader Sussan Ley a fresh test over the party&amp;apos;s stance on climate action. The warning comes a day after Liberal MP Andrew Hastie threatened to quit the party if it pursued a policy of net zero emissions by 2050.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">348807a5b201db1ec34ef79aa7b88747</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;As data-minimising as possible&amp;apos;: under-16 social media ban guidelines published</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/as-data-minimising-as-possible-under-16-social-media-ban-guidelines-published/8u91iu8ae</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s eSafety commissioner has published regulatory guidelines for social media platforms, giving effect to the government&amp;apos;s under-16 social media ban. While the ban won&amp;apos;t be in place until December 10th, the eSafety commissioner says they want it to be as minimally invasive as possible. Under the guidance, social media platforms will not have to verify the age of every user on their platforms.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90e4f62ebaf692b332097cf37f780736</guid></item><item><title>Cocaine, cartels, and questions: Concerns over Trump&amp;apos;s drug boat &amp;apos;hunt&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/venezuela-us-boat-strikes-war/7w0nk7bdw</link><description>The US has carried out deadly strikes on Venezuelan boats it alleges carried &amp;apos;narcoterrorists&amp;apos;. But are these killings lawful? And why is the US turning its focus to the South American nation?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97722cd8dfd9fff5254087834f46e035</guid></item><item><title>Modified and dangerous: The popular &amp;apos;illegal motorbikes&amp;apos; on Australia&amp;apos;s roads</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/e-bike-hack-speed-limit/aczay55hs</link><description>Modified e-bikes that can run well over their legal speed limit are causing serious injuries and even deaths — is it time for Australia to crack down?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df103d0d076f1cb9cf067487a6fc40a9</guid></item><item><title>When Andrea’s husband died, their blended family was &amp;apos;instantaneously decimated&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/when-andreas-husband-died-their-blended-family-was-instantaneously-decimated/vi18cevkf</link><description>Maintaining contact with step or blended family after a separation can be difficult and give rise to mixed emotions — especially when there are no legal responsibilities between stepparents and stepchildren.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e97cd625be3266938e7501a1d56118c</guid></item><item><title>Chalmers reacts to Trump&amp;apos;s rebuke as ABC journalist says president was &amp;apos;feisty&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/you-are-hurting-australia-donald-trumps-blow-up-with-abc-journalist-john-lyons/85u3mdbz1</link><description>The ABC&amp;apos;s Americas editor John Lyons joked he would have to &amp;quot;brace himself&amp;quot; after US President Donald Trump said he was going to tell Prime Minister Anthony Albanese about him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">25f1936702ed5ff8a762df4245e79b40</guid></item><item><title>Australia-PNG defence pact on hold, but PM insists it&amp;apos;ll still be inked</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/defence-australia-papua-new-guinea/a51ydrt2a</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese was expected to sign the landmark defence treaty while visiting Papua New Guinea.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88a7730562e09113e6a572e0b02d1c53</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 17 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-17-september-2025/wbr4eiodu</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">077bcf2e404217cef131c139ff7c495e</guid></item><item><title>Four arrested after Epstein, Trump images projected on castle ahead of president&amp;apos;s visit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/protesters-arrested-for-projecting-epstein-and-trump-on-windsor-castle-before-state-visit/bmbysh0z2</link><description>Four adults were arrested on suspicion of malicious communications after protesters unfurled a massive banner featuring a photograph of Trump and Epstein near Windsor Castle, and later projected several images of the pair onto one of its towers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9e1583f7fee843901ebdf0cdcb69696</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk&amp;apos;s alleged killer has been charged. Trump&amp;apos;s base has its sights on a different target</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/charlie-kirk-trump-administration-left-wing-political-violence/tqj7w0mey</link><description>Fears are growing of a looming crackdown on Donald Trump&amp;apos;s perceived political opponents after the US president and members of his administration warned the &amp;quot;radical left&amp;quot; would face consequences for the assassination of right-wing commentator Charlie Kirk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a12813ed6287b2c9cbf0076f8331d7e</guid></item><item><title>No deal: Albanese leaves empty-handed after PNG delays defence pact</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/no-deal-albanese-leaves-empty-handed-after-png-delays-defence-pact/ybdmue64f</link><description>The Prime Minister is leaving Papua New Guinea empty-handed after a landmark security agreement wasn&amp;apos;t signed in the final hours. The delayed deal comes less than two weeks after a similar defence with Vanuatu was delayed over concerns it will affect their other relationships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e51811559a1784834f489eb6cb72dc53</guid></item><item><title>The bank of mum and dad helping first home buyers, &amp;amp; investors look to US Federal Reserve</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-bank-of-mum-and-dad-helping-first-home-buyers-investors-look-to-us-federal-reserve/89w9sotms</link><description>Parents and grandparents are increasingly offering financial assistance to family members with 20 per cent saying they provided help in the last quarter, so SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with UBS Economist Stephen Wu to find out to what extent they&amp;apos;re helping. Plus Kyle Rodda from capital.com looks through the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action and previews the Federal Reserve&amp;apos;s interest rate decision.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">331daecf74125ff50bf11ef01888d1f6</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s newest citizens welcomed in ceremonies on Australian Citizenship Day</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australias-newest-citizens-welcomed-in-ceremonies-on-australian-citizenship-day/ysjxez62u</link><description>Thousands are celebrating becoming new Australians, as local councils hosted ceremonies around the country for Australian Citizenship Day. SBS spoke to some of the new citizens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ed29a3364679e7422e874b3ac02d7eb</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout soars into semifinal &amp;apos;against the big dogs&amp;apos; at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gout-gout-qualifies-for-200m-semifinals-at-world-athletics-championships/0hm54qjrf</link><description>Sprint sensation Gout Gout has lived up to the hype by qualifying for the 200m semi-finals at the world championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8a0ae1bbfccdf5051b7bb82628c6039</guid></item><item><title>I grew up in several blended families. Olivia was the only stable maternal figure in my life</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/tottie-goldsmith-on-aunt-olivia-newton-john-as-a-maternal-figure/g5vm5cfy6</link><description>Actor and singer Tottie Goldsmith didn’t have much contact with her mother growing up and was raised in blended families as her dad remarried several times. She says that she craved emotional stability and connection during this time and so found a consistent maternal figure in her late aunt, Olivia Newton-John.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4d11ed25678bcb78f23652d13b6adf0</guid></item><item><title>The key question for Australia after UN report&amp;apos;s Gaza genocide finding</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/genocide-finding-australia-violence-gaza/p7tjzdeg0</link><description>The UN Independent International Commission of Inquiry report found Israel is committing genocide in Gaza — an accusation it denies. Experts say the recommendations provide a blueprint for the Australian government to take stronger action, but will it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04b35d33df97625b1d378c59d9aef373</guid></item><item><title>Pomp, protests and an &amp;apos;eternal&amp;apos; bond on day one of Donald Trump&amp;apos;s UK state visit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/donald-trump-uk-first-day/81qb9ywqb</link><description>The visit, marked by record security, protests and awkward questions over Jeffrey Epstein, is being used by UK Prime Minister Keir Starmer to push trade talks and secure major US tech investments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1409d5ec5cd1101d6ee1836cc3bee5a</guid></item><item><title>The transnational links between extremist groups fuelling protests in Australia and the UK</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-transnational-links-between-extremist-groups-fuelling-protests-in-australia-and-the-uk/z852pgtde</link><description>Experts say there are a number of driving forces behind recent mass demonstrations in Australia and the UK, and says they are &amp;quot;not particularly exceptional&amp;quot;. They also say media organisations need to treat this issue with caution when reporting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a481c14c72c1cd725a2cda7f76715210</guid></item><item><title>Albanese unveils 2035 emissions reduction target — and billions in new funding</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-2035-emissions-reduction-climate-albanese-government/941q08lrn</link><description>The federal government has unveiled a target to cut emissions by 62 to 70 per cent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a015036180737ad1108533b732245da</guid></item><item><title>Calls for change to Low Income Super Tax Offset rule</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/calls-for-change-to-low-income-super-tax-offset-rule/u270fhxh2</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ceaf9d3a5bdb8950054d8a4a96429c35</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Kimmel Live taken off air indefinitely after host&amp;apos;s Charlie Kirk comments</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jimmy-kimmel-live-taken-off-air-indefinitely-after-hosts-charlie-kirk-comments/gftrceo0u</link><description>Kimmel suggested during his show this week that Donald Trump&amp;apos;s base had used the death of right-wing commentator Kirk for political gain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">859db719df69f0a6b2fd2a860f34eed5</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians fleeing Gaza City as Israel opens additional exit passage</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/palestinians-fleeing-gaza-city-as-israel-opens-additional-exit-passage/7jdofl7ek</link><description>Hundreds of thousands of Gazans are fleeing south as Israel’s bombardment of the enclave intensifies, with families forced to carry children and the elderly along designated so-called safe routes.Meanwhile, Israel’s far-right finance minister has controversially described Gaza as a potential real estate bonanza once demolished.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06f8cac8001e838cb3e240d2245b4c51</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 18 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-18-september-2025/pvnleyaxc</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e301b4acdc1fa625f38fc04616a73a77</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Not likely to please anyone&amp;apos;: Labor&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;ambitious&amp;apos; new emissions target faces criticism</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/labors-new-emissions-target-faces-criticism/xxfp490yw</link><description>The updated target has been criticised as both insufficient and overly ambitious.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57eb33ad36faecbbbbe57bc3116e7fde</guid></item><item><title>Too high or too low? Australia&amp;apos;s 2035 climate target pleases no one</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/too-high-or-too-low-australias-2035-climate-target-pleases-no-one/b56y8dn44</link><description>As one of the world&amp;apos;s biggest greenhouse gas emitters per capita, Australia has announced its new 2035 emissions reduction target. The federal government has committed to a target to cut emissions by 62 to 70 per cent by 2035, based on 2005 levels. Some say the target is too high, others say it&amp;apos;s too low. Labor says it&amp;apos;s both ambitious and achievable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb03a2f19144c240425216cb2b9b5b5e</guid></item><item><title>Full-time jobs tumble, US cuts rates &amp;amp; future of chocolate prices</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/full-time-jobs-tumble-us-cuts-rates-future-of-chocolate-prices/b7upp8x6w</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Blair Chapman from Seek about the latest jobs data which showed a near 41,000 fall in full-time jobs; Lochlan Halloway from Morningstar takes a look at the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action including the reaction to the US Federal Reserve&amp;apos;s first interst rate cut this year; and Stephanie Youssef discusses the future of chocolate prices with Paul Joules from Rabobank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f92eb9f4c92dcbac9e62432783ca424c</guid></item><item><title>The $500 million problem caused by an &amp;apos;out-of-date&amp;apos; super rule</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-500-million-problem-caused-by-an-out-of-date-superannuation-rule/4ghyi1b2f</link><description>One part of Australia&amp;apos;s superannuation system has been &amp;quot;frozen for years&amp;quot; — and its a problem that could be leaving some shortchanged, according to a new report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31b6886198a217311231a9a80ae734ce</guid></item><item><title>Trump&amp;apos;s royal treatment, UN declares &amp;apos;genocide&amp;apos; in Gaza &amp;amp; Albania&amp;apos;s AI minister</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trumps-royal-treatment-un-declares-genocide-in-gaza-albanias-ai-minister/h31rz89h4</link><description>Donald Trump gets some face time with the King &amp;amp; Queen on a state visit to the UK. A UN commission of inquiry finds Israel’s war in Gaza amounts to genocide as Israel’s ground operation in Gaza City gets underway. MAGA vows war on the left in response to Charlie Kirk&amp;apos;s killing and Bolsonaro is sentenced to 27 years in jail. Plus, Albania unveils an all AI minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce9a2f7292b5a7841655507530b31a5a</guid></item><item><title>Foreign policy, free speech and Epstein: Takeaways from Trump and Starmer&amp;apos;s press conference</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/british-pm-starmer-hosts-trump-at-chequers-as-leaders-tackle-trade-ukraine-and-gaza/ha9alivgz</link><description>The US and UK leaders hailed the renewal of the countries&amp;apos; &amp;quot;special relationship&amp;quot; as Trump&amp;apos;s state visit drew to a close.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f17a9368be4ffcc29c46a6534873168f</guid></item><item><title>Gout Gout is out of the World Athletics Championships — but time is on his side</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/teen-sprinting-sensation-gout-gout-falls-short-on-200m-sprint-at-world-athletics-championships/ujqsra2nb</link><description>The 17-year-old placed fourth in the second semi-final on Thursday night with a time of 20.36 seconds.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f16cc55e4af10e53d1fc925017d2c693</guid></item><item><title>Ned&amp;apos;s grandson died in police custody. Three months on, the cause still isn&amp;apos;t confirmed.</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/kumanjayi-white-justice-family-sues-nt-government/kyq19rxzc</link><description>The police-led investigation into Kumanjayi White&amp;apos;s death in custody is still ongoing, amid growing frustration and anger from the Yuendumu community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">23e6fb731cd1a6d9aaea1acb369dde69</guid></item><item><title>The Aussie dollar is having a moment. Here&amp;apos;s what it means for you</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-aussie-dollar-is-having-a-moment-but-its-not-all-good-news/n875p5dci</link><description>The Australian dollar is trading at around a 10-month high against the US dollar and has been broadly performing &amp;quot;very well&amp;quot;. But it&amp;apos;s not the whole story, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16181be12514e54ef1715b90b5ff232f</guid></item><item><title>Sydney&amp;apos;s army of Olympic volunteers mark 25 years</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sydneys-army-of-olympic-volunteers-mark-25-years/gv0veefu1</link><description>This week marks 25 years since the opening of the Sydney Olympics. From welcoming athletes to washing t-shirts, an army of than 46,000 volunteers helped maintain the smooth running of the games - including pioneer volunteers who volunteered in the years leading up to the games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01324e6a0b9642f934c4b509eb73740c</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 19 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-19-september-2025/blrw8q0cx</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3c577df1f08ee6de1f73c0e03db9951c</guid></item><item><title>What we know about Charlie Kirk&amp;apos;s memorial service</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/charlie-kirk-memorial-service-what-we-know/o07jvi90o</link><description>Charlie Kirk, a right-wing political commentator, was assassinated while speaking at a university campus in the US state of Utah last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64b119dfd8a924ae6ae5484ad792b26d</guid></item><item><title>Why we&amp;apos;re retiring five years later — and the &amp;apos;big problem&amp;apos; for future generations</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/behind-the-significant-shift-forcing-australians-to-retire-later/29i3wx7d0</link><description>A &amp;quot;significant shift&amp;quot; has pushed back the age Australians are retiring, according to an author of a new report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fe93b1066bf90ab6e08d0182ee88053</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Right plan for Australia&amp;apos;: Government ministers defend 2035 climate target</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/right-plan-for-australia-government-ministers-defend-2035-climate-target/valq4hga4</link><description>Climate advocates say the federal government&amp;apos;s 2035 emissions reduction target falls &amp;quot;dangerously short&amp;quot;, while the Coalition has said its plan is &amp;quot;grounded in fantasy land&amp;quot;. Government ministers are now working to justify the target to the public and the community, as the Coalition is under pressure to outline their climate policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebc84b70a57343be1a1ddd233edc32d3</guid></item><item><title>Age pension to rise &amp;amp; is AI in bubble territory?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/age-pension-to-rise-is-ai-in-bubble-territory/n4w04zxam</link><description>Stephanie Youssef speaks with Omkar Joshi from Opal Capital Management for the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket news, including whether AI is in bubble territory, while SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves goes through the upcoming age pension changes with Joshua Parisotto from HESTA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90c04e68d051f861af732150e544c39a</guid></item><item><title>Israelis shot at Allenby Crossing into Jordan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israelis-shot-at-allenby-crossing-into-jordan/gnca6lfb3</link><description>The Israeli military has confirmed four of its personnel were killed in Rafah as well as two Israeli citizens, in a shooting described as a terrorist attack at Allenby Crossing. The crisis has deepened divisions around the world and at the United Nations, where a US veto blocked a resolution calling for a ceasefire and unrestricted aid.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">404bb714f4b2d2085ed89d62b70fa06d</guid></item><item><title>Three people dead after Optus network upgrade sparked triple-zero call failure</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/three-people-dead-after-optus-tech-outage/p3nnritko</link><description>Two of the deceased were from South Australia and one from Western Australia, Optus CEO Stephen Rue said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc839d84b6579fe15ea60b9bd0371664</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Really angry&amp;apos;: Isabel is one of hundreds considering class action against this IVF provider</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ivf-patients-demand-justice-after-medical-data-exposed-in-cyberattack/ih7slpxfh</link><description>Hundreds of Australians have shown interest in a class action lawsuit, which could be the first test of new reforms to Australia&amp;apos;s Privacy Act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc6dba138f50905f83a082e23d05a45a</guid></item><item><title>Free speech fears continue to roil US as Trump says unfair media coverage is &amp;apos;illegal&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/donald-trump-jimmy-kimmel-and-free-speech-questions/2u5tx5gyx</link><description>What began as a late-night joke has spiralled into a test of free speech in Trump’s America.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0ee1b52ba9c4d73934277d9fef82da24</guid></item><item><title>Healing land and spirit through Noongar knowledge and regenerative land management</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/healing-land-and-spirit-through-noongar-knowledge-and-regenerative-land-management/p1p5026u4</link><description>In Western Australia&amp;apos;s Wheatbelt, a region long shaped by industrial farming practices, a new model of regenerative agriculture is taking root. At Yaraguia farm, Ballardong Noongar man Oral McGuire is healing Country, reconnecting First Nations knowledge of caring for Country with modern land management to restore ecosystems and produce food that benefits both the land and the community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">844c927a6712a5c08235ccb3e576e02f</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Incredibly tragic event&amp;apos;: Fourth death linked to 10-hour Optus triple-zero outage</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/baby-among-deaths-after-optus-network-upgrade-sparked-triple-zero-call-failure/0tejm01pf</link><description>South Australian Premier Peter Malinauskas blasted the telco&amp;apos;s slow and &amp;quot;bewildering&amp;quot; response, vowing it would be held to account for the outage that affected approximately 600 triple-zero calls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9385ea9f685509504ca85fe357b6c24d</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Incredibly tragic event&amp;apos;: Fourth death linked to 10-hour Optus triple-zero outage</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fourth-death-linked-to-optus-triple-zero-outage/0tejm01pf</link><description>South Australian Premier Peter Malinauskas blasted the telco&amp;apos;s slow and &amp;quot;bewildering&amp;quot; response, vowing it would be held to account for the outage that affected approximately 600 triple-zero calls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac8b75acd6828d638449cdc953708b2b</guid></item><item><title>I feel like privacy is dead: IVF data breach triggers interest in class action lawsuit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/i-feel-like-privacy-is-dead-ivf-data-breach-triggers-interest-in-class-action-lawsuit/cjewja2h0</link><description>After years of trying to conceive, Isabel Lewis thought the hard part was over — until cybercriminals targeted her fertility clinic. The data breach at Genea Fertility included patient&amp;apos;s medical histories, diagnoses and treatments, medications and prescriptions, as well as pathology and diagnostic test results. Now, hundreds of Australians have shown interest in a class action lawsuit over the breach, which could be the first test of new reforms to Australia&amp;apos;s Privacy Act.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d623350fbe1becacded6c2de1ea175f</guid></item><item><title>The 80th General Assembly of the UN is meeting in New York. How does it work - and why?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-80th-general-assembly-of-the-un-is-meeting-in-new-york-how-does-it-work-and-why/0kzy3p06v</link><description>World leaders will gather in New York next week for the annual General Assembly. Secretary-General Antonio Guterres has highlighted peace, climate, responsible innovation, gender equality, development financing and UN reform as central themes of the week. But the high-level week of the General Assembly also marks the 80th anniversary of the founding of the United Nations. We take a look at just what the UNGA is and what its powers are.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9db66fe1423d86074eb49c04475b1bb5</guid></item><item><title>Jess Hull breaks Australian record and qualifies for 800m final at World Athletics Championships</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jess-hull-breaks-australian-record-and-qualifies-for-800m-final-at-world-athletics-championships/8ypl2tj37</link><description>The 28-year-old recorded a time of 1:57.15 and placed third in her semi-final heat in Tokyo on Friday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28b820ef4f9d07b2d34a9ef8c6bb61a9</guid></item><item><title>Why some Australian parents are giving their kids as much as $200k</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-some-australian-parents-are-giving-their-kids-as-much-as-200k/3ljc87ncz</link><description>Parents and grandparents are increasingly offering financial assistance to family members with 20 per cent saying they provided help in the last quarter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e145f20734b7cc2ee25aec4344848562</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Unprecedentedly brazen&amp;apos;: Estonia invokes Nato treaty after Russian jets violate airspace</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/unprecedentedly-brazen-estonia-invokes-nato-treaty-after-russian-jets-violate-airspace/50lbeuflp</link><description>Russia&amp;apos;s defence ministry denied its jets violated Estonian airspace, saying they flew over neutral waters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10b20386de8ecc186e4cc54d070f1786</guid></item><item><title>The &amp;apos;quite simple&amp;apos; way this group of Australians could save lives</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-quite-simple-way-this-group-of-australians-could-save-lives/dx9i8syah</link><description>Australians receiving treatment for &amp;quot;urgent&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;critical&amp;quot; diseases are having to wait for people overseas to make life-saving donations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a12f1b1e068a5343c7ae2a2e4208469b</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Not exactly glamorous&amp;apos;: The &amp;apos;disheartening&amp;apos; reality of dating in rural Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/not-exactly-glamorous-the-disheartening-reality-of-dating-in-rural-australia/nwk6ljyl7</link><description>Rural Australians say dating in the country is a whole lot harder than in the city, with geographic isolation the least of their worries. Finding someone with the same values and lifestyle priorities is often the hardest challenge, which is why singles events in the sticks are having such a big impact.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2eaa670e1523adf9747d62d37d71dfc7</guid></item><item><title>The UN has reached a historic milestone. The world will be watching what it does next</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-un-has-reached-a-historic-milestone-the-world-will-be-watching-what-it-does-next/uewo1uz58</link><description>This week&amp;apos;s United Nations meeting will be a landmark occasion for multiple reasons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a315465a3b52331977c1e7d80247e6ed</guid></item><item><title>Opinions divided on how to save our precious mountain ash forests</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/opinions-divided-on-how-to-save-our-precious-mountain-ash-forests/op16qt6ej</link><description>New research has found Australia&amp;apos;s heat-stressed forests are rapidly thinning, and could even be producing carbon emissions. It comes as the government prepares to release its 2035 emissions targets and a climate risk report later this month. But local researchers, politicians and Traditional Owner land groups remain divided on how to protect the forest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e33c95c736d2925c88938f0b35bff432</guid></item><item><title>John Santi lays his brother&amp;apos;s remains to rest after finding out museum displayed specimens without consent</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/john-santi-lays-his-brothers-remains-to-rest-after-finding-out-museum-displayed-specimens-without-consent/hl1qtneb3</link><description>A coronial investigation launched in Tasmania in 2016 has found the University of Tasmania removed and kept human remains without consent or approval. The investigation raises broader questions about collections of human remains in other universities and museums in Australia, and what obligation these institutions have to identify their origin.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7af8c244563f7d7a4509c0861a7f982</guid></item><item><title>White House issues clarification after Trump hits H-1B visas with $150,000 fee</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/white-house-issues-clarification-after-trump-hits-h-1b-visas-with-150-000-fee/4twsvuybx</link><description>The announcement sparked concerns among employees across swaths of corporate America.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">01cc247becefc388b2615302acaa1ea4</guid></item><item><title>Here&amp;apos;s the tea: Global shortage means steep prices for matcha lovers</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/heres-the-tea-global-shortage-means-steep-prices-for-matcha-lovers/mo2j9gaqg</link><description>Global matcha prices are surging due to poor weather in Japan, rising global demand, labour shortages, and steep US tariffs on imports from Japan and China. Now, the world’s love affair with matcha may be tested - at the checkout counter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">440955bfb89df9d50804ee222428742e</guid></item><item><title>At least 60 Palestinians killed as Israel presses on with Gaza City assault</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/at-least-60-palestinians-killed-as-israel-presses-on-with-gaza-city-assault/a6qut4gzs</link><description>The Israeli military estimates it has demolished up to 20 Gaza City tower blocks over the past two weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">657b2bcc723cf0ea4b44e312a5c9d057</guid></item><item><title>Republicans warn Australia of &amp;apos;punitive measures&amp;apos; recognising Palestinian statehood</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-arrives-in-new-york-for-united-nations-general-assembly/brwy9gygs</link><description>Anthony Albanese will recognise Palestinian statehood along with other world leaders at the UN General Assembly this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2088e0f8675431337726da2b236c533</guid></item><item><title>A cyber attack has hit some of Europe&amp;apos;s busiest airports. Here&amp;apos;s what you need to know</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cyberattack-on-european-airports/fr7ztrpmh</link><description>The cyber attack on check-in systems caused cancellations and long delays for thousands of passengers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6f0648f1ee58498a8d7530fcaa7ed4a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Disgraceful&amp;apos;: Optus launches investigation, reveals two more emergency call failures</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/more-people-impacted-by-optus-outage-with-investigation-to-begin/qoht29ixb</link><description>Optus says alongside an investigation, it will launch a new compulsory escalation process following any customer reports of 000 failures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dafed8235a1754f6cf5fd4836946f710</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Wait for it&amp;apos;: Netanyahu warns Australia, other nations for recognising Palestinian state</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-formally-recognises-a-palestinian-state/31a83nmyd</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s recognition does not require ratification in the parliament or any United Nations vote to come into effect — it is now official government policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c4b73b8d4747322b054fff3f084e68e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Remarkable&amp;apos;: How Gaza protests unfolded in Australia and around the world</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-in-top-10-countries-for-pro-palestinian-protests-data-reveals/6g4nkqzpd</link><description>Australia is considered a &amp;quot;low protest country&amp;quot; but it has held some of the biggest pro-Palestinian protests in the world. Explore how Gaza protests have unfolded in our interactive map.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">009fc00709d3b9a3a7f09490eb8ced3c</guid></item><item><title>Some Australians are not confident about their retirement. Here&amp;apos;s how much you need a year</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cost-of-retirement-on-the-rise-for-many-australians/acuunp273</link><description>Australians looking for work in their 40s and women, especially those divorced or single with children, are not feeling confident about retirement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">feb210a413726c3539cf4168267c9e37</guid></item><item><title>The penalties Optus could face after its &amp;apos;second significant and egregious failure&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/telco-regulator-launches-investigation-into-optus-failure/gkr1a9sel</link><description>The Australian Communications and Media Authority has announced its investigation into the Optus triple-zero outage, with the communications minister warning there will be consequences for the sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f1818080f2d07adfe4b2a856a114cb</guid></item><item><title>More Israeli strikes hit Lebanon, Gaza</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/more-israeli-strikes-hit-lebanon-gaza/l84riwvvv</link><description>An Israeli drone strike on the Lebanese town of Bint Jbeil has killed five people, including three children, despite a US-brokered ceasefire with Hezbollah. The tragedy comes as Gaza endures another wave of bombardments, with dozens killed in the past day alone.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2598aa8207b41bf139ecaf73fee94e6f</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 22 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-22-september-2025/4nkw7zk8b</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0793cdad57021b2c2b75bdab63e1534</guid></item><item><title>Prosecutors to consider charges as police end investigation into Kumanjayi White&amp;apos;s death</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nt-prosecution-to-decide-on-criminal-charges-following-kumanjayi-whites-death-police-say/kgfjp2yxv</link><description>A mandatory coronial investigation into the death in custody of Kumanjayi White remains ongoing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">644cd01d35a33fae57a368410c082eac</guid></item><item><title>Simone was a loyal Optus customer. Then her husband needed an ambulance</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/simone-was-a-loyal-optus-customer-then-her-husband-needed-an-ambulance/gsno5tkoc</link><description>Hundreds of calls to triple-zero failed to connect during an Optus network outage linked to three deaths.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb87a8156740986af719e7ea99811e82</guid></item><item><title>Australia recognises Palestinian state at the UN</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australia-recognises-palestinian-state-at-the-un/tb615vbwz</link><description>Australia has joined Canada, Portugal and the United Kingdom in formally recognising a Palestinian state at the UN. The declaration was made by Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and Foreign Minister Penny Wong outside the United Nations headquarters in New York City, with the government saying it comes as part of a push for a two-state solution to the Israeli-Palestinian conflict. Israel&amp;apos;s Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has issued a warning to the countries, while saying he aims to ensure there will never be a Palestinian state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3b045f727e13e10255c9e5b838211f8</guid></item><item><title>Spring brings warmer weather, flower shows... and food safety concerns</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/spring-brings-warmer-weather-flower-shows-and-food-safety-concerns/8zt0q2zqs</link><description>As spring has arrived in Australia, a leading food safety advocate group is calling Australians to also conduct a spring clean for their fridges, freezers and pantries. The call comes as a recent survey finds over half of Australians see food-borne illness as their main food safety concerns, but less than half consumers consistently perform food safety behaviours when preparing food at home. And with a hot summer approaching, advocates and health experts say Australians need to be more careful about food poisoning this year</description><guid isPermaLink="false">20e64b747603de969c5e53543f6ab094</guid></item><item><title>Australia urged to stand firm on COP31 hosting</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australia-urged-to-stand-firm-on-cop31-hosting/mrani5ixa</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab5935be08f74daaf21e3cd11f8bb219</guid></item><item><title>Are more interest rate cuts on the cards?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/are-more-interest-rate-cuts-on-the-cards/6rkqw5scp</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b87ad528d29147385ac5eeb0d0be87a9</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Optus will be held to account&amp;apos;: Penalties on the telco loom as AMCA investigates</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/optus-will-be-held-to-account-penalties-on-the-telco-loom-as-amca-investigates/amyby7pxl</link><description>The Federal Communications Minister says Optus can expect to suffer significant consequences following last week&amp;apos;s triple-0 outage, that&amp;apos;s been linked to multiple deaths. The Australian Communications and Media Authority [[ACMA]] has launched an investigation into the failure, with authorities looking to obtain significant information from the telco to understand what happened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8d19df95d2e0832c8d23ff74c397e28</guid></item><item><title>Albanese in New York: Will the PM finally meet Trump — and what happens if he doesn&amp;apos;t?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anthony-albanese-donald-trump-new-york-un-general-assembly/shxxwmvcw</link><description>The prime minister has wasted no time since arriving in the Big Apple. What lies ahead?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">973f3a9d78162613a87ad565b854cc01</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Russian blood oil&amp;apos;: Australia faces calls to ban oil products refined from Russian crude</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/were-accepting-russian-blood-oil-pressure-to-sanction-petroleum-made-of-russian-crude/kp2dtrcxy</link><description>Australia has joined a coalition of nations in lowering the price cap on Russian oil and imposing new sanctions on Russia&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;shadow fleet&amp;apos;. But experts warn the move may be little more than a distraction from deeper issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1faf288e46fb1af9c772f87f5dfdc2d2</guid></item><item><title>Why Brooke chose Facebook over an IVF clinic to find a sperm donor</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/why-brooke-chose-facebook-over-an-ivf-clinic-to-find-a-sperm-donor/338mg4cam</link><description>As demand for sperm donors increases, some are avoiding fertility clinics in favour of less formal networks. Meanwhile, for donors, there is a range of ethical considerations and potential unintended consequences to consider.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f6a134ce044e57da6274911a26a532cd</guid></item><item><title>Why many Australians don&amp;apos;t feel financially confident &amp;amp; ASX rises as market waits for US inflation</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/why-many-australians-dont-feel-financially-confident-asx-rises-as-market-waits-for-us-inflation/6m4rs5zov</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Luke McMillan from Ophir Asset Management about the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action while Stephanie Youssef looks through the latest AMP research with Ben Hillier which reveals half of Australians don&amp;apos;t feel financially confident as they approach retirement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9335cfbce512e85e9e1080b80bc5aa6</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;A uniquely delicate crime&amp;apos;: Dangers of stealthing poorly understood by Australians</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-uniquely-delicate-crime-dangers-of-stealthing-poorly-understood-by-australians/xs598chxg</link><description>Stealthing, the removal of a condom during sex without a partner&amp;apos;s knowledge or consent, has in recent years become a criminal offence in almost all parts of Australia. But experts say there is still a lack of awareness about what stealthing is and the dangers it poses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a1dae1a7aaa137dd72d7ccf369c41ab</guid></item><item><title>UK charities end links with Prince Andrew&amp;apos;s ex-wife over Epstein email</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/uk-charities-end-links-with-prince-andrews-ex-wife-over-epstein-email/ziixfivwk</link><description>In a 2011 email to convicted US sex offender Jeffrey Epstein, the ex-wife of disgraced Prince Andrew, Sarah Ferguson, said she considered him a &amp;quot;supreme friend&amp;quot; and apologised for publicly disowning him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6cba7f21d32262a1ec7d11b8fa2c17d</guid></item><item><title>Qantas warns of flight disruptions as Typhoon Ragasa approaches Hong Kong</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/qantas-warns-of-flight-disruptions-as-typhoon-ragasa-approaches-hong-kong/1cs6ffv9t</link><description>Thousands of people have been evacuated in the northern Philippines as one of the strongest typhoons this year threatens to cause flooding and landslides.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91ddc0c0db239de8a1e8985200fb8c77</guid></item><item><title>Trump is pushing an unproven link between paracetamol and autism. What does the science say?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-is-pushing-an-unproven-link-between-paracetamol-and-autism-what-does-the-science-say/e4xjw79sr</link><description>Identifying the root of autism has long been a pet cause of Trump&amp;apos;s controversial health chief, Robert F Kennedy Jr. But new claims have been rejected by medical experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09b6f357492cc8bd6e94c76a035ac651</guid></item><item><title>France joins Australia and others in recognising a Palestinian state at the UN General Assembly</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/france-joins-australia-and-others-in-recognising-a-palestinian-state-at-the-un-general-assembly/u2toctsr6</link><description>France has formally recognised the state of Palestine in what President Emmanuel Macron hailed as a historic step towards Middle East peace. The decision, welcomed by Palestinian leaders and backed by several allies, set the tone for the United Nations&amp;apos; 80th anniversary session, even as Israel and the United States condemned it and boycotted proceedings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee402b8a585a020e6e3b31d9649e53c2</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 23 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-23-september-2025/z9fdl6ept</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9f7e58bb560dc9fed5420ca3dd8bf82</guid></item><item><title>Why the ICC has charged ex-Philippine president Rodrigo Duterte with crimes against humanity</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rodrigo-duterte-philippine-president-crimes-against-humanity-icc/sstirzcup</link><description>The 80-year-old is accused of being criminally responsible for several murders that took place during his so-called &amp;apos;war on drugs&amp;apos;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f967d76a49e4bd94deca457101aa7dd</guid></item><item><title>The states and territories where renters have it the best — and worst</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/new-report-card-shows-where-renters-have-it-best-and-worst/7orqs41sq</link><description>Two years after a national pledge to deliver a &amp;apos;Better Deal for Renters&amp;apos;, a new report finds progress remains uneven — with rights still dictated by postcode.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">938219f1f254586a79ca62beedfb0772</guid></item><item><title>Sydney&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;Night Stalker&amp;apos; rapist admits to committing multiple sexual assaults in 1990s</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sydneys-night-stalker-rapist-admits-to-committing-several-sexual-assaults-in-1990s/ttzbk1pmq</link><description>Decades after multiple women reported being assaulted in Sydney&amp;apos;s Moore Park and inner-west areas in the early 1990s, the 61-year-old admitted to more than a dozen offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d06087eaa8658b0e3466aea8c7f16b0</guid></item><item><title>Nvidia&amp;apos;s huge OpenAI deal, and Myer&amp;apos;s profit tumbles</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nvidias-huge-openai-deal-and-myers-profit-tumbles/snhqvpyxp</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Michael McCarthy from MooMoo Australia about the day&amp;apos;s market action including Myer&amp;apos;s disappointing profit result, and Nvidia&amp;apos;s huge OpenAI deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1edc4161ab9c59324c6414500ff4984</guid></item><item><title>Are your blueberries safe? Why a pesticide scare has some concerned</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/are-your-blueberries-safe-pesticides-scare-raises-alarm/tf1nqutcv</link><description>Pesticide suspended after tests on store-bought berries found high levels of harmful chemicals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4da24278f147e69a1804ae34a457f684</guid></item><item><title>Third time&amp;apos;s a charm? Albanese and Trump meeting confirmed for next month</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-and-trump-to-meet-next-month-white-house-official-confirms/1o4a71oz2</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has finally locked in a formal face-to-face meeting with Donald Trump, after a number of false starts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15c2baea60df811e6998ba1fa14d203e</guid></item><item><title>Third time&amp;apos;s a charm? Albanese and Trump meeting confirmed for next month</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-and-trump-one-on-one-meeting-confirmed-for-next-month/1o4a71oz2</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has finally locked in a formal face-to-face meeting with Donald Trump, after a number of false starts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae07d185a570b31e491d38308fc3fe6c</guid></item><item><title>Australian doctors describe &amp;apos;slaughterhouse&amp;apos; in Gaza hospital as medicine runs out</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/a-killing-field-australian-doctors-describe-horrific-operations-in-gaza/06663yej6</link><description>Two Australian doctors volunteering in one of Gaza&amp;apos;s last functioning hospitals say nothing prepared them for what they have witnessed in the past two weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70c9dd1b7efefefb25b3f57d023ab14d</guid></item><item><title>These girls are only able to study in secret. For many, their &amp;apos;last hope&amp;apos; is being taken away</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/afghanistan-study-secret-online-taliban-internet-ban/x60fs025y</link><description>With a new internet ban in the north of Afghanistan in force, members of the diaspora in Australia worry their families will be even more isolated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dda905b2ac493db9b67fa4df798ef8e9</guid></item><item><title>Meeting set between Albanese and Trump | Morning News Bulletin 24 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/meeting-set-between-albanese-and-trump-morning-news-bulletin-24-september-2025/pjfthehud</link><description>A meeting is finally set between Prime Minister Anthony Albanese and US President, four dead as Israeli tanks advance in Gaza, a new national football competition launched in Sydney.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31a5778d10e871e765d021e17c6dfdeb</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Ukraine in a position to &amp;apos;fight and win&amp;apos; back all territory lost to Russia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-says-ukraine-in-a-position-to-fight-and-win-back-all-territory-lost-to-russia/ov1bwyti3</link><description>Donald Trump criticised Russia, saying it had been fighting &amp;quot;aimlessly&amp;quot; in a war that a &amp;quot;real military power&amp;quot; would have won in less than a week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bf1e1b473437d80d36d84599145b64a</guid></item><item><title>Countries &amp;apos;going to hell&amp;apos; and other key takeaways from Donald Trump&amp;apos;s UN speech</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/countries-going-to-hell-five-takeaways-from-trumps-un-speech/q2qd7wirp</link><description>Trump warned that migration is sending Western nations &amp;quot;to hell&amp;quot; and dismissed climate change as a &amp;quot;con job&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">252238fecf20bf79051e082036ea0f99</guid></item><item><title>ABC ordered to pay Antoinette Lattouf $150,000 over unlawful sacking</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/abc-ordered-to-pay-antoinette-lattouf-150-000-over-unlawful-sacking/ui74d598r</link><description>Lattouf was dismissed three days into a five-day ABC Radio hosting stint in December 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31f68f212d15c32e36a57134b49af531</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Ragasa: Cyclone bears down on southern China after 17 killed in Taiwan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/super-typhoon-ragasa-14-dead-in-taiwan-as-hong-kong-prepares-for-serious-threat/7uwmshid2</link><description>Millions of people in southern China are in Typhoon Ragasa&amp;apos;s sights after the most powerful cyclone of 2025 battered Hong Kong and killed 17 people in Taiwan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8892157252f770910a98306fd9775f7</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Ragasa: Cyclone bears down on southern China after 17 killed in Taiwan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/super-typhoon-ragasa-bears-down-on-china-after-killing-15-in-taiwan/7uwmshid2</link><description>Millions of people in southern China are in Typhoon Ragasa&amp;apos;s sights after the most powerful cyclone of 2025 battered Hong Kong and killed 17 people in Taiwan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c821fde5cb881ca08fa9bbdbe00cdc2</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Ragasa: Cyclone bears down on southern China after 17 killed in Taiwan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/super-typhoon-ragasa-17-killed-in-taiwan-as-new-flood-fears/7uwmshid2</link><description>Millions of people in southern China are in Typhoon Ragasa&amp;apos;s sights after the most powerful cyclone of 2025 battered Hong Kong and killed 17 people in Taiwan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ecfa842c5edc7a2f6373205972bc444d</guid></item><item><title>Super Typhoon Ragasa: Cyclone bears down on southern China after 17 killed in Taiwan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/super-typhoon-ragasa-cyclone-bears-down-on-southern-china-after-17-killed-in-taiwan/7uwmshid2</link><description>Millions of people in southern China are in Typhoon Ragasa&amp;apos;s sights after the most powerful cyclone of 2025 battered Hong Kong and killed 17 people in Taiwan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed51b04cb912c588dbeb7bc78363aa9d</guid></item><item><title>Australian doctors threatened in Gaza | Midday News Bulletin 24 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australian-doctors-threatened-in-gaza-midday-news-bulletin-24-september-2025/fu9dw1ecl</link><description>In this bulletin... Australian doctors threatened and forced to flee as they provide care in Gaza, Super Typhoon Ragasa lashing Hong Kong, England announces its five-test Series team as it looks to regain the Ashes from Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">094bfaf8caa1e36f43ffe3f2096faa8e</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 24 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-24-september-2025/0xn6bwx5q</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15463bda1c6346fc19f2738369f89006</guid></item><item><title>150-plus countries now recognise Palestine - what does it mean and could it impact the war?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/150-plus-countries-now-recognise-palestine-what-does-it-mean-and-could-it-impact-the-war/kmsj70oy5</link><description>Australia has joined 150-plus countries who now officially recognise a Palestinian state. But after nearly two years of war in Gaza, and a death toll in excess of 65,000, what would a state of Palestine even look like? Is this recognition purely symbolic, or does it have real-world implications? And could it help bring an end to the conflict?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">787f0f1a6d68c136d10671b95fed2a19</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump walks his own path on autism research. Health experts say claims don&amp;apos;t stack up</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/donald-trump-walks-his-own-path-on-autism-research-health-experts-say-claims-dont-stack-up/qfmspyi5t</link><description>US President Donald Trump has announced his administration will direct doctors not to recommend paracetamol for pregnant women, claiming it may be linked to autism in children. Australian medical experts have responded, re-confirming that paracetamol is safe for use in pregnancy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dafea371f8ae06979ff31b3a4995a86</guid></item><item><title>NT hit-and-run case spotlights deep disparities in criminal justice system, advocates say</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nt-hit-and-run-case-spotlights-deep-disparities-in-criminal-justice-system-advocates-say/kebdv26tn</link><description>The Northern Territory has been engulfed by significant backlash regarding the sentencing of a driver who fatally struck an Aboriginal man in a hit and run and his familial connection to the Territory&amp;apos;s Attorney General. First Nations communities and legal experts argue the sentence given to Jake Danby, a 12-month community corrections order, is inconsistent with the &amp;apos;tough on crime&amp;apos; approach of the Country Liberal Party government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffd9e3c94967d13901eb2f98bf8882db</guid></item><item><title>Aboriginal people report less respectful hospital care. Here&amp;apos;s what can make a difference</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/aboriginal-people-report-less-respectful-hospital-care-report-finds/dk8qh9vdv</link><description>More than a quarter of Aboriginal patients said there had been a time in the past year they needed to go to hospital but didn&amp;apos;t, a report has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77ed9b7a28e82ffe9b6c732c6486e92b</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Should&amp;apos;ve done more&amp;apos;: Commissioner&amp;apos;s apology at Tian Jarrah Denniss inquest</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/should-have-done-more-commissioners-apology-at-tian-jarrah-denniss-inquest/wq29gjxzh</link><description>The Corrective Services NSW commissioner has delivered an apology to the family of Indigenous man Tian Jarrah Denniss, who died in custody in 2023.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37cdbe136647b1fd1c62888fa5c4a021</guid></item><item><title>Three-year inflation high could mean &amp;apos;wafer-thin&amp;apos; chance of interest rate cut pre November</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-august-inflation-data-could-affect-reserve-bank-rates/7db0sjp24</link><description>Freshly released inflation data will prompt the Reserve Bank to keep the cash rate on hold in September, but a cut in November is still &amp;quot;very much on the cards&amp;quot;, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4270c7ca83b5ef859465acde19269540</guid></item><item><title>Optus fined $100 million for unconscionable sales practices | Evening News Bulletin 24 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/optus-fined-100-million-fine-for-questionable-sales-practices-evening-news-bulletin-24-september-2025/xgbsbnoff</link><description>Optus to pay $100 million fine for sales practices targeting vulnerable Australians; Inflation hits a 12-month high; and in sport, the Wallabies suffer injury blow ahead of Bledisloe opener.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">945e9187c2f8c2a5b66b28ecf2bd6f6f</guid></item><item><title>President Trump&amp;apos;s extraordinary address at the UN General Assembly</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/president-trumps-extraordinary-address-at-the-un-general-assembly/gkpl8mbuc</link><description>Donald Trump has stunned the United Nations, using his speech at the General Assembly to suggest other countries are “going to hell” because of migration and denying science by calling climate change a ‘con’. In an extraordinary address, he slammed the UN for not doing enough to end wars. The US President also said he’d support NATO countries shooting down a Russian aircraft that breaches their airspace, and declared Kyiv can win back ‘all of Ukraine’.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80540eaaf0c52cbf90bbde89d847ea61</guid></item><item><title>Higher inflation threatens rate cuts &amp;amp; is the US market overvalued?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/higher-inflation-threatens-rate-cuts-is-the-us-market-overvalued/1m3j0wor1</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Paul Bloxham from HSBC about today&amp;apos;s stronger than expected inflation figures and what it means for interest rates, plus the day on the sharemarket with Francesco De Stradis from Ord Minnett.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31fc2f24036eecd9cffad706a531fa29</guid></item><item><title>Optus to pay $100m fine for sales practices targeting vulnerable Australians</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/optus-to-pay-100m-fine-for-sales-practices-targeting-vulnerable-australians/7o8xqa595</link><description>Amid Optus&amp;apos; triple-zero outage crisis, the Federal Court has added to the company&amp;apos;s woes after approving a $100 million penalty for &amp;quot;appalling and predatory&amp;quot; conduct in the telco&amp;apos;s sales practices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ddf9bbacd39ef3e5fe478236ebfef9a8</guid></item><item><title>This Christian community embraces traditional living. But ex-members allege it has dark secrets</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/this-christian-community-embraces-traditional-living-but-ex-members-allege-it-has-dark-secrets/w4bfz3zzm</link><description>When Dateline journalist Rhiona-Jade Armont travelled to the US for a story about tradwives, she’d never heard of Homestead Heritage. She soon learned the Christian group had a dark history of abuse — and former members allege there’s more. But current members and leaders say it’s a sovereign sanctuary from the outside world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d275b7314532eac01dd6703ffd2cf3c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Anti-ICE&amp;apos; message found on unused bullet after fatal attack on Dallas immigration office</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anti-ice-message-found-on-unused-bullet-after-fatal-attack-on-dallas-immigration-office/88jqbqbrm</link><description>US Homeland Security secretary Kristi Noem and vice president JD Vance condemned rhetoric directed at Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) since Donald Trump&amp;apos;s return to office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44005bc94b0b3028f14d76790916cfdf</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese meets Donald Trump in New York | Morning News Bulletin 25 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/anthony-albanese-meets-donald-trump-in-new-york-morning-news-bulletin-25-september-2025/y7qs3o0gm</link><description>Albanese and Trump meet socially as Penny Wong clarifies Australia&amp;apos;s concerns to her Iranian counterpart; Europe backs Australia&amp;apos;s impending ban on underage social media accounts; and in sport, two players at the centre of an A-League betting scandal are sentenced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed85503038bfc1fba1ef90bf74ae686a</guid></item><item><title>Stop Russia&amp;apos;s war or face dangerous arms race, Zelenskyy tells UN</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/stop-russias-war-or-face-dangerous-arms-race-zelenskyy-tells-un/lsnnzgiop</link><description>Volodymyr Zelenskyy also accused Vladimir Putin of seeking to expand his war beyond Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6485b817a11c42393a97b087e50e2fbe</guid></item><item><title>Greta Thunberg calls alleged drone attacks on aid flotilla a &amp;apos;scare tactic&amp;apos; as UN demands probe</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/thunberg-calls-alleged-drone-attacks-on-aid-flotilla-a-scare-tactic-as-un-demands-probe/nn0eq4adx</link><description>The United Nations has called for an independent investigation into alleged drone attacks on the Global Sumud Flotilla, an international convoy carrying humanitarian aid to Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3b7627a9d548adce3050c9bb9150ea3</guid></item><item><title>Greta Thunberg calls alleged drone attacks on aid flotilla a &amp;apos;scare tactic&amp;apos; as UN demands probe</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/spain-sends-naval-ship-to-protect-gaza-aid-flotilla-after-drone-attack/nn0eq4adx</link><description>The United Nations has called for an independent investigation into alleged drone attacks on the Global Sumud Flotilla, an international convoy carrying humanitarian aid to Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68fec2542eb579ba9b59de5a4202fa55</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Warm chat&amp;apos; and a selfie: Albanese finally comes face-to-face with Trump</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-finally-comes-face-to-face-with-trump/h9stfg2iw</link><description>Anthony Albanese has met Donald Trump at the president&amp;apos;s welcome reception for world leaders in New York after the pair locked in a formal sit-down for October.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e46dba1f1dcf75a99fbfa6021a2a38d0</guid></item><item><title>Albanese pushes for Security Council seat and calls out Iran in first major UN speech</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-makes-first-un-address-with-call-for-australia-to-have-security-council-seat/tmkdjguai</link><description>The UN risks &amp;quot;being trusted with nothing&amp;quot; unless it works together to tackle climate change and end wars in Gaza and Ukraine, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has said during his first UN General Assembly address.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3fb24ea04345b3cb51fb4dfd1540da8e</guid></item><item><title>When will humans return to the moon? NASA&amp;apos;s new mission is offering clues</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/when-will-humans-return-to-the-moon-nasas-new-mission-is-offering-clues/xhx83nuyn</link><description>The last time humans landed on the moon was in December 1972.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec806f7c6c65f9407cf1a21070d087fe</guid></item><item><title>When will humans return to the moon? NASA&amp;apos;s new mission is offering clues</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nasa-artemis-program-the-first-crewed-mission-to-the-moon-in-50-years/xhx83nuyn</link><description>The last time humans landed on the moon was in December 1972.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3d404a900f8b32d5e44356985138e6c</guid></item><item><title>PM urges greater cooperation at UN | Midday News Bulletin 25 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pm-urges-greater-cooperation-at-un-midday-news-bulletin-25-september-2025/ocmyqzu6x</link><description>In this bulletin, the Prime Minister to meet with Turkey as both countries bid to host a major climate conference, police voice concern over a surge in Victorian crime rate in recent years. And in football, FIFA considers expanding to 64 countries to mark 100 years of the World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eafce1d7df08a2584092c49fc078d9ab</guid></item><item><title>Greenlandic girls as young as 12 were forcibly fitted with IUDs. Denmark just apologised</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/greenlandic-girls-as-young-as-12-were-forcibly-fitted-with-iuds-denmark-just-apologised/8vpyoef0x</link><description>By the end of 1970, roughly every second Greenland-born woman of childbearing age had been fitted with an IUD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a7d2a148ddea060935fb4df782a2ab2</guid></item><item><title>Greenlandic girls as young as 12 were forcibly fitted with IUDs. Denmark just apologised</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/greenlandic-girls-as-young-as-12-were-forcibly-fitted-with-iuds-the-danish-pm-just-apologised/8vpyoef0x</link><description>By the end of 1970, roughly every second Greenland-born woman of childbearing age had been fitted with an IUD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c715bd98ed29fca4802e68e20d9be07</guid></item><item><title>Liberal Gisele Kapterian abandons court challenge and concedes defeat in Bradfield</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/liberal-gisele-kapterian-abandons-court-challenge-and-concedes-defeat-in-bradfield/g0h4s9v3k</link><description>After 145 days, Liberal Gisele Kapterian has conceded defeat in the Sydney seat of Bradfield to her rival, independent MP Nicolette Boele.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34ed8cd55e989655ef87b6f1932bacae</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese makes the case for Australia at the UN</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/anthony-albanese-makes-the-case-for-australia-at-the-un/v93qzyxlq</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has delivered his first leader&amp;apos;s speech to the United Nations General Assembly, promoting Australia as a significant middle power. He&amp;apos;s used the speech to push for more global co-operation on tackling the climate crisis, and peacekeeping efforts. And he&amp;apos;s also pushing for Australia to co-host the next COP climate summit in 2026, and hold a seat on the UN Security Council.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c4a5e613795893944b49e4b7b69d6c9</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 25 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-25-september-2025/ypv4annba</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f5882b0f464f14fb010969dcb64891c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Thanks for waking me up&amp;apos;: Untold story behind Cathy Freeman&amp;apos;s Olympic glory</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/our-cathy-my-mums-part-in-olympic-glory/o4v5o9e5d</link><description>On the 25th anniversary of Cathy Freeman&amp;apos;s 400m gold win at the Sydney Olympics, John-Paul Janke looks back at the time she stayed at his home in Canberra.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b61a62e77770a33486dab194955a30a</guid></item><item><title>It&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;third time lucky&amp;apos; for an Alzheimer&amp;apos;s drug. But many Australians like Peter will miss out</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tga-approves-alzheimers-drug-for-use-in-australia/3ebn6rgu9</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s medicines watchdog has approved Alzheimer&amp;apos;s drug lecanemab, which has been shown to &amp;quot;significantly&amp;quot; extend quality of life. But it comes at a great cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0d3fe0aec728c7df028e40c8434e14e</guid></item><item><title>Australia pushes for seat on UN Security Council | Evening News Bulletin 25 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australia-pushes-for-seat-on-un-security-council-evening-news-bulletin-25-september-2025/ysz7utboh</link><description>In this bulletin, the Prime Minister bids for Australia to have a seat on the UN Security Council, a grieving mother urges global leaders to follow Australia&amp;apos;s child social media ban. And in rugby league, Melbourne Storm coach Craig Bellamy says returning halfback Jahrome Hughes&amp;apos; teammates will protect him from harm.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f618ad281ff76ba7316120c9f4c40e5</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Penny Wong on the upcoming Albanese-Trump meeting and Australia&amp;apos;s bid to host COP31</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-penny-wong-on-the-upcoming-albanese-trump-meeting-and-australias-bid-to-host-cop31/mjew16ej9</link><description>Foreign Minister Penny Wong says the upcoming meeting between Anthony Albanese and Donald Trump will seek to advance areas of co-operation but also underline issues of sovereignty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb161e5e16858720340dd474679ab8f1</guid></item><item><title>Special Episode: Palestine recognition, Trump unfiltered &amp;amp; paracetamol panic</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/special-episode-palestine-recognition-trump-unfiltered-paracetamol-panic/tnptxg0lk</link><description>Ten Western nations (including Australia, the UK, and France) formally recognise a Palestinian state at the UN General Assembly. Our correspondents bring you the latest from New York, as they break down the statehood debate, MAGA’s escalating war on the left, and Trump’s unsubstantiated claims linking paracetamol and autism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4ac35a9b7c9c6e6f6d36f18d15f4651</guid></item><item><title>New research shows more Australians being harmed by gambling</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-research-shows-more-australians-being-harmed-by-gambling/0m2ee2x2e</link><description>An increasing number of Australians are being harmed by gambling according to new research. The study highlights the link between problem gambling and domestic violence, suicide, and financial hardship, with more than 3-million Australians said to be impacted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3262dc58d4028eee068058370e13d553</guid></item><item><title>Industries at risk of technology and AI &amp;amp; big dividend day</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/industries-at-risk-of-technology-and-ai-big-dividend-day/1op2dgni7</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves delves into Barrenjoey&amp;apos;s report on the industries most exposed to technological change and AI with Johnathan McMenamin; plus the day on the sharemarket with Mark Gardner from MPC Markets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf846076200e45ef163c7298da50e300</guid></item><item><title>Key questions behind this controversial United Nations address</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/key-questions-behind-this-controversial-united-nations-address/5trcpd0tm</link><description>He once led a designated terrorist group. Now, Syria&amp;apos;s Ahmed al-Sharaa leads the country and has addressed the United Nations. But was his appearance there really another step in a &amp;quot;dramatic&amp;quot; political transformation?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b57c0185fdaa39baf1c49b852172e95</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Hybrid attack&amp;apos;: Drones over Danish airports intended to spread fear, authorities say</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hybrid-attack-drones-over-danish-airports-intended-to-spread-fear-authorities-say/3eg3a4h6q</link><description>The incidents are just the latest in a series of drone incursions — including two days ago in Denmark — in the past few weeks that have exposed the vulnerability of European airspace.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b3242c81105f2589bc35b8f65fce7ff</guid></item><item><title>Former French President Nicolas Sarkozy jailed for five years over Libyan criminal conspiracy case</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/former-french-president-nicolas-sarkozy-jailed-for-five-years-over-libyan-criminal-conspiracy-case/grw7m3dp4</link><description>Sarkozy, who has always denied the charges, was accused of making a deal with former Libyan leader Muammar Gaddafi to obtain campaign financing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be6bac62f93e06551789c8d0677e8f8c</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s battle to take out a rival bid and host its &amp;apos;biggest diplomatic summit ever&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-australia-could-become-an-energy-superpower-as-pm-works-to-secure-cop31/r8vn79fyh</link><description>The summit would likely provide an economic boost for the hopeful host city, Adelaide, after a record 80,000 people attended last year&amp;apos;s event in Dubai.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ffcbd6bf26dfc13c2193b534657a26d</guid></item><item><title>From Silicon Valley to Sydney: How Trump&amp;apos;s H-1B visa move could make ripples in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/from-silicon-valley-to-sydney-how-trumps-h-1b-visa-move-could-make-ripples-in-australia/amcd339a5</link><description>As Donald Trump&amp;apos;s H-1B visa order seeks to restrict the United States&amp;apos; intake of skilled migrants, could it provide an opportunity for Australia?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37fafd6743414d2477d3669a2035320c</guid></item><item><title>Perth grandmother loses drug-smuggling appeal in Japan | Morning News Bulletin 26 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/an-australian-woman-loses-her-drug-smuggling-appeal-in-japan-morning-news-bulletin-26-september-2025/n2ht3up1t</link><description>An Australian woman loses her drug smuggling appeal in Japan; The President of the State of Palestine addresses the UN General Assembly; And in sport, Lions co-captain Lachie Neale named in the side for the AFL grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bf809d0fc3a0608e6fe77004e68e493</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian leader condemns Israel&amp;apos;s assault on Gaza, rejects Hamas during UN address</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/palestinian-leader-rejects-hamas-at-un-saying-they-have-no-role-in-post-war-gaza/cbdoh9d5h</link><description>Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas addressed the UN General Assembly via video, accusing Israel of war crimes and declaring that Hamas will have no future role in governing Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9ad504f299be61310cafbac18f3c1ce</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Unauthorised&amp;apos; edit of Australian film Together removes same-sex couple for audiences in China</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/unauthorised-edit-of-australian-film-removes-queer-couple-for-chinese-audiences/u8vtdhy8j</link><description>The film Together has reportedly been altered using artificial intelligence by a Chinese film distributor.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45fc490ff09e70a580b2e2cc0f73a72c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says any Israeli annexation of the West Bank is &amp;apos;not going to happen&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/donald-trump-israeli-annexation-west-bank/dmuh8nt5q</link><description>The US president has rejected calls from some members of the Israeli prime minister&amp;apos;s coalition for Israel to fully annex the West Bank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f43834fb1b9be4a5846b0f6297f298c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Unusual&amp;apos;: Passenger on board Qantas flight speaks after emergency landing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/qantas-plane-lands-in-auckland-after-reports-of-a-fire-on-board/rjrcmg2if</link><description>The plane landed safely at Auckland Airport after concerns of a fire in the cargo hold. The local ambulance service said no passengers on board required its assistance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a72f9bb135469461c9e2fdf0bc6bf5e3</guid></item><item><title>Trump overcomes &amp;apos;resistance&amp;apos; from China to transfer TikTok to US investors</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/donald-trump-confirms-tiktok-deal-with-china-ahead-of-us-ban/qdyc5vwor</link><description>The US president said Rupert Murdoch, along with other &amp;quot;world-class investors&amp;quot;, would be involved in the deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e161fd6395bb9da6317069a2866526c</guid></item><item><title>PM in UK for military talks | Midday News Bulletin 26 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pm-in-uk-for-military-talks-midday-news-bulletin-26-september-2025/ojzc4hvul</link><description>In this bulletin, hefty new tariffs on pharmaceuticals imported to the U-S, the Prime Minister arrives in the UK for security talks. And in sport, thousands expected for the annual A-F-L Grand Final parade in Melbourne&amp;apos;s CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b000ecf1b090d441baaaa73115114329</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump announces 100% tariffs on branded medicines from October</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/donald-trump-announces-100-tariffs-on-branded-medicines-from-october/x7jee0sy4</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bdcdcbca0cb92cbe8d0f17e590a8c08</guid></item><item><title>Who is James Comey, the Trump critic and ex-FBI director who has just been indicted?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/who-is-james-comey-trump-critic-indictment/oywvzmyyg</link><description>James Comey, who was fired by Donald Trump during the US president&amp;apos;s first term, has been charged with two criminal counts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52891cfe9a6e930af7e0f9e24afe8fa8</guid></item><item><title>Gaza death toll exceeds 65,500 as Israeli military intensifies strikes on enclave</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gaza-death-toll-exceeds-65-500-as-israeli-military-intensifies-strikes-on-enclave/68xz48f6q</link><description>The war in Gaza has now claimed more than 65,500 lives, according to Palestinian health officials, as Israeli forces intensify their campaign both inside the Strip and beyond. While Israel expands air and ground operations deep into Yemen, Palestinian Authority President Mahmoud Abbas is calling for a post-Hamas future and an immediate ceasefire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48f8bd08bf20586ee6ce6d4c9c797c69</guid></item><item><title>The rise and fall of France&amp;apos;s Nicolas Sarkozy after conviction</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-rise-and-fall-of-frances-nicolas-sarkozy-after-conviction/cvxdb1ww1</link><description>Former French president Nicolas Sarkozy has been sentenced to five years in prison after being found guilty of criminal conspiracy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9e28f827d4169c1911edeca4852b8e6</guid></item><item><title>Butler criticises Trump&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;unfair&amp;apos; pharma tariffs that Ley says are &amp;apos;shocking but unsurprising&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/health-minister-responds-to-trumps-100-per-cent-pharma-tariff-hike/ngur97kvl</link><description>Medicines and pharmaceuticals are among Australia&amp;apos;s top exports to the US, according to the Australian Bureau of Statistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3564c30351ad0429c7e99283ced9447d</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 25 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-25-september-2025/8xv6ewgm9</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9124f94f69627c49fa98fd747d3a52c5</guid></item><item><title>UN says millions of young people are being left behind</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/un-says-millions-of-young-people-are-being-left-behind/52hlk4jox</link><description>Youth advocates from around the world have gathered at the UN headquarters in New York to participate in the high-level plenary meeting of the General Assembly. Their meeting marked the thirtieth anniversary of the World Programme of Action for Youth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">143002988049f6a5672843f72b63f8e4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Exclusion or punishment&amp;apos;: Fears of a growing problem in Australian schools</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anti-palestinian-racism-in-schools-apan-report/8ak0h6ka3</link><description>There&amp;apos;s an anti-Palestinian racism &amp;quot;crisis&amp;quot; in Australian schools, according to a new report by an advocacy group, with students and teachers being punished for showing support for the Palestinian cause.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">583d801dfb3b129c925fe92475f79221</guid></item><item><title>Black market tobacco boom a major threat | Evening News Bulletin 26 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/black-market-tobacco-boom-a-major-threat-evening-news-bulletin-26-september-2025/lzcx8k3p6</link><description>In this bulletin, the boom of black-market tobacco becomes the nation&amp;apos;s biggest health threat, strong words for Australia&amp;apos;s Pacific Minister, as Vanuatu considers deals with Australia and China. And in sport, Australian hip hop star Baker Boy will perform with Snoop Dog at tomorrow&amp;apos;s AFL grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8eec09e8f336f15d60d57758cd57c2a7</guid></item><item><title>What time does the 2025 AFL grand final start? All the key details to know</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/afl-grand-final-2025-key-information/7cphviiz9</link><description>Around 100,000 people are anticipated to go to the Geelong v Brisbane match this weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66146d8eacf385e9983830eab95301d5</guid></item><item><title>Pharma stocks tumble following US pharma import tariffs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pharma-stocks-tumble-following-us-pharma-import-tariffs/mud4bfff3</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Shane Oliver from AMP and Marcus Bogdan from Blackmore Capital about the reaction to a US decision to apply 100% import tariffs to pharmaceutical products from Wednesday, plus all the latest from the sharemarket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b12b0e39c24005e76a3b975b6812b43</guid></item><item><title>How a radical three-month experiment changed Australia&amp;apos;s TV landscape forever</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sbs-marks-50-years-with-documentary-on-indigenous-broadcasting/15v4lpjqo</link><description>Celebrating five decades on air, a landmark SBS documentary shows how a radical idea evolved into a national platform for Indigenous and multicultural storytelling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a8982ac99eecd52818cb8e07ad6ef2c</guid></item><item><title>Court drops terror-related charge against member of Irish rap group Kneecap</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/court-throws-out-terror-related-charge-against-irish-rap-group-kneecap/vbjsav2g0</link><description>The punk-rap group has issued a statement saying &amp;quot;they do not, and have never, supported Hamas or Hezbollah&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a588d04beb4a95e1b5aa9930b161a97f</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese to meet King Charles, consult Middle East peace during UK visit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anthony-albanese-to-meet-king-charles-consult-middle-east-peace-during-uk-visit/ndq30f7im</link><description>Anthony Albanese has swapped the US for the UK, landing in London for political talks and a conference of global leaders.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea42d29bc09dbcf6953fd2f0f2e7187d</guid></item><item><title>Morning News Bulletin 27 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/morning-news-bulletin-27-september-2025/evfdd0ktp</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s health minister reacts to a fresh round of tariffs on pharmaceutical exports to the US; Fury over the digital alteration of an Australian film in China; And in sport, today is the day for this year&amp;apos;s AFL Grand Final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5bb397e6345bdbe7d426081557bea108</guid></item><item><title>Dreaming of spreadsheets and battling stage fright: Behind the world Excel championships</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-its-like-to-compete-in-microsoft-excel-world-championship/xdada7hn3</link><description>From spreadsheets to showdowns, the Excel World Championship turns number-crunching into a high-stakes spectacle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de6cf9898e100219c9b3ac6800c3b2f8</guid></item><item><title>Australia has around 100,000 eggs in IVF storage. Some want to see unclaimed eggs donated</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/egg-donation-ivf-australia/kx9zbvh3u</link><description>The demand for eggs far outpaces the number donated in Australia, leaving those wanting to start families with few options. Experts say something needs to change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46a88d94868d7af5965bc0c61d8c7052</guid></item><item><title>What&amp;apos;s next for South Australia&amp;apos;s algae bloom?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/whats-next-for-south-australias-algae-bloom/6jag2297p</link><description>South Australia&amp;apos;s algal bloom continues to spread, leading to significant environmental, ecological and mental health harm. Those impacts have been heard at a Senate inquiry examining support arrangements for those affected, but also long-term prevention strategies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf09055980d41d84633ea374ffc9d6a6</guid></item><item><title>Dozens walk out on Netanyahu UN speech calling Palestinian recognition a &amp;apos;mark of shame&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dozens-walk-out-on-netanyahu-un-speech-calling-palestinian-recognition-a-mark-of-shame/1exg6a8sx</link><description>A procession of delegates exited the United Nations General Assembly hall ahead of Benjamin Netanyahu&amp;apos;s speech denouncing Australia, France, Britain, Canada and other countries for recognising a Palestinian state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67859f146a622636a445e43fc8bc557e</guid></item><item><title>New deep space antenna in Australia to aid exploration of universe while also creating local jobs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-deep-space-antenna-in-australia-to-aid-exploration-of-universe-while-also-creating-local-jobs/wu02b46fa</link><description>More than three years after it was first announced, a new deep space antenna is being brought online in Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d848ae9022e4e09bac451b0af89dd69</guid></item><item><title>How to deep clean your fridge ahead of summer</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-to-deep-clean-your-fridge-ahead-of-summer/521ho9ztx</link><description>Those neglected items at the back of your fridge can become a health hazard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cee068de68a67a2a0dbfe956af29cf0b</guid></item><item><title>Six-pack diplomacy: Albanese joins Starmer and Carney for high-stakes talks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/beer-diplomacy-and-warnings-about-far-right-populism-dominate-albanese-london-trip/v450k88es</link><description>The Australian, British and Canadian leaders used a London summit to warn against the far-right and to discuss migration and renewed support for Palestinian statehood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f79c80fc03f02c8382a3d6b5e32ee47b</guid></item><item><title>A mass delegate walk-out and what comes next: Benjamin Netanyahu&amp;apos;s speech to the UN</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/a-mass-delegate-walk-out-and-what-comes-next-benjamin-netanyahus-speech-to-the-un/czpfanep1</link><description>Speaking at the United Nations, the Israeli leader pushed back in his harshest terms yet against a flurry of diplomatic moves that have deepened Israel&amp;apos;s international isolation. But one thing was missing — any suggestion for what comes next, besides more war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26fbf030d34aeae18a8d5e484a968594</guid></item><item><title>UN sanctions on Iran set to return after Russian, Chinese Security Council effort fails</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/un-sanctions-on-iran-set-to-return-after-russia-and-chinas-efforts-fails/v8vnqwld4</link><description>All UN sanctions on Iran are set to be reinstated on the weekend after European powers accused Tehran of breaching a 2015 agreement aimed at preventing Iran from developing a nuclear weapon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ae80b4e8f5d933f531a00202adf8353c</guid></item><item><title>UN sanctions on Iran set to return after Russian, Chinese Security Council effort fails</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sanctions-on-iran-to-return-after-russian-chinese-un-effort-fails/v8vnqwld4</link><description>All UN sanctions on Iran are set to be reinstated on the weekend after European powers accused Tehran of breaching a 2015 agreement aimed at preventing Iran from developing a nuclear weapon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4be4e4dd405cd56c1618fcd35fbb20d9</guid></item><item><title>UN sanctions on Iran set to return after Russian, Chinese Security Council effort fails</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/un-sanctions-on-iran-to-return-after-russian-chinese-un-effort-fails/v8vnqwld4</link><description>All UN sanctions on Iran are set to be reinstated on the weekend after European powers accused Tehran of breaching a 2015 agreement aimed at preventing Iran from developing a nuclear weapon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d57781942985cbad2661babf95b231c</guid></item><item><title>Trump isn&amp;apos;t the first to push an unproven claim about autism. Why are they so pervasive?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/donald-trump-autism-disinformation-misinformation-tylenol-vaccines/zvsep8k5i</link><description>One expert says an &amp;quot;information void&amp;quot; has allowed non-evidence-based claims and conspiracy theories around autism to flourish.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ae6b5217e8e5f04bcdfed4ad05151dc</guid></item><item><title>Midday News Bulletin 27 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/midday-news-bulletin-27-september-2025/v6qwg2hs6</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s PM declines to endorse Tony Blair for a key post-war Gaza role; Broadcasters to vote on excluding Israel from Eurovision; And in sport, Lewis Hamilton skips a testing session to sit at the bedside of his beloved dog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9bb778a149310b26b15006a6dea39855</guid></item><item><title>Afraid of AI replacing you? Here are jobs that may be future-proof</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/afraid-of-ai-replacing-you-here-are-jobs-that-may-be-future-proof/g84ryofgy</link><description>Jobs including tax preparation, legal advice and education may have the lowest risk of being replaced by technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2832f2b830d5b4c41ba4a107c1a914fd</guid></item><item><title>Evening News Bulletin 27 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/evening-news-bulletin-27-september-2025/w6ix6v70z</link><description>Pacific Island leaders address the UN General Assembly on the climate crisis; Anthony Albanese discusses a Gaza reconstruction plan during a meeting with former British prime minister Tony Blair; and in sport, the Storm book a spot in the NRL grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76f225c78e1984f82b84b2be6a757601</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Is this still happening?&amp;apos;: Elon Musk named in new Epstein files</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/is-this-still-happening-elon-musk-named-in-new-epstein-files/dfb8gea5z</link><description>Prince Andrew and PayPal co-founder Peter Thiel are among the other names in the documents released by Democrat politicians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">087653cae4c83e925aae0febaf669bc7</guid></item><item><title>New Zealand won&amp;apos;t recognise a Palestinian state &amp;apos;at this time&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/new-zealand-says-it-wont-recognise-a-palestinian-state-at-this-time/8ax1fk5nt</link><description>The decision puts the country at odds with its Commonwealth allies Australia, Canada and the United Kingdom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf44d906a56e1a0c0663c7223dd77905</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Could a new UN declaration protect aid workers amid the growing death toll?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-could-a-new-un-declaration-protect-aid-workers-amid-the-growing-death-toll/i6tzu58gi</link><description>More than 100 states have signed an Australian-led declaration to protect aid workers. Australian Red Cross CEO Andrew Colvin explains what the declaration is aiming to achieve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a7aee2bbedfd24a7cc1a6fc6fe775fa</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Unbroken whispers&amp;apos;: How Indigenous women map whale songlines</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/whale-migration-mapping-project-reveals-indigenous-songlines/7nqere56s</link><description>A trio of First Nations researchers is blending traditional knowledge and science to map whale migration and advocate for improved conservation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b7d809fbe9e4d1d1b1291d689c79769</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Jekyll and Hyde&amp;apos;: How to win over Australia&amp;apos;s most polarising bird</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-to-win-over-australias-most-polarising-bird/c52yvb0xg</link><description>Culturally revered in Dreamtime stories but feared by cyclists, the magpie has a &amp;quot;Jekyll and Hyde&amp;quot; presence in our suburbs. But one expert says there are ways to win them over — even if you&amp;apos;re magpie enemy number one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58dcc52a2f1862c3da45a3beaef188b3</guid></item></channel></rss>