<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>SBS English News (Unofficial Aggregation)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 16:04:32 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>South African man&amp;apos;s Australian visa cancelled after neo-Nazi rally outside NSW parliament</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/neo-nazi-matthew-gruters-visa-has-been-cancelled/kotrcbjyg</link><description>Matthew Gruter was one of the 60 demonstrators who took part in a protest touting Hitler slogans outside NSW parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">938d721325ab77dd08ccb8b39392453b</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Not just fear&amp;apos;: Why some Australians are sending their gold overseas</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-quiet-rush-to-hide-gold-safely-away/kd41rhi9c</link><description>Gold prices have been glimmering, keeping buyers and sellers busy. But for some Australians, it&amp;apos;s more than a market play.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d152439746e45f23ef623de63fa6ab1</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: SBS talks to Kaveh Madani on Tehran&amp;apos;s water crisis</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-sbs-talks-to-kaveh-madani-on-tehrans-water-crisis/qamlv6is5</link><description>Kaveh Madani warned Iran about water scarcity 20 years ago. He was called a &amp;quot;water terrorist.&amp;quot; Now Iran is experiencing an extreme water crisis, its like not seen for more than six decades. Tehran, famous for its surrounding snowy mountains, has had no rain in over 200 days. Its main water sources are in a dire situation; two major dams supplying the capital are at less than 10 per cent capacity. Kaveh Madani is the director of the United Nations University Institute for Water, Environment and Health, and warned of this situation back in the early 2000s, and he&amp;apos;s speaking here to SBS broadcaster Niv Sadrolodabaee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ad99199dbf18bd75ae633db846b1473</guid></item><item><title>UK&amp;apos;s planned overhaul of asylum system slashes key protections for refugees</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/uk-overhaul-of-asylum-system-slashes-key-protections-for-refugees/rhpwjwnvd</link><description>The UK government has called the proposed changes the &amp;quot;most sweeping reforms to tackle illegal migration in modern times&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e3605152f06e656beaf3381b9d55f19</guid></item><item><title>What does the Gaza plan endorsed by the UN Security Council include?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/united-nations-security-council-united-states-gaza-plan/ed735kr26</link><description>The resolution endorses US President Donald Trump&amp;apos;s 20-point ceasefire plan, which calls for a transitional authority in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af8ccbfe44b383a788a21d4d942ff7d0</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;FIFA Pass&amp;apos;: Donald Trump announces fast-tracked visas for World Cup ticket holders</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/donald-trump-visas-world-cup-2026-fifa/xwt5xd9yz</link><description>The US has promised a seamless experience for next year&amp;apos;s tournament despite concerns that Trump&amp;apos;s border crackdown could hurt fans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8354ff99c5fc2c0e672c9f81920168e7</guid></item><item><title>Scammers &amp;apos;love&amp;apos; it: The $260 million reason Aussies are urged to be on alert</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/shopping-scams-black-friday-warning-australia/ewnlty0t2</link><description>Australians have lost nearly $260 million to scams this year, with shopping scams surging as sales season kicks off.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49140d38fb6156d465bd4be7f89d6718</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 18 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-18-november-2025/tjoclbebj</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97fe5ee049b60b7628a92bf70a12236e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;They hate modern Australia&amp;apos;: South African neo-Nazi detained after visa cancelled</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/south-african-neo-nazi-taken-into-detention-after-visa-cancelled/dgu2j4zl1</link><description>Matthew Gruter was one of 60 black-clad demonstrators who were allowed to assemble outside NSW parliament and yell Hitler youth chants on 8 November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0da425d158ca0a70d0ed707659b69cce</guid></item><item><title>Penny Wong demands answers on Australian methanol deaths, urges hostel not to reopen</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/wong-demands-answers-on-australian-methanol-deaths-urging-hostel-not-reopen/mqfzm4m0v</link><description>A year after two Australian teens died from methanol poisoning in Laos, Penny Wong says the investigation has &amp;quot;not been good enough&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d129854aa43b308180f9e161783bb0e</guid></item><item><title>Hannah McGuire&amp;apos;s parents relieved after ex-boyfriend jailed for 28 years for murder</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ballarat-man-lachlan-young-jailed-for-nearly-three-decades-over-murder-of-hannah-mcguire/l36a8sc4l</link><description>Lachlan Young was midway through his trial when he changed his plea and admitted strangling his ex-girlfriend at their home in April 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bb97439163c00c5f00d6be1070e4e73</guid></item><item><title>$60bn wiped from ASX &amp;amp; scams rise ahead of Black Friday sales</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/60bn-wiped-from-asx-scams-rise-ahead-of-black-friday-sales/pn6vyu2mw</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with David Lane from Ord Minnett about why the ASX200 had its second worst day of the year as $60bn is wiped off the value of the local sharemarket; plus Angelica Waite discusses the rise of scams ahead of Black Friday with the ACCC&amp;apos;s Catriona Lowe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9c9ffe521fe6abe5563ead97b278223</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Clearly bitter&amp;apos;: Liberal senator responds after ex-colleague&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;inept&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;lazy&amp;apos; claims</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/former-liberal-senator-hollie-hughes-lashes-ex-colleagues-as-inept-and-lazy-as-she-quits-party-live-on-radio/xjqprnvgj</link><description>Liberal senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price has responded to a former colleague&amp;apos;s claims she&amp;apos;s being used to undermine party leader Sussan Ley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f48874979475bc07cbbc6a692ceb33e9</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Things happened&amp;apos;: Donald Trump defends Saudi crown prince over journalist&amp;apos;s murder</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-mohammed-bin-salman-jamal-khashoggi-white-house/xde7pl6vk</link><description>The US president gave the de facto ruler of Saudi Arabia a lavish welcome to the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1707bc78bd0ae15d15a7c6c07150b5dc</guid></item><item><title>US Congress votes to force release of Epstein files</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-congress-votes-to-force-release-of-epstein-files/07lksfnlf</link><description>The US Congress has voted overwhelmingly to release the Department of Justice files on disgraced financier and convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein. After months of political pressure to release the files, survivors of Epstein&amp;apos;s abuse say they hope this can lead to some justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b854049ba25cd8d46905deb83697f156</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 19 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-19-november-2025/sc3j1u0n4</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">291e5f16dd06bdf4ee019e2ee0da0c3e</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos lose to Colombia in New York as World Cup preparations continue</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/socceroos-vs-colombia-international-friendly-results/7wlu8shlj</link><description>Australia took on Colombia in an international friendly in New York, following their loss against Venezuela on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9f1d47b7b31aaa7f75f29202541fa29</guid></item><item><title>Flattery, fighter jets and a trillion dollar pledge as Saudi Crown Prince meets Trump</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/flattery-fighter-jets-and-a-trillion-dollar-pledge-as-saudi-crown-prince-meets-trump/ggli2fgn7</link><description>Saudi Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, returning to the White House for the first time since the murder of journalist Jamal Khashoggi, has met President Donald Trump at the Oval Office. The two leaders discussed a number of matters including Saudi Arabia investing a trillion US dollars in America for AI Chips, F-35 fighter jets, the Khashoggi assassination and Gaza&amp;apos;s reconstruction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">449550480d9a814bead6449795bc79c9</guid></item><item><title>Curaçao makes World Cup history after completing fairytale qualification campaign</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/curacao-the-smallest-nation-to-qualify-for-fifa-world-cup/d8s2koj01</link><description>Curaçao has replaced Iceland as the smallest nation by population to qualify for a World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1f621a902ac4ab687706af40150557e</guid></item><item><title>Waste, harassment claims and walkouts: Behind a city&amp;apos;s months-long bin workers&amp;apos; strike</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-are-birmingham-bin-workers-on-strike/fe6fle5pm</link><description>The situation became more complicated when agency workers covering during the strike voted to take industrial action themselves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64b67719cbe09c2c0dbc12ce51c83874</guid></item><item><title>Eyes on Nvidia &amp;amp; wages rise above inflation</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/eyes-on-nvidia-wages-rise-above-inflation/41eyofmex</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Matt Sherwood from Perpetual about the day&amp;apos;s market action including why Nvidia&amp;apos;s quarterly results tomorrow may be a turning point; plus Paula Gadsby from EY goes through the latest wages data and what it means for interest rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd643cd5d764470059617dff1a05f30e</guid></item><item><title>Chris Minns on hospital funding row: we can&amp;apos;t all be wrong</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/chris-minns-on-hospital-funding-row-we-cant-all-be-wrong/b6qoqlhwf</link><description>State premiers have come together for an urgent meeting, as tensions rise over reaching a new public hospital funding deal with the federal government. A new report from the Grattan Institute also finds Australia&amp;apos;s hospitals are wasting more than $1 billion a year on avoidable spending.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60632243963ab5d32461ccaa5e7a5122</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Sheer terror&amp;apos;: Palestinians arrive in Australia after &amp;apos;mysterious&amp;apos; South Africa flight saga</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-australian-link-to-mysterious-flight-of-palestinians-arriving-in-south-africa/7ymf696hr</link><description>A small group of Palestinians with Australian visas were onboard a flight to South Africa making headlines around the world, and have since made their way to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa4e345edfa263124b444dca67f4b4e2</guid></item><item><title>Calls for superannuation protections as some retirees could lose up to $205,000</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/calls-for-superannuation-protections-as-some-retirees-lose-up-to-205-000/f8oephznl</link><description>A new report is calling on the federal government to include protections for retirees when it comes to super performance testing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e07ef14abd301da19e98d46506dcec58</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The worst we&amp;apos;ve seen&amp;apos;: The type of job that&amp;apos;s getting harder to find in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-jobs-disappearing-at-a-growing-rate/lk203bdkr</link><description>A new report has painted a grim picture of Australia&amp;apos;s employment system, calling on the federal government to urgently intervene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0e62fd58c2745ed7c59032c6898a10c</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia’s drowning island takes historic climate case to court</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/indonesias-drowning-island-takes-historic-climate-case-to-court/902jxfpoi</link><description>Indonesia is home to more than 17,000 islands, but its smallest are highly vulnerable to the impacts of climate change. The tiny community of Pari Island is facing multiple climate-induced threats, including to its entire existence.Four people on the island are now trying to launch a landmark legal case against a European cement giant over its historic carbon emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69b53c546e00b2669b258b453e0eabd5</guid></item><item><title>At least 25 Palestinians killed in Israeli airstrikes across Gaza, medics say</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/at-least-25-palestinians-killed-in-israeli-airstrikes-across-gaza/xtik6ym7u</link><description>Wednesday&amp;apos;s strikes were among the deadliest in the territory since the ceasefire came into force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">641e5c2716bedf95f0344980529a078d</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Pushing its own agenda&amp;apos;: PNG&amp;apos;s top diplomat lashes Türkiye after Australia withdraws COP31 bid</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-concedes-cop31-hosting-to-turkiye-bowen-to-lead-negotiations/o0dv8xuy2</link><description>Australia has abandoned its bid to host COP31 in Adelaide, meaning the event will be held in Türkiye.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbfcadfad7e6df68b5c36685a82f12c2</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 20 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-20-november-2025/u3l9mlf59</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb96c6f536b0cc6fc4570ca3ade50d92</guid></item><item><title>Bicycle kicks and tears: Here are the teams who have qualified for the 2026 FIFA World Cup</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/who-have-qualified-for-the-fifa-2026-world-cup-and-who-is-still-in-the-hunt/1jte6ykoy</link><description>In the November qualifying rounds, 14 additional teams, including some surprising names, secured their places for the 2026 FIFA World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50830a96aa1331cda0253c1cbd8d5446</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Completely emptied&amp;apos;: Human rights report alleges Israeli war crimes in West Bank camps</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/human-rights-report-alleges-israeli-crimes-against-humanity-displacement-in-west-bank-camps/y68thxfuc</link><description>Human Rights Watch reports 32,000 Palestinians were forcibly displaced from West Bank camps in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f7ef83973531b2270c82f03b6b0864b</guid></item><item><title>Trump, Epstein &amp;amp; the Saudi Crown Prince, and autocrat karaoke</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trump-epstein-the-saudi-crown-prince-and-autocrat-karaoke/xlpen4ps3</link><description>Trump wipes the slate clean of murder for Mohammed bin Salman because ‘things happen’. The Epstein files move a big step closer to being released and what it’s like reporting on the ground in the Democratic Republic of the Congo. Plus, the comment that sent China-Japan relations plummeting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc75745de742a7e4a359d5b0ad97eedc</guid></item><item><title>Nvidia goes off the charts as ASX recovers</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nvidia-goes-off-the-charts-as-asx-recovers/wipyytn89</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Ben Clark from TMS Private Wealth to go through AI chip giant Nvidia&amp;apos;s record results and whether this is the turning point the market was looking for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc3f55637738c5065df9439bcaff9a66</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Can&amp;apos;t have it all&amp;apos;: Australia abandons bid for COP31 climate summit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/cant-have-it-all-australia-abandons-bid-for-cop31-climate-summit/shmhxtcsh</link><description>The federal government has abruptly abandoned its bid to host the United Nations climate conference next year, conceding Turkiye will oversee the COP31. The Pacific countries and environmental activists have criticised the federal government&amp;apos;s failure to bring the event to Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d89a21e8192a1c342fc3b08f734670b7</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Daily challenge&amp;apos;: The hidden cost of living crisis affecting families</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/food-and-school-supply-charities-overwhelmed-with-demand/xqpsveb7g</link><description>A food relief charity says it has so much demand it&amp;apos;s forced to turn schools away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a5e35f45f010c38ace703556982a336</guid></item><item><title>PNG questions &amp;apos;what planet&amp;apos; the Opposition is on, after it ditches net zero support</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/png-questions-what-planet-the-opposition-is-on-after-it-ditches-net-zero-support/yxyrbeab7</link><description>Papua New Guinea&amp;apos;s foreign minister has said the Opposition&amp;apos;s position on climate change &amp;quot;won&amp;apos;t do them any favours, or us any favours&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5b641fe8a5004caad4a2d67c4058984</guid></item><item><title>Why government debt matters: spoiler, it’s not just Monopoly money</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/why-government-debt-matters-spoiler-its-not-just-monopoly-money/casb5am3m</link><description>We know government debt is around $1 trillion, we&amp;apos;ve heard it&amp;apos;s bad for younger generations -- but we don&amp;apos;t really know what any of it means. This week, Elfy and Rania chat with Professor Richard Holden from the University of New South Wales about government debt and why it matters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fd1d1d7b70fae465b29b2dbd0839abb</guid></item><item><title>Fire forces evacuation of Brazil climate conference with negotiations still short of a deal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fire-forces-evacuation-of-brazil-climate-conference-with-negotiations-still-short-of-a-deal/vpoditrg5</link><description>The fire has now been brought under control and 13 people have been treated for smoke inhalation, officials said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8829b7616954f007543c2463600cc9f</guid></item><item><title>Rules on this common travel item change today. Here’s why they’re risky</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/power-banks-banned-planes-qantas-virgin-explainer/odb7ekq16</link><description>Rules around power banks are increasingly tightening after a string of incidents. How do you know if yours is safe?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7863138c9b0d35ab4d910cd09a7b2b5</guid></item><item><title>Warning issued over &amp;apos;quick cash&amp;apos; scam targeting international students</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/warning-issued-over-quick-cash-scam-targeting-international-students/i8rb75ts6</link><description>An urgent warning has been issued to international students departing Australia to not sell their bank accounts and ID to criminals. The Australian Federal Police says students are offered &amp;apos;quick cash&amp;apos; - but accepting it could see them indelibly linked to crime networks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cb495e93082f9fb1b0283958022e1a0</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;That courageous girl&amp;apos;: Matildas coach&amp;apos;s support for Mary Fowler after alleged racism experience</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/its-happening-everywhere-advocate-says-mary-fowler-racism-incident-goes-deeper/kj0buoxg2</link><description>Matildas star Mary Fowler has alleged she experienced racism during her time with French club Montpellier, which has denied the allegations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24e0c5dea70f66757998dba3ad915399</guid></item><item><title>Where Kunzang&amp;apos;s from there&amp;apos;s no ocean. Now in Darwin, he&amp;apos;s worried about the cyclone</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tropical-cyclone-fina-expected-to-strengthen-as-it-approaches-the-northern-territory/kh7n09ii5</link><description>The man from Bhutan has only been in the NT for three months, and says he doesn&amp;apos;t know what to expect from Fina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50e4aa438696d5d562c29512f7a79f5d</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 21 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-21-november-2025/czqbf7wpg</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">683e0fc781c2718b3dd4a84a996ac297</guid></item><item><title>US rate fears trump Nvidia&amp;apos;s better than expected result</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-rate-fears-trump-nvidias-better-than-expected-result/l3s5d95k7</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Lochlan Halliday from Morningstar to find out what spooked investors despite Nvidia&amp;apos;s better than expected profit and if it&amp;apos;s likely to last.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b186488bf4baf6f40c48f76afb5b64b5</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The odds are against us&amp;apos;: Why some Australian homeowners may never upgrade</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-three-bedroom-properties-are-getting-harder-to-find/6h2g8zswv</link><description>The property ladder has changed since the COVID-19 pandemic. Data shows some homeowners may never get the chance to upgrade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7173759bc140448eef7e5aa28983d6f4</guid></item><item><title>‘No food, no money’: Khoa was abandoned and owed $10,000 in unpaid wages. He’s not alone</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/no-food-no-money-khoa-was-abandoned-and-owed-10-000-in-unpaid-wages-hes-not-alone/o9uj8zvmv</link><description>As the academic year ends, thousands of international students are signing on for holiday work. But if things go wrong, experts warn that few understand their legal entitlements or how to recover unpaid wages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a92900f996f08d932d1290e03cc9d249</guid></item><item><title>Leadership spills and policy reversals: How healthy is our democracy?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/leadership-spills-and-policy-reversals-how-healthy-is-our-democracy/nj201gjdp</link><description>With the abandonment of its net-zero policies, and leadership spills in two of Australia&amp;apos;s largest states, the Coalition is undergoing a period of major upheaval. So what does that mean for a Westminster democracy which analysts say depends on two different political positions to succeed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">535650e0f953ceb60e6b9c1d25412719</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine faces &amp;apos;difficult choice&amp;apos; on US plan to end Russia&amp;apos;s war, Zelenskyy says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ukraine-russia-war-zelenskyy-putin-us-plan-trump/5l1zz9a7d</link><description>Donald Trump has given Ukraine a week to accept the proposal, which would see it cede territory, among other concessions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c5f4deea43ee62f6e2b608a16a1dde8</guid></item><item><title>Owed $10,000, Khoa was left stranded on a farm with no food or funds. He&amp;apos;s not alone</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/migrant-worker-exploitation-underpayment-australia-khoa-nguyen-story/0h7n03pah</link><description>Despite recent reforms, exploitation of migrant workers remains a serious issue in Australia, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">600fee42e8c84363f2fad600282a271f</guid></item><item><title>The two words missing from the world&amp;apos;s most important climate conference agreement</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cop-negotiations-fossil-fuels/3mbq2dzbc</link><description>An agreement on climate action has been reached at COP30 in Brazil — but not everyone is happy with the final result.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fcf416d792fcc7b7c0cc062c7a442b8</guid></item><item><title>Some world leaders make decisions while chronically sleep-deprived. Should they?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sanae-takaichi-two-hours-sleep-raises-leadership-questions/fynnp01gj</link><description>Sleep deprivation undermines our ability to think clearly. So what should we make of leaders who say they run on just a few hours?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113cf7d3e3561f639ad8e3b434551f83</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;You don&amp;apos;t have the freedom to leave&amp;apos;: The human cost of Australia&amp;apos;s solar boom</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-human-cost-of-australias-solar-boom/ztxkq52wj</link><description>As Australia&amp;apos;s uptake of solar panels booms, human rights groups have raised alarm about links to Uyghur forced labour in the supply chain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f0eb8bad5e36aa2b39485c38ac6b0f7</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Isolation and shame&amp;apos;: Australians are avoiding perinatal mental health support, new research reveals</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/isolation-and-shame-australians-are-avoiding-perinatal-mental-health-support-new-research-reveals/71wsofd52</link><description>Around one in four Australians are failing to seek support when experiencing perinatal mental health issues. Experts say the data released by the Gidget Foundation highlights a lack of awareness around signs and symptoms, and ongoing stigma around the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffe9d58fbdecd408b34a4d247b57a81c</guid></item><item><title>Underground struggles: Illegal miners risk death in Morocco&amp;apos;s forgotten coal town</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/underground-struggles-illegal-miners-risk-death-in-moroccos-forgotten-coal-town/xszzlmjvx</link><description>In one of Morocco&amp;apos;s impoverished coal towns, illegal miners continue to risk their lives to make ends meet. In an exclusive sit-down interview with SBS News, a photojournalist has shared the harsh realities he witnessed of the miners in Jerada. Ahead of the International Mining Congress in Morocco, experts are calling for better health and safety regulations to be implemented in the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0e712e9db3008d66e19ed0eaf2e697e</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Associate Professor Bassina Farbenblum</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-associate-professor-bassina-farbenblum/0qnmbvopq</link><description>As thousands of international students prepare to take summer holiday jobs, Associate Professor Bassina Farbenblum, an expert on migrants&amp;apos; rights from the University of New South Wales, warns that more is needed to protect students from wage theft and abuse. She says Australia has a ‘pervasive problem’ with workplace exploitation of international students and those on temporary visas. Dr Farbenblum is speaking to SBS’s Sandra Fulloon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0c18729dd2be5ce7d71063e89149364</guid></item><item><title>New names added to migration Welcome Wall at National Maritime Museum</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-names-added-to-migration-welcome-wall-at-national-maritime-museum/m1j44tn0z</link><description>Two panels have been unveiled at Australia&amp;apos;s National Maritime Museum to honour a new group of migrant families. Museum Director and CEO Ms Daryl Karp and Home Affairs Minister Tony Burke say the Monument is a celebration of the long history of migrants who have shaped modern Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48d94554856bd3c7a4352b62cf02903e</guid></item><item><title>Fresh wave of Israeli airstrikes kills more than 20 people in Gaza</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-airstrikes-gaza-ceasefire/3b5hykn8n</link><description>Israel and Hamas have accused each other of violating the tenuous ceasefire in Gaza multiple times over the last six weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e156783fc8e88b549950ef2040793c7f</guid></item><item><title>How a major MAGA figure went from Trump devotee to calling quits on Congress</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/marjorie-taylor-greene-resigns-congress-donald-trump-feud/eg8yg2qb6</link><description>Marjorie Taylor Greene announced her resignation this weekend after a dramatic falling out with the president that was months in the making.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">610bf75ad657d889b44ec4d008216c62</guid></item><item><title>Trump signals room to negotiate Ukraine peace deal, as Rubio insists plan is US-led</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-signals-room-to-negotiate-ukraine-peace-deal-as-rubio-insists-plan-is-us-led/7aa9whego</link><description>The US president had given Ukraine until Thursday to approve the plan, which requires it to cede territory to Russia, cut its army and pledge never to join NATO.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa3f1903cb33884f79c0b2212b8ee126</guid></item><item><title>A &amp;apos;massive&amp;apos; number of wildlife die on our roads. Experts say protections are falling far short</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/wildlife-road-kill-protections-falling-short/79d7h3jxe</link><description>Wildlife-safe road features remain largely optional, a “nice-to-have, not need-to-have”, the author of new research warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2128ae7262c4be046d60ef641d5e50e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;No way out&amp;apos;: Vietnam flooding death toll reaches 90 as search continues for missing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/vietnam-floods-death-toll-reaches-90-amid-relentless-rain/csxvjkk6s</link><description>Relentless rain has lashed south-central Vietnam since late October and popular holiday destinations have been hit by several rounds of flooding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">170c0e6bd14ce5e4128db7ad7ef7ad33</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;It&amp;apos;s just impossible&amp;apos;: The rental crisis pushing working families to the brink</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rental-crisis-single-mothers-affordability-perth-housing/sanyz35v6</link><description>Rental stress is at its worst levels on record, with renters in one city now spending nearly a third of their income on housing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f60cd36a2f99c12adadce25001cda37</guid></item><item><title>A Russian &amp;apos;wish list&amp;apos; or path to peace? The evolving plan to end Russia&amp;apos;s war on Ukraine</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rubio-calls-geneva-talks-the-best-meeting-yet-in-ukraine-peace-effort/e2zu5s50l</link><description>Donald Trump has given Ukraine until Thursday to accept the US proposal to end Russia&amp;apos;s war. But European leaders have now stepped in with different plans — more palatable for Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">316981ddc6500675457bc5c1ae0ce1e1</guid></item><item><title>What we know about Israel&amp;apos;s latest strike on Hezbollah in Beirut</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/senior-hezbollah-official-ali-tabtabai-killed-in-israeli-air-strike-on-beirut/qfw29fas3</link><description>The strike came a week before Pope Leo was set to land in Lebanon on his first foreign trip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b58ebe658101a6ab259c0195190c9c3d</guid></item><item><title>What we know about Israel&amp;apos;s latest strike on Hezbollah in Beirut</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-we-know-about-israels-latest-strike-on-hezbollah-in-beirut/qfw29fas3</link><description>The strike came a week before Pope Leo was set to land in Lebanon on his first foreign trip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ee3b2ff90230112623fed9bc5b924be</guid></item><item><title>The human cost of renewables: Why Australia should build solar here</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-human-cost-of-renewables-why-australia-should-build-solar-here/hpelo3l2p</link><description>With the renewable energy transition underway in Australia, the higher than expected uptake of solar panels has human rights groups concerned about links to Uyghur forced labour in the supply chain. As Australia looks into developing its own solar panel industry, rights groups say government and industry should work to ensure the clean energy transition isn&amp;apos;t at the cost of freedom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0782864d709d68c8e0cb337d2f8653d3</guid></item><item><title>What Black Friday sales shopping does to your brain, and how to stay in control</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-black-friday-sales-shopping-does-to-your-brain/b2z4qtdbz</link><description>Black Friday feels like a celebration of savings, but it is also a masterclass in behavioural and brain science.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93083da307adb1c9a9dc90eee4767c29</guid></item><item><title>COP30 deal keeps humanity &amp;apos;in the fight for a liveable planet&amp;apos;: UN chief</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/cop30-deal-keeps-humanity-in-the-fight-for-a-liveable-planet-un-chief/654vdjsqd</link><description>Delegates to the COP30 summit in Brazil have reached an agreement to address still rising global emissions. The deal increases money to countries hit by climate change, but contains no explicit fossil fuel plan. The agreement has mollified some - and horrified others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64f58575410d7cfc33c4407be8371b20</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 24 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-24-november-2025/jykb577a3</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0767bc1f192244212731e4a51e57bc04</guid></item><item><title>Ashwini&amp;apos;s biggest concerns now will cost the country &amp;apos;billions&amp;apos; in the future</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/childrens-report-highlights-growing-anxieties/zbtpw7pin</link><description>Children are growing more anxious and worried as they age, a new report says. Failing to address their concerns is costly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">989ae58b0963a655763c8b277405e6d1</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Women have choice&amp;apos;: Anne Aly says Pauline Hanson&amp;apos;s burqa stunt &amp;apos;unacceptable&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/women-have-choice-anne-aly-says-pauline-hansons-burqa-stunt-unacceptable/4uxl3ozms</link><description>Multiculturalism Minister Anne Aly says Pauline Hanson aims to divide with burqa stunt, arguing women &amp;quot;have choice&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebc36f9deb7fe78ef61661bf1b73453e</guid></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology weathers website storm</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/bureau-of-meteorology-weathers-website-storm/y5in22ruo</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology&amp;apos;s controversial website redesign carries a staggering 96 million dollar price tag. The cost blowout has drawn sharp criticism from both government ministers and the opposition. Federal Environment Minister Murray Watt has expressed deep concern over the massive expenditure, while Nationals Leader David Littleproud warns the public that the exorbitant cost will further erode trust in the agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f2ef1b6c4b7546ca9f9344c743b3add</guid></item><item><title>ASX bounces back as BHP walks away from AA</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asx-bounces-back-as-bhp-walks-away-from-aa/nakjhnvqw</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Raymond Chan from Morgans Financial Limited about the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action including a recovery on the ASX as the chance of a US rate cut in December swings back up and why BHP walked away from a second crack at Anglo American.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d564190e5e12a3619dccf700536901db</guid></item><item><title>Not just a &amp;apos;women&amp;apos;s issue&amp;apos;: New fertility guidelines bring men into focus</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-new-health-guidelines-changing-the-narrative-on-fertility-being-a-womens-issue/2yfu2j0fg</link><description>Australian researchers have unveiled the first male infertility guidelines, standardising care and recognising men&amp;apos;s significant role in fertility challenges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">822099d8c6c29f662682e161a22944ab</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Extraordinary rise&amp;apos;: Australia&amp;apos;s housing affordability hits worst levels yet</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/housing-affordability-hits-worst-levels-yet-new-report-shows/a4d8b7cni</link><description>In Sydney&amp;apos;s eastern suburbs, it would take 35 years for an average wage earner to save up a 20 per cent deposit for a median-priced house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2dd73a06ce98b6012accde4405ea113</guid></item><item><title>US judge dismisses criminal case against ex-FBI chief James Comey</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-judge-dismisses-case-against-ex-fbi-chief-james-comey/75k6l7nta</link><description>James Comey was charged in September with making false statements to Congress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f23702f0c3148cd4f7d328466ff0e0c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I stabbed another boy&amp;apos;: 15-year-old&amp;apos;s alleged confession to police after fatal stabbing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/teen-charged-with-murder-after-stabbing-near-school/lcf89nx7e</link><description>The victim, a boy aged 17, died from stab wounds to his thigh after a confrontation at a park in Sydney&amp;apos;s north-west about 4.20pm on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbc3d429ff4707cebbf6e11d7fbb8634</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Adult’ pressures hit hard as UNICEF warns teens are losing hope</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/adult-pressures-hit-hard-as-unicef-warns-teens-are-losing-hope/jeoepobxn</link><description>A new report from UNICEF Australia has found less than a third of Australian teens are feeling excited or hopeful about their futures. Mental health issues and anxiety around &amp;apos;adult&amp;apos; challenges like housing and money are key drivers of declining wellbeing. For marginalised children and teens, these kind of pressures are felt even more acutely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adc5369beed4a5f124d249c825c8fe58</guid></item><item><title>Sudan&amp;apos;s RSF paramilitary declares truce after army dismisses US proposal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sudans-rsf-paramilitary-declares-truce-after-army-dismisses-us-proposal/nn5k5slav</link><description>The war in Sudan, which broke out in April 2023, has killed tens of thousands of civilians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a1b9de37f157d262aeeb39df061175e</guid></item><item><title>Hanson&amp;apos;s parting election threat, as she&amp;apos;s censured and suspended for seven days</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fresh-fears-after-hansons-burqa-stunt/a05xlk3gb</link><description>Foreign Minister Penny Wong raised the motion on Tuesday after Hanson wore a burqa into the Senate a day earlier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbca81d1dd83c92c6c6d97decc3d4940</guid></item><item><title>Confirmed: A deadly bird flu strain has reached an Australian territory</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/deadly-h5-bird-flu-confirmed-on-heard-island/im66dxzyw</link><description>Detection underscores the need to prepare for a possible outbreak on the mainland, the government says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">298a118c2a6627848588532a7408a433</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 25 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-25-november-2025/qrx1ygl9t</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a706f5e923af8f05108eed08d5d645fc</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Immediate pause&amp;apos; urged on &amp;apos;secret&amp;apos; Nauru deal, after speech sparks safety concerns</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/calls-for-immediate-pause-of-secret-nauru-deal-after-speech-sparks-safety-concerns/b0w76susd</link><description>A translation of remarks by the president of Nauru has sparked safety concerns for people being deported to the Pacific nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf180e56879b112da108c0541dcab621</guid></item><item><title>US judge dismisses Comey and James cases, rules Halligan appointment unlawful</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-judge-dismisses-comey-and-james-cases-rules-halligan-appointment-unlawful/6hrejhdne</link><description>A judge in the United States has dismissed two high-profile criminal charges brought by the Trump administration against the president&amp;apos;s perceived enemies. The judge says the administration violated the Constitution in its appointment of Lindsay Halligan to prosecute the pair, rendering the charges she brought unlawful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d74cce2abe0feaf5b9a90d3fba99888c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I felt powerless&amp;apos;: calls to improve legal literacy for victim-survivors of sexual violence</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/i-felt-powerless-calls-to-improve-legal-literacy-for-victim-survivors-of-sexual-violence/qxrrho3mm</link><description>One in five women and one in 16 men have experienced sexual violence as adults in Australia, according to the 2023 Australian Bureau of Statistics - and yet 92% of women don&amp;apos;t report their most recent sexual assault. A new report is calling for legal literacy among victim-survivors, frontline services and legal professionals, to help victims navigate a complex criminal justice system and address high attrition rates in sexual assault cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d83da4f593a5f586a74b485371c30aff</guid></item><item><title>Fair Work shake-up: gig workers secure pay rise and protection</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/fair-work-shake-up-gig-workers-secure-pay-rise-and-protection/rnprlmqjx</link><description>In a landmark agreement hailed as world-leading, the Transport Workers Union, Uber, and DoorDash have put forward a minimum standards deal for Australian gig workers to the Fair Work Commission today. This major reform guarantees food delivery riders a 25% wage increase, injury insurance, and protection from unfair algorithmic dismissal, fundamentally changing a commission-based system that workers say left them making virtually no money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">def87b8d62584786ed39a1c8a39013c3</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Nothing is fixing it&amp;apos;: The devastating numbers in Australia&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;national crisis&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-domestic-violence-still-national-crisis/0bwe1lk0b</link><description>Advocates fear momentum for action against gender-based violence has slowed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d1865a8e182decd40d65c604369957c</guid></item><item><title>Sudan military rejects ceasefire</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sudan-military-rejects-ceasefire/npubmrg4r</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">603774e5beaeacf135e5eae15e019d1f</guid></item><item><title>Parties unable to agree on environment laws</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/parties-unable-to-agree-on-environment-laws/uqg4yy7w8</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3a7132201863c442d912e102b2b412d</guid></item><item><title>LGBTIQ+ Topics to be included in Census</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/lgbtiq-topics-to-be-included-in-census/uun7ysyhp</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3532a2a1a0e796fda2c51945929609b6</guid></item><item><title>Teachers strike in Queensland</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/teachers-strike-in-queensland/ypmdl2q44</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8fab8e054fd44b8c453ce99f45bd092</guid></item><item><title>Investors brace for Aussie CPI data as US rate cut looks increasingly likely</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/investors-brace-for-aussie-cpi-data-as-us-rate-cut-looks-increasingly-likely/7vf7xkf3c</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Julia Lee from FTSE Russell to find out how investors are feeling ahead of official inflation data out on Wednesday, as traders feel increasingly confident of a US rate cut in December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">850a8c65712d1e862befa2f7940895f7</guid></item><item><title>Rental squeeze intensifies: Perth now Australia’s least affordable city</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/rental-squeeze-intensifies-perth-now-australias-least-affordable-city/itb0xvotp</link><description>Despite interest rates stabilising, rental stress remains unchanged across Australia. In many capital cities, households are still handing over almost a third of their income just to keep a roof over their heads. And once again, Perth has it the worst. The nation’s least affordable capital has slipped even further — recording another four per cent drop in affordability on top of last year’s record low.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c661ec7192458ad808dbfe1067380b87</guid></item><item><title>What is the Cartel de los Soles and why has the US designated it a terror organisation?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-is-the-cartel-de-los-soles-and-why-has-the-us-designated-it-a-terror-organisation/ehhth8itm</link><description>Venezuela says the organisation does not exist and the designation was a &amp;quot;ridiculous lie&amp;quot; by the US to justify an intervention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcaa33a871a10ff981af1492967f24b6</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Value per bite&amp;apos;: The Ozempic-sized force turbocharging an Aussie food shake-up</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-ozempic-sized-force-turbocharging-an-aussie-food-shake-up/i7cvou9f7</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s GLP-1 boom is accelerating trends reshaping Australia&amp;apos;s food landscape, according to experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e01b115914fc70e441a3ed57f03d781f</guid></item><item><title>The risky transformation that led this Australian to fly 16,000km for new eyes</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/samantha-paid-30k-to-change-her-eye-colour-she-had-to-leave-australia-to-do-it/v5hdwf5qv</link><description>Samantha travelled to New York into medical territory that Australian experts won’t touch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">743c9d5384918dcf304b32cece8fe5f2</guid></item><item><title>NSW braces for worst bushfire risk in years amid hot and windy conditions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nsw-braces-for-worst-bushfire-risk-in-years-amid-hot-and-windy-conditions/d7d0t110j</link><description>The warnings come as the country is still reeling from a deadly start to bushfire season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00b943c93b437695b312905739b5bd06</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy says &amp;apos;principles&amp;apos; of revised US peace plan could lead to &amp;apos;deeper agreements&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ukraine-ready-to-move-forward-together-with-us-peace-plan/r8fubnpyl</link><description>Donald Trump told a White House event on Tuesday he thought a deal on Ukraine was getting close, but gave no other details.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e03b74eb737a944a366554c76e4376ae</guid></item><item><title>First-ever recorded eruption of Ethiopian volcano forces Asia flight cancellations</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/first-ever-recorded-eruption-of-ethiopian-volcano-forces-asia-flight-cancellations/4gxqol5eo</link><description>The ash has blanketed parts of Pakistan and northern India, according to Flightradar24, and is moving towards China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c83af6ff578d574971bd6d8657831f3</guid></item><item><title>G20 hailed as multilateral success: but US absence casts a shadow</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/g20-hailed-as-multilateral-success-but-us-absence-casts-a-shadow/di5zok8jv</link><description>World leaders have hailed the first G20 summit in Africa as a victory for multilateralism, even as they addressed challenges of climate change, inequality and war, against a backdrop of shifting geopolitical rivalries. The notable absence of President Donald Trump has raised questions the role of the United States, in a changing world order.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98e140b93d6dedc94d75c0d8bb0720f6</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 26 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-26-november-2025/43u07kv0g</link><description>A daily 5-minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9fe759b4b6c43d6fa232243cfc07fec1</guid></item><item><title>Trump says peace between Russia and Ukraine is close, but Ukrainians remain defiant</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trump-says-peace-between-russia-and-ukraine-is-close-but-ukrainians-remain-defiant/rqj80r5dy</link><description>United States President Donald Trump claims a peace deal between Russia and Ukraine is close, while Volodymyr Zelenskyy has agreed in principle to a new U--proposed peace framework. However, the Ukrainian president remains wary of being pushed into accepting a deal on Russian terms, while Ukrainians seem unwilling to meet their neighbour&amp;apos;s demands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75adb6c2086376f4b7800905e857bbef</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Significant concern&amp;apos; about fire season as thousands under emergency warning</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/significant-concern-about-fire-season-as-thousands-under-emergency-warning/pl03xa4vp</link><description>Parts of the east and west are at a heightened risk for fire according to forecasters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5f4bfc3325cc0a19d19522fd27b2de2</guid></item><item><title>‘Everywhere is not safe’: Nigeria faces spate of mass abductions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/everywhere-is-not-safe-nigeria-faces-spate-of-mass-abductions/rma5xuqwd</link><description>A wave of mass abductions in Nigeria have triggered school closures across the country with anxiety, panic and anger spreading. One of these attacks saw over 300 school children kidnapped from a Catholic secondary school in the worst single kidnapping incident in five years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62d2d71c99aaf606a34a3637f20f726a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;quot;Total impunity&amp;quot;: Israeli settler lawlessness in the West Bank destroys livelihoods of Palestinian farmers</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/total-impunity-how-israeli-lawlessness-in-the-west-bank-destroys-the-livelihoods-of-palestinian-farmers/sqhi3yymr</link><description>For Palestinian-Australian winemaker Sari Kassis, the reality of farming in the West Bank is one of constant physical and psychological danger. With settler violence surging in the West Bank, this year&amp;apos;s harvest has seen a record number of Israeli attacks on farms and properties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb3ff0842d1178e5abd86b9d2f01e35c</guid></item><item><title>Senate erupts as Pauline Hanson wears burqa, gets suspended</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/senate-erupts-as-pauline-hanson-wears-burqa-gets-suspended/kwn7lkw0o</link><description>The Australian Senate descended into chaos as One Nation leader Pauline Hanson wore a black burqa into the chamber, prompting immediate condemnation from Muslim Senators and a forceful intervention by Foreign Minister Penny Wong. Following the rejection of her motion to ban the burqa, Ms. Hanson&amp;apos;s stunt, which she claimed was about &amp;quot;protecting national security,&amp;quot; was decried as racist and disrespectful to people of faith, ultimately leading to her suspension from the Senate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbda38a26360bafde55695110b5a92ff</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Political move&amp;apos; or &amp;apos;invaluable tool&amp;apos;? Police powers to search without warrant questioned</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/political-move-or-invaluable-tool-police-powers-to-search-without-warrant-questioned/h37wapzmr</link><description>Victoria Police has announced expanded powers to search people in and around the Melbourne CBD without a warrant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fb1c2fe9d779d0db11b6daed2f1f3d0</guid></item><item><title>Stronger inflation dashes hopes of any more interest rate cuts</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/stronger-inflation-dashes-hopes-of-any-more-interest-rate-cuts/iq21qh7an</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Goncalves speaks with Damien Boey from Wilson Asset Management and Belinda Allen from the Commonwealth Bank as headline inflation continues to rise at 3.8 per cent in October to find out what that means for interest rates and investments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52b8546f72b885889354f288b9afcd9b</guid></item><item><title>Was housing the problem in Australia&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;surprising&amp;apos; economic check up?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/zero-chance-of-interest-rate-cut-soaring-prices-drive-inflation/ko2g8lruo</link><description>Some economists blamed housing for raising inflation but energy prices soared more than 37 per cent in the twelve months to October 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9eaa290db114dcd696673d89dc1f23a2</guid></item><item><title>Controversy over Melbourne event appearing to celebrate Israeli pager operation</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/controversy-over-melbourne-event-appearing-to-celebrate-israeli-pager-operation/ehy44r697</link><description>Lebanese and Jewish groups have condemned a planned event in Melbourne that appears to celebrate last year&amp;apos;s Israeli pager operation in Lebanon, which killed dozens and injured thousands more. The event run by the group called Lions of Zion has been labelled &amp;apos;disgraceful&amp;apos; - but organisers say they are celebrating what they describe as one of the most ingenious military operations in history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55b59584c123e4dd5cbbc2637c22bf79</guid></item><item><title>The new &amp;apos;widespread&amp;apos; scam to watch out for this Black Friday</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-new-widespread-scam-to-watch-out-for-this-black-friday/2jqkmgtef</link><description>The scam can be difficult to spot at first glance — but there are a few red flags to watch out for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9156c1253ec7b3f243c15b4b44465ca</guid></item><item><title>Sadness turns to anger in Hong Kong after city&amp;apos;s worst fire in decades kills at least 128</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dozens-killed-hundreds-still-missing-as-fire-rips-through-hong-kong-residential-block/1a122jlnp</link><description>Authorities have launched a corruption probe and three construction company officials have been arrested on suspicion of manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9951b2846c2d1119f66e5c9d09d258ab</guid></item><item><title>Sadness turns to anger in Hong Kong after city&amp;apos;s worst fire in decades kills at least 128</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hong-kong-residential-tower-fire-wang-fuk-court/1a122jlnp</link><description>Authorities have launched a corruption probe and three construction company officials have been arrested on suspicion of manslaughter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e018bdedbef5547da4fad0db285a1ce4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;What a dealmaker does&amp;apos;: Trump brushes off US envoy appearing to advise Putin aide</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-witkoff-putin-russia-ukraine-war-deal/uch8xrgd7</link><description>Russian diplomats have warned that Russia will make no major concessions on a plan to end its war on Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c46053737ae0e6d5a6ecb0e7a1164131</guid></item><item><title>US national guard shooting suspect identified as Afghan national</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/national-guard-washington-dc-white-house-lockdown/oeisan2y6</link><description>The attack is being investigated as an act of terrorism, a US official has said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a55a9485abd6a4233d9420a44c578948</guid></item><item><title>Major environmental laws are about to pass after &amp;apos;tough&amp;apos; negotiations, so what are they?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/five-years-in-the-making-environment-laws-to-pass-parliament-albanese-says/jynwe51dr</link><description>The seven bills are set to pass the Senate on the final day of the parliamentary year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e600c001148fcd6ac8f3cfd074391a6</guid></item><item><title>Bystander praised for heroic actions after Swiss tourist killed in NSW shark attack</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nsw-fatal-shark-attack/clbbqnd8w</link><description>Emergency services were called to a beach at Crowdy Bay, near the Kylies Beach campground on the NSW Mid North Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4833f949783f68cdc9bfad93d6f9e3f1</guid></item><item><title>Deepfake &amp;apos;nudify&amp;apos; services used by thousands of Australians blocked by government</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/deepfake-services-used-by-thousands-of-australians-blocked-by-government/mtv72irgg</link><description>The decision comes after students were found to be using the services to create fake nude images of their peers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ffc96a88e65a5ca729c71fc4621ce9c</guid></item><item><title>Concerns linger about Russian advantages in new US peace plan for Ukraine</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/concerns-linger-about-russian-advantages-in-new-us-peace-plan-for-ukraine/ljbulfngx</link><description>The United States has amended its peace plan for Ukraine, reducing it to 19 points and opening a dual diplomatic track with Moscow and Kyiv. But the new plan is stirring anxiety that Donald Trump might be willing to push Ukraine to sign a peace deal heavily tilted towards Russia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">785b46798db81b31355bacc39a093c2e</guid></item><item><title>Two National Guard members shot near White House</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/two-national-guard-members-shot-near-white-house/8xyf5905c</link><description>Two U-S National Guard soldiers have been shot near the White House. A suspect has been taken into custody, and police say he was also shot - though his injuries are not life threatening.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">036010778d026de409fcacddabc34188</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 27 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-27-november-2025/vpn0h8rnj</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bca2c9735e9a5e1cf219aaffad2b183f</guid></item><item><title>All about Australia&amp;apos;s biggest environmental reforms this century</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/all-about-australias-biggest-environmental-reforms-this-century/eozehvfko</link><description>After five years of review, the government has struck a deal with the Greens to pass the largest reforms to Australia’s environmental laws in 26 years, which includes new environmental standards, protections for native forests, and the effective end of fast-tracked approvals for coal and gas projects. Despite these wins, the deal faces criticism from environmental experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f95924b2c56ed702ea18a016d55aa2f</guid></item><item><title>Don’t call abusers &amp;apos;delightful&amp;apos;: Plea from Lilie James&amp;apos; father as coroner issues warnings</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/heartfelt-plea-from-father-of-lilie-james-as-inquest-findings-handed-down/npi0mbs30</link><description>The NSW coroner has handed down her findings into the 2023 death of Lilie James at the hands of her ex-boyfriend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07b06654c78521c4436641cc07d977b9</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine peace plan or Putin power play? Climate COP-out and Trump’s new bromance…</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ukraine-peace-plan-or-putin-power-play-climate-cop-out-and-trumps-new-bromance/orl8iybao</link><description>Alarm bells in Kyiv and Europe as the US is accused of presenting Putin’s peace plan for Ukraine. The ‘make or break’ COP30 climate conference ends in failure – have the petro-states won? Plus, the unlikely bromance blossoming in the Oval Office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e58a94f6e299d2d8642732ef2f9ce7b2</guid></item><item><title>Australia is facing a hot summer — but the forecast comes with caveats</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-kind-of-weather-can-australians-expect-this-summer/aeepj0hfy</link><description>With little rainfall, there&amp;apos;s an increased fire risk for parts of Australia, and authorities are urging caution.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d972e23563e6973d39a83df92da0f07b</guid></item><item><title>Australia falling well short of 2035 climate target, as Bowen concedes more work needed</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-falling-well-short-of-2035-climate-target-as-bowen-concedes-more-work-needed/2n9nqsfl6</link><description>The federal government has already acknowledged tougher policies would be needed to meet the 2035 goal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd0b9524263ec5d646118e55248cb828</guid></item><item><title>APRA tightens lending rules, and investors continue to question rate outlook</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/apra-tightens-lending-rules-and-investors-continue-to-question-rate-outlook/u5090hd9o</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Nathan Zaia from Morningstar about APRA&amp;apos;s tightening of lending rules for high risk borrowers to find out if it will make a difference; plus, the day on the sharemarket with Hugh Lam from Betashares.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b75987ebca9fd1b178e47a5af09d4f04</guid></item><item><title>Australia lists Iranian group as terrorist sponsors as Wong cites &amp;apos;dangerous acts&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-lists-irans-islamic-revolutionary-guard-as-a-state-sponsor-of-terrorism/kpecfjksj</link><description>The listing comes after the group was accused of being behind two separate arson attacks against Australia&amp;apos;s Jewish Community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5a24b44e094b82a3edbd3fb3fbc9a51</guid></item><item><title>The most common holiday-season scams targeting Australians — and how to spot them</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-most-common-holiday-season-scams-targeting-australians-and-how-to-spot-them/50uucmt8g</link><description>Some Australians are reporting losses of up to $5,000 due to scams during the holiday shopping season.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4022a59dc7c4c8c11a12e2222398cb17</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Lions of Zion&amp;apos; group event celebrating Israel&amp;apos;s pager attacks condemned</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-pager-attack-event-condemned/2oh6qa33w</link><description>Victoria Police has said it will continue to monitor the event billed as &amp;quot;fun for all ages&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff1396ab5b67671b84c7b49631388540</guid></item><item><title>Scores dead, hundreds missing in Hong Kong high-rise blaze | Morning News Bulletin 28 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/scores-dead-hundreds-missing-in-hong-kong-high-rise-blaze-morning-news-bulletin-28-november-2025/jp230ot81</link><description>Eighty-three people dead and hundreds missing in Hong Kong high-rise fire; Vladimir Putin responds to a proposed Ukraine peace plan; And in golf, Australian golfers chase the lead in the rain hit Australian PGA.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cba1716b5ef91a4048624aac593b6e74</guid></item><item><title>Israeli forces kill Palestinian men who appeared to be surrendering in West Bank raid</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-west-bank-jenin-raid-men-killed/vyzuz2kxc</link><description>Footage appeared to show Israeli security forces shoot and kill two unarmed Palestinian men who were attempting to surrender during a raid in Jenin in the occupied West Bank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">810aa4ae89ab4f01e24629a15772db61</guid></item><item><title>Trump blames Biden-era vetting after national guard member killed in Washington shooting</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-national-guard-shooting-death-trump/1i1jwfkts</link><description>Sarah Beckstrom was one of two national guard troops who were shot while patrolling an area near the White House on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3f8bdac8783550be9dfb7560d627b8b</guid></item><item><title>PM praises &amp;apos;yes-alition&amp;apos; as environmental reforms pass and parliament adjourns for the year</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/environmental-win-parliament-adjourns-until-february/j1jtrlwur</link><description>Politicians have returned for a final sitting hour to secure Labor&amp;apos;s environmental Christmas win.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afcf4a42ee985979e86878705f59ec6f</guid></item><item><title>Iran claims Australia &amp;apos;complicit&amp;apos; with Israel as it shares &amp;apos;disgust&amp;apos; at IRGC terror listing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/iran-claims-australia-complicit-with-israel-as-it-shares-disgust-at-irgc-terror-listing/1p99kv7pr</link><description>Iran has denounced Australia&amp;apos;s listing of the IRGC as state sponsors of terror, accusing the government of acting on fabricated claims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce0cde73b2c33a8891a7596e96b5a5b5</guid></item><item><title>94 dead in Hong Kong towers inferno | Midday News Bulletin 28 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/94-dead-in-hong-kong-towers-inferno-midday-news-bulletin-28-november-2025/v6ykktjnb</link><description>In this bulletin, Hong Kong&amp;apos;s high-rise fire still out of control as the death toll rises, two men charged with assaulting police in Melbourne protests last month. And in football, Aston Villa scores a 2-1 victory against the Young Boys in the Europa League.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93fadcfa058c7d67c49bd86f29005996</guid></item><item><title>Arrests made in connection with deadly Hong Kong fire</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/arrests-made-in-connection-with-deadly-hong-kong-fire/ajbkfi8fm</link><description>A blaze that began in bamboo scaffolding at Hong Kong’s Wang Fuk Court has become the city’s worst fire in decades, killing at least 83 people and leaving hundreds missing. Police have arrested two directors, and an engineering consultant of a firm contracted to perform maintenance on the buildings.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a47946157793c7de2bbb0e11e3330e4b</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 28 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-28-november-2025/1p3uqevt7</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5c0669b6aa25d72c1280ebc3f425bd88</guid></item><item><title>Trump says US will begin taking land action against alleged Venezuelan drug traffickers</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-says-us-will-begin-taking-land-action-against-alleged-venezuelan-drug-traffickers/w5gfn8vn0</link><description>The announcement follows months of military strikes against alleged drug boats in the Caribbean and eastern Pacific.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37d528151b53065fe7761072bc707b94</guid></item><item><title>Why these near-identical Chinese restaurants have caused mass confusion</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/chinese-noodle-house-closure-confusion/9a3q4lsxf</link><description>Its plastic grapes and braised eggplant are an iconic Sydney staple. But Chinese Noodle House&amp;apos;s closure has sparked grief ... and confusion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed19f2ec4df5a1846d1582b98187ac90</guid></item><item><title>Police officer convicted over teen&amp;apos;s death will appeal | Evening News Bulletin 28 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/police-officer-convicted-over-teens-death-will-appeal-evening-news-bulletin-28-november-2025/nruqmf9vo</link><description>In this bulletin, a police officer vows to appeal his conviction over the death of an Aboriginal teenager, arrests after a man is shot dead in a daylight attack in Sydney. And in cricket, big calls as the squad is unveiled for the second Ashes test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c0e50da9cf55236eaaf3534d7885527</guid></item><item><title>Increased bushfire risk in parts of Australia this summer, fire authorities warn</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/increased-bushfire-risk-in-parts-of-australia-this-summer-fire-authorities-warn/yvyhcjjz1</link><description>The latest bushfire outlook forecasts an increased fire risk across parts of Australia this summer. Despite recent rainfall in the country&amp;apos;s southeast, authorities say it won&amp;apos;t take long for a blaze to take hold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">807cdc971b9bcfc2d0dfd15e8d6da120</guid></item><item><title>Trump announces migration freeze for ‘third world countries’ after national guard shooting</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-announces-plan-to-halt-all-migration-from-third-world-countries/87sqx0niq</link><description>The US president said the plan would include cases approved under former president Joe Biden&amp;apos;s administration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56450cd2841686e4693299dc775a7c17</guid></item><item><title>Exclusive: El Jannah CEO speaks with SBS as company goes global &amp;amp; ASX rises</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/exclusive-el-jannah-ceo-speaks-with-sbs-as-company-goes-global-asx-rises/nd4hkjyer</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with El Jannah CEO Brett Houldin as the charcoal chicken company secures international funding valuing it at hundreds of millions of dollars, allowing it to quadruple its national footprint and explore options in the Middle-East; plus the week on the sharemarket with Tony Sycamore from IG Markets Securities Limited.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bde1688cf0e941f9edafba989596676e</guid></item><item><title>The billion dollar deportation deal Australia doesn&amp;apos;t want to talk about ft. David Shoebridge</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-billion-dollar-deportation-deal-australia-doesnt-want-to-talk-about-ft-david-shoebridge/nno1im9x4</link><description>Australia is expected to spend billions of dollars to deport non-citizens to the small Pacific nation of Nauru. Meanwhile, Pauline Hanson as repeated a years-old stunt, environment laws have passed, and Barnaby Joyce has cosied up with One Nation. Greens Senator David Shoebridge talks about the Nauru deal, after a translation of an interview with the nation&amp;apos;s president was controversially put on the record in the Senate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dae1e437a3f338e11d42592f5b9a4ac5</guid></item><item><title>Floods across Southeast Asia kill at least 250 as rescuers step up recovery operations</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/southeast-asia-floods-indonesia-thailand-malaysia/tr5djkdyo</link><description>The death toll from floods across large swathes of Southeast Asia rose to at least 250 on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d91eb9d7f16b23b8541a6e9e37558af5</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Time to step forward&amp;apos;: Australia could be making billions with this untapped export</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-australia-can-learn-from-japan-south-korea-global-content-success/kihj9n86r</link><description>Japan and South Korea are both soft power success stories. Here&amp;apos;s how Australia could follow suit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">87f24d599a02012ffac1d79b0ff5abcf</guid></item><item><title>See the list: The Aussie suburbs where home prices more than doubled in five years</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-australian-suburbs-where-home-values-have-more-than-doubled-in-five-years/3hfye21xy</link><description>Domain&amp;apos;s latest house price report reveals an uptick in desirability for regional suburbs, away from the CBD.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fba86747f64631b5b48476daedf49ce</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump to pause migration from some countries |Morning News Bulletin 29 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/donald-trump-to-pause-migration-from-some-countries-morning-news-bulletin-29-november-2025/24bor10yq</link><description>Eight more arrests made over the Hong Kong apartement fire, Donald Trump to pause migration from some countries, Oscar Piastri rules out helping his teammate, Lando Norris, win the world championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">68a1ee2e9f16bb1d49d1196f7e89ff1a</guid></item><item><title>How Olympia’s &amp;apos;maggot farms&amp;apos; are helping to tackle a $36 billion problem</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/how-olympias-maggot-farms-are-helping-to-tackle-a-36-billion-problem/slatxh81t</link><description>In Australia, around 7.6 million tonnes of food is wasted every year. One female-founder has developed a solution in a box.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">760dc57af31daf91e7883b71ad8b9249</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy&amp;apos;s chief of staff quits after anti-corruption agents search his home</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/zelenskyys-chief-of-staff-quits-after-anti-corruption-agents-search-his-home/urdk2d7dx</link><description>The removal of Andriy Yermak deals a serious blow to Volodymyr Zelenskyy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50494afb7b2258efadb65bcd27e9fdb7</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Australian youth identify cost of living as top concern in survey</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-australian-youth-identify-cost-of-living-as-top-concern-survey-finds/0iqytymby</link><description>Cost of living was the number one challenge identified by Australian youth surveyed by Mission Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c0b4918b2c9cad347d4d14928d0a2f8</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Australian youth identify cost of living as top concern in survey</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-australian-youth-identify-cost-of-living-as-top-concern-in-survey/0iqytymby</link><description>Cost of living was the number one challenge identified by Australian youth surveyed by Mission Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">15d0a79b2960ab019bf259eae34f04d6</guid></item><item><title>Here&amp;apos;s what we know about the Airbus A320 recall</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/airbus-issues-recall-of-significant-number-of-a320s-after-flight-control-incident/7kvbv3rtt</link><description>The global recall for Airbus A320s is impacting Australian travellers, with Jetstar reporting cancellations of some of its flights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38cc9c28ec0cc2b60c1bf8edeee0d3a5</guid></item><item><title>Here&amp;apos;s what we know about the Airbus A320 recall</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/airbus-recall-jetstar-flights-cancelled-as-thousands-of-a320s-grounded/7kvbv3rtt</link><description>The global recall for Airbus A320s is impacting Australian travellers, with Jetstar reporting cancellations of some of its flights.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4508c7f5d1848caf3f1e34e79cb7597c</guid></item><item><title>Olympia farms millions of maggots in Aussie warehouses — for this $36bn reason</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/how-these-tiny-insects-are-helping-to-tackle-a-36-billion-problem/2tnedixpp</link><description>Australia is wasting 7.6 million tonnes of food a year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc3b8a01324e2fff4fef473749b18db7</guid></item><item><title>National guard shooting suspect to face murder charge, as Trump blames migration</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/un-issues-plea-after-trumps-promise-to-stop-migrants-from-third-world-countries/icvwc7c32</link><description>Afghan national Rahmanullah Lakanwal is accused of shooting two national guard members, one of them fatally, in Washington DC on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ea1956c53a5dba82fa2a863ef9992e90</guid></item><item><title>Police prepare for competing protests in Melbourne and Sydney | Midday Bulletin 29 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/police-prepare-for-competing-protests-in-melbourne-and-sydney-midday-bulletin-29-november-2025/5fwrrxje6</link><description>Police prepare for competing protests in Melbourne and Sydney, Syrian officials say Israeli forces in southern Syria have killed at least 13 people in a military operation, The Matildas beat injury woes to triumph over New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b3c7913e2fa0d4cbb6c459e800eba5c</guid></item><item><title>How El Jannah grew from a family charcoal chicken restaurant to a global contender</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/from-sydney-to-the-world-the-phenomenal-story-of-a-lebanese-family-restaurant/0srd9tqbl</link><description>In an exclusive interview, El Jannah CEO Brett Houldin tells SBS News of the Lebanese chicken chain&amp;apos;s global ambitions after a major US buyout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70674974333b21fd33243d68dd5dc1aa</guid></item><item><title>Australia blitzed transmission of HIV, but a neighbour&amp;apos;s crisis threatens the entire region</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fijis-hiv-crisis-and-what-australia-is-doing-to-help/hp1x1osis</link><description>Australia has committed $48m to support Fiji&amp;apos;s fast-growing HIV crisis, targeting testing, treatment and community-led prevention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">276841c02ed60f34dce55f391b92752d</guid></item><item><title>Why Donald Trump is cancelling Joe Biden&amp;apos;s autopen executive orders</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-says-he-is-cancelling-all-bidens-autopen-signed-orders/p7h2c3t5g</link><description>Trump has previously said Biden&amp;apos;s autopen use proves the then-president was mentally incapacitated and not in control of the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">16a222a6f09ce72a64b2023850ad0285</guid></item><item><title>Heat wave expected across Australia | Evening News Bulletin 29 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/heat-wave-expected-across-australia-evening-news-bulletin-29-november-2025/zzrw6u19p</link><description>Heat wave expected across Australia; The UN says Israeli killing of Palestinians in West Bank appeared to be summary execution; And in football, Iran vows to boycott World Cup draw in US after Visa issues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b9d90c8ecfb36d044fcf2831204a9fa</guid></item><item><title>New Prime Minister elected in St Vincent and the Grenadines</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-prime-minister-elected-in-st-vincent-and-the-grenadines/ta8lax268</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8267ce5af51b76660dda9508511d246f</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Delighted to share our love&amp;apos;: Anthony Albanese marries Jodie Haydon at The Lodge</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anthony-albanese-marries-fiancee-jodie-haydon-at-the-lodge/tx3mpjdni</link><description>The small private ceremony with family and close friends on Saturday afternoon was kept under wraps until after it had concluded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d3a6a2e2d7714f8d316cb0ceb2b64991</guid></item><item><title>Prime Minister &amp;apos;delighted&amp;apos; as he celebrates wedding to fiancée Jodie Haydon</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/prime-minister-delighted-as-he-celebrates-wedding-to-fiancee-jodie-haydon/e8yakbv6f</link><description>The Prime Minister and his fiancée Jodie Hayden have just married, at a ceremony in the nation’s capital. The country&amp;apos;s been kept guessing as to exactly when the wedding would take place for months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f15f185a26c117cc3b973114ab54e12e</guid></item><item><title>From DMs to &amp;apos;I do&amp;apos;: The Rabbitohs romance that led to Australia&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;royal wedding&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anthony-albanese-and-jodie-haydon-married-in-canberra/m2ojw0xn9</link><description>A six-year romance between Anthony Albanese and Jodie Haydon began with social media messages and a shared love of footy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66d674f5326c85febaa6b221a940218e</guid></item><item><title>The surprising technology that could be key to saving the Great Barrier Reef</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/first-nations-rangers-protecting-the-great-barrier-reef/zlpgif3hc</link><description>First Nations rangers from the world&amp;apos;s biggest reef are learning coral spawning techniques in one of the largest restoration trials to date.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7714ef9b3b0fcb2c74146cacde90fa4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Gone nowhere&amp;apos;: Government criticised as progress fizzles on &amp;apos;dangerous&amp;apos; reforms</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gone-nowhere-government-criticised-as-progress-fizzles-on-dangerous-reforms/u953o31me</link><description>Labor has quietly parked its transparency overhaul as parliament breaks for Christmas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">284307f0edb12789e2b52ddf2613016b</guid></item><item><title>Death toll rises from floods in Southeast Asia | Morning Bulletin 30 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/death-toll-rises-from-floods-in-southeast-asia-morning-bulletin-30-november-2025/k7awsapz7</link><description>The death toll from sweeping floods in Southeast Asia rises dramatically, The Prime Minister marries his fiancee Jodie Hayden in Canberra, Australia&amp;apos;s Oscar Piastri returns to form with a win in Qatar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5a2678b3e29a103c5819a78c6ab54ff</guid></item><item><title>Trump declares Venezuela airspace &amp;apos;closed in its entirety&amp;apos; as tensions surge</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-declares-venezuela-airspace-closed-in-its-entirety-as-tensions-surge/1tzmd9ivb</link><description>Venezuela&amp;apos;s government condemned Trump&amp;apos;s comments, describing them as a &amp;quot;colonialist threat&amp;quot; against the country&amp;apos;s sovereignty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02fa36ff82750613a3344e7b803620d6</guid></item><item><title>Trump declares Venezuela airspace &amp;apos;closed in its entirety&amp;apos; as tensions surge</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-declares-venezuelas-airspace-closed-in-its-entirety-as-tensions-surge/1tzmd9ivb</link><description>Venezuela&amp;apos;s government condemned Trump&amp;apos;s comments, describing them as a &amp;quot;colonialist threat&amp;quot; against the country&amp;apos;s sovereignty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc04a3ad985f3d2a71a61a4011ba40a6</guid></item><item><title>More details emerge about interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/more-details-emerge-about-interstellar-comet-3i-atlas/gw74zsw8k</link><description>There&amp;apos;s been widespread and growing speculation that interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS is an alien craft. But scientists have debunked the claims. New observations from NASA and South Africa’s MeerKAT telescope confirm it is a natural, volatile-rich comet showing textbook outgassing, hydroxyl radio emissions and expected orbital shifts. Far from extraterrestrial engineering, 3I/ATLAS offers a rare window into the deep past, likely originating in a star system billions of years older than our own.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8a7fa20affa888ae2395c7bc03726b3</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;At risk of losing everything&amp;apos;: The frontline rangers protecting the Great Barrier Reef</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/at-risk-of-losing-everything-the-frontline-rangers-protecting-the-great-barrier-reef/mf2qseg4w</link><description>Indigenous rangers from the Great Barrier Reef are learning coral spawning techniques in one of the largest reef restoration trials to date. The pilot program involves rangers working in the reefs off Queensland&amp;apos;s Keppel Islands, which were hit hard by last year&amp;apos;s mass coral bleaching event.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1635e4d8253ff72198706a85417a7461</guid></item><item><title>Southeast Asia floods: More than 400 killed as clean-up begins</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/southeast-asia-floods-more-than-400-killed-as-clean-up-begins/lhz8vginz</link><description>Heavy monsoon rain overwhelmed swaths of Indonesia, Thailand and Malaysia this week and left thousands stranded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6299a7123eed44e390a784705272e28</guid></item><item><title>Russian missiles and &amp;apos;anarchisation&amp;apos;: How could Venezuela respond to a US attack?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/russian-missiles-and-anarchisation-how-could-venezuela-respond-to-a-us-attack/dxk6vvg9p</link><description>The Venezuelan foreign ministry called the latest remarks from Donald Trump a &amp;quot;new extravagant, illegal, and unjustified aggression against the people of Venezuela&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8e0a8609caa1352d10aa10813802700</guid></item><item><title>Hidden cameras and earpieces: Kazakhstan couple arrested over alleged $1m casino scam</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/kazakhstan-couple-arrested-over-alleged-1m-casino-scam/4d7t9fxfn</link><description>NSW detectives said they were called to a casino in Sydney&amp;apos;s CBD after staff noticed something on a woman&amp;apos;s shirt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">973f81d1796523091a17bcd3066cea50</guid></item><item><title>A new values test for temporary visa holders &amp;apos;won&amp;apos;t hurt&amp;apos;, David Littleproud says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/a-new-values-test-for-temporary-visa-holders-wont-hurt-david-littleproud-says/h2bmk9med</link><description>The Coalition is set to unveil its immigration policy, expected to include cuts to migration levels, by the year&amp;apos;s end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">259d11299c754f6709a6a0d3cef93baa</guid></item><item><title>Childcare centres to be given more time for safety training | Midday News Bulletin 30 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/childcare-centres-to-be-given-more-time-for-safety-training-midday-news-bulletin-30-november-2025/fzmj9fidq</link><description>Childcare centres allowed to close early to enable mandatory safety training, New Metro Tunnel rain line opens in Melbourne, North Melbourne wins the AFLW grand final for the second year running.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad5d733883d5c0a901fca999340d8dff</guid></item><item><title>Expert view: Will Australia have another Christmas COVID wave this year?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/will-australia-have-another-christmas-covid-wave-this-year/lprxvr8vq</link><description>Since the start of the pandemic, Australia has experienced an increase in COVID-19 cases during the summer and winter months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff4dd253c690fcf7231a653f6f0329e1</guid></item><item><title>Nationwide passport system outage leaves travellers stuck at airports</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nationwide-passport-system-outage-leaves-travellers-stuck-at-airports/nh3l0lj1c</link><description>Passengers reportedly had to be processed manually through immigration services.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c427befb02fe4e38637d6deea412976</guid></item><item><title>Israel kills two children in Gaza in ceasefire violation | Evening News Bulletin 30 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israel-kills-two-children-in-gaza-in-ceasefire-violation-evening-news-bulletin-30-november-2025/67hav6ttv</link><description>Sussan Ley warns Labor Greens deal will hurt forestry sector in Tasmania; Israel kills two children in Gaza in violation of ceasefire; And in cricket, Pakistan wins the Twenty20 tri-series against Sri Lanka.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7191c0bd699a217b82957a612939f608</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I remember being so scared&amp;apos;: Chrissy&amp;apos;s traumatic three-year battle to have her ex convicted</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/i-remember-being-so-scared-chrissy-faced-a-three-year-battle-to-have-her-ex-convicted/tgwtko741</link><description>Chrissy says she faced traumatic experiences navigating the justice system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6e996ec51374d943be4d32ee88c2e45</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;He&amp;apos;s been buried twice&amp;apos;: Why John had to open his brother&amp;apos;s grave after 49 years</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/why-john-had-to-bury-his-brother-twice-rodda-museum-utas/dargqg576</link><description>Recent findings of a coronial inquest confirmed that 177 human specimens were handed to the University of Tasmania without consent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70d33bb549d4ccb4790b8bbf2bd64508</guid></item><item><title>Housing prices increase amid record levels of unaffordability | Morning News Bulletin 1 December 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/housing-prices-increase-amid-record-levels-of-unaffordability-morning-news-bulletin-1-december-2025/y3lbsnkil</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s housing prices increase amid record levels of unaffordability; Benjamin Netanyahu seeks a pardon in a bid to end a five-year corruption trial; And in Formula One, Max Verstappen wins the Qatar Grand Prix.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31e3f1a7fb01fc997dd8e3826d55bd52</guid></item><item><title>Netanyahu seeks &amp;apos;extraordinary&amp;apos; presidential pardon amid ongoing corruption trial</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/netanyahu-seeks-extraordinary-presidential-pardon-amid-ongoing-corruption-trial/z8vz08vif</link><description>Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu has argued that his legal proceedings impede his ability to govern and a pardon would benefit Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b900716c344ac922050df78a826c99b</guid></item><item><title>Militaries step in to aid Asia flood victims as death toll passes 1,000</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/more-than-600-killed-as-floods-and-landslides-devastate-south-east-asia/0j4gaaulg</link><description>Separate weather systems last week led to deadly floods and landslides in Sri Lanka, Indonesia, Thailand and Malaysia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0093d40c60cee886156545e649043576</guid></item><item><title>Militaries step in to aid Asia flood victims as death toll passes 1,000</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nearly-1000-killed-as-floods-and-landslides-devastate-south-east-asia/0j4gaaulg</link><description>Separate weather systems last week led to deadly floods and landslides in Sri Lanka, Indonesia, Thailand and Malaysia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">342b84f2f2531df50ea455b752ed7626</guid></item><item><title>Soaring home prices erase benefits of recent interest rate cuts</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cotality-finds-soaring-home-prices-erase-benefits-of-recent-interest-rate-cuts/iisjp84go</link><description>Data from Cotality shows rapid home price growth across Australia has erased affordability gains from recent rate cuts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e906141e31ddcad271fbe041a9e1ae5</guid></item><item><title>Government to target &amp;apos;dark patterns&amp;apos; behind hidden fees and subscription traps</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/crackdown-on-dark-patterns-to-stop-australians-being-trapped-by-hidden-fee-subscriptions/0ycwj85nz</link><description>The government wants to outlaw drip pricing and subscription traps, targeting manipulative online tactics that cost Australians millions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22ada3184d622934483520d7cfeacaac</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Can&amp;apos;t afford to ask nicely anymore&amp;apos;: Why Myles locked himself to port equipment</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anti-coal-protests-lead-to-more-arrests/zfqq2db2x</link><description>NSW Police have charged more than 150 people in relation to the protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6dd3ed32377a2109ef801374b362bc49</guid></item><item><title>&amp;quot;Weapons on wheels&amp;quot; smart cars abuse warning| Midday News Bulletin 1 December 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/weapons-on-wheels-smart-cars-abuse-warning-midday-news-bulletin-1-december-2025/4ry6k3b6n</link><description>In this bulletin, a warning over smart cars being used to facilitate domestic abuse, Donald Trump says latest deal proposal could likely end war in Ukraine. And in athletics, high jumper Nicola Olyslagers the second ever Australian to be recognised at the World Athletics Awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304d7875c945ee80fc7ab403ae188817</guid></item><item><title>Protests follow request for pardon by Netanyahu</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/protests-follow-request-for-pardon-by-netanyahu/qk36hlahq</link><description>Israel is facing a political shock wave after Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu formally asked President Isaac Herzog for a pardon in his ongoing corruption trial. The unprecedented move has triggered fierce protests, legal warnings and a deeply polarised public debate over whether clemency would unify the nation or erode the rule of law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71b66b9708d7e69c22ded81a853013ca</guid></item><item><title>He vowed to uncover harm. Police allege he led a satanic child sex abuse material ring</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-charged-over-alleged-satanic-child-sex-abuse-material-ring/0s5973f6q</link><description>Four men from an alleged Sydney-based paedophile network — including the founder of an independent news website — were arrested last week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1086a107492c33d4cb5d2bc43e2af635</guid></item><item><title>Global arms giants hit record $1 trillion in revenue, fuelled by Ukraine and Gaza wars</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/global-arms-giants-hit-record-1-trillion-in-revenue-fuelled-by-ukraine-and-gaza-wars/3ehm3xp58</link><description>An increase in national defence spending also contributed to a surge in sales for the world&amp;apos;s largest arms-makers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de666f256d87aca063ef6f12deab70d9</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 1 December 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-1-december-2025/qeza5fh8n</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28a103cba837d1865ad4fbb4ed9d31b7</guid></item><item><title>Australia monitoring Chinese &amp;apos;task group&amp;apos; in the Philippine Sea</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-monitoring-chinese-task-group-in-the-philippine-sea/ksh3xo6xv</link><description>The news came as Acting Prime Minister Richard Marles announced a huge shake-up of Australia&amp;apos;s defence department.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3daca6064aa7a927fcf66eb63cc7a1c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Moving in the wrong direction&amp;apos;: The debt divide leaving some Australians even worse off</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/personal-debt-on-the-rise-but-for-fewer-australians/f9p7idunm</link><description>Housing remains the top financial concern for Australians amid unrelenting cost of living issues, though many are continuing to save.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f34fb89a110ffdf3f36dd9ebb7c6574</guid></item><item><title>First major changes to Defence industry in 40 years | Evening News Bulletin 1 December 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/first-major-changes-to-defence-industry-in-40-years-evening-news-bulletin-1-december-2025/tdfofhvzz</link><description>In this bulletin, a defence department overhaul aims to end cost blowouts and major project delays, an update on Australia’s transition to renewable energy. And in sport, Sam Kerr still a chance to return to play for the Matilda&amp;apos;s on Tuesday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">206fb2e9c39721cc6bbeb02aeaa87231</guid></item><item><title>ASX outage hits company announcements &amp;amp; property price growth eases</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asx-outage-hits-company-announcements-property-price-growth-eases/q1a9t6tqt</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Chris Weston from Pepperstone about the day&amp;apos;s market action including another outage at the ASX. Plus Eliza Owen from Cotality Australia takes a look at the latest property price data and future moves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0fdf07c3352f2ab9b80cbd40280ba4ac</guid></item><item><title>Hong Kong officials say mesh on apartments failed fire safety standards as death toll rises</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hong-kong-fires-scaffolding-mesh-safety-standards/gf65naix8</link><description>Officials have also said that fire alarms were not working properly, as questions swirl over whether the inferno was preventable.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e779e424c96195d058d3b4e996b21a1</guid></item></channel></rss>