<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>SBS English News (Unofficial Aggregation)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:08:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Special Episode: Palestine recognition, Trump unfiltered &amp;amp; paracetamol panic</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/special-episode-palestine-recognition-trump-unfiltered-paracetamol-panic/tnptxg0lk</link><description>Ten Western nations (including Australia, the UK, and France) formally recognise a Palestinian state at the UN General Assembly. Our correspondents bring you the latest from New York, as they break down the statehood debate, MAGA’s escalating war on the left, and Trump’s unsubstantiated claims linking paracetamol and autism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4ac35a9b7c9c6e6f6d36f18d15f4651</guid></item><item><title>Industries at risk of technology and AI &amp;amp; big dividend day</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/industries-at-risk-of-technology-and-ai-big-dividend-day/1op2dgni7</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves delves into Barrenjoey&amp;apos;s report on the industries most exposed to technological change and AI with Johnathan McMenamin; plus the day on the sharemarket with Mark Gardner from MPC Markets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf846076200e45ef163c7298da50e300</guid></item><item><title>Key questions behind this controversial United Nations address</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/key-questions-behind-this-controversial-united-nations-address/5trcpd0tm</link><description>He once led a designated terrorist group. Now, Syria&amp;apos;s Ahmed al-Sharaa leads the country and has addressed the United Nations. But was his appearance there really another step in a &amp;quot;dramatic&amp;quot; political transformation?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4b57c0185fdaa39baf1c49b852172e95</guid></item><item><title>Former French President Nicolas Sarkozy jailed for five years over Libyan criminal conspiracy case</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/former-french-president-nicolas-sarkozy-jailed-for-five-years-over-libyan-criminal-conspiracy-case/grw7m3dp4</link><description>Sarkozy, who has always denied the charges, was accused of making a deal with former Libyan leader Muammar Gaddafi to obtain campaign financing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">be6bac62f93e06551789c8d0677e8f8c</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s battle to take out a rival bid and host its &amp;apos;biggest diplomatic summit ever&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-australia-could-become-an-energy-superpower-as-pm-works-to-secure-cop31/r8vn79fyh</link><description>The summit would likely provide an economic boost for the hopeful host city, Adelaide, after a record 80,000 people attended last year&amp;apos;s event in Dubai.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ffcbd6bf26dfc13c2193b534657a26d</guid></item><item><title>From Silicon Valley to Sydney: How Trump&amp;apos;s H-1B visa move could make ripples in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/from-silicon-valley-to-sydney-how-trumps-h-1b-visa-move-could-make-ripples-in-australia/amcd339a5</link><description>As Donald Trump&amp;apos;s H-1B visa order seeks to restrict the United States&amp;apos; intake of skilled migrants, could it provide an opportunity for Australia?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37fafd6743414d2477d3669a2035320c</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says any Israeli annexation of the West Bank is &amp;apos;not going to happen&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/donald-trump-israeli-annexation-west-bank/dmuh8nt5q</link><description>The US president has rejected calls from some members of the Israeli prime minister&amp;apos;s coalition for Israel to fully annex the West Bank.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f43834fb1b9be4a5846b0f6297f298c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Unusual&amp;apos;: Passenger on board Qantas flight speaks after emergency landing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/qantas-plane-lands-in-auckland-after-reports-of-a-fire-on-board/rjrcmg2if</link><description>The plane landed safely at Auckland Airport after concerns of a fire in the cargo hold. The local ambulance service said no passengers on board required its assistance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a72f9bb135469461c9e2fdf0bc6bf5e3</guid></item><item><title>Who is James Comey, the Trump critic and ex-FBI director who has just been indicted?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/who-is-james-comey-trump-critic-indictment/oywvzmyyg</link><description>James Comey, who was fired by Donald Trump during the US president&amp;apos;s first term, has been charged with two criminal counts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52891cfe9a6e930af7e0f9e24afe8fa8</guid></item><item><title>Butler criticises Trump&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;unfair&amp;apos; pharma tariffs that Ley says are &amp;apos;shocking but unsurprising&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/health-minister-responds-to-trumps-100-per-cent-pharma-tariff-hike/ngur97kvl</link><description>Medicines and pharmaceuticals are among Australia&amp;apos;s top exports to the US, according to the Australian Bureau of Statistics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3564c30351ad0429c7e99283ced9447d</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 25 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-25-september-2025/8xv6ewgm9</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9124f94f69627c49fa98fd747d3a52c5</guid></item><item><title>UN says millions of young people are being left behind</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/un-says-millions-of-young-people-are-being-left-behind/52hlk4jox</link><description>Youth advocates from around the world have gathered at the UN headquarters in New York to participate in the high-level plenary meeting of the General Assembly. Their meeting marked the thirtieth anniversary of the World Programme of Action for Youth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">143002988049f6a5672843f72b63f8e4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Exclusion or punishment&amp;apos;: Fears of a growing problem in Australian schools</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anti-palestinian-racism-in-schools-apan-report/8ak0h6ka3</link><description>There&amp;apos;s an anti-Palestinian racism &amp;quot;crisis&amp;quot; in Australian schools, according to a new report by an advocacy group, with students and teachers being punished for showing support for the Palestinian cause.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">583d801dfb3b129c925fe92475f79221</guid></item><item><title>What time does the 2025 AFL grand final start? All the key details to know</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/afl-grand-final-2025-key-information/7cphviiz9</link><description>Around 100,000 people are anticipated to go to the Geelong v Brisbane match this weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66146d8eacf385e9983830eab95301d5</guid></item><item><title>Pharma stocks tumble following US pharma import tariffs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pharma-stocks-tumble-following-us-pharma-import-tariffs/mud4bfff3</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Shane Oliver from AMP and Marcus Bogdan from Blackmore Capital about the reaction to a US decision to apply 100% import tariffs to pharmaceutical products from Wednesday, plus all the latest from the sharemarket.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b12b0e39c24005e76a3b975b6812b43</guid></item><item><title>Dreaming of spreadsheets and battling stage fright: Behind the world Excel championships</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-its-like-to-compete-in-microsoft-excel-world-championship/xdada7hn3</link><description>From spreadsheets to showdowns, the Excel World Championship turns number-crunching into a high-stakes spectacle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">de6cf9898e100219c9b3ac6800c3b2f8</guid></item><item><title>Australia has around 100,000 eggs in IVF storage. Some want to see unclaimed eggs donated</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/egg-donation-ivf-australia/kx9zbvh3u</link><description>The demand for eggs far outpaces the number donated in Australia, leaving those wanting to start families with few options. Experts say something needs to change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46a88d94868d7af5965bc0c61d8c7052</guid></item><item><title>What&amp;apos;s next for South Australia&amp;apos;s algae bloom?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/whats-next-for-south-australias-algae-bloom/6jag2297p</link><description>South Australia&amp;apos;s algal bloom continues to spread, leading to significant environmental, ecological and mental health harm. Those impacts have been heard at a Senate inquiry examining support arrangements for those affected, but also long-term prevention strategies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf09055980d41d84633ea374ffc9d6a6</guid></item><item><title>New deep space antenna in Australia to aid exploration of universe while also creating local jobs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-deep-space-antenna-in-australia-to-aid-exploration-of-universe-while-also-creating-local-jobs/wu02b46fa</link><description>More than three years after it was first announced, a new deep space antenna is being brought online in Western Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d848ae9022e4e09bac451b0af89dd69</guid></item><item><title>How to deep clean your fridge ahead of summer</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-to-deep-clean-your-fridge-ahead-of-summer/521ho9ztx</link><description>Those neglected items at the back of your fridge can become a health hazard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cee068de68a67a2a0dbfe956af29cf0b</guid></item><item><title>Six-pack diplomacy: Albanese joins Starmer and Carney for high-stakes talks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/beer-diplomacy-and-warnings-about-far-right-populism-dominate-albanese-london-trip/v450k88es</link><description>The Australian, British and Canadian leaders used a London summit to warn against the far-right and to discuss migration and renewed support for Palestinian statehood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f79c80fc03f02c8382a3d6b5e32ee47b</guid></item><item><title>A mass delegate walk-out and what comes next: Benjamin Netanyahu&amp;apos;s speech to the UN</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/a-mass-delegate-walk-out-and-what-comes-next-benjamin-netanyahus-speech-to-the-un/czpfanep1</link><description>Speaking at the United Nations, the Israeli leader pushed back in his harshest terms yet against a flurry of diplomatic moves that have deepened Israel&amp;apos;s international isolation. But one thing was missing — any suggestion for what comes next, besides more war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26fbf030d34aeae18a8d5e484a968594</guid></item><item><title>Trump isn&amp;apos;t the first to push an unproven claim about autism. Why are they so pervasive?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/donald-trump-autism-disinformation-misinformation-tylenol-vaccines/zvsep8k5i</link><description>One expert says an &amp;quot;information void&amp;quot; has allowed non-evidence-based claims and conspiracy theories around autism to flourish.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ae6b5217e8e5f04bcdfed4ad05151dc</guid></item><item><title>Afraid of AI replacing you? Here are jobs that may be future-proof</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/afraid-of-ai-replacing-you-here-are-jobs-that-may-be-future-proof/g84ryofgy</link><description>Jobs including tax preparation, legal advice and education may have the lowest risk of being replaced by technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2832f2b830d5b4c41ba4a107c1a914fd</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Is this still happening?&amp;apos;: Elon Musk named in new Epstein files</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/is-this-still-happening-elon-musk-named-in-new-epstein-files/dfb8gea5z</link><description>Prince Andrew and PayPal co-founder Peter Thiel are among the other names in the documents released by Democrat politicians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">087653cae4c83e925aae0febaf669bc7</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Could a new UN declaration protect aid workers amid the growing death toll?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-could-a-new-un-declaration-protect-aid-workers-amid-the-growing-death-toll/i6tzu58gi</link><description>More than 100 states have signed an Australian-led declaration to protect aid workers. Australian Red Cross CEO Andrew Colvin explains what the declaration is aiming to achieve.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a7aee2bbedfd24a7cc1a6fc6fe775fa</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Peeling back the water&amp;apos;: How these women are mapping ancient whale migration paths</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/whale-migration-mapping-project-reveals-indigenous-songlines/7nqere56s</link><description>A trio of First Nations researchers is blending traditional knowledge and science to map whale migration and advocate for improved conservation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b7d809fbe9e4d1d1b1291d689c79769</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Jekyll and Hyde&amp;apos;: How to win over Australia&amp;apos;s most polarising bird</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-to-win-over-australias-most-polarising-bird/c52yvb0xg</link><description>Culturally revered in Dreamtime stories but feared by cyclists, the magpie has a &amp;quot;Jekyll and Hyde&amp;quot; presence in our suburbs. But one expert says there are ways to win them over — even if you&amp;apos;re magpie enemy number one.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58dcc52a2f1862c3da45a3beaef188b3</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: &amp;apos;We are family, we should work together&amp;apos;: Palau President&amp;apos;s challenge to Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-we-are-family-we-should-work-together-palau-presidents-challenge-to-australia/mcmwdac58</link><description>Palau, an independent island nation in the western Pacific Ocean, consists of more than 300 islands in Micronesia. It&amp;apos;s a popular destination for divers and ecotourists and visitors are required to take the &amp;quot;Palau Pledge&amp;quot; to protect its ecosystems. But Palau is already facing the immediate reality of climate change, with rising sea levels, coral bleaching, extreme weather events, and biodiversity loss. Surangel Whipps Junior, the President of Palau, has spoken at the United Nations General Assembly in New York, and wants to see the COP31 global climate conference held in the Pacific region rather than in Turkiye, because this is where climate change is already having devastating impacts. He&amp;apos;s been talking to SBS Senior International Correspondent Ben Lewis, and told him that Palau and Australia are family - and the two countries need to work together.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bc8d99d4218ddff18c78bb6e03b40e1</guid></item><item><title>The effects of Tonga&amp;apos;s massive volcanic explosion linger, three years on</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-effects-of-tongas-massive-volcanic-explosion-linger-three-years-on/ro26186xy</link><description>It&amp;apos;s been more than three and a half years since one of the most powerful volcanic eruptions in recent history left devastation in Tonga. An Australian-led scientific team has been studying the area surrounding the underwater volcano, in collaboration with researchers from across the world, looking for signs of life. The eruption changed the shape of the sea floor and devastated the underwater environment but early signs of life are beginning to emerge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8641530ae1996f8058525e34c7b7b7ac</guid></item><item><title>Russia says West will &amp;apos;very much regret&amp;apos; any aggressive action inside its airspace</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/russia-says-west-will-very-much-regret-any-aggressive-action-inside-its-airspace/zok5nth57</link><description>The Russian foreign minister also said that only the &amp;quot;politically blind&amp;quot; would expect Ukraine to return to pre-2022 borders, an indirect response to a recent assertion made by the US president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0f621ceea2c2576bad39df984916703</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump deploys troops into another US city, authorising use of &amp;apos;full force, if necessary&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/donald-trump-deploys-troops-into-portland-oregon/7ooxqtd7m</link><description>The Portland mayor and Oregon governor have both rejected Donald Trump&amp;apos;s planned deployment of the US military into the north-western city.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a36e1f435cbac6f40ce5f36a2106707a</guid></item><item><title>The hidden form of sexual assault you may not know about</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-hidden-form-of-sexual-assault-you-may-not-know-about/1svz4t6mv</link><description>Stealthing — the removal of a condom during sex without a partner&amp;apos;s knowledge or consent — is criminalised in most of Australia. But experts warn many people remain unaware of what it is and the risks it poses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">850e2fad608803f8eeff2ea290f369c9</guid></item><item><title>The hidden form of sexual assault you may not know about</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-hidden-form-of-sexual-assault-most-people-dont-know-about/1svz4t6mv</link><description>Stealthing — the removal of a condom during sex without a partner&amp;apos;s knowledge or consent — is criminalised in most of Australia. But experts warn many people remain unaware of what it is and the risks it poses.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">152ed3426fe78e1151f27efea20076b4</guid></item><item><title>What to know about UN&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;snapback&amp;apos; sanctions on Iran, reimposed after a decade</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/un-has-reimposed-snapback-sanctions-on-iran-after-a-decade/l3d35tc70</link><description>The &amp;quot;snapback&amp;quot; process reactivates UN resolutions, but their practical implementation requires UN member states to update their laws to comply.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c86d8047ad197216a7cbcdb86483b1f2</guid></item><item><title>Russia&amp;apos;s major drone and missile attack on Ukraine kills four in Kyiv</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/russian-missile-and-drone-barrage-kills-four-in-kyiv/dz12wa430</link><description>Russia rained down 643 drones and missiles, including glide bombs, across eastern, central and southern Ukraine, Ukraine&amp;apos;s general staff said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74c343d8a4b46d613740d84cc564cbda</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Part of my job&amp;apos;: Albanese fires back at critics questioning his taxpayer-funded UK itinerary</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-fires-back-at-critics-questioning-his-taxpayer-funded-uk-trip/w4lupllva</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese addressed concerns about participating in a party-political event in an interview with SBS News.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ac2413488e6078ac7004a9748db73c9</guid></item><item><title>Nuclear bombs on drones: The next arms race that has experts &amp;apos;very concerned&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nuclear-bombs-on-drones-this-might-be-the-next-arms-race-started-by-russia/fizt682bo</link><description>While drones flying over different parts of Europe have raised concerns in many countries, some are worried about a more dystopian future with the technology.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a10419c842d35e2af578c6fb0fb5474f</guid></item><item><title>In America&amp;apos;s war on autism, families like Eileen&amp;apos;s are on the frontline</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/in-americas-war-on-autism-families-like-eileens-are-on-the-frontline/ayj8r6zze</link><description>US health secretary Robert F Kennedy Jr has faced widespread criticism over his comments about autism. And in a changing America, community members from all parts of the spectrum are navigating societal and political divisions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c195e225cd246bd1412afe3971df134</guid></item><item><title>Working in a Gaza field hospital: The view from an Australian emergency nurse</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/working-in-a-gaza-field-hospital-the-view-from-an-australian-emergency-nurse/m1eyvcolm</link><description>An Australian nurse is among the few international staff still on the ground at a Red Cross field hospital in southern Gaza. He shares the challenges of working in one of the only facilities still fully functioning in the enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bafea68df19beeb90c7ad4a3c62f4c1</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;In real danger&amp;apos;: Hamas says it lost contact with two hostages during Israeli offensive</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hamas-lost-contact-two-israeli-hostages-during-gaza-fighting/tuqh60lco</link><description>Hamas&amp;apos;s armed wing said the hostages&amp;apos; lives were under threat and called on Israeli forces to &amp;quot;immediately withdraw&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">426b30ae599786337800d1a479f7db33</guid></item><item><title>Jobs and wages boost budget bottom line ahead of Tuesday&amp;apos;s interest rates call</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jobs-and-wages-have-boosted-budgets-bottom-line-ahead-of-rates-call/jdopyy4vp</link><description>Strong jobs and wages numbers have more than halved the budget deficit that was projected last financial year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b9b638b182d077d7d0777c6762073c19</guid></item><item><title>SBS News In Easy English 29 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-29-september-2025/je7fogmc8</link><description>A daily 5 minute news bulletin for English learners, and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a0030a54b27e151e7ce7039a496eee7</guid></item><item><title>Trump hints at Middle East peace plan: &amp;apos;All on board for something special&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trump-hints-at-middle-east-peace-plan-all-on-board-for-somnething-special/puqoc60eg</link><description>The prospect of a long-awaited Middle East peace initiative has re-emerged, with President Donald Trump signalling that his administration is ready to unveil a comprehensive plan for Gaza. While US and Israeli leaders express cautious optimism, the humanitarian crisis in Gaza continues to worsen, with tens of thousands dead and entire neighbourhoods reduced to rubble.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd81dec6f4104b1e8b1ee3d17eeeb2a7</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Weird weather&amp;apos;: Why this year&amp;apos;s spring and summer just became tricky to predict</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hot-weather-summer-forecast-australia/nhobygggg</link><description>A clash of wind and air currents 30km above Antarctica has suddenly thrown Australia&amp;apos;s spring and summer weather forecast into question.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf330d9649339af144380b81f10c1855</guid></item><item><title>Police pursuit ends in Bourke Street Mall, multiple arrests in Melbourne CBD</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/multiple-arrests-made-in-bourke-street-mall-melbourne/gl90irpml</link><description>Four teenagers have been arrested after police saw a vehicle being driven &amp;quot;erratically&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b5633ec02a9cb071dc621b7d3a9f2fb</guid></item><item><title>Tony Blair: Ruler of Gaza? Why the former British leader is suddenly in the frame</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-do-tony-blair-and-gaza-have-in-common/g8v0suayv</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has praised former UK prime minister Tony Blair for his &amp;quot;constructive&amp;quot; involvement in the Middle East.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04dca45c3b0bc9d2797e51f524207c67</guid></item><item><title>What happened to an Australian republic? Why Albanese has quashed the idea</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-happened-to-an-australian-republic-why-albanese-has-quashed-the-idea/3m63klhlc</link><description>The prime minister isn&amp;apos;t willing to risk his renewed political capital by holding another referendum, experts argue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1d6005b4c4ef59821ab79511a433188</guid></item><item><title>Brisbane Broncos light up sharemarket &amp;amp; final budget outcome revealed</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/brisbane-broncos-light-up-sharemarket-final-budget-outcome-revealed/jtv30xpuy</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Stephen Smith from Deloitte Access Economics abut what the government&amp;apos;s final budget outcome says about the economy; plus Kyle Rodda from Capital.com on the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cce80ab9bf1dc2f599d08903abc87361</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Significant discrepancies&amp;apos; found in imported melatonin products, medical regulator warns</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/significant-discrepancies-found-in-imported-melatonin-products-medical-regulator-warns/02rbtheht</link><description>Testing of unregulated melatonin revealed one product contained four times its labelled amount, while another did not have any at all.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00fee4ca907cd1a449f90ec00450ecd0</guid></item><item><title>Here are the travel destinations Australians are heading to this spring</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/where-australians-are-travelling-spring/wkn0xklma</link><description>Many Australians will be heading out of state or the country this spring but cost is proving to be one of the greatest barriers for making plans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b39273b64e7b50dd8d1cc654b0d181b4</guid></item><item><title>First Nations youth train as firefighters to defend Country and Community: &amp;apos;I want to make a difference&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/first-nations-youth-train-as-firefighters-to-defend-country-and-community-i-want-to-make-a-difference/ukq0tojjo</link><description>A group of young First Nations men and women have blazed their way through a training program for firefighter hopefuls. The initiative is a partnership between TAFE and the New South Wales Fire Service - to help young Indigenous people get into their dream job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3e21a5cf1f002e079ee9fe791d04cc6</guid></item><item><title>Natural disasters are growing; could an army of young volunteers help?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/natural-disasters-are-growing-could-an-army-of-young-volunteers-help/nv2fml0m7</link><description>Could a &amp;apos;Climate Army&amp;apos; of young volunteers bolster Australia&amp;apos;s capability to cope with natural disasters? That&amp;apos;s the question before a Senate inquiry looking at proposals for a new national scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4012959b048ebd549cdba64bd93b0dc3</guid></item><item><title>Dozens killed as Typhoon Bualoi batters Vietnam and Philippines</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/typhoon-bualoi-kills-dozens-in-vietnam-and-philippines/zgrii0crt</link><description>In Vietnam, Bualoi made landfall as a typhoon late on Sunday, generating winds of 130 kmh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">294bb33600199b981f46222561e08fce</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;They destroy lives&amp;apos;: How property investors lost millions to a failed housing scheme</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/these-investors-lost-millions-to-failed-sda-housing-scheme/zid4j9ewc</link><description>A group of Iranians were told that investing in Australian specialist disability accommodation would be as safe as houses. However, those plans never eventuated, and they&amp;apos;ve collectively lost $1,178,500.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53300a3f9b334dcbc924a094f88a0858</guid></item><item><title>Spouses for sale: Inside the black market for skilled visa applications</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/spouses-for-sale-inside-the-black-market-for-skilled-visa-applications/hrvnc37nc</link><description>SBS has uncovered a black market operating on apps targeting members of the Chinese community, selling places for &amp;quot;spouses&amp;quot; in permanent residency skilled visa applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e7a77bd82514e11385471ec271d5e9a</guid></item><item><title>Australia supports Trump&amp;apos;s 20-point Gaza peace plan backed by Israel</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-and-netanyahu-agree-to-a-20-point-peace-plan-for-gaza/zr7diqq2v</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said the country &amp;quot;welcomes President Trump&amp;apos;s plan to bring peace to Gaza after almost two years of conflict and a devastating loss of civilian life&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a28a611ca688d8f736a030859da3838</guid></item><item><title>Vital role of translators celebrated amid AI challenge</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/vital-role-of-translators-celebrated-amid-ai-challenge/maplcq05e</link><description>It&amp;apos;s been eight years since the United Nations first recognised International Translation Day. The celebration falls on 30 September and recognises the work of language professionals who foster cultural understanding, connection and social cohesion. But some translators and interpreters in Australia believe more needs to be done to protect the workforce and bridge language barriers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cca7c253dab026db32408cdd3090946b</guid></item><item><title>Albanese invites Arab &amp;apos;hypermarket&amp;apos; to compete with Coles and Woolworths</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-courts-middle-eastern-supermarket-giant/fr23o8co1</link><description>As Australia grapples with a supermarket monopoly, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese hopes the expansion of this Emirati &amp;quot;hypermarket&amp;quot; might bring in some competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">502127dd08d1fa8a44e6a84c3eb9bf1e</guid></item><item><title>JK Rowling lashes out at &amp;apos;ignorant&amp;apos; Emma Watson over trans rights row</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jk-rowling-lashes-out-at-ignorant-emma-watson-over-trans-rights-row/7mfsc04k8</link><description>The author criticised the Harry Potter star, who said in a recent interview that she can still love people with whom she disagrees.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9cddc0932c3c40cc4c80043d07de74a</guid></item><item><title>The country under internet blackout after cables cut over &amp;apos;vice&amp;apos; and immorality</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/afghanistan-internet-blackout-after-taliban-cuts-internet/1rtgkw8ml</link><description>The country is experiencing a total connectivity blackout, according to Netblocks, the internet watchdog.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6a8f0fb944db9d6d6c77d60aea23d4c5</guid></item><item><title>SBS News In Easy English 30 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-30-september-2025/jdhualamn</link><description>A daily 5 minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2b9a3cdb73d968e31be53f8812b1113</guid></item><item><title>Not the outcome Australians wanted, Chalmers says, as Reserve Bank holds cash rate</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rba-decision-cash-rate/nwdfe3zp2</link><description>The Reserve Bank of Australia board was widely tipped to hold the cash rate after inflation data showed successive rises.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edcaa0ba558c5d68fd1ac4541a30ade9</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Disappointing&amp;apos;: Critics say Riyadh Comedy Festival has an unfunny human rights problem</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/saudi-arabia-riyadh-comedy-festival-backlash/hw44zsdc5</link><description>Comedy heavyweights including Dave Chappelle, Jimmy Carr and Louis CK are on the bill of the Riyadh Comedy Festival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">832467142398885fd15650d23814716f</guid></item><item><title>Middle East peace talks: US, Israel propose plan as Hamas weighs response</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/middle-east-peace-talks-us-israel-propose-plan-as-hamas-weighs-response/s7rwdloq8</link><description>Israel and the United States have agreed to a plan for ending the war in Gaza. But both US President Donald Trump and Israel&amp;apos;s Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu have indicated if Hamas rejects the plan, the militant group will face the consequences. Hamas says it is reviewing the proposals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46ad4bd03bef4b55c7348587b34a360a</guid></item><item><title>New guidelines developed for helping people with dementia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-guidelines-developed-for-helping-people-with-dementia/03ev9eyth</link><description>A framework has been developed to track and improve the treatment options for dementia patients in aged care. The proposal come after the Australian Institute of Health and Welfare named dementia as the leading cause of death in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ea802cc61d8b0ad130cb82dc87abdef</guid></item><item><title>Key questions around the &amp;apos;tone deaf, very tricky&amp;apos; Trump-Netanyahu Gaza peace plan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-plan-for-gaza-peace-between-hamas-and-israel-explained/wmzir1eb0</link><description>A United States proposal for peace in Gaza has received endorsement from Israel and the Palestinian Authority, but its long-term success is on a knife-edge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa41b708580e8539fd7d807386cc3d99</guid></item><item><title>The PM&amp;apos;s new supermarket proposal might cut your bills, but it&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;no silver bullet&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-the-pms-new-supermarket-proposal-might-cut-your-grocery-bill-but-its-no-silver-bullet/mdb5fp6k9</link><description>The prime minister needs to consider preconditions, such as space and a break-up of Coles and Woolworths, if he wants a competing supermarket to thrive and bring down prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fd78e743146c58f35bc9919d9bf8008</guid></item><item><title>Optus faces backlash over triple-zero failures, with calls for consequences</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/optus-faces-backlash-over-triple-zero-failures-with-calls-for-consequences/fk52tw1of</link><description>A meeting between Communications Minister Anika Wells and leaders from Optus and its parent company, Singtel, has yielded little new information or action. It comes as calls for stronger consequences grow in the wake of multiple triple-zero failures that have been linked to deaths. Critics say there&amp;apos;s more the minister could be doing right now to restore public trust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0036491d85440f57d28325ad47e4778e</guid></item><item><title>RBA holds fire; energy stock sell-off</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/rba-holds-fire-energy-stock-sell-off/lsl4zdbqb</link><description>Despite solid gains by the gold miners, a sell-off in energy stocks – fuelled by a continued decline in oil prices – has dragged the Australian sharemarket. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Jonathan Shead, Head of Investment at State Street Investment Management. Plus, the Reserve Bank left interest rates unchanged at 3.6 percent, as expected, at its September board meeting. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Pradeep Philip from Deloitte Access Economics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0550cd1a89a7d892e7859770c95814b</guid></item><item><title>Decision to allow registered nurses to prescribe medicines solves many health service problems</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/decision-to-allow-registered-nurses-to-prescribe-medicines-solves-many-health-service-problems/jmvjlk8bw</link><description>Tens of thousands of registered nurses across the country will be able to up-skill to prescribe medications usually authorised by a doctor. It&amp;apos;s a reform that could change the medical landscape in Australia... and the lives of many patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93ace09bc523bf1c9d83859ab2095c04</guid></item><item><title>Pizza, porn, and getting high: Inside the grip of a severe tech addiction</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/how-talking-in-online-chat-rooms-as-a-teen-changed-quentins-life-as-an-adult/dl6a804ch</link><description>Technology seems a non-negotiable part of everyday life. For Quentin, it became an addiction. After years of trying different ways to break free, it was a 12-step program that helped her into recovery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">021ecadbbe87617c73bac0a51ff36a19</guid></item><item><title>Fast entry or backwards step? What Labor&amp;apos;s new housing scheme means for you</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fast-entry-or-backwards-step-what-the-new-5-per-cent-deposit-scheme-means-for-you/l7zi865te</link><description>Analysis shows the government&amp;apos;s new First Home Guarantee scheme could slash years off savings times — but experts warn it could come at a cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fcc072a72eed8694761788337fdaa92</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Invasion from within&amp;apos;: Trump says US cities should be used as military training grounds</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-says-us-cities-should-be-used-as-military-training-grounds/ffy33gfnx</link><description>Donald Trump said that under his administration, the US military was now &amp;quot;reawakening the warrior spirit&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">035d75333244af17f26d03f4b5df62bb</guid></item><item><title>Nicole Kidman files for divorce from Keith Urban, citing &amp;apos;irreconcilable differences&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nicole-kidman-files-for-divorce-from-keith-urban-after-19-years-of-marriage/cg9evz0sz</link><description>Oscar-winning star Nicole Kidman and Grammy-winning country musician Keith Urban had been living apart for some time, according to US media reports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45ab256f4fbe8908a59896353472c35f</guid></item><item><title>SPF slip-ups: More sunscreens withdrawn as TGA finds claims don&amp;apos;t stack up</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tga-says-more-sunscreens-are-failing-to-meet-spf-rating/u7ietpzcd</link><description>The Therapeutic Goods Administration has announced 21 more sunscreen products, all linked to the same base formulation, are under review after failing to provide the SPF protection they advertise.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3db777d98eed00f19c3a2c2f7485f6cc</guid></item><item><title>A new push for peace: What part did Australia play in the 20-point plan for Gaza?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-pumps-up-a-gaza-peace-plan-so-did-australia-play-a-part/ono1izwo7</link><description>Anthony Albanese&amp;apos;s stopover in the Middle East came after more lengthy engagements in the US — for the leaders&amp;apos; week at the United Nations — and the UK.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4af1490419d8f3bce1c855eaedc7c881</guid></item><item><title>A new push for peace: What part did Australia play in the 20-point plan for Gaza?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-part-did-australia-play-in-the-20-point-plan-for-gaza/ono1izwo7</link><description>Anthony Albanese&amp;apos;s stopover in the Middle East came after more lengthy engagements in the US — for the leaders&amp;apos; week at the United Nations — and the UK.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d53efcac4bd727814c78b8c53dbf7535</guid></item><item><title>New move in latest Optus triple-zero failure, as Albanese says it &amp;apos;failed customers&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/optus-triple-zero-failure-anthony-albanese/ofzfap6d5</link><description>Anthony Albanese says Optus has &amp;quot;failed&amp;quot; its customers and has called for the company to &amp;quot;be transparent&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f90ac348c4616a3ef3d92b1f698e094a</guid></item><item><title>The US government has shut down. What happens now?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-to-know-about-the-us-government-shutdown/ipl8gg8s0</link><description>The US government has entered a shutdown, meaning thousands of federal employees are being placed on leave or asked to work without pay until the government reopens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3d73438cbd8bfd61429a238bb9c93d1</guid></item><item><title>Albanese &amp;apos;concerned&amp;apos; over China&amp;apos;s reported BHP iron ore ban</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anthony-albanese-concerned-over-chinas-reported-bhp-iron-ore-ban/y9hjt8lcs</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese hopes a pricing dispute between China and the Australian mining giant will be resolved &amp;quot;very quickly&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ad1be6d97a325f8eebc4ca2935f9884</guid></item><item><title>Hamas, Qatar review peace deal as global reaction remains mixed</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/hamas-qatar-review-peace-deal-as-global-reaction-remains-mixed/9bozgpjon</link><description>The United Nations has welcomed the US-led peace plan in achieving a ceasefire to end a nearly two-year war for Gaza and the region. But internationally, the plan continues to receive mixed reactions, as Hamas and Qatar mediators review the deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07d15efb78340f01f80a6e3a114d590d</guid></item><item><title>SBS News In Easy English 1 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-1-october-2025/og0ij6kg9</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">634c7c07679bc14f068964ced9de631f</guid></item><item><title>Democrats take aim at &amp;apos;erratic and unhinged&amp;apos; Trump as US government shuts down</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/democrats-take-aim-at-erratic-and-unhinged-trump-as-us-government-shuts-down/bs6u23hx4</link><description>The White House, meanwhile, has blamed the Democrats for the shutdown, which has healthcare as a key sticking point.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53d05d86d53f4ee45392496efc27f101</guid></item><item><title>Magnitude-6.9 earthquake kills more than 70 people in the Philippines</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/philippines-6-9-magniture-earthquake-kills-at-least-60/eexymigxd</link><description>The quake, which struck off the central island of Cebu, was the country&amp;apos;s deadliest in more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77b052b3a82d21bd7b5ba439b5f17230</guid></item><item><title>It happened &amp;apos;by accident&amp;apos;, but Mark is helping tackle a $2.7bn Australian problem</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-in-a-loneliness-crisis-research-suggests/ut4p7mu9o</link><description>Loneliness among men has been described as a &amp;quot;crisis&amp;quot; in Australia, and its estimated to cost the health system billions each year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edb259298a6eaedb69908518aa23d266</guid></item><item><title>BHP-China iron ore stand-off; house prices continue to rise</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/bhp-china-iron-ore-stand-off-house-prices-continue-to-rise/zflasuw75</link><description>The Australian sharemarket has fallen flat, as investors react to the US government shutdown and reports of China temporarily banning purchases of BHP’s iron ore. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Niv Dagan from Peak Asset Management. Plus, Australian house prices continue to rise, as the Albanese Government’s Home Guarantee scheme is expanded to all first home buyers. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Tim Lawless, Asia-Pacific research director at Cotality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70dcf961fdca3dd7adda15e950311621</guid></item><item><title>A new First Nations voice to guide Australia&amp;apos;s public health sector</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-new-first-nations-voice-to-guide-australias-public-health-sector/tqvwcecqm</link><description>The Public Health Association of Australia has announced they will be establishing an Aboriginal and Torres-Strait Islander voice to help guide their work after a near unanimous vote by their members. Nearly two years after the failed referendum saw a First Nations voice to parliament shot down, NGOs like the PHAA and state governments have chosen to follow the wishes of the majority of Indigenous communities in Australia who voted for this special representation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8949dfecda1f4bb674fc5069c318ac17</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: What does the US shutdown mean in practice?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-what-does-the-us-shutdown-mean-in-practice/5bxj2lx2k</link><description>The U.S. federal government has entered a shutdown, a few hours after the U.S. Senate failed to pass a short-term spending bill on Tuesday night US East Coast time. It&amp;apos;s the first government shutdown in nearly seven years. The last and also the longest federal government shutdown occurred from late 2018 to early 2019 during President Trump&amp;apos;s first term when Democrats opposed funding the U.S.-Mexico border wall. The result was a shutdown lasting over five weeks, during which some 800,000 federal employees were forced to work without pay or take unpaid leave. Hundreds of thousands of federal employees will be forced to take unpaid leave this time too, with some public services potentially suspended or delayed, and the release of economic data possibly impacted as well. Bruce Wolpe is a senior fellow at the University of Sydney&amp;apos;s United States Studies Centre and has served on the Democratic staff in the US Congress. He&amp;apos;s been speaking to SBS&amp;apos;s Virginia Langeberg about the impact of the shutdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43aabe12548320f0c34d8f8378765ad2</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;No more signs of life&amp;apos;: Dozens remain missing after Indonesian school collapse</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/91-children-still-missing-after-indonesian-school-building-collapse/l4aps5xg5</link><description>After days of rescue operations, 59 people were still feared buried under the rubble after at least five people had been confirmed dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10c1787f60aefe5ecf75c329a17da7a8</guid></item><item><title>Is your sunscreen safe? What to know amid Australia&amp;apos;s SPF ratings storm</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-sunscreen-tga-recall-explainer/rz9nt85bm</link><description>Eighteen sunscreens have either been recalled or had their sale paused in Australia. Here&amp;apos;s what you need to know as the weather gets warmer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39b79060ee7e02aaab39b3a367f61d50</guid></item><item><title>In a battle to build, these five charts show Labor&amp;apos;s housing headache</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-two-year-question-in-labors-housing-battle/ji1yydwv5</link><description>There are doubts major inroads into Australia&amp;apos;s housing supply problem can be made in a couple of years and questions over the government&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;ambitious&amp;quot; 2029 target. So, what can be done?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da71e36dd57187d50283b30ed59ba3a0</guid></item><item><title>I started feeling sick making lunch — and never could&amp;apos;ve expected what came next</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/i-called-triple-zero-after-my-smartwatch-showed-something-unusual-it-saved-my-life/x26zfaffp</link><description>Corinne Laurent doesn’t believe she would still be alive if not for her smartwatch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02ca9d26e84779f88d214d4b0e3afbbd</guid></item><item><title>Jane Goodall, pioneering scientist and conservationist, dies at 91</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jane-goodall-pioneering-scientist-activist-death/9q2d3od1b</link><description>The primatologist drew the public into the wild with her groundbreaking research, later shifting to climate advocacy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f14e6e3cb3afec0f1aef8e03edd679b5</guid></item><item><title>Wildlife advocate and primate expert Jane Goodall dies at 91</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/wildlife-advocate-and-primate-expert-jane-goodall-dies-at-91/i6ec7swnj</link><description>The renowned conservationist, scientist, and global activist Jane Goodall has died at the age of 91. The Jane Goodall Institute announced the primatologist&amp;apos;s death of natural causes on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">543c18495ebcda15eb2c82d8aec941e4</guid></item><item><title>See the full list: The biggest Australian companies paying the least tax</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/see-the-full-list-the-biggest-australian-companies-paying-the-least-tax/kdgh1o7wg</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s largest companies paid $95.7 billion in taxes, with those paying zero dropping to an 11-year low.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fe1d3fada847653e05eca180847932d</guid></item><item><title>Erin Patterson to appeal murder convictions over deadly mushroom lunch, lawyer says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/erin-patterson-to-appeal-her-murder-convictions-lawyer-says/z2xwf8csp</link><description>Patterson&amp;apos;s legal team will have 28 days to lodge the relevant paperwork before a court considers whether to approve the appeal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b4e706a8e3abe3f9da7385548a14cf5</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 2nd October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-2nd-october-2025/98pmdmae7</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2960dd08a4922185aa54540a6215bbed</guid></item><item><title>Albanese welcomes PNG&amp;apos;s decision to sign landmark defence pact</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-png-defence-pact-gets-green-light-following-cabinet-delay/nt085b3mc</link><description>The pact will elevate the Pacific partnership, ensuring an attack on one would be a &amp;quot;danger to the peace and security of both countries&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a92f04b61fa6d04c67d70b78d7e9ba4d</guid></item><item><title>Albanese welcomes PNG&amp;apos;s decision to sign landmark defence pact</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-welcomes-pngs-decision-to-sign-landmark-defence-pact/nt085b3mc</link><description>The pact will elevate the Pacific partnership, ensuring an attack on one would be a &amp;quot;danger to the peace and security of both countries&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d26cacb840ff16f519299547599c3165</guid></item><item><title>Animal shelter accused of having &amp;apos;blood on its hands&amp;apos; after euthanising 12-week-old puppy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/blood-on-their-hands-row-erupts-over-lost-dogs-homes-puppy-euthanasia-decision/x1ndqdphz</link><description>A couple who had fostered the dog, Murphy, had called Victoria&amp;apos;s Lost Dogs Home to ask how he was going, only to be told he would be put down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cae637382778e0ba4c6cc697d819a617</guid></item><item><title>Australian men face loneliness crisis: what’s driving it and how to fix it</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australian-men-face-loneliness-crisis-whats-driving-it-and-how-to-fix-it/k47gy4q99</link><description>Loneliness among men has been described as a &amp;quot;crisis&amp;quot; in Australia, and it appears to be on the rise. This social isolation can not only hurt mens mental health and overall wellbeing, it is also costing the Australian economy billions of dollars. A recent Australian study could hold the answer as to why men appear to be stuggling more with loneliness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2699cdf7843c4ff11fd65a92f917da1b</guid></item><item><title>Gaza peace plan, US shuts down &amp;amp; China combats whingers</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gaza-peace-plan-us-shuts-down-china-combats-whingers/sy8wo6r3a</link><description>A new 20-point plan for peace in Gaza gains support among the international community. Trump warns the US military of the enemy from within as Hegseth tells Generals to slim down for the war on woke. Plus, Democrats and Republicans point the finger at each other as the US government shuts down. Also, Moscow warns of a new red line in the war in Ukraine. And, China launches a campaign to stamp out online negativity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cae9b3556147066c2d14b3ea166cca48</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Israeli forces take action against flotilla trying to deliver aid</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-israeli-forces-take-action-against-flotilla-trying-to-deliver-aid/pnvgmh51q</link><description>Israeli military personnel have intercepted an international flotilla trying to deliver medicine and food to Gaza and boarded its boats as it approached the area. The Global Sumud Flotilla consists of more than 40 civilian boats carrying about 500 parliamentarians, lawyers and activists including Swedish climate campaigner Greta Thunberg. The organisers say they are trying to break Israel&amp;apos;s blockade of Gaza, despite repeated warnings from Israel to turn back. The United Nations last month ruled that Israel had committed genocide in Gaza, a claim Israel denies. Israel has imposed a naval blockade on Gaza since Hamas took control of the coastal enclave in 2007 and they claim it is a legal part of the action they are taking against Hamas. They&amp;apos;ve accused the flotilla of having connections to Hamas - which the organisers strongly deny, while other critics accuse them of grandstanding. Judy Patterson&amp;apos;s son, Hamish, is the captain of the Wahoo, one of the ships taking part in the action, and she spoke to SBS&amp;apos;s Tee Mitchell.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fc72ddbc50eebbb6ffe2fe1950cb84e</guid></item><item><title>Nuclear energy sank the Coalition at the election — can it power their comeback?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nuclear-energy-sank-the-coalition-at-the-election-can-it-power-their-comeback/eqd6mzqsd</link><description>The coalition are revamping their proposal for nuclear energy, despite suffering an election loss with this policy. The details are yet to be confirmed, but the Opposition Energy Minister says they will adapt their plan to meet developments in the space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce95ff0c869a7707f7ba7c89bf33d0ea</guid></item><item><title>NIMBYs, YIMBYs — and BIMBYs: The new group in Australia&amp;apos;s housing stoush</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/yimbys-nimbys-and-bimbys-in-australias-housing-stoush/684pjcwmn</link><description>As state governments roll out plans to battle Australia&amp;apos;s housing crisis, community groups are mobilising to have a say in how their suburbs are — or are not — changed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac71bb540a7137e724f30e60564c8b9e</guid></item><item><title>ASX rallies despite US government shutdown</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asx-rallies-despite-us-government-shutdown/ln743tnhv</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Callam Pickering about the latest household spending data and what it means for interest rates, plus Henry Jennings from Marcus Today on the days market action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1c37f8b542f20920bc0294ef6e85ada</guid></item><item><title>UK police name Jewish men killed in Manchester synagogue attack</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/four-people-injured-in-car-and-stabbing-attack-at-a-synagogue-in-manchester/hssm6j2ng</link><description>Three others were injured in the attack, which took place on Yom Kippur, the most sacred day of the Jewish calendar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c83a33d1dfa04e1a9a5508867f0d09ca</guid></item><item><title>Police say they &amp;apos;will not rest&amp;apos; despite scaling back search for boy missing in outback</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/they-just-dont-disappear-into-thin-air-hopes-fading-for-boy-missing-in-south-australian-outback/hhegfsq12</link><description>No significant evidence was found to indicate where Gus may have gone during the massive search involving police, defence force personnel and large numbers of volunteers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e77e1a1ad583bb9fcdf9b59eba347a7</guid></item><item><title>Why experts are &amp;apos;rewriting&amp;apos; Australia&amp;apos;s bushfire risk this summer</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-experts-are-rewriting-australias-bushfire-risk-this-summer/cm2ns4rb1</link><description>Unusual weather patterns and climate change are raising concerns for parts of Australia, as well as popular travel destinations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74b84ba4c6053b03df899ae3bf840b38</guid></item><item><title>New trick Australians are using to &amp;apos;maximise&amp;apos; tax returns — but beware of the risks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-turning-to-ai-to-maximise-tax-returns-research-suggests/cxv17n2n4</link><description>It might be free to use and readily available, but it could also be giving incorrect advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18fb8425575513f0bd3949ff904ed080</guid></item><item><title>Israel says more than 400 people detained from Gaza aid flotilla, will start deportations</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-gaza-global-sumud-flotilla-detention/vywvutrbu</link><description>Six Australians are among those Israeli forces detained after they intercepted several vessels that had been bound for Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a194a9402a557a6dfafccb3330e6cf32</guid></item><item><title>UK government promises greater security for Jewish community after deadly synagogue attack in Manchester</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/uk-government-promises-greater-security-for-jewish-community-after-deadly-synagogue-attack-in-manchester/bdghdduln</link><description>A WARNING THAT THE FOLLOWING STORY CONTAINS CONTENT THAT MAY BE DISTRESSING FOR SOME LISTENERS Two people have been killed and three others seriously hurt after an assailant drove a car into pedestrians and stabbed a security guard near a synagogue in Manchester in northern England. Greater Manchester Police say officers shot and killed the suspect, who investigators say attacked just as Jewish communities around the world mark Yom Kippur, the holiest holiday in the Jewish calendar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78e356f2781e4148efa5ab88aa031d58</guid></item><item><title>Federal government seeks answers over Australians on intercepted Gaza flotilla</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/questions-over-detained-australians-as-protests-erupt-after-gaza-flotilla-intercepted/qm8hlecou</link><description>Embassy staff in Tel Aviv were travelling to Ktzi&amp;apos;ot — a detention centre in Israel&amp;apos;s south — to provide consular assistance to any detained Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07e836b8a9b12f033bf6edef1193d99d</guid></item><item><title>What we know so far as Donald Trump&amp;apos;s Gaza deal deadline approaches</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-gaza-deal-deadline/cmnz7f3m2</link><description>US President Donald Trump has warned Hamas will &amp;quot;pay in hell&amp;quot; if they don&amp;apos;t agree to the ceasefire plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6316f6a79bbae42dc6229f491e3b963</guid></item><item><title>Court rules on appeal for underworld figure Tony Mokbel</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tony-mokbel-appeal-drug-conviction/1s3lebafp</link><description>Three judges overturned two of the 60-year-old&amp;apos;s convictions, but he must face a retrial in one of them, while an appeal of a third conviction was dismissed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db11e5f155bf9e62b78a1dee668bbdd4</guid></item><item><title>Organisers vow to fight police bid to stop pro-Palestinian Opera House rally</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nsw-police-to-fight-pro-palestine-protesters-march-to-sydney-opera-house/9wu8ucyud</link><description>Organisers said banning the rally would violate fundamental rights and set a &amp;quot;dangerous precedent&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a54fc1c86a081a687594ef8d2860c119</guid></item><item><title>What is the Global Sumud Flotilla - and why has Israel intercepted it?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/what-is-the-global-sumud-flotilla-and-why-has-israel-intercepted-it/zj4jw42vi</link><description>Israeli naval forces have intercepted the Global Sumud Flotilla, seizing more than 40 civilian boats and hundreds of activists - including Australians. The action has sparked global protests and condemnation, with Israel saying it is necessary for its own security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c69b95d6469a538fd67e1752dcdbd87b</guid></item><item><title>New twist in &amp;apos;offensive&amp;apos; pamphlet saga targeting teal MP Allegra Spender</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/new-twist-in-offensive-pamphlet-saga-targeting-teal-mp-allegra-spender/634jez0un</link><description>Legal action follows an investigation by the electoral watchdog into allegedly unauthorised pamphlets targeting the independent MP that she had said were part of a campaign of &amp;quot;dirty tricks&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f41bd9dd226c3d6871f0a96dffbbb75</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 3 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-3-october-2025/yloxqghu5</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">768b0278ce23523b8b3fabba58bc3ec3</guid></item><item><title>Footy, culture, and so much more: welcome to the Koori knockout</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/footy-culture-and-so-much-more-welcome-to-the-koori-knockout/ardx4qeqz</link><description>This weekend will see the largest annual gathering of Indigenous people in the country at the New South Wales Koori knockout rugby league tournament. It&amp;apos;s a sporting competition... but also, so much more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1aa459fcf3b03e862c3e2aed8b15fe8e</guid></item><item><title>Forwards or backwards? Daylight saving starts soon — here&amp;apos;s what to know</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/when-daylight-saving-time-starts-in-australia-in-2025/67t60uuqb</link><description>Here&amp;apos;s everything you need to know, including tips on how to adjust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f095370d70d3af25e324360142a0835</guid></item><item><title>Man dead and teenager in critical condition after helicopter crash in Sydney</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/man-dead-and-teenager-in-critical-condition-after-helicopter-crash-in-sydney/y1c2ebjkb</link><description>The crash occurred at Bankstown in Sydney&amp;apos;s south-west about 1.30pm on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2cfbdcc3e6327379670445b745d05998</guid></item><item><title>Police, protesters face court over planned march | Evening News Bulletin 3 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/police-protesters-face-court-over-planned-march-evening-news-bulletin-3-october-2025/c3kyl58wv</link><description>In this bulletin, police and activists in court over pro Palestine protests in Sydney next weekend, flights grounded as drones seen around Munich airport. And in Rugby League, fans are treated to a show ahead of the grand final, when the Broncos and Storm face off.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08078281b9d12e869cd86ea3139aea08</guid></item><item><title>When do the 2025 NRL and NRLW grand finals start? Here&amp;apos;s everything you need to know</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/everything-you-need-to-know-about-the-2025-nrl-and-nrlw-grand-finals/fdj88sefp</link><description>It will be a busy day of footy on Sunday with both the NRL and NRLW grand finals taking place. Here&amp;apos;s what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fe5d29943173b248b1456c4d6606b02f</guid></item><item><title>When do the 2025 NRL and NRLW grand finals start? Here&amp;apos;s everything you need to know</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/when-do-the-2025-nrl-and-nrlw-grand-finals-start/fdj88sefp</link><description>It will be a busy day of footy on Sunday with both the NRL and NRLW grand finals taking place. Here&amp;apos;s what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46d15fe9fc47865d6df86970a318c2c9</guid></item><item><title>Oil prices tumble to 4 month low as ASX edges closer to record high</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/oil-prices-tumble-to-4-month-low-as-asx-edges-closer-to-record-high/ee4eoyhss</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Dianne Colledge from Morgans Financial Limited about the days sharemarket action including the opportunites for investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa53c66df7caad74aee6a6f6ac9017d0</guid></item><item><title>How the Dezi Freeman search could wind down — and how major Australian manhunts ended</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dezi-freeman-police-manhunt/h9o270lc9</link><description>While the operation to find Dezi Freeman is the biggest manhunt in Australia to date in terms of resources, it is far from the longest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3acb245cf6e9c9d2be5a7aeff339c82</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;No evidence&amp;apos; blueberries unsafe to eat, watchdogs say, after banned pesticide concerns</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/no-evidence-blueberries-unsafe-to-eat-watchdogs-say/39tc8g2za</link><description>The berry industry welcomed the finding, with a key figure saying it was &amp;quot;devastating&amp;quot; to have been &amp;quot;wrongfully targeted&amp;quot;. The researcher who raised the concerns says that wasn&amp;apos;t her intention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb95552da5a847a9c3d7b8e9a05dd541</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie quits Liberal front bench over immigration row</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/andrew-hastie-quits-liberal-front-bench-over-immigration-row/ykj28wrv4</link><description>His exit comes after he publicly pushed for net-zero emissions goals to be dropped and migration to be curbed, as well as touting himself as a future leadership aspirant.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4a989416706104d091ce92b07ca3ad6</guid></item><item><title>Andrew Hastie quits Liberal frontbench | Morning News Bulletin 4 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/andrew-hastie-quits-liberal-frontbench-morning-news-bulletin-4-october-2025/vqcjn0wg6</link><description>Andrew Hastie quits the Coalition frontbench; Australia still in the dark after several citizens detained by Israel; And in sport, Australia bats first against New Zealand in second Twenty20 International.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd1120205893618da7b86ca9a350447c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The 99 per cent are not your enemy&amp;apos;: Genesis Owusu on power, politics and racism</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/some-things-need-to-be-said-genesis-owusu-on-speaking-truth-in-a-divided-world/vnmtwxihp</link><description>Genesis Owusu has battled racism, depression and industry pressures — but his third album is his most direct yet. He says it’s a blunt call for truth in an era of division.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d57c833150ae3b366294ff78e399fa4</guid></item><item><title>700 Australians were recruited for a yoga study. What researchers found surprised them</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/yoga-study-older-people-falls/s4gqz30zo</link><description>Many older Australians who practice yoga say it gives them strength and confidence, but a new study suggests one particular type of yoga could be associated with a higher risk of falls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">766326cb3fadeacdbd152085fa484ad8</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Could a First Nations voice help tackle stubborn public health challenges?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-could-a-first-nations-voice-help-tackle-stubborn-public-health-challenges/9o1r5o95q</link><description>Nearly two years after the failed referendum saw a First Nations voice to parliament shot down, some NGOs and state governments have been taking the initiative to follow the wishes of the majority of Indigenous communities in Australia who voted for this special representation. Australia&amp;apos;s principal non-government organisation for public health, the Public Health Association of Australia, has announced they will be instituting an Aboriginal and Torres-Strait Islander voice to help guide their work after a near unanimous vote by their members. SBS spoke to Dr Summer May Finlay, a Yorta Yorta woman, an Associate Professor at the University of Wollongong and the Vice President (Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander) of the Public Health Association about the importance of a First Nations voice in helping to Close the Gap on healthcare outcomes between Indigenous and non-Indigenous Australians</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b72abcb3c66a7c1aa036143c6a6ed3c</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Everyone loves a ghost train: but why do we love being scared?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-everyone-loves-a-ghost-train-but-why-do-we-love-being-scared/u32c8730l</link><description>Scary movies, haunted houses and trick or treating, October is the unofficial start to “spooky season” - at least, that&amp;apos;s what you would think judging by what&amp;apos;s on the shelves in our local shops. Sarah Kollat, teaching professor of psychology at Penn State University in the US, says there are lots of reasons people like to be scared. At a chemical level, our brains and bodies are reacting to the jump scares in a movie and “surviving” a haunted house. But psychologists also say getting scared in a safe environment prepares us for real danger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80dd3f386e756d22769ecab32573d2e2</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Violent night&amp;apos; of strikes in Gaza reported despite Trump&amp;apos;s order for Israel to &amp;apos;immediately&amp;apos; stop</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/strikes-reported-despite-hamas-agrees-to-release-all-israeli-hostages/4rbbvz4dl</link><description>The Gaza Civil Defence Agency reported &amp;quot;a very violent night&amp;quot; of Israeli strikes in Gaza after US President Donald Trump ordered Israel to &amp;quot;immediately&amp;quot; stop its attacks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">768d37a44ca8866c2b2dedef23b98602</guid></item><item><title>Sean &amp;apos;Diddy&amp;apos; Combs sentenced to more than four years in prison</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sean-diddy-combs-sentenced-to-more-than-four-years-in-prison/xiexv549b</link><description>In an address to the court before the US district judge imposed the sentence, Combs apologised to his victims, saying his behaviour was &amp;quot;disgusting, shameful and sick.&amp;quot;</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc248fd5727bdb742439352bb036e752</guid></item><item><title>Hamas signals partial acceptance of US Gaza peace plan | Midday News Bulletin 4 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/hamas-signals-partial-acceptance-of-us-gaza-peace-plan-midday-news-bulletin-4-october-2025/4jtgqfqrv</link><description>Hamas signals partial acceptance of US Gaza peace plan; DFAT confirms consular help for Australians detained over Gaza aid flotilla; And in golf, Cameron Percy storms to three-shot lead in Jacksonville.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0124018bf6664b8a640ecca80832a208</guid></item><item><title>Manchester synagogue victim accidentally shot, police say, as attacker identified</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/manchester-synagogue-victim-accidentally-shot-police-say-as-attacker-identified/ffm37qrfb</link><description>In a fresh statement, Greater Manchester Police says they believe the attacker may have been influenced by &amp;quot;extreme Islamist ideology&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce2053ce4d12e3649a9e24ee5ba468eb</guid></item><item><title>Manchester synagogue victim accidentally shot, police say, as attacker identified</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/manchester-synagogue-attack-victim-accidentally-shot-police-say-as-attacker-identified/ffm37qrfb</link><description>In a fresh statement, Greater Manchester Police says they believe the attacker may have been influenced by &amp;quot;extreme Islamist ideology&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d35c95272223ab42519b7dcd3f5eb43c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I support Sussan&amp;apos;: Andrew Hastie denies resignation about leadership push</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hastie-denies-front-bench-resignation-about-leadership-push/pi37crdxo</link><description>The Liberal MP&amp;apos;s exit from the Opposition front bench comes after he publicly pushed for net-zero emissions goals to be dropped and migration to be curbed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f7e9d38a8369cedf06d79be147c5ed9</guid></item><item><title>Australian officials &amp;apos;on the ground&amp;apos; helping Gaza flotilla activists detained in Israel</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dfat-officials-are-on-the-ground-helping-australian-activists-detained-in-israel/6celmoybe</link><description>The Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade says at least five Australians are detained in Israel, while Global Sumud Flotilla organisers say Israel has seven Australians in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fae0eb32e3a8045cd8675e6eb35dafa2</guid></item><item><title>Evening News Bulletin 4 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/evening-news-bulletin-4-october-2025/xs3qbksqs</link><description>Andrew Hastie explains why he quit the Opposition frontbench, Calls for aid workers detained by Israel to be released, And in rugby league, Melbourne Storm prepare for tomorrow night&amp;apos;s NRL Grand Final against the Brisbane Broncos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc5d425fb05c790659a99c483e6eb124</guid></item><item><title>The major sticking points that could still upend the partially accepted Gaza peace deal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-major-sticking-points-that-could-still-upend-the-partially-accepted-gaza-peace-deal/r1v3u1nn3</link><description>One expert says a hostage-prisoner exchange between Israel and Hamas is &amp;quot;highly likely&amp;quot; to go ahead, but he and others remain wary about the prospects for other parts of a Gaza peace deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eafb2a9b36df924305576090a027935a</guid></item><item><title>Israel continues assault on Gaza despite Trump ceasefire plea | Morning News Bulletin 5 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israel-continues-assault-on-gaza-despite-trump-ceasefire-plea-morning-news-bulletin-5-october-2025/c16uo4oor</link><description>The bodies of two women found in Victoria&amp;apos;s remote alpine region after blizzard conditions; Israel continues assault on Gaza City despite US President Trump&amp;apos;s ceasefire appeal; And in AFL, Premiership forward Brody Mihocek leaves Collingwood for the Melbourne Demons.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73d56b8064df5d42200fafc97a106405</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I passed out multiple times at work&amp;apos;: The health problem costing Australia billions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-health-problem-costing-australia-billions/g3usjolbe</link><description>Endometriosis affects one in seven Australian women, yet experts warn workplaces remain years behind in providing support for those living with this &amp;quot;invisible&amp;quot; condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6dcadce6efd2c049bdf54d58ac15c0d</guid></item><item><title>Why Joel spends his evenings being stabbed in the head with skewers — for fun</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-is-deathmatch-wrestling-and-why-is-it-controversial/nj1sz5e5z</link><description>Blood, thumbtacks, fire, cactus plants and even whipper snippers. Welcome to the world of Australian deathmatch wrestling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f61856630983c73041efd339266439b</guid></item><item><title>Yazidi refugees in Toowoomba find community through hockey</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/yazidi-refugees-in-toowoomba-find-community-through-hockey/j814wa3h1</link><description>The Queensland city of Toowoomba has become home to thousands of Yazidi refugees. A local hockey program is aiming to develop confidence and language skills for this community, with the help of retired locals on the field.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5f81e55f17530c791f21bcf7b4d475a</guid></item><item><title>Smooth Snake slithering its way back to life in the UK</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/smooth-snake-slithering-its-way-back-to-life-in-the-uk/epgsvimyj</link><description>Snakes may be ten a penny here in Australia but in the UK it&amp;apos;s a different story. Britain&amp;apos;s rarest reptile, known as the Smooth Snake, is thriving again after conservation efforts were introduced to save it in 2009. But monitoring exactly how many Smooth Snakes there are can be a challenge due to the reptile&amp;apos;s reclusive nature.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0577ac3c3db7bfe3fe5b9ffc9a5f20b</guid></item><item><title>Netanyahu says he hopes to bring home all hostages from Gaza &amp;apos;in the coming days&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/netanyahu-bring-back-hostages-gaza-peace-deal/j1mxj8dzn</link><description>The Israeli leader vowed that Gaza will be demilitarised and Hamas disarmed, after the militant group partially accepted terms of a peace deal laid out by the White House.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef41c269980b33e46b319ec78f53b131</guid></item><item><title>Location-tracking apps: A harmful invasion of privacy or a great tool to keep loved ones safe?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/location-tracking-apps-a-great-tool-to-keep-loved-ones-safe-or-a-harmful-invasion-of-privacy/isma6nxvo</link><description>With consent, location-tracking can be immensely useful in some situations, experts say, but they warn that the technology is certainly not without potential harms and can lead to controlling and coercive behaviours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a5fa3dd319ea39f2d1f365c795522bf</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Determination and ingenuity&amp;apos;: Australia&amp;apos;s oldest man just turned 112</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australias-oldest-man-celebrates-life/p7v9yud7i</link><description>Ken Weeks was still walking into town for shopping after he turned 100 more than a decade ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bacbbd1941638773676ab40810dfdc13</guid></item><item><title>Mystery surrounds deaths of two hikers in Victoria&amp;apos;s high country</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/mystery-surrounds-deaths-of-two-hikers-in-victorian-high-country/du6a48d1r</link><description>Police have appealed for help to identify two women who were found dead near Mount Bogong on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4a0e1bc265264db20ccff05e5ff0de1</guid></item><item><title>We now know when your HECS debt will be slashed, and by how much</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/millions-of-australians-to-see-their-student-debts-slashed-heres-what-you-need-to-know/jk27nb331</link><description>About three million Australians with a student debt will soon see their balance owed reduced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca91d2f5055b26f7ea83ab864b48208d</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine accuses Russia of drone attack on railway station | Midday News Bulletin 5 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/midday-news-bulletin-5-october-2025/nhaqq1cco</link><description>Ukraine accuses Russia of drone strike hit on railway station; Melissa McIntosh defends Coalition ‘charter letters’ amid shadow cabinet resignations; And in Rugby League, Payne Haas seeks to understand new Broncos coach Michael Maguire’s winning drive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a75f149d3cc6c38a61a98bfdc1e55061</guid></item><item><title>A Thatcher-loving heavy metal drummer: Meet Japan&amp;apos;s first female PM-in-waiting</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/japan-woman-prime-minister-sanae-takaichi/31clccs47</link><description>Sanae Takaichi has repeatedly referred to former UK leader Margaret Thatcher as a source of inspiration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c735d6c116c76970cdae66146c730cd</guid></item><item><title>Trump authorises deployment of 300 national guard troops to Chicago</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-national-guard-troops-chicago/x87t47pvr</link><description>The state&amp;apos;s governor said it was &amp;quot;absolutely outrageous and un-American to demand a governor send military troops within our own borders and against our will&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d37794feb24eaed597e65f51d2396b84</guid></item><item><title>Evening News Bulletin 5 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/evening-news-bulletin-5-october-2025/rcfu4wlq7</link><description>Syrians head to the polls for first election since the fall of Assad regime, Albanese government claims Australia helped lead the way to Gaza peace process, Chelsea beat Liverpool 2-1 to make it three defeats in a row for the reigning Premier League champions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c87fcdb53893efb2f804497251c8ee6</guid></item><item><title>Police warn sovereign citizens are &amp;apos;not above the law&amp;apos; as over 100 firearms seized</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/police-warn-sovereign-citizens-are-not-above-the-law-as-over-100-firearms-seized/nnppwv7dt</link><description>Western Australian authorities have warned that no-one should consider themselves above the law after carrying out a major seizure of guns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08ea09c04f57f90c9c56fb8606466313</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Heartbreaking&amp;apos;: The children Australia won’t bring home from a Syrian detention camp</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-children-australia-wont-bring-home-from-a-syrian-detention-camp/jwnozrffs</link><description>The women and children who recently smuggled themselves out of a Syrian detention camp and returned to Australia proved that the government could bring its citizens home if it had the will, advocates say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4bd65b9a2da97199f0fe974960967c6</guid></item><item><title>Israelis like Michal and Yarden act as &amp;apos;human shields&amp;apos; in the West Bank. They&amp;apos;ve been called traitors</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/israelis-like-michal-and-yarden-act-as-human-shields-in-the-west-bank-theyve-been-called-traitors/il4m5r6gi</link><description>As the second anniversary of October 7 and Israel’s war in Gaza approaches, settler violence in the West Bank is steadily escalating. A small number of Israelis like Yarden want to end the &amp;apos;status quo&amp;apos; — and they&amp;apos;re willing to act as human shields to achieve it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">974283754e15dfcfaddb901970f9ce39</guid></item><item><title>Government summons Optus, Telstra to Canberra over triple-zero failings</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/government-summons-optus-telstra-to-canberra-over-triple-zero-failings/tic2vlzkt</link><description>From 1 November, telcos will be required to provide real-time updates on network failures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1ed9f436ffaf8e337e494512a209a42</guid></item><item><title>Several injured in inner-west Sydney shooting | Morning News Bulletin 6 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/several-injured-in-a-public-shooting-in-inner-west-sydney-morning-news-bulletin-6-october-2025/jnvtyl27t</link><description>A man arrested and several injured after a public shooting in inner-west Sydney; Five killed by Russian air attacks in Ukraine; And in the NRL, the Broncos win the men&amp;apos;s and women&amp;apos;s grand finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57ae84e897a65c7e4d50ddd2595e99e0</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We do not see any change&amp;apos;: Israel pounds Gaza despite Trump&amp;apos;s call for end to bombing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-says-gaza-deal-talks-to-go-on-couple-days-as-rubio-asks-israel-to-stop-bombing/kcyspcgfz</link><description>There was no let-up in Israeli attacks on Gaza over the weekend as planes and tanks pounded areas across the enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49494d7d2fb7fc0e2c5cb09883993f98</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy criticises world &amp;apos;silence&amp;apos; after yet another large-scale Russian attack</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/zelenskyy-criticises-world-silence-after-large-scale-russian-attacks-on-ukraine/0rwbgt2u2</link><description>Five people have died after the Russian military attacked Ukraine overnight with 53 missiles and several waves of drones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">606b8824cc69c840c6e7dcfe55b0aa92</guid></item><item><title>Police charge alleged gunman with 25 offences after Sydney shooting spree</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sydney-croydon-park-inner-west-shooting-bullets-fired/ba3gob1zg</link><description>Numerous bystanders, cars and police were fired on during a two-hour window in Croydon Park on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40ecb8a44f1738fce9a8b85a3199def5</guid></item><item><title>Space monster: gas-guzzling rogue planet eats all in its path</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/space-monster-gas-guzzling-rogue-planet-eats-all-in-its-path/jd175wu8e</link><description>It sounds like the plot of a science fiction movie from the 1950s - a giant rogue planet, moving through the galaxy at a record-breaking speed, consuming vast quantities of dust and gas . But this isn&amp;apos;t the product of the fevered imagination of a Hollywood writer. This lone planet is very real.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfc4848bc0506bfd7161abd10b64d191</guid></item><item><title>It&amp;apos;s on Australia&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;do not travel&amp;apos; list. But influencers are promoting it anyway</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/its-on-australias-do-not-travel-list-influencers-are-promoting-it-anyway/l6ladosss</link><description>A surge of travel vloggers is putting Afghanistan back on the tourism map, even as the Taliban tightens restrictions on women and security risks remain high.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9739ed1e9708b066c8679a8ce0741373</guid></item><item><title>Australia and Papua New Guinea sign defence treaty | Midday News Bulletin 6 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australia-and-papua-new-guinea-sign-defence-treaty-midday-news-bulletin-6-october-2025/rc1crjxm8</link><description>A signing ceremony finalises the defence treaty between Australia and Papua New Guinea, new laws imminent on a triple-zero custodian, Broncos star Reece Walsh reveals how he helped his team overcome Melbourne Storm in the grand final.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1b4ad81c4c0a5bbd8bd54291a2c3999</guid></item><item><title>Gaza ceasefire talks begin in Egypt</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gaza-ceasefire-talks-begin-in-egypt/epo5gncpm</link><description>Talks aimed at implementing US President Donald Trump’s 20-point peace plan for Gaza are set to begin in Cairo, marking what could be the most significant diplomatic push since the conflict began two years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e465a7eda75c8634b5f20a1dee7a607d</guid></item><item><title>The Australians who think it&amp;apos;s fine to steal, and those who disagree</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-retail-theft-survey/b1yrp6vki</link><description>A new survey found a generational divide when it comes to rationalising retail theft behaviours, including scanning items incorrectly at self-checkout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f73afe8aefb91168f2b15b3bcb87181</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 6 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-6-october-2025/22ssjf5lu</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">645ce9f66c6f1ad98a25360b9cd23743</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Equals, mates, and now allies&amp;apos;: What is the new treaty between Australia and PNG?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/pukpuk-treaty-australia-png-defence-pact/snprmvu55</link><description>Australia has signed its first alliance in 70 years. In a battle for Pacific influence, is it a threat to China?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a96a757a06cea19c022013e7239c935</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Undignified&amp;apos;: Albanese criticises Greens leader over Manchester attack comments</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/undignified-albanese-criticises-greens-leader-over-manchester-attack-comments/y63za8lal</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said he watched the interview with the Greens leader, Larissa Waters, and was left &amp;quot;stunned&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a19a6396495d336e002dc87ac044c62e</guid></item><item><title>At least 16 injured after shooting in Sydney&amp;apos;s Inner West | Evening News Bulletin 6 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/at-least-16-injured-after-shooting-in-sydneys-inner-west-evening-news-bulletin-6-october-2025/hvylz7czb</link><description>At least 16 people injured in shooting at Sydney&amp;apos;s inner west, Friend of an Australian activist in Israeli detention claims he&amp;apos;s been physically abused by authorities, Ange Postecoglou under pressure at new Premier League side Nottingham Forest after fifth defeat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6aac85e51907a92dcacf99ae3e9ca49a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;quot;Excitement, then everything changed&amp;quot;: survivors remember October 7 attack as calls grow for end to Gaza war</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/excitement-then-everything-changed-survivors-remember-october-7-attack-as-calls-grow-for-end-to-gaza-war/gcgwne2p3</link><description>Thousands of Australians are joining vigils across the nation to mark the second anniversary of the deadly Hamas attack on Israel. Around 1200 people were killed and 250 taken hostage during the designated terror group&amp;apos;s attack on October 7, 2023, which triggered a brutal military response from Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90e3b1dc68c0fb2458a0b763135949f9</guid></item><item><title>Australian claims dislocated arm from soldiers in prison called Israel&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;worst&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-prison-thunberg-australians-flotilla-ketziot-prison/4k67kxy2j</link><description>Ketziot prison was once called the &amp;quot;largest and the worst&amp;quot; of Israel&amp;apos;s prisons by Human Rights Watch. There are welfare concerns for Australians detained there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3479ab3351f4cc7f88d1ea8e3eb0dcfd</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Manifestly inadequate&amp;apos;: Prosecutors to appeal Erin Patterson&amp;apos;s sentence</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/prosecutors-appealing-erin-patterson-mushroom-murders-sentence/aso8ou568</link><description>The 51-year-old was sentenced to life in prison for the murder of three relatives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f8c554efb5ea2d7d46ee2ca47ba8c60</guid></item><item><title>Gold and copper prices surge and why you shouldn’t ignore your annual super statement</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gold-and-copper-prices-surge-and-why-you-shouldnt-ignore-your-annual-super-statement/ycyf7efc7</link><description>The ASX-200 has started the week in the red, as a tech sell-off offset strong gains by gold and copper miners. Plus, Japanese stocks have hit a record high just a day after the country’s ruling Liberal Democratic Party named Sanae Takaichi as its leader. For more, Rena Sarumpaet spoke with George Boubouras from K2 Asset Management. As annual superannuation statements start to arrive in the mail, Australians are being urged to not ignore them with research from Canstar showing about a fifth of respondents only check their super once every few years - or never. For more on how a financial health check could benefit your nest egg, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Canstar Data Insights Director Sally Tindall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf769f3e207d0282dbc7a810668680f0</guid></item><item><title>France&amp;apos;s new prime minister resigns weeks after his appointment</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/france-prime-minister-resigns/5vwlv0qic</link><description>Sébastien Lecornu said the conditions that would allow him to stay in office were not in place.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f39eaa87cf7de22781fb28827438fe6f</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Fighting a war on two fronts&amp;apos;: Behind the rise of a new threat in Gaza</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hamas-influence-is-waning-in-gaza-palestinians-fear-armed-gangs-more/nz8wiwgfy</link><description>Newly released data shows a major spike in intra-Palestinian violent incidents this year, as well as a significant rise in stolen aid packages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e010bbb46bdb0e33ece03d84dbb1b80a</guid></item><item><title>The unseen impact of missing or damaged teeth — and the key to addressing it</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/unseen-impact-of-dental-issues/qxmy885wl</link><description>Why is it so shameful to have missing teeth or gum disease? And what can we do about it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5c6536419384386081ada9d87c84a61</guid></item><item><title>Reflections on anniversary of October 7 attacks | Morning News Bulletin 7 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/reflections-on-anniversary-of-october-7-attacks-morning-news-bulletin-7-october-2025/b9x5srls1</link><description>Papua New Guinea Prime Minister James Marape hails the new defence treaty with Australia; reflections on the second anniversary of the October 7 attacks; and in rugby league, the Newcastle Yowies win the men&amp;apos;s and women&amp;apos;s major titles at the Koori Knockout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">697a4ade734cdc4dac1cc0e8a0b3dd6e</guid></item><item><title>Australians from Gaza aid flotilla deported by Israel to Jordan following detention</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/thunberg-greeted-by-cheering-crowd-in-athens-after-israel-expels-flotilla-activists/mf2qe8dj9</link><description>Seven Australians were among those arrested and detained by Israel as part of the Global Sumud Flotilla, with some having alleged violence and mistreatment from Israeli soldiers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79606fccfeaecb0d2ba332a2ba68edc8</guid></item><item><title>Gaza peace talks to continue as October 7 anniversary marked by commemoration, protests</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gaza-peace-talks-begin-as-october-7-anniversary-marked-by-commemoration-protests/08rf6jaqb</link><description>As Gaza marks two years under devastating Israeli bombardment, commemorations of the October 7 attacks and demonstrations in support of Palestinians are planned around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0633872b0d7cba4a7204b1bbac0fc2b0</guid></item><item><title>University students panicked after fraudulent emails &amp;apos;revoked&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;disqualified&amp;apos; degrees</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/western-sydney-university-hacks-scams-fraudulent-emails/9qa23rd0r</link><description>Western Sydney University said the emails are &amp;quot;not legitimate&amp;quot; and have been reported to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52ce0f86abd8ab03886197cfd7efdcee</guid></item><item><title>NSW Premier backs police in protest fight | Midday News Bulletin 7 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nsw-premier-backs-police-in-protest-fight-midday-news-bulletin-7-october-2025/dh7oattld</link><description>In this bulletin, a court to decide whether a pro-Palestine protest will go ahead this weekend at the Opera House, Donald Trump heralds a breakthrough in Gaza peace talks. And in football, historic clubs return as the Australian Championship kicks off this weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9d211851cc5cb4c121c6af4922c54815</guid></item><item><title>Advocates alarmed as major change for autistic kids looms</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/advocates-alarmed-as-major-change-for-autistic-kids-looms/n2rj2ev77</link><description>There are fears that many children with autism or learning difficulties will fall between the cracks of a new support system that aims to limit access to the National Disability Insurance Scheme. The Thriving Kids initiative will be rolled out from the middle of next year, with a focus on providing support to children with so-called mild to moderate autism within community and mainstream settings. But disability advocates have told a parliamentary inquiry it is these children that are most often overlooked or misunderstood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbcbfc97c8481df7a17e0c2a379464dc</guid></item><item><title>Few women, minorities win seats in Syria&amp;apos;s parliamentary election, initial results show</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/few-women-minorities-win-seats-in-syria-parliamentary-election-initial-results-show/z3ml3vdl1</link><description>One of the election observers described the new parliament as overwhelmingly Sunni Muslim and male.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acf27dd02885eb9b224cabce22dd4f5a</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 7 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-7-october-2025/pj6h2owkh</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76159309e4392687a2c1f21694cde629</guid></item><item><title>Federal government admits handballing truth-telling process as only &amp;apos;half a person&amp;apos; employed</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/federal-government-admits-handballing-truth-telling-process-as-only-half-a-person-employed/6yvl7nghg</link><description>The Greens have questioned what progress is being made on truth-telling and treaty at a federal level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c089253e246d0c2480ff6db83e911471</guid></item><item><title>Talks on Gaza peace plan progress - but can the sticking points be overcome?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/talks-on-gaza-peace-plan-progress-but-can-the-sticking-points-be-overcome/wr735q857</link><description>Israeli and Hamas officials are meeting in Egypt this week in hopes of progressing a deal for a potential ceasefire in Gaza. It comes as the world marks two years of intense war in the enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c390c44c2c1c13e6a5aa05e92f9c6b6</guid></item><item><title>France plunges into chaos as anger mounts over political deadlock</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/france-plunges-into-chaos-as-anger-mounts-over-political-deadlock/qk99nmupt</link><description>French politics has been in disarray since President Emmanuel Macron called an early legislative election last year, producing a deeply fragmented National Assembly. Now, with Prime Minister Sébastien Lecornu resigning after less than a month in the job, there are fears the French parliament has plunged into political deadlock.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4bcbb17803c79ddd415ae773e8c258b</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;You are not alone&amp;apos;: PM and Ley recall horrors of Hamas attack, commemorating October 7</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/you-are-not-alone-pm-and-ley-recall-horrors-of-hamas-attack-commemorating-october-7/upzbe0n52</link><description>Both major party leaders have stood in solidarity with Australia&amp;apos;s Jewish community as it remembers the Hamas-led attack on Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d6219dd60cc721c68945832cd80d23f</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The purpose of my voice is to teach history&amp;apos;: Survivor tells how a party turned to trauma</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jewish-community-groups-mark-7-october-but-remain-divided-over-israels-response/8wbljra59</link><description>Nova Festival attack survivor Natalie Sanandaji shares her ordeal escaping the massacre on 7 October 2023 in southern Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f54ac3b662d720cf0b52eb64f2f47c7</guid></item><item><title>GP snapshot reveals why the job has become more complicated</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gp-snapshot-reveals-why-the-job-has-become-more-complicated/qpql0lgde</link><description>A snapshot of Australian general practice has revealed that GPs are having to see patients for longer appointments to treat more complex medical needs. The Health of the Nation industry survey of almost 2,500 GPs also shows a growing number of general practitioners are managing patient conditions typically handled by specialists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c160cb3c86a6aded30a18e7d0e9289a</guid></item><item><title>ASIC approves ASX listing market competitor; is AI in a bubble? and gold approaches US$4,000</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asic-approves-asx-listing-market-competitor-is-ai-in-a-bubble-and-gold-approaches-us-4-000/15pn8lg7y</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Todd Hoare from LGT Wealth Management Australia Management about the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action, including ASIC&amp;apos;s approval of Cboe Australia&amp;apos;s listing market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a14fecba3f407f02c5f75ddaca796de3</guid></item><item><title>Government fast-tracks legislation to strengthen 000 call system</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/government-fast-tracks-legislation-to-strengthen-000-call-system/w83hkwzos</link><description>The government has fast-tracked legislation into parliament aimed at strengthening the 000 call system after failures by Optus to ensure access to emergency calls. As parliament resumed, the nation&amp;apos;s leaders made time to commemorate the second anniversary of the October 7 attack on Israel by Hamas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eae27ff927fc8446f700e60af6c28d2</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;They&amp;apos;re on notice&amp;apos;: New AFP boss&amp;apos; warning to Australia&amp;apos;s adversaries</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/new-afp-boss-warning-to-australias-adversaries/uoe8cwes4</link><description>Krissy Barrett, the first woman to lead the Australian Federal Police, has revealed some of her early moves in her new role.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df95e56a41e0bde6905104a8371410c8</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Israel marks October 7 anniversary</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-marks-october-7-anniversary/7nytd3mxs</link><description>Bereaved friends and family members gathered at the site of the Nova music festival, while others came together in Tel Aviv and held ceremonies across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f40f4967660e93d469c317547818f0e</guid></item></channel></rss>