<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>SBS English News (Unofficial Aggregation)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:04:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Why these skincare products with a banned ingredient are still being sold in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-these-skincare-products-with-a-banned-ingredient-are-still-being-sold-in-australia/6zz7tsa7t</link><description>Six skincare brands have been ordered to withdraw their products from supermarket shelves in NSW after being found to contain banned microbeads.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">afaec5c160ccd5fe66df422053179ab1</guid></item><item><title>When power isn’t guaranteed: Indigenous families in northern Australia face deadly risks in extreme heat</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/when-power-isnt-guaranteed-indigenous-families-in-northern-australia-face-deadly-risks-in-extreme-heat/ax4dvkwbk</link><description>Thousands of Indigenous households across northern Australia live with prepaid power, where disconnection can happen at any moment. Now a new report has warned that without stronger protections, the system could turn deadly in extreme heat. SBS’s Christopher Tan travelled to the Kimberley to see what life is like when power is a privilege, not a guarantee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e46f58cd22b380e0238c4c337e4d29db</guid></item><item><title>New concussion guidelines launched to help patients get the right care</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-concussion-guidelines-launched-to-help-patients-get-the-right-care/qf7c6wjso</link><description>New national clinical guidelines for the treatment of concussion have been released. They are aimed at helping healthcare professionals treat patients with greater consistency, amid concern that providing the right care can still be a blind spot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bd745b3f59d8906988e9901f4434a04</guid></item><item><title>Will you benefit? Here&amp;apos;s how Labor&amp;apos;s three hours of free power will work</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/free-power-labor-solar-sharer/hnternt0d</link><description>Several parts of the country will have access to the Solar Sharer program in its initial phase.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17e388f4e2e005e1dc51e81f74476dbe</guid></item><item><title>Israeli army&amp;apos;s former top lawyer arrested after leaking video of alleged detainee abuse</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/yifat-tomer-yerushalmi-arrested-after-alleged-palestinian-detainee-abuse-video-leak/7rx33v6nc</link><description>The leaked video, which allegedly shows soldiers abusing a Palestinian detainee, piled pressure on Israel&amp;apos;s political and military leaders during the Gaza war.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67a926bd0595acf0a41a26e789bd9e21</guid></item><item><title>RBA &amp;apos;not wedded to a particular path&amp;apos;, Bullock says, after rates kept on hold again</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/reserve-bank-leaves-rates-on-hold-again-after-surprise-inflation-figures/sebbqc4up</link><description>For the second meeting in a row, the central bank has left the official cash rate target at 3.6 per cent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24a6641181951bd60bae071273addaf8</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 4 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-4-november-2025/13i1wbfr1</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0bea7cde18b3834b76be1280ccedf06</guid></item><item><title>Unlikely alliance forces Senate showdown over Labor’s ‘Jobs for mates’ report</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/unlikely-alliance-forces-senate-showdown-over-labors-jobs-for-mates-report/5uruyzqes</link><description>An unusual alliance of crossbenchers and the Coalition has forced an ongoing extension of Question Time in the Senate. They are demanding the Labor government immediately release the &amp;quot;jobs for mates&amp;quot; report, which it has withheld for two years. Critics, including Transparency International, say the government&amp;apos;s refusal to release the report is further evidence of a &amp;quot;culture of secrecy&amp;quot; at a time when its integrity standards are under heightened scrutiny.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c009c462b64a26dfd41ddd400b70db2e</guid></item><item><title>Rates on hold as RBA lifts inflation forecast</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/rates-on-hold-as-rba-lifts-inflation-forecast/fwyie69b0</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Laura Cooper from Nuveen and Gemma Dale from nabtrade about the RBA&amp;apos;s decision to leave interest rates on hold and why its revised inflation forecasts risks an end to its rate cutting cycle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51c4caa7d9e9aefd9c646f4e8b17e8a8</guid></item><item><title>Three free hours of power under new plan - or is it?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/three-free-hours-of-power-under-new-plan-or-is-it/erx9ank1n</link><description>Australians in three states are to be offered three hours of free electricity in the middle of the day, under a scheme to share abundant solar energy harvested in non-peak hours. The plan has been welcomed by environmental groups, but some in the Opposition are unimpressed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">866a92e4947d6e7a271e3e7c2efd7688</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Little did they know&amp;apos;: ASIO boss reveals spy confrontation, and fresh Russia threats</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/asio-boss-reveals-spy-confrontation-and-fresh-russia-threats/8x648j2mc</link><description>Mike Burgess said his agency foiled an elaborate plot by spies from a country that claims it &amp;quot;does not spy on Australia&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">717ac186335134082a26fd78f8a25474</guid></item><item><title>These women beat &amp;apos;incurable&amp;apos; cancers, but others can&amp;apos;t access their treatment</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/these-women-beat-incurable-cancers-but-their-treatment-may-never-get-to-market/hrgufnruq</link><description>Two Australian scientists have developed a cancer treatment that has the potential to save millions of lives — if people can access it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">830bd88240a835100dc2b7e1423f328e</guid></item><item><title>Temu, a plug-in heater that &amp;apos;doesn&amp;apos;t plug in&amp;apos;, and more: 2025&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;Shonkys&amp;apos; revealed</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/choice-shonky-awards-2025-commonwealth-bank-temu-hcf/idn9r4kbv</link><description>Consumer advocacy group Choice has released its annual report card of products, services and companies it deems dodgy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c65c663b7760601c5c5442c94bba9b08</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I feel guilty that I&amp;apos;m safe&amp;apos;: Sudanese-Australians fear for families after Al-Fasher massacres</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/i-feel-guilty-that-im-safe-sudanese-australians-fear-for-families-after-al-fasher-massacres/ev01ias40</link><description>Members of the Sudanese-Australian community are anxiously awaiting news from their family trapped in the city of Al-Fasher after an explosion of violence. The city was captured by the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces one week ago, with experts believing thousands may have been killed in widespread massacres. With internet and phone services cut off, those living abroad are forced to sit and wait to learn if their loved ones are still alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2235058b9b51b18f07ba6699022d351b</guid></item><item><title>Shark Bay: where Indigenous knowledge and marine science meet</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/shark-bay-where-indigenous-knowledge-and-marine-science-meet/oikkw7tur</link><description>Professor Michael Wear, a Malgana Traditional Custodian from Shark Bay, has been honoured at the 26th Prime Minister’s Prizes for Science for his groundbreaking work uniting Indigenous knowledge and marine science. He is the inaugural winner of the Prime Minister’s Prize for Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Knowledge Systems. Through his company Tidal Moon, Professor Wear is leading a world-first seagrass restoration project that employs Aboriginal divers, supports sustainable livelihoods, and restores cultural connections to Sea Country. His work highlights how traditional wisdom and Western science can come together to protect Australia’s oceans and climate.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6dcad2213b5c53306a8310a0757d7b0</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Stay away&amp;apos;: Fresh threat after Kentucky crash as authorities fear death toll will rise</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cargo-plane-crashes-after-take-off-in-us-state-of-kentucky/y32zhdpzw</link><description>Several buildings in an industrial area beyond the runway were on fire after the crash, with thick black smoke rising into the evening sky.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beb951a1709fffb943707c743dec8939</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Foodbank Australia CEO Kylea Tink</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-foodbank-australia-ceo-kylea-tink/lw84dygf8</link><description>One in three Australian households experienced food insecurity in the past 12 months, according to the Foodbank Hunger Report 2025. The report paints a stark picture of widening food insecurity across the nation, debunking the myth that hunger only affects the unemployed or homeless. The report reveals that cost-of-living pressures remain the number one concern for 91% of food-insecure households, followed by housing and the broader economy. Behind the data are the real stories of families forced to skip meals so children can eat, workers going hungry to pay rising rents, and people living with disability or illness struggling to put food on the table. Foodbank Australia CEO Kylea Tink spoke with SBS&amp;apos;s Cameron Carr</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73e91f139f597f3d44b6dfb5806dd383</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Turn the volume up&amp;apos;: Mamdani speaks after historic win as Trump reacts to Democrat victories</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/zohran-mamdani-elected-as-mayor-of-new-york-city-in-historic-win/c5abq2a8k</link><description>Zohran Mamdani&amp;apos;s win caps a meteoric rise from a little-known state politician to one of the nation&amp;apos;s most visible Democrats.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb701b977cbd05db5bae3d370512185f</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 5 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-5-november-2025/0718v85ph</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English Language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">526c43852bd6ffc95f27b5bb7cf70404</guid></item><item><title>The &amp;apos;insidious problem&amp;apos; leaving Australians like Jessica &amp;apos;lucky&amp;apos; to eat twice a day</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/food-insecurity-worsening-in-australia-according-to-foodbank/w2sediuu0</link><description>Millions of Australian families are struggling with hardship that &amp;quot;is not getting better&amp;quot;, a charity warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64e3f190d88b1017c2da715a7fe4ed0b</guid></item><item><title>Questions linger over which platforms to ban as Reddit and Kick included in eSafety list</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/questions-linger-over-which-platforms-to-ban-as-reddit-and-kick-included-in-esafety-list/0ali0sxt7</link><description>Reddit and live-streaming platform Kick will be added to the platforms required to ban 16s when the new rules come into effect in December. Australia&amp;apos;s impending social media ban for under-16s, which covers eight major platforms, hinges on ongoing eSafety assessments that distinguish between social media, messaging, and gaming services, explaining why platforms like Steam and Twitch were not initially included.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3450acf78f552bde8836f53d392484ca</guid></item><item><title>Bitcoin bear market &amp;amp; AI valuation fears</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/bitcoin-bear-market-ai-valuation-fears/i26uo5hfr</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Rachael Lucas from BTC Markets about bitcoin&amp;apos;s latest plunge while Luke Laretive from Seneca Financial Solutions takes a look at the day&amp;apos;s trading action including a global sell-off triggered by interest rate and AI valuation concerns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85bcde19ed3f31c81ec448208f46b6c2</guid></item><item><title>Do Russia sanctions really affect Australia&amp;apos;s fuel prices?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/russian-sanctions-oil-prices/zlp3yj79y</link><description>Oil market analysts differ on how these measures could ripple through to Australia. Some argue the impact will be minimal, while others caution it could be more pronounced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">467c7860bcaa4cf185dc20646579045b</guid></item><item><title>Do Russia sanctions really affect Australia&amp;apos;s fuel prices?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-fuel-prices-turning-point/zlp3yj79y</link><description>Oil market analysts differ on how these measures could ripple through to Australia. Some argue the impact will be minimal, while others caution it could be more pronounced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd9e3c72f128d418906e15b74c83de21</guid></item><item><title>New government powers to keep ASIO, AFP in check as intelligence agencies expand</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/asio-afp-on-notice-under-new-intelligence-agency-oversight-powers/iwhqz74jw</link><description>In the biggest reforms since the 1980s, intelligence agencies such as ASIO will have their functions increasingly scrutinised.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7b3865be8873ba0dec5069779abbd5f</guid></item><item><title>Should you be freaking out about microplastics?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/should-you-be-freaking-out-about-microplastics/2l6tlt0rg</link><description>Microplastics are turning up everywhere, but some scientists say how harmful they are to our bodies is still uncertain. Here&amp;apos;s why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f46657b2dd2d5a3933091ab79069a36</guid></item><item><title>Teaching was the &amp;apos;perfect career&amp;apos; for Rachel. Racist comments pushed her to quit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-last-straw-that-led-to-rachel-quitting-her-perfect-career/u2xtr0ec7</link><description>A problem that spanned staff and students led Rachel to quit a teaching career she loved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edcf6a6c815d878b3554588e77047632</guid></item><item><title>US Supreme Court scrutinises legality of Trump&amp;apos;s sweeping tariffs in landmark case</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-supreme-court-scrutinises-legality-of-trumps-sweeping-tariffs-in-landmark-case/av4gvkivl</link><description>Since returning to the White House, US President Donald Trump has brought the average effective tariff rate to its highest since the 1930s.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8dc0cb82210a206291bb7e6527161064</guid></item><item><title>Japan deploys military to combat wave of deadly bear attacks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/japan-deploys-troops-as-bear-attacks-surge-across-the-country/8yuk1frcs</link><description>Bears have attacked customers inside a supermarket, jumped a tourist waiting at a bus stop and mutilated a worker at a hot spring resort.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0963f20c2e8c3be7a1ce574c3dd04ee8</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Can Zohran Mamdani deliver on his election promises?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-can-zohran-mamdani-deliver-on-his-election-promises/afo89blkp</link><description>New York City Mayor-elect Zohran Mamdani led a new generation of Democrat victories this week with his victory over the old guard and Andrew Cuomo. Mr Mamdani, the first Muslim to be elected mayor of the biggest U.S. city, defeated former Democratic Governor Andrew Cuomo, who ran as an independent after losing the nomination to Mamdani earlier this year. Mr Cuomo, who resigned as governor four years ago after sexual harassment allegations that he has denied, painted Mr Mamdani as a radical leftist whose proposals were unworkable and dangerous. Mr Mamdani himself has proposed raising taxes on corporations and the wealthy to pay for ambitious policies such as rent freezes, free childcare and free city buses. But like other winning candidates from the off-year elections, Mr Mamdani focused intensely on economic issues, particularly the cost of living, an issue that helped propel U.S. President, Donald Trump, to the White House last year but has remained top-of-mind for voters. In this episode of weeke nd omne-on-one, we hear from Eric Gander, who&amp;apos;s the chair of the Department of Communications at New York&amp;apos;s Baruch College.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">046921ed942ac4494c7aad60edace58e</guid></item><item><title>Behind Zohran Mamdani&amp;apos;s historic win, and what it means for the Democratic Party&amp;apos;s future</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-will-zohran-mamdani-affect-us-politics/nwxpbg5cj</link><description>The mayor-elect of New York City was just one of the Democrats to win an election this week.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">780bb083212a6ecfc7e941d85376da46</guid></item><item><title>Mexico&amp;apos;s president was groped on the street. She&amp;apos;s now calling for tougher sexual assault laws</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/mexicos-president-was-groped-on-the-street-shes-now-calling-for-tougher-sexual-assault-laws/5az1ujs5t</link><description>The incident highlighted Mexico&amp;apos;s troubling record on women&amp;apos;s safety as rights groups warned of a femicide crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e4ddf1a577e2761aee7ed8f44a3da77</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 6 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-6-november-2025/niagalysh</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbcc38ec52622e6ce76b380376edbcad</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Many will be misled&amp;apos;: A superannuation boost for workers comes with a warning</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/superannuation-boost-for-workers-comes-with-a-warning/xzbkhafo5</link><description>Omitted superannuation changes have sparked concern some Australians may face unnecessary costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7409317f67254367dd36d815f1573de</guid></item><item><title>Hanson outlines One Nation agenda at surprise Mar-a-Lago address</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hanson-outlines-one-nation-agenda-at-surprise-mar-a-lago-address/fyjltejve</link><description>The speech to American conservatives comes as polling suggests support for One Nation has surged.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb724d6bd8fdbf0836bf1a84604a7726</guid></item><item><title>Advocates flag &amp;apos;make or break time&amp;apos; for planet as COP30 begins</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/advocates-flag-make-or-break-time-for-planet-as-cop30-begins/ljmniw6xk</link><description>This year&amp;apos;s global climate summit - COP30 - is being hailed as the most significant in ten years, with experts describing it the &amp;quot;make or break decade&amp;quot; for action on global warming. But doubts are being raised about whether enough can be achieved.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca7d43271a48b8580e9302498f009a2f</guid></item><item><title>Sudan’s civil war ‘spirals out of control’, Mamdani takes on Trump &amp;amp; would you snip and share?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sudans-civil-war-spirals-out-of-control-mamdani-takes-on-trump-would-you-snip-and-share/l5ds2hdw6</link><description>Confronting reports of mass killings in Sudan, after a key city in Darfur falls to the RSF. The plan for an international stabilisation force for Gaza makes its way to the UN and it’s ‘GAME ON’ after the democratic socialist Zohran Mamdani wins NY – with Donald Trump threatening to cut federal funding to the city. Plus, why young men in China are opening up about getting the snip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef5b5bb5513cd823d32536cac4d1c1df</guid></item><item><title>NAB results disappoint &amp;amp; bank sector challenges</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nab-results-disappoint-bank-sector-challenges/818xmrp7p</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Michael Wayne from Medallion Financial about the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action including why investors were disappointed with NAB&amp;apos;s $7.1bn cash earnings full- year report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed40291d26cd6911585095e31d214ff9</guid></item><item><title>Man arrested after groping Mexican President on the street</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/man-arrested-after-groping-mexican-president-on-the-street/ipodk4tac</link><description>Mexican President Claudia Sheinbaum has called for sexual harassment to be made a criminal offence nationwide after being groped on the street. The incident occurred as she walked to an event near the presidential palace, shaking hands and taking pictures with people along the way.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c67bffa2106e3f2d549664366841aa49</guid></item><item><title>These Aussie regions have posted &amp;apos;astronomical&amp;apos; price gains — but there&amp;apos;s a catch</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/astronomical-price-gains-regional-property/nh4mia09c</link><description>Looks — even when pristine and coastal — can be deceiving.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bb46c3cfc26aa0a0a4b87ab7ab8d183</guid></item><item><title>Sudan&amp;apos;s Rapid Support Forces agrees to US-Arab humanitarian truce proposal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sudans-rapid-support-forces-agrees-to-us-arab-humanitarian-truce-proposal/2wdcv1w9l</link><description>Both the RSF and the Sudanese army have agreed to various ceasefire proposals during the two-and-a-half-year-old war, though none have succeeded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4cbd5d954e5ecaafb046b10d530a87f6</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Sense of impending doom&amp;apos;: Should the Liberals and Nationals break up forever?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sense-of-impending-doom-should-the-liberals-and-nationals-break-up-forever/g7992uf1h</link><description>The Nationals have officially dumped their net zero policy - but does that mean the Liberals are going to dump them? This week, we speak to Jill Sheppard, a political scientist from the Australian National University, about what&amp;apos;s happening to the Coalition&amp;apos;s relationship and if they should break up. We also have news about a very spooky White House Halloween and - for some reason - horse racing commentary in the House of Representatives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8972f79a2c774c184b71248369cdaca</guid></item><item><title>South Lebanon villages face evacuation orders as Israel launches heavy airstrikes</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/south-lebanon-villages-face-evacuation-orders-as-israel-launches-heavy-airstrikes/vy16w33h7</link><description>The Israeli armed forces said armed group Hezbollah was trying to rebuild its military capabilities in southern Lebanon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a4f2d2b75bbb553bf282bc9c65b0117</guid></item><item><title>Masculinity crisis deepens as half of Australian teen boys feel pressure to ‘be strong’</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/masculinity-crisis-deepens-as-half-of-australian-teen-boys-feel-pressure-to-be-strong/tjpn77mhu</link><description>A landmark report released this week has found Australian boys are feeling pressure to follow restrictive ideas about masculinity - and when they do - they are more likely to hurt themselves and others. Advocates have used a National Press Club address to call for urgent government reform, including a national action plan to improve young people&amp;apos;s wellbeing and reduce violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8caa4a2e3b3a6db08b7447fa9f63db6</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Ask her&amp;apos;: Sussan Ley fires back over colleague&amp;apos;s criticism of her leadership</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sussan-leys-liberal-colleague-thinks-her-leadership-is-in-need-of-a-miracle/zl47osmi5</link><description>Sarah Henderson, who was dumped by Sussan Ley from the frontbench earlier this year, says the party is in a &amp;quot;dire situation&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73c6905439703e5e4cbb66714e13f805</guid></item><item><title>Sudan&amp;apos;s RSF agrees to humanitarian truce: but will it ever happen?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sudans-rsf-agrees-to-humanitarian-truce-but-will-it-ever-happen/suq6eskul</link><description>Sudan’s paramilitary Rapid Support Forces, the RSF, has agreed to a humanitarian truce proposed by mediators, the first sign of possible peace after nearly three years of brutal conflict. The group says the pause is meant to allow aid to reach civilians, but the Sudanese Army has yet to accept the terms, insisting RSF fighters must first withdraw from populated areas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">590613b5ee596d696d07285457c26315</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 7 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-7-november-2025/wcuvkst6i</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18fbd1fd5e5f92df4353df29d27eed0c</guid></item><item><title>Elon Musk&amp;apos;s path to $1 trillion: These are the &amp;apos;aggressive goals&amp;apos; he must hit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/elon-musk-trillionaire-pay-package/uj2zmnioi</link><description>He&amp;apos;s already the world&amp;apos;s richest man by some estimates, and he could become richer — if he meets aggressive performance goals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4556ba619e1158c07d8f5a774b3fa9a7</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Deadly negligence&amp;apos;: Stern warning issued as COP30 climate summit opens in Brazil</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/deadly-negligence-stern-warning-issued-as-cop30-climate-summit-opens-in-brazil/o8mqqvndj</link><description>Leaders are gathering in Brazil for the UN COP30 Climate Summit as the United Nations declares the world will not meet the 1.5 degree warming limit set in 2015. With 2025 set to be one of the warmest years on record, the most vulnerable small island nations are pleading for stronger action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b65a3b0ea0b3cfbcbf4419bbf15f7b70</guid></item><item><title>Many Australians face &amp;apos;unsettled&amp;apos; weekend with severe storms and rain</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/weekend-weather-rain/atrmjisi9</link><description>A wet and stormy weekend is forecast for parts of the country, with giant hail and flash flooding possible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cd6833e5e9ccc84967f3b75b6984b1f</guid></item><item><title>Elon Musk’s trillion-dollar payday; uncertainty creeps back into markets</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/elon-musks-trillion-dollar-payday-uncertainty-creeps-back-into-markets/a9zn17411</link><description>Tesla shareholders have approved a US$1 trillion dollar compensation package for CEO Elon Musk, tying him to the electric vehicle maker for a decade. Plus, the Australian sharemarket has followed Wall Street on a downward tilt, thanks to concerns over tech stock valuations and economic uncertainty. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Heath Moss, Portfolio Manager at HLM Investments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">879a7da7416e7b527b35f8dfa3a19ab7</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Won&amp;apos;t make a lick of difference&amp;apos;: Why building apartments may not bring prices down</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/does-building-more-apartments-help-housing-affordability/0opkcmpj4</link><description>Allowing developers to build high-density housing doesn&amp;apos;t automatically make homes affordable. This is why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67d56819c2d2c19d7d40369b0bb3ee5b</guid></item><item><title>How an offer to carry a strange package to Australia almost turned Susi into a drug courier</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/susi-agreed-to-carry-a-package-to-australia-it-turned-out-to-have-a-20-million-street-value/1ik7l7bza</link><description>A Thai woman who regularly travels to Australia to visit family narrowly escaped becoming an unwitting drug courier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d720ab2f93e38d6a43a748868ea86288</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Heartbreaking&amp;apos;: Experts argue egg donation rules could change to help Australia&amp;apos;s fertility issues</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/heartbreaking-experts-argue-egg-donation-rules-could-change-to-help-australias-fertility-issues/4cd5nz1zc</link><description>Demand for donated eggs is growing in Australia as more people face fertility challenges. But the demand for eggs far outstrips their supply and now, experts are arguing Australia should consider changing the rules around donation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e82b9f1811c5bd250c05e1269c36421</guid></item><item><title>Princess Anne will arrive in Australia days after Prince Andrew was stripped of his title</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/princess-anne-in-australia/7108p5ld3</link><description>While the controversy surrounding Prince Andrew will linger, one expert said the tour could take some heat off the royals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f98ddf2d2f1525d962c89350a8909469</guid></item><item><title>At least 54 injured in blasts at high school mosque in Jakarta</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jakarta-mosque-school-bombing/5uv6rg5a7</link><description>A 17-year-old student has been identified as the suspected perpetrator of the attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ad2f1bcee1b8b5074910e5e544c1b88</guid></item><item><title>Palestinian militant group returns the body of Israeli hostage</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/islamic-jihad-hands-over-body-of-israeli-hostage/tlqnlxxd3</link><description>So far, the bodies of 22 hostages have been returned to Israel as part of a fragile ceasefire agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51b02b21cef0b463ca4c37513d06ac3d</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Please wake up&amp;apos;: Leaders and activists prepare for &amp;apos;make or break&amp;apos; COP30 in Brazil</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cop-30-brazil-belem/awobisgtu</link><description>COP30 is being hailed as the most significant climate summit since the Paris Agreement was signed ten years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">08a851d16fe9de0a557fb8b8eff10ca2</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Unacceptable&amp;apos;: Hospitals are missing opportunity to vaccinate for whooping cough</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/whooping-cough-vaccine-rates/fdcd1iz7d</link><description>Immunisation Foundation founder Catherine Hughes, who lost her son to whooping cough, says Australia needs to boost vaccination rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96d59c368df4c78f8a1681aa0e51e86b</guid></item><item><title>Ukrainian-Australians call for further action on Russian &amp;apos;blood oil&amp;apos; entering the country</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ukrainian-australians-call-for-further-action-on-russian-blood-oil/5imqsjgdu</link><description>The Ukrainian-Australian community wants more government action to close a loophole allowing sanctioned Russian oil to enter the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02153feb1387254ccf0d0309ad90a1d8</guid></item><item><title>Police authorisation of Sydney neo-Nazi demonstration sparks calls for protest law review</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/minns-and-nsw-police-commissioner-call-for-legal-review-after-neo-nazi-protest1/n3unuuvst</link><description>A neo-Nazi protest received NSW Police authorisation to go ahead outside NSW parliament on Saturday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">149550e52f2da8c3d18259f958f63667</guid></item><item><title>Police authorisation of Sydney neo-Nazi demonstration sparks calls for protest law review</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/minns-and-nsw-police-commissioner-call-for-legal-review-after-neo-nazi-protest/n3unuuvst</link><description>A neo-Nazi protest received NSW Police authorisation to go ahead outside NSW parliament on Saturday morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a15ea1937cc716f523ab4b3c5ceae06c</guid></item><item><title>The first Miss Palestine hopes to make history in the &amp;apos;Olympics of women&amp;apos;s beauty&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/the-first-miss-palestine-hopes-to-make-history-in-the-olympics-of-womens-beauty/jtulqx3d4</link><description>This year&amp;apos;s Miss Universe will include Miss Palestine for the first time. But do beauty pageants have an impact outside of the arena?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">315719879d248b48c2f093b68b9ae102</guid></item><item><title>Naughty and downright bad: The First Nations characters Kodie wants to put on screen</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/reckless-the-first-nations-characters-kodie-bedford-wants-to-put-on-screen/lft0cvzd1</link><description>Australian writer Kodie Bedford wants to change the way we think about First Nations characters. The first step? Making them downright bad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a225e0e8773a11284d1c94f2efa89917</guid></item><item><title>The Alzheimer&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;imbalance&amp;apos; this Australian has under the microscope</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-alzheimers-imbalance-this-australian-has-under-the-microscope/janflm0p2</link><description>The researcher hopes to uncover clues to explain one group is particularly at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">032a7bc217999b7bc44e2b95dc175436</guid></item><item><title>Calls for a better refugee response as Australia approaches one millionth visa milestone</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/calls-for-a-better-refugee-response-as-australia-approaches-one-millionth-visa-milestone/w4obit4j6</link><description>Australia is set to issue its one millionth permanent humanitarian visa since the end of World War II as early as the end of this year. The milestone has prompted celebration over the immense contribution refugees make to Australia&amp;apos;s national story. But refugee rights organisations say it&amp;apos;s a pertinent time to consider how Australia can improve its response to mass global displacement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f70cdc921b48f5be70f40616d36d57a</guid></item><item><title>Families await five more remains as Israel identifies latest hostage body</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/families-await-five-more-remains-as-israel-identifies-latest-hostage-body/2c5c3z26t</link><description>Five more bodies remain to be returned — three Israelis and one Thai national seized in the October 7 attack, and one Israeli officer who died in combat in 2014.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">31809c9e6713e6044ac855f1bbb2c778</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Bruce Stillman on the life and legacy of DNA pioneer James Watson</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-bruce-stillman-on-the-life-and-legacy-of-dna-pioneer-james-watson/bp6n7fgvi</link><description>Australian scientist Bruce Stillman reflects on the complicated legacy of American biologist James Watson who has died at the age of 97. He co-discovered the double helix structure of the DNA molecule - but his remarks in later life have drawn criticism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c1bf6398627d1a846a49ef82f28e57b</guid></item><item><title>Report of single gunshot opens up a new line of inquiry in the search for Dezi Freeman</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dezi-freeman-manhunt-gunshot/41nl9vd88</link><description>Police are investigating reports of a gunshot heard in the vicinity moments after Dezi Freeman allegedly opened fire, killing two officers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c13ff67b69a356419f1100f4fe69c3e</guid></item><item><title>Nearly one in 10 Australians believe violence can be justified by political causes, study finds</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-democracy-political-violence-survey/3n3e3g5pp</link><description>The new annual survey has been set up to measure Australia&amp;apos;s democratic health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5fa6d7686652222699520fb6093d7f89</guid></item><item><title>One million permanent humanitarian visas: Calls for change as milestone nears</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-one-million-refugees/bhi7f43ml</link><description>While advocates celebrate Australia&amp;apos;s one millionth permanent humanitarian visa, experts also say Australia needs to reassess its approach.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">091fd67b1f0afbc53afe1ee3d4688702</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We now have a group chat&amp;apos;: How five single mothers came together to reveal a love scam</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-five-single-mothers-came-together-to-reveal-a-love-scam/0flvkuhb3</link><description>A group of Chinese Australian single mothers were shocked to discover they&amp;apos;d all dated the same man — in some cases at the same time.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb029ba90298fa29b20f9728177494a0</guid></item><item><title>Israel confirms remains returned are soldier Hadar Goldin killed in Gaza in 2014</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-confirms-remains-returned-are-soldier-hadar-goldin-killed-in-gaza-in-2014/za51hibi9</link><description>Israeli authorities have received the remains of a hostage which Hamas says is the body of an Israeli soldier who was killed in 2014 and held for 11 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">374b1de25093f93b38e48459c43ed961</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;It shouldn&amp;apos;t be painful to be a woman&amp;apos;: Victorian report lays bare health care battle</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/it-shouldnt-be-painful-to-be-a-woman-victorian-report-lays-bare-health-care-battle/a2roecgtf</link><description>The Victorian government has released the final report of an inquiry into women&amp;apos;s experiences of pain - and it&amp;apos;s made for some uncomfortable reading. Shaped by the experiences of 13,000 women and girls, the report has revealed gender health gaps, experiences of medical bias, sexism and misogyny, and feelings of being ignored or dismissed by clinicians are rampant throughout the Victorian health system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e7fcdc0f7749003a0a7378da3eceac6</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 10 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-10-november-2025/0sd556x13</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56a96c1d0976a632e571d10b2f8e4ba8</guid></item><item><title>Activists accuse NSW of double standards, reject more police powers after neo-Nazi rally</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nsw-neo-nazi-rally-police-government-activists/p5rpdge58</link><description>A neo-Nazi rally held outside NSW Parliament on Saturday was given authorisation by police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29ad4aa896435dabe019a7df2f654655</guid></item><item><title>Hopes of end to US shutdown lifts markets; ANZ profit slump</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/hopes-of-end-to-us-shutdown-lifts-markets-anz-profit-slump/ati80gmsq</link><description>Growing optimism that the US government shutdown could end this week has lifted share markets, including the ASX-200. Plus, ANZ has reported a full-year cash profit of $5.8 billion, down by 14 per cent after factoring in legal penalties and the costs of mass redundancies. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Mathan Somasundaram, CEO of Deep Data Analytics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa4b9e451a09f95730bfdeaad02ba22b</guid></item><item><title>Tributes flow for broadcaster John Laws who has died aged 90</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/tributes-flow-for-broadcaster-john-laws-who-has-died-aged-90/hs0vqmpxb</link><description>John Laws, one of the Australia&amp;apos;s most influential talkback radio presenters, has died aged 90. Tributes have been flowing for the legendary broadcaster from former colleagues to politicians who once feared him. His career spanned more than seven decades - not without its controversies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d500dff6794a7f74ac2add1e16d9edf</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Blind spot&amp;apos;: Researchers warn of hidden crisis undercutting environmental progress</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/conservation-abandonment-undermining-climate-nature-goals/fl3srmhik</link><description>Experts say the issue may be far more widespread than is recognised — and we should be keeping track.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79346013c937828221924964cedb0505</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s spy boss warned of a Russian threat — and it&amp;apos;s unfolding in real time</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-russia-uses-ai-to-spread-disinformation/h4kf3947p</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s spy chief has expressed concern about the potential for AI to take online radicalisation and disinformation to new levels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c0a67f14545bb85891113cf9ce62639</guid></item><item><title>France&amp;apos;s Nicolas Sarkozy freed from prison three weeks into five-year sentence</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/frances-nicolas-sarkozy-freed-from-prison-three-weeks-into-five-year-sentence/aijjo9bg4</link><description>Sarkozy entered jail on 21 October, becoming the first former head of a European Union state to be incarcerated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3307c07e3a07d8527a5b7c7652db5d25</guid></item><item><title>Deadly Delhi car explosion being investigated under anti-terrorism law, police say</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/car-explosion-in-indias-new-delhi-kills-eight-people-injures-at-least-19/nbsu4ce4v</link><description>Eyewitnesses described how the car exploded in traffic and that people caught up in the surge of flames were set on fire.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9503792e369006418e625a6adc3596d8</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The future of information warfare&amp;apos;: Is Australia prepared?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-future-of-information-warfare-is-australia-prepared/wpkbrdz5g</link><description>Issuing a warning last week, Australia’s spy chief expressed concern about the potential for artificial intelligence to take online radicalisation and disinformation to new levels. Speaking to the spread of false news and violent narratives, Russian operatives were singled out. This growing threat has prompted experts to warn of quote: &amp;apos;information warfare&amp;apos; If it’s not combatted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b66e67bfc6acfc9882445719f831a85</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: BBC is facing an orchestrated campaign to undercut public trust says analyst</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-bbc-is-facing-an-orchestrated-campaign-to-undercut-public-trust-says-analyst/rflxsczy4</link><description>The director for the International Centre for Journalists says the resignation of two senior figures at the BBC is a result of an &amp;quot;orchestrated campaign to undercut public trust&amp;quot; in the broadcaster. The head of the BBC, director-general Tim Davie and news CEO Deborah Turness both resigned after criticism of the broadcaster’s editing of a speech by US President Donald Trump. Critics said the way the speech was edited for the BBC&amp;apos;s flagship documentary program Panorama last year was misleading and cut out a section where Donald Trump said that he wanted supporters to demonstrate peacefully. Mr Trump has threatened legal action against the BBC over the way the speech he made was edited. Julie Posetti is a professor of journalism at City St George&amp;apos;s University of London and director for the International Centre for Journalists and she&amp;apos;s speaking here to AP.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6f82c58ef8334b8925097a9cb7b8c37</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;No other alternative&amp;apos;: Howard weighs in on Whitlam&amp;apos;s controversial dismissal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/john-howard-weighs-in-on-gough-whitlams-dismissal/geaumvze0</link><description>John Howard, part of the Opposition at the time of the dismissal, said then governor-general Sir John Kerr made the right call.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9aa46150e9607ff6c06a442c7f7e9c1e</guid></item><item><title>Deadly car blast near India’s Red Fort kills at least eight</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/deadly-car-blast-near-indias-red-fort-kills-at-least-eight/sdrpmcv7r</link><description>A powerful car explosion near New Delhi’s historic Red Fort has killed at least eight people and injured around twenty others. The blast, which erupted near the Red Fort metro station in the city&amp;apos;s old quarter, tore through one of the city’s busiest streets, setting vehicles ablaze and scattering debris and human remains along the road.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7ec3458e457bc2ea1dc3b5d0bc141f9</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 11 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-11-november-2025/0v13l4byz</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English Language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb987a294973d29c8f81584d464e52f2</guid></item><item><title>Why consumers are optimistic despite inflation &amp;amp; CBA Q2 profit rises 2%</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/why-consumers-are-optimistic-despite-inflation-cba-q2-profit-rises-2/2fb8jxq6d</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Westpac&amp;apos;s Matt Hassan about a dramatic rise in consumer confidence, despite reaccelerating inflation and diminishing prospects of lower interest rates; plus the day on the sharemarket with Jamie Hannah from VanEck, including a closer look at the Commonwealth Bank&amp;apos;s latest profit result.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c275cd63eca036d04507c1dab7b3eb9</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;You could die, make a will&amp;apos;: Australia&amp;apos;s fresh warning amid &amp;apos;dark&amp;apos; travel trend</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australias-fresh-travel-warning-amid-dark-travel-trend/iqecjtaqf</link><description>Australians have been kidnapped, detained and targeted by terror attacks in this central Asian country, Smartraveller warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83cdda00445652f8db1e0e71021abef7</guid></item><item><title>The Dismissal: how it all played out</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-dismissal-how-it-all-played-out/1s5ql15ph</link><description>On November 11, 1975, Australia experienced its most dramatic constitutional crisis when Governor-General Sir John Kerr dismissed Prime Minister Gough Whitlam 50 years ago. We examine the full story of the Dismissal, from the political deadlock and the Loans Affair to Prime Minister Anthony Albanese&amp;apos;s recent claim of a &amp;quot;partisan political ambush&amp;quot; and new evidence suggesting foreign interference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c56cddfd12fbe9f0069c9be5572305cb</guid></item><item><title>The &amp;apos;incredibly toxic&amp;apos; hidden ingredient experts want banned from our supermarkets</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/calls-to-ban-industrial-trans-fats-in-food-products/4ycgwslw4</link><description>Researchers analysed 28,000 products stocked in Australian supermarkets. Here&amp;apos;s what they found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c7a10fbf0428963e6187fa51e2b39e5</guid></item><item><title>Is your blocked nose a sign of hay fever or a cold? Here&amp;apos;s what to know</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/is-your-blocked-nose-a-sign-of-hay-fever-or-a-cold-heres-what-to-know/47qu35u39</link><description>Duration and triggers for symptoms can provide clues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3eead27787ad396f2cd07c1bb39d7a03</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;State of war&amp;apos;: Pakistan defence minister&amp;apos;s warning after suicide bombing kills 12</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/suicide-bomber-kills-12-people-in-blast-outside-court-in-pakistan/8swr3p1c7</link><description>Pakistani government ministers accused neighbouring Afghanistan of complicity in the bloodshed — an accusation they denied.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1dfe5a9c6f03a477f3b0cb146a3073fd</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;God&amp;apos;s not making any more land&amp;apos;: Price gap between homes and apartments growing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gap-between-home-and-apartment-prices-growing-due-to-undersupply-domain-report-finds/32e5uklgm</link><description>On average, houses in capital cities are nearly 50 per cent more expensive than apartments. Five years ago, the gap was only 20 per cent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dd7ccb3c2e66b57638b33cb76ce810a</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s dispute with Türkiye over COP31 hosting rights could see both miss out</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ethiopia-announced-as-cop32-host-as-australia-and-turkiye-vie-for-cop31/ptxfop4gk</link><description>Ethiopia will host the UN&amp;apos;s COP32 climate summit in 2027, but next year&amp;apos;s COP31 remains a contest between Türkiye and Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37598ea11a910280016936b6f971c974</guid></item><item><title>Hop to it! Australia’s biggest frog count croaks to a record start</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/hop-to-it-australias-biggest-frog-count-croaks-to-a-record-start/q5dj9l7sq</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s biggest citizen science project and the world&amp;apos;s largest week-long frog count is underway. The croaks, chirps and clicks of 1.3 million frogs have already been recorded through the FrogID app. The initiative, led by the Australian Museum has contributed to the discovery of 13 new Australian frog species, including four which were described as &amp;quot;new to science&amp;quot; in the past year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3db6bd394c6a28329c42bc488f549e7f</guid></item><item><title>Victoria to introduce &amp;apos;adult time for violent crime&amp;apos; reform in response to rising crime</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/victoria-to-introduce-adult-time-for-violent-crime-reform-in-response-to-rising-crime/rn01525p0</link><description>Children as young as 14 could face possible life sentences under the proposed changes to be announced by the Victorian premier on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0c3dafa5f175702b2a40e5aa9e14920</guid></item><item><title>Russia loses legal battle over Canberra embassy site, but will be compensated</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/russia-loses-legal-battle-over-canberra-embassy-site-but-will-be-compensated/a0w12xtea</link><description>Russia launched a court challenge after the federal government cancelled its lease on a plot of land near parliament where it planned to build an embassy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6ae7ae48e6c0aab0e95f04196027bfd</guid></item><item><title>At COP30, Indigenous leaders demand greater powers to protect their land.</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/at-cop30-indigenous-leaders-demand-greater-powers-to-protect-their-land/l1zpibmif</link><description>Indigenous leaders in the Amazon are urging leaders at the UN Climate Summit to empower First Nations people to protect their land and rainforests. As world leaders gather in the Amazonian city of Belem, pressure is on to go beyond words and ideas and start implementing meaningful policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d77edf4a873699a2063777d022cc2f8</guid></item><item><title>$1 billion per incident: ASIO boss warns of &amp;apos;aggressive&amp;apos; cyber threat to Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/1-billion-per-incident-asio-boss-warns-of-aggressive-cyber-threat-to-australia/cg2hyvdsb</link><description>Mike Burgess says foreign cyber attacks could cause major disruptions, from shutting off telecommunications to polluting drinking water.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0590fef2a113931104040060e0dab0ea</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 12 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-12-november-2025/oimrouj1f</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02e13009faebf374bf0de6b24ef1591a</guid></item><item><title>Food delivery service Menulog closing down after nearly two decades</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/delivery-service-menulog-closing-services-in-australia/cdgf5v387</link><description>The announcement follows the closure of Deliveroo in 2022 and Foodora in 2018.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc4797942ab5f5f945c72351f93567dc</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Acting together&amp;apos;: Australia to sign a new defence and security treaty with Indonesia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-to-sign-a-new-defence-and-security-treaty-with-indonesia/9z3h7yaf2</link><description>Australia and Indonesia have committed to briefing each other on security threats, in a major step for the security alliance.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29171aaf4626ecde00bb624f881b70a0</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Punishing trauma&amp;apos;: Experts say proposal to fix &amp;apos;crime capital&amp;apos; could have opposite effect</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/victoria-jail-plan-young-offenders/otrb671kk</link><description>Young offenders in Victoria could face life imprisonment under proposed reforms, but advocates say the move won&amp;apos;t make communities safer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">112603308bbb11e1921d1c459e97c1a0</guid></item><item><title>Property investor loans at record &amp;amp; market sentiment bullish despite down day</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/property-investor-loans-at-record-market-sentiment-bullish-despite-down-day/zzimwrjub</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Maree Kilroy from Oxford Economics Australia about the latest home loan data which shows lending to investors hit a record high to find out what it means for supply; plus James Gerrish from Market Parters takes a look at the day&amp;apos;s market action and reveals what he&amp;apos;s telling his clients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82ea05a166fc57ac9376c7872342165f</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: SBS Portuguese speaks to Assistant Climate Change Minister Josh Wilson at COP30</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-sbs-portuguese-speaks-to-assistant-climate-change-minister-josh-wilson-at-cop30/oaze4njh7</link><description>Assistant Minister for Climate Change Josh Wilson is Australia&amp;apos;s highest-ranking official at COP30, now underway in Belem, Brazil. He&amp;apos;s spoken with SBS Portuguese in a wide-ranging interview about the balance between the urgency and the opportunity that climate action represents, Australia&amp;apos;s fossil fuel exports and renewable energy ambitions, and how COP can achieve results without USA and China. The Assistant Minister has also talked about Australia&amp;apos;s continuing bid to host COP31, the absence of Prime Minister Anthony Albanese at this climate summit, and his response to the Liberals party room discussions on net zero.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa244ee4a765851252f2724374456d48</guid></item><item><title>Why young, child-free men like Trent are choosing permanent contraception</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/why-more-younger-men-like-trent-are-choosing-permanent-contraception/hp2qzhz9b</link><description>Trent is among the men choosing a vasectomy, challenging ideas around contraception and rethinking having kids in a world of rising costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd2f067faa37fc1a69a9e71429f58a65</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Demands urgent attention&amp;apos;: Study finds widening disparities in cancer survival rates</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cancer-survival-rates-disadvantaged-patients-study/p1od389mp</link><description>The equity gap has swelled since four decades ago, according to analysis of data from almost one million cancer patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">328713eca21d95678fc85c12603bda88</guid></item><item><title>Ukrainian ministers resign over alleged involvement in corruption scandal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ukrainian-ministers-resign-over-alleged-involvement-in-corruption-scandal/8yn7t9426</link><description>Ukrainian President Volodomyr Zelenskyy had called on the justice and energy ministers to step down amid an investigation into the energy sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf031784c591b176636b4bc66bc3d26d</guid></item><item><title>The record-breaking US shutdown has finally ended, as bill heads to Trump&amp;apos;s desk</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-record-breaking-us-shutdown-may-finally-be-ending-what-still-needs-to-happen/2ev3uju71</link><description>The House passed a spending bill that will end the longest government shutdown in US history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b69f0fde7b4d9740c79c9223a3cbd1b3</guid></item><item><title>The record-breaking US shutdown has finally ended, as bill heads to Trump&amp;apos;s desk</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-record-breaking-us-shutdown-is-finally-ending-as-bill-heads-to-trumps-desk/2ev3uju71</link><description>The House passed a spending bill that will end the longest government shutdown in US history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1eb10b354fad6beabb788525dd9e284</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Side by side&amp;apos;: Australia&amp;apos;s first treaty with Aboriginal people signed into law in Victoria</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/victoria-aboriginal-treaty-agreement-signed-into-law/qy0tg1sv2</link><description>Before today, Australia was one of few Commonwealth countries without any treaties in place with its First Nations peoples.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48829ec8e79affa0c245362bd2fe4932</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine&amp;apos;s Zelenskyy orders ministers to quit over $100 million energy scandal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ukraines-zelenskyy-orders-ministers-to-quit-over-100-million-energy-scandal/9kvi1z57o</link><description>Ukraine&amp;apos;s President, Volodymyr Zelenskyy, has called for the removal of the nation&amp;apos;s justice and energy ministers, amid a wide-reaching corruption scandal involving the state nuclear power company. One minister has submitted her resignation, the other has been suspended. Ukraine’s anti-corruption agency has carried out a major investigation, involving alleged kickbacks worth around $100 million in the energy sector.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ea5a81375bffb87954d3c04cb6ecb93</guid></item><item><title>Nearly 1,000 a week: The &amp;apos;dodgy&amp;apos; behaviours Australians are tipping off the tax office about</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tax-evasion-ato-tip-offs-whistle-blowers/76liegaum</link><description>The Australian Tax Office says there have been more than 300,000 tip-offs since it launched its whistleblower service six years ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">11975744a48034b953de625bc283a8c4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Fortune teller&amp;apos; charged over alleged $70m fraud network as luxury bags, gold bar seized</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fortune-teller-charged-over-alleged-70m-fraud-network-as-luxury-bags-gold-bar-seized/ifm59wko7</link><description>The arrests come as part of an investigation into a syndicate the crime squad commander says is &amp;quot;one of the most sophisticated&amp;quot; he has seen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35a87a7e38e6602036425eef054806d3</guid></item><item><title>Coalition meeting looms as Liberal rejects &amp;apos;Nationals-lite&amp;apos; label after net zero dumped</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/liberal-party-dumps-net-zero-by-2050-target-from-policy-platform/vol0x5gcq</link><description>The Liberals and Nationals will hold talks on Sunday to negotiate a joint Coalition climate policy, with three members from both parties to attend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d84be5bf989be49fde8120a96a8b7d9d</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 13 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-13-november-2025/abkrr0bh3</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4639cdfb659722124c7cc41a2947c699</guid></item><item><title>White House dismisses emails that raise new questions about Trump ties to Epstein</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/white-house-dismisses-emails-that-raise-new-questions-about-trump-ties-to-epstein/aw0tx5bx0</link><description>US House Democrats have released emails they say raise new questions about President Donald Trump&amp;apos;s ties to Jeffrey Epstein and how much he knew about the financier&amp;apos;s abuse of underage girls. The correspondence released by Democrats on the U-S House Oversight Committee consist of messages between Epstein, Ghislaine Maxwell and journalist Michael Wolff that directly name Mr Trump, and suggest he may have spent hours at Epstein’s home with one of the victims.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">794f5b91e20259597e11351e8c2b9d3c</guid></item><item><title>The Liberal Party has dumped net zero — but the Coalition&amp;apos;s real battle lies ahead</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/liberals-climate-policy-shift/getjsnzo5</link><description>Sussan Ley has held her ground as the Liberals drop their net zero pledge. But unity, and credibility on climate, remain up for grabs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34e2ad7e6350922d90dc4a5ffa0a4b06</guid></item><item><title>What is next for the Liberals now they have scrapped their net zero commitment?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/what-is-next-for-the-liberals-now-they-have-scrapped-their-net-zero-commitment/0wpdb6fjq</link><description>The Liberal Party has voted to officially abandon its net zero by 2050 emissions reduction target, following a contentious internal meeting. This dramatic policy reversal, which will also seek to remove the target from the Climate Change Act, has triggered fierce internal debate among senior members and drawn criticism from the government and independents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbe966d91f27e2db4a18970970eddf29</guid></item><item><title>Philippines in tatters, Trump taps a former terrorist and, well, Bob Ross</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/philippines-in-tatters-trump-taps-a-former-terrorist-and-well-bob-ross/sbweyrlv1</link><description>Typhoon Fung Wong leaves a vast trail of destruction in the Philippines, Syrian President Al-Sharaa shoots hoops before meeting Trump and Trump COPs it in Brazil. Also Zelenskyy under fire from corruption allegations, why AI is spreading Russian propaganda, and Bob Ross makes a splash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b4aa2dac9a2fef38e6230d1c2e65c2f</guid></item><item><title>Neo-Nazi Thomas Sewell freed on bail over alleged Camp Sovereignty attack</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/neo-nazi-thomas-sewell-freed-on-bail-after-leading-alleged-attack-on-camp-sovereignty/c6l25kf2k</link><description>Sewell was met with jeers after he was bailed from court on Thursday, more than two months after he allegedly led a group attack on Camp Sovereignty.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4688a81b40322c4547cc3653a684341e</guid></item><item><title>CEO Series: Xero&amp;apos;s Sukhinder Singh Cassidy &amp;amp; ASX tumbles on jobs gain</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ceo-series-xeros-sukhinder-singh-cassidy-asx-tumbles-on-jobs-gain/ehl367j13</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Xero CEO Sukhinder Singh Cassidy following the accounting software group&amp;apos;s 42% rise in half-year profit to find out where growth is coming from and how it is using AI; Devika Shivadekar from RSM Australia goes through the better-than expected labour force report to explain what it means for interest rates; plus the market reaction with Zoran Kresovic from Blueberry Markets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95f1ea75c6d424498affe771fdb4d075</guid></item><item><title>FIFA World Cup qualifiers: Who is locked in, as former winners still chase a 2026 spot</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/who-is-in-and-who-is-chasing-a-fifa-world-cup-2026-spot/oxr5s7wx3</link><description>More than half of the men&amp;apos;s World Cup teams are already confirmed, while the fate of several others will be decided in the coming days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e637d004e5a331ecc2d7b206159f3ff</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Cigars and champagne&amp;apos;: The Netanyahu corruption case at the centre of Trump&amp;apos;s pardon plea</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/netanyahu-corruption-case-trump-pardon/v4gxdetkv</link><description>The Israeli prime minister has faced a years-long trial over allegations of fraud and accepting bribes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1750883f232dae4f7e801aeaccea802</guid></item><item><title>Historic Victorian treaty the start of a new era, Indigenous leaders say</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/historic-victorian-treaty-the-start-of-a-new-era-indigenous-leaders-say/7ipkigzi4</link><description>It&amp;apos;s been hailed as a moment centuries in the making: the signing of Australia&amp;apos;s first ever state-wide treaty with Aboriginal people, described as something once thought impossible. The Australian-first treaty will take effect just before Christmas but will not be up and running until mid-2026. And for both sides signing the pact in Victoria, there&amp;apos;s recognition of more hard work that needs to be done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ae4a4374684fe32c399b54720e3ad5b</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;flawed&amp;apos; health star ratings face criticism as they hit a deadline</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/health-star-rating-system-changes-criticism/g2el9r52i</link><description>A deadline for Australia&amp;apos;s contentious Health Star Rating system has arrived — and could spark big change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9fe374081f72f80f4ecf16caeade36d</guid></item><item><title>How this rising star responded to men telling her she was &amp;apos;too pretty to do comedy&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/elouise-eftos-on-being-hot-and-funny/o9g7f07xl</link><description>Elouise Eftos is used to people judging her on her appearance. With her hit debut comedy show, she&amp;apos;s having the last laugh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9c44e9f97a145f55d9c0b0d66b7dfb6</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley rejects claims Liberals are losing young voters | Morning News Bulletin 14 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sussan-ley-rejects-claims-liberals-are-losing-young-voters-morning-news-bulletin-14-november-2025/t2skmz0t9</link><description>Sussan Ley rejects claims Liberals are losing young voters after net-zero shift; Tasmania lower house backs $1.13b Macquarie Point stadium plan; And in Soccer, Deni Juric ruled out as Socceroos prepare for Venezuela clash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb55d3845c31565625bc943cdf4e6648</guid></item><item><title>Israel identifies deceased hostage returned by Hamas</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-receives-hostage-body-hamas/hn8fmz46m</link><description>Israeli authorities say the bodies of three hostages are still being held in the Gaza Strip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0f8f02fe00b8aa6aedde2b473d22ee2</guid></item><item><title>Having &amp;apos;a crack&amp;apos;: What&amp;apos;s the go with the social media ban?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/having-a-crack-whats-the-go-with-the-social-media-ban/einc5zepz</link><description>Weeks out from Australia&amp;apos;s world-first age restrictions being implemented, there are still plenty of questions about the platforms that will fall under the ban, the ones that won&amp;apos;t and how companies are actually going to figure out users&amp;apos; ages at all. This week, Elfy and Rania chat about what we know so far and how it&amp;apos;s all reflecting on the Albanese government right now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cf8a3211a93d713ed815b19fff6d734</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Crushing waves&amp;apos;, not &amp;apos;shore dumps&amp;apos;: Are beach warnings failing overseas visitors?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fatal-risk-beach-signs-cause-confusion-for-international-visitors-and-australians-born-overseas/n881v9j9l</link><description>As summer approaches and many gear up for a swim at the beach, a study suggests unclear warning signs to non-English speakers are posing risks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8461982c271d3f7ba8c1b097c7088024</guid></item><item><title>BBC apologises to Donald Trump over documentary speech edit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bbc-apologises-to-trump-over-documentary-speech-edit/qpu91ix8b</link><description>The news organisation said, however, that it strongly disagrees that there are grounds for a defamation claim.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7a5600a0ee84650f7939434436909a8c</guid></item><item><title>Schools in Canberra and Brisbane closed after asbestos found in children&amp;apos;s coloured sand</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sudden-closure-of-several-canberra-schools-after-asbestos-found-in-childrens-coloured-sand/02ridnmhf</link><description>The children&amp;apos;s sand — used for sensory play and arts and crafts — has been recalled after testing revealed it may contain traces of asbestos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef73db22f869c6757ea5cab4d0e50c67</guid></item><item><title>The mystery of Australia&amp;apos;s deepest lake has finally been solved</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lake-st-clair-tasmania-depth-revealed-by-csiro/zghb92b9j</link><description>A CSIRO team spent nine days on Tasmania&amp;apos;s Lake St Clair, and they&amp;apos;ve finally answered one key question: how deep it really is.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8de106bf1d27dc4afd0c9c357ddb2fb6</guid></item><item><title>Settler attack on a mosque sparks international condemnation</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/settler-attack-on-a-mosque-sparks-international-condemnation/67vj1xmja</link><description>A fresh settler attack on a mosque in the occupied West Bank has drawn sharp international condemnation and intensified scrutiny of Israel’s handling of rising violence in the territory. The arson and vandalism at Deir Istiya, which left Korans burned and hate-filled graffiti on the walls, comes amid warnings from the United Nations that such assaults risk fuelling a wider regional crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e0e5c73bbf34590a027b5e8f06b88e9</guid></item><item><title>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley defends her new climate policy | Midday News Bulletin 14 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/opposition-leader-sussan-ley-defends-her-new-climate-policy-midday-news-bulletin-14-november-2025/2poqb97w9</link><description>Opposition Leader Sussan Ley defends the international acceptability of her new climate policy, Some Canberra schools closed over asbestos contamination fears, Former Socceroos coach Graham Arnold has Iraq within touching distance of next year&amp;apos;s World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58ba7616c5a41f92d518128258457b7d</guid></item><item><title>Hopes dashed as global fossil fuel emissions increase in 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/hopes-dashed-as-global-fossil-fuel-emissions-increase-in-2025/k0id8j79i</link><description>For the second straight year, emissions from fossil fuels rose by slightly more than one per cent. Scientists at the COP30 climate conference in Brazil say it&amp;apos;s one of the smallest in recent non-pandemic years - but it means efforts to curb warming global temperatures by getting fossil fuel emissions to stop rising are still not meeting targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bb89cf3af108eb31aae56f05e72fa63</guid></item><item><title>‘Popping champagne corks’: Climate change boss lashes Coalition for dumping net zero</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/climate-change-authority-criticises-coalition-net-zero/i7ygs99y5</link><description>Matt Kean said his former party is walking away from scientific evidence — and pandering to mining lobbyists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80e5ca7fad5fee5fdf12a2ef71eb66df</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 14 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-14-november-2025/zvuq0y2fb</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db5a251ad6708b93703da194f4c63cc4</guid></item><item><title>Concerns growing after 20th US strike on alleged Venezuelan drug boats</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/concerns-growing-after-20th-us-strike-on-alleged-venezuelan-drug-boats/x1gr4nwb3</link><description>The Venezuelan army is vowing to defend the nation as a 100 thousand tonne US warship is stationed in its waters. The aircraft carrier’s deployment follows the US defence secretary announcing a new operation to counter drug trafficking in the western hemisphere. But there’s concern about the legality of the US operations, and the truth of their allegations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41be2003b7a33f3b9ff856006a9de6aa</guid></item><item><title>What does the treaty with Indonesia actually mean?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/what-does-the-treaty-with-indonesia-actually-mean/peupx11yr</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s leaders remain circumspect about the terms of a security agreement with a key northern neighbour after finalising the deal with Indonesia&amp;apos;s president. But Prime Minister Anthony Albanese says the deal commits the nations to consult regularly on matters of security, and consider possible measures should either&amp;apos;s security be threatened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eecb989414f61d536de60c5697e054d7</guid></item><item><title>Dementia now Australia&amp;apos;s biggest killer, as leading causes of death revealed</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-causes-of-death-dementia-2024/h18jp7paz</link><description>Dementia deaths have risen steadily over the past decade, reflecting Australia&amp;apos;s ageing population, according to the ABS.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3887ae3583fd296d2201bed87229222a</guid></item><item><title>Former boyfriend of childcare teacher pleads guilty to her murder | Evening News Bulletin 14 November 2024</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/former-boyfriend-of-childcare-teacher-pleads-guilty-to-her-murder-evening-news-bulletin-14-november-2024/b8fsokvyl</link><description>The former boyfriend of childcare teacher Molly Ticehurst pleads guilty to her murder, Chris Bowen says Coalition have counted themselves out of climate conversation, Kylian Mbappe helps France book a spot in their eighth consecutive World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3ccfd0353b60db204772696623843d6</guid></item><item><title>20,000 new Epstein documents just dropped. Here&amp;apos;s what we learned</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/20-000-new-epstein-documents-just-dropped-heres-what-we-learned/6107i153v</link><description>The White House criticised the Democrats&amp;apos; smaller document release, saying it was selectively chosen to make Trump look bad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85b5919cb62675f87990c7c9007d85ef</guid></item><item><title>UK court rules BHP liable for Brazil&amp;apos;s environmental disaster | Morning Bulletin 15 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/uk-court-rules-bhp-liable-for-brazils-environmental-disaster-morning-bulletin-15-november-2025/k20xa4e6x</link><description>A UK court rules mining company BHP is liable for Brazil&amp;apos;s worst environmental disaster; schools remain on alert after an asbestos warning issued in the ACT; and in rugby league, the future of Melbourne Storm star Eli Katoa uncertain after brain surgery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4bc7ed3e5912b98f1dc3bc9867616079</guid></item><item><title>This film starring Rose Byrne airs the unspeakable parts of motherhood</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/if-i-had-legs-id-kick-you-film-asks-what-if-a-mother-regrets-children/88i3o5x66</link><description>Motherhood is often seen as an idealised, glossy experience. But this new film from Rose Byrne aims to unpack the stigma that comes with regretting having children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7eb1a186806a1035a3b69616bd323e80</guid></item><item><title>How David&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;game-changing&amp;apos; system saves him up to $50,000 a year</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/david-game-changing-system-saves-50000/opo8a2a37</link><description>Small business owner David Stuart was spending about $24,000 a year on electricity — until a solar overhaul changed everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2f27ef33f0ae96a3f14d50e0d659416</guid></item><item><title>Trump orders criminal investigation into Epstein&amp;apos;s alleged ties to Clinton and other Democrats</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-orders-criminal-investigation-into-epsteins-alleged-ties-to-clinton-and-other-democrats/lap4lr4dx</link><description>The move comes two days after a congressional committee released thousands of documents that raised new questions about Trump&amp;apos;s relationship with the late financier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">347ca41ad7aeb7899c961b98f2d90b51</guid></item><item><title>Mining giant BHP can be held liable over deadly Brazilian dam collapse, UK court rules</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/mining-giant-bhp-can-be-held-liable-over-deadly-brazilian-dam-collapse-uk-high-court-rules/nwomwtyq0</link><description>Hundreds of thousands of Brazilians, dozens of local governments and around 2,000 businesses sued BHP over the collapse of the Fundao dam in Mariana in 2015.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74f3cef1f2f6406acf17fbf3ab873f35</guid></item><item><title>April Le Sueur claims 2025 NATSI Sports Award</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/april-le-sueur-claims-2025-natsi-sports-award/clej1o01a</link><description>A young volunteer for a football club in central Victoria has won the National Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander (NATSI) Sports Awards this year. April Le Sueur has been volunteering at the Rumbalara Football and Netball Club in the Victorian town of Shepparton. She&amp;apos;s also the AFL Young Leader of the Year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88e329b65f1d649113dbe61ab844c0be</guid></item><item><title>As power prices surge, David has found ways to cut running costs by thousands</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/as-power-prices-surge-david-has-found-ways-to-cut-running-costs-by-thousands/b8175zrzi</link><description>Rising electricity prices are a major driver of headline inflation, putting pressure on households and Australia’s 2.6 million small business owners. Some are beating the odds – here’s how.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a65646c60d35224cd829b93c9f3bc12d</guid></item><item><title>Three dead, others injured after bus ploughs into stop in Stockholm</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/three-dead-others-injured-after-bus-ploughs-into-stop-in-stockholm/i42yrmore</link><description>Swedish police said the driver had been arrested, but there was no information pointing to it being an attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e1497bf954997a603e49c205fc035d2</guid></item><item><title>Australia welcomes Trump&amp;apos;s backtrack on food-import tariffs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-cuts-tariffs-on-food-imports-including-australian-beef-amid-grocery-price-fears/n7710l8um</link><description>The new exemptions mark a sharp reversal for US President Donald Trump, who has long insisted that his import duties are not fuelling inflation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4c895325469b89f8db6a2ccb2c7197f</guid></item><item><title>Bowen heads to Brazil to push Australia&amp;apos;s COP31 hosting bid amid standoff with Türkiye</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bowen-heads-to-brazil-to-push-for-australias-cop31-bid-amid-standoff-with-turkiye/6yupway4l</link><description>The climate change minister said the COP31 bid was backed by Pacific island nations and would allow Australia to showcase its clean energy industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6862f70a65a4fb30498efd381f1bb57</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s Climate Change Minister travels to Brazil for UN summit | Midday Bulletin 15 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australias-climate-change-minister-travels-to-brazil-for-un-summit-midday-bulletin-15-november-2025/jcz1dkfe2</link><description>In this bulletin, Australia&amp;apos;s Climate Change Minister travels to Brazil for the final week of negotiations at the UN Climate Summit; a five-metre tall statue of Pope Leo unveiled in Peru; and in tennis, Alex De Minaur to face defending champion Jannik Sinner in the semis of the ATP Finals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">823f087750c0ac85aaa6a7ccc308a8c6</guid></item><item><title>Worth up to $100k and hidden in chocolate boxes: Inside Australia&amp;apos;s illegal animal trade</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/wildlife-black-market-in-australia/r4p7qz2m7</link><description>Global illegal trade in wildlife is estimated to be worth $32 billion, with rare species in Australia at risk.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4788a1f38cac23238f9867c1e2d90610</guid></item><item><title>&amp;quot;You turn on the tap and there&amp;apos;s no water&amp;quot;: inside Iran&amp;apos;s water crisis</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/you-turn-on-the-tap-and-theres-no-water-inside-irans-water-crisis/lcb3o8u9c</link><description>Iran is experiencing an unprecedented water crisis, which has not been seen for more than six decades. Tehran, famous for its surrounding snowy mountains, has had no rain in over 200 days, and its main water sources are in a dire situation. Two major dams supplying the capital are at less than 10 per cent capacity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">134d30181c26298c77b8e31a68f618da</guid></item><item><title>Evening News Bulletin 15 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/evening-news-bulletin-15-november-2025/dnp7gykov</link><description>A Sydney driver charged over the death of a woman and her unborn baby; The UN to probe allegations of atrocities in Sudan; Scans clear England ace Mark Wood ahead of the first Ashes test against Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db401773e41c51ab7f0334bbd985be27</guid></item><item><title>New health advice issued after asbestos found in kids&amp;apos; play sand sold at major retailers</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/new-health-advice-issued-after-asbestos-found-in-kids-play-sand/e2gc116j7</link><description>Regulators say the health risk is low but recommend careful disposal methods as the investigation into contaminated play sand continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">809cc6c136a05261bdc2b0cbde55e9d3</guid></item><item><title>At least nine killed, 27 injured in &amp;apos;accidental explosion&amp;apos; in Indian-controlled Kashmir</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/at-least-nine-killed-29-injured-in-confiscated-explosives-blast-in-indian-controlled-kashmir/jtnod0nsg</link><description>A police official said forensic and chemical examinations of previously recovered explosive materials were underway when &amp;quot;an accidental explosion&amp;quot; occurred.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">359c40183dcab2915c1f1ef35ed54f5b</guid></item><item><title>Morning News Bulletin 16 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/morning-news-bulletin-16-november-2025/wkgncdsp8</link><description>Coalition to finalise new climate stance as party drops net-zero target; Heavy rainfall destroys makeshift shelters in Gaza; And in football, Socceroos coach says the team must improve after losing to Venezuela.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d28c27ba0c2221be876f6cdefe946d47</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;So fast, so powerful&amp;apos;: What it&amp;apos;s like to survive one of Japan&amp;apos;s bear attacks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/a-rise-in-bear-attacks-in-japan-has-locals-hunting-for-answers-this-town-has-an-innovative-solution/zj1ooywde</link><description>Japan has unleashed the army and riot police to deal with record-high bear attacks. Here&amp;apos;s how one town is using dogs to stay safe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5990b0b886ee12c62f143c676d82e27e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The worst possible situation&amp;apos;: This major city only has a few days of water left</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tehran-only-has-a-few-days-of-water-left/c7u3x80ig</link><description>Tehran&amp;apos;s main water sources are in a dire situation, with two major dams reaching what officials are calling &amp;quot;dead capacity&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8c3b76ca9d59ac5b161a4462d018f23</guid></item><item><title>Rare Australian animals increasingly targeted for illegal wildlife trade</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/rare-australian-animals-increasingly-targeted-for-illegal-wildlife-trade/z3kd2q3o6</link><description>The estimated global illegal trade in wildlife is estimated to be worth 32 billion dollars - and with so many rare species in Australia, the nation&amp;apos;s animals are vulnerable to being targeted by black market traders. To mark the International Day for the Prevention of and Fight Against All Forms of Transnational Organised Crime, local researchers are working to expose, prevent and disrupt this industry which is having a devastating impact on ecology and industry.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35e57ed80520173d3bc0cce69c00023a</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: NITV Radio talks to Dr Harry Hobbs on Victoria&amp;apos;s treaty becoming law</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-nitv-radio-talks-to-dr-harry-hobbs-on-victorias-treaty-becoming-law/rj3bkrqua</link><description>This week a treaty between Victoria and the state&amp;apos;s First Nations people became law. Victorian Premier Jacinta Allan, First Peoples&amp;apos; Assembly of Victoria co-chairs Ngarra Murray and Rueben Berg signed the treaty at a formal ceremony at Government House on Thursday morning. Kerri-Lee Barry from SBS&amp;apos; NITV Radio has spoken with UNSW Law &amp;amp; Justice Associate Professor, Dr Harry Hobbs, about the historic agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80e3e86b27c533cf6abd7572ba4ca693</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy renews calls for more air defence after deadly Russian strike on Kyiv</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/zelenskyy-renews-calls-for-more-air-defence-after-deadly-russian-strike-on-kyiv/bskuq0ic5</link><description>The death toll from Friday&amp;apos;s attack on Kyiv had risen to seven after an elderly woman died in hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46f22e85c2688ddaa4bd44f4303fdc63</guid></item><item><title>Major MAGA figure says she&amp;apos;s facing threats fuelled by Trump after split over Epstein files</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/marjorie-taylor-greene-says-facing-threats-fueled-by-trump-after-split-over-epstein-files/9r4n1te0d</link><description>Marjorie Taylor Greene was one of only four House Republicans who joined Democrats in signing a petition to force a vote on releasing the files related to Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d467692916c6ce7115b0e6a2dd4afb0b</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: The Great Koala Count and the citizen scientists involved</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-the-great-koala-count-and-the-citizen-scientists-involved/mlasfn4vm</link><description>Scientists in South Australia are asking the public to help count koalas - in a citizen science initiative that could have national implications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67813a585a5c73646fc792a677c17eed</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: The Great Koala Count and the citizen scientists involved</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-the-great-koala-count-and-citizen-scientists-involved/mlasfn4vm</link><description>Scientists in South Australia are asking the public to help count koalas - in a citizen science initiative that could have national implications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d78b6d21cb55259b0dd82caaa181bc1</guid></item><item><title>Coalition attempts to present united front on climate policy | Midday News Bulletin 16 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/coalition-attempts-to-present-united-front-on-climate-policy-midday-news-bulletin-16-november-2025/qdvnpok7q</link><description>The Coalition attempts to present a united front on climate policy; Pope Leo celebrates cinema in a meeting with Hollywood stars; And in Tennis, Alex de Minaur says he will come back stronger after ATP Finals defeat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29fab18c6d61c09210ee97f06f07e313</guid></item><item><title>Coalition attempts to present united front on climate policy | Midday News Bulletin 16 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/midday-news-bulletin-16-november-2025/qdvnpok7q</link><description>The Coalition attempts to present a united front on climate policy; Pope Leo celebrates cinema in a meeting with Hollywood stars; And in Tennis, Alex de Minaur says he will come back stronger after ATP Finals defeat.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8734636e913c03e64a755b982bbe8f45</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians who &amp;apos;mysteriously&amp;apos; landed in South Africa had third-country approval, Israel says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gazans-palestinians-mysteriously-land-on-a-plane-in-south-africa/6yvrhb4w6</link><description>South African President Cyril Ramaphosa said it seemed like the Gazans &amp;quot;were being flushed out&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdeeb309b555a8e27576f088b69689ab</guid></item><item><title>Thousands march in Brazil in first big UN climate protest in years</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/thousands-march-in-brazil-in-first-big-un-climate-protest-in-years/t1fxiwnwj</link><description>It was the first major protest outside the annual climate talks since COP26 four years ago in Glasgow.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67286e528706bb1980dc3a8e7e830ea5</guid></item><item><title>UK Labour strips asylum seeker rights amid surging support for Nigel Farage&amp;apos;s Reform party</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/uk-labour-strips-asylum-seeker-rights-amid-surging-support-for-nigel-farages-reform-party/b2gp2vjks</link><description>Among other changes, the duty to provide support to certain asylum seekers, including housing and weekly allowances, will be revoked.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7338167010cd13120672bdaac90e07f</guid></item><item><title>Evening News Bulletin 16 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/evening-news-bulletin-16-november-2025/h56mhv8gj</link><description>The Coalition deciding on its formal net zero climate position; Britain to announce massive changes to its asylum seeker policies; The Wallabies record a major loss to Ireland in their Dublin tour match.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0f687781de07176baa1e3a9ded59e54</guid></item><item><title>Opposition presents its plan to put power prices at the centre of climate and energy policy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/opposition-presents-its-plan-to-put-power-prices-at-the-centre-of-climate-and-energy-policy/f2dnh0zl3</link><description>After a period of internal dispute over emissions reduction targets, the Coalition has presented a climate and energy plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4aeb9a96b848c7f26a740e5246549466</guid></item><item><title>&amp;quot;Australia have got this&amp;quot;: Socceroos remember World Cup qualifier against Uruguay, 20 years on</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australia-have-got-this-socceroos-remember-world-cup-qualifier-against-uruguay-20-years-on/hln45p3bt</link><description>In 2005, the Socceroos defeated Uruguay in Sydney, qualifying for the FIFA World Cup for the first time in 32 years. Twenty years later, two of the men that played a key role in securing the victory have reunited to recount the night few will ever forget.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c6b5ecbd6935f31b1144244ece8e90b</guid></item><item><title>Need a new job? These are the top 10 skills Australian employers are looking for</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/top-job-skills-australian-employers-are-looking-for/ztg10usiz</link><description>Despite concerns about AI and job losses, there is enduring demand for uniquely human skills, new analysis suggests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90a8960348d06e42bb89c22ebd47fa2f</guid></item><item><title>I was abandoned as a baby. I want to ask my mother why</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/i-was-abandoned-as-a-baby-i-want-to-ask-my-mother-why/tzx5ywxvm</link><description>As a newborn, Caron Michelle Brown was left on the steps of a health clinic. She&amp;apos;s still searching for her mother — and her own identity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffb13f973cf24310f0a247ad8d4f107a</guid></item><item><title>Asbestos scare spreads as nearly 70 ACT public schools to close over contaminated sands</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/asbestos-scare-spreads-as-nearly-70-act-public-schools-to-close-over-contaminated-sands/0nx5uo40x</link><description>An asbestos scare linked to coloured sand products has prompted dozens of school closures as decontamination work continues.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5658e7a64d20426786d4e9bdd0fb7b8</guid></item><item><title>Australia downplays co-hosting COP31 after Türkiye proposes sharing event</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/turkiye-proposes-co-hosting-cop31-with-australia-amid-deadlock-over-hosting-rights/63vhu2hdr</link><description>Australia and Türkiye both submitted bids in 2022 to host COP31, and neither has withdrawn, leading to an attention-sapping impasse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55e1703a2a61e505e375c7b217065e63</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Uniquely placed&amp;apos;: Albanese to pitch Australia&amp;apos;s trade potential after tariff breakthrough</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-set-to-pitch-australias-trade-potential-after-tariff-breakthrough/hskecckna</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s place as a middle power on the international stage is the focus of a major speech by the prime minister.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a929b7dfe8ee7094c747c16a41e86135</guid></item><item><title>Coalition to unveil policy to cut immigration | Morning News Bulletin 17 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/coalition-set-to-prioritise-migration-cuts-before-next-election-morning-news-bulletin-17-november-2025/kgtttx8b6</link><description>The Coalition sets a timeline for unveiling immigration policy, nearly 70 schools in the ACT closed due to asbestos concerns, Portugal qualify for the World Cup after defeating Armenia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">234abe74ef439f29665a89e68538f0b6</guid></item><item><title>Murder of anti-drug mayor sparks Gen Z protests in Mexico</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gen-z-protests-against-crime-and-corruption-in-mexico-after-mayors-murder/3k1s8yra4</link><description>More than 100 people were injured in the protests, which were sparked by the assassination of the mayor of the western city of Uruapan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">666049af5b6bd247d603fc7ef5efc6f1</guid></item><item><title>Coalition cements climate policy: no net zero, more fossil fuel as a move towards nuclear</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/coalition-cements-climate-policy-no-net-zero-more-fossil-fuel-as-a-move-towards-nuclear/s3xi9d3di</link><description>The Coalition has formally solidified its dumping of the net zero emissions target in a party room meeting in Canberra. But it&amp;apos;s gone much further, with the Liberals and Nationals unveiling a plan to strip climate change from the national energy regulator&amp;apos;s list of objectives, while vowing to continue to reduce emissions by monitoring the progress of other countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2692039584d691af58407f93aa904a0</guid></item><item><title>More schools found to have asbestos-contaminated sand products | Midday News Bulletin 17 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/more-schools-found-to-have-asbestos-contaminated-sand-products-midday-news-bulletin-17-november-2025/qdqk8uupv</link><description>Remediation underway after the recall of asbestos-contaminated sand products, The Coalition attempts to win over voters with its energy policy, Jannik Sinner successfully defends his ATP Finals title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7cba89d32dbf128cb95b8f040bdeb6ae</guid></item><item><title>Netanyahu voices opposition to Palestinian state ahead of UN Security Council vote on Gaza</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/netanyahu-voices-opposition-to-palestinian-state-ahead-of-un-security-council-vote-on-gaza/divvx2sje</link><description>The draft resolution would follow the US-brokered ceasefire deal between Israel and Hamas and mentions a possible future Palestinian state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb96222e77e937f2a6d00e8ab566b5ee</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We are heartbroken&amp;apos;: Australian cycling mourns Paralympian gold medallist Paige Greco</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-paralympic-gold-medallist-paige-greco-dies-aged-28/rfmq1rg8u</link><description>The para-cyclist died in her Adelaide home on Sunday after experiencing a &amp;quot;sudden medical episode&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dbc9956691a27e1da9df00e46e0b1d7</guid></item><item><title>As the play sand asbestos scare continues to grow, here&amp;apos;s what we know so far</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/coloured-sand-asbestos-explainer-schools/yljs38aya</link><description>More recalls, more Canberra school closures, and the sand has been found at over 100 sites in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6684590fd0c1a90309a8a321afd34feb</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 17 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-17-november-2025/j3vw1spz1</link><description>A five minute bullet in for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95d72df35870f7fa843e1ded3dfd0b8b</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese dismisses the Coalition&amp;apos;s climate policy | Evening News Bulletin 17 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/anthony-albanese-dismisses-the-coalitions-climate-policy-evening-news-bulletin-17-november-2025/pyent4mv2</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese dismisses the Coalition&amp;apos;s climate policy, Donald Trump says Republicans should vote to release the Epstein files Australian Paralympic cyclist Paige Greco dies suddenly, aged 28.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24b73764aafa866b84a7060b6df86246</guid></item><item><title>Three day US government shutdown ends, but investors still nervous</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/three-day-us-government-shutdown-ends-but-investors-still-nervous/5h0s17ups</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with George Boubouras from K2 Asset Management Ltd about the day&amp;apos;s market moves including how the US government shutdown will impact the US Federal Reserve&amp;apos;s next interest rate decision, plus a preview of Nvidia&amp;apos;s quarterly results.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">075fc07c3cc023472110c4a78b7bf218</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Difficult territory&amp;apos;: What happens if we don&amp;apos;t reach net zero?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/difficult-territory-what-happens-if-we-dont-reach-net-zero/1b7jbom72</link><description>Failing to achieve net zero would &amp;quot;disproportionately&amp;quot; exacerbate the climate impacts projected for Australia, experts say. Here&amp;apos;s how.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89e1743eef401f185e4becb62ba7bfc8</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Gets under the skin&amp;apos;: The disadvantage shaping the future of 950,000 Australian kids</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/child-poverty-australian-children-future/c2lpnm276</link><description>A new report shines a light on how poverty is impacting a growing number of Australian kids.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73d1992197486863a9dc7bbb3f7bf626</guid></item><item><title>SBS News goes one on one with Federal Opposition Leader Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-goes-one-on-one-with-federal-opposition-leader-sussan-ley/4fi9gxm9m</link><description>Just days after her party ditched its support of net zero emissions targets, federal Opposition Leader Sussan Ley talks to SBS Chief Political Correspondent Anna Henderson about that policy, immigration, and more in a lengthy one on one interview.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc16ecff020484dffd458bb692a50257</guid></item><item><title>UK cuts asylum seeker rights in major overhaul</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/uk-cuts-asylum-seeker-rights-in-major-overhaul/il4723ly1</link><description>Sweeping changes have been announced to Britain&amp;apos;s controversial asylum system as polls show immigration has overtaken the economy as voters&amp;apos; top concern. The Labour government has been hardening its immigration policies as it seeks to stem the surging popularity of the populist Reform UK party, which has driven the immigration agenda and forced Labour to adopt a tougher line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">646b9363840b136f5c89df47f5fa9af2</guid></item><item><title>South African man&amp;apos;s Australian visa cancelled after neo-Nazi rally outside NSW parliament</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/neo-nazi-matthew-gruters-visa-has-been-cancelled/kotrcbjyg</link><description>Matthew Gruter was one of the 60 demonstrators who took part in a protest touting Hitler slogans outside NSW parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">938d721325ab77dd08ccb8b39392453b</guid></item><item><title>Ley confident she retains Liberal party room support amid leadership speculation</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ley-confident-retains-liberal-support-leadership-speculation/owasmf1iq</link><description>Amid fresh leadership chatter, the Opposition leader says the Coalition&amp;apos;s energy deal proves she still has party support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c92d3873214fa1486211d9f4b9a8be4</guid></item><item><title>Bangladesh&amp;apos;s ousted prime minister sentenced to death over students crackdown</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bangladeshs-ousted-prime-minister-sentenced-to-death-over-students-crackdown/fov6r7uzu</link><description>The highly anticipated ruling, which was broadcast live on national television, comes ahead of the first polls since her overthrow in August 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">13d6c12e55adab52e954159be7a3f0e2</guid></item></channel></rss>