<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>SBS English News (Unofficial Aggregation)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Natural disasters are growing; could an army of young volunteers help?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/natural-disasters-are-growing-could-an-army-of-young-volunteers-help/nv2fml0m7</link><description>Could a &amp;apos;Climate Army&amp;apos; of young volunteers bolster Australia&amp;apos;s capability to cope with natural disasters? That&amp;apos;s the question before a Senate inquiry looking at proposals for a new national scheme.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4012959b048ebd549cdba64bd93b0dc3</guid></item><item><title>Dozens killed as Typhoon Bualoi batters Vietnam and Philippines</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/typhoon-bualoi-kills-dozens-in-vietnam-and-philippines/zgrii0crt</link><description>In Vietnam, Bualoi made landfall as a typhoon late on Sunday, generating winds of 130 kmh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">294bb33600199b981f46222561e08fce</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;They destroy lives&amp;apos;: How property investors lost millions to a failed housing scheme</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/these-investors-lost-millions-to-failed-sda-housing-scheme/zid4j9ewc</link><description>A group of Iranians were told that investing in Australian specialist disability accommodation would be as safe as houses. However, those plans never eventuated, and they&amp;apos;ve collectively lost $1,178,500.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53300a3f9b334dcbc924a094f88a0858</guid></item><item><title>Spouses for sale: Inside the black market for skilled visa applications</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/spouses-for-sale-inside-the-black-market-for-skilled-visa-applications/hrvnc37nc</link><description>SBS has uncovered a black market operating on apps targeting members of the Chinese community, selling places for &amp;quot;spouses&amp;quot; in permanent residency skilled visa applications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e7a77bd82514e11385471ec271d5e9a</guid></item><item><title>Vital role of translators celebrated amid AI challenge</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/vital-role-of-translators-celebrated-amid-ai-challenge/maplcq05e</link><description>It&amp;apos;s been eight years since the United Nations first recognised International Translation Day. The celebration falls on 30 September and recognises the work of language professionals who foster cultural understanding, connection and social cohesion. But some translators and interpreters in Australia believe more needs to be done to protect the workforce and bridge language barriers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cca7c253dab026db32408cdd3090946b</guid></item><item><title>Albanese invites Arab &amp;apos;hypermarket&amp;apos; to compete with Coles and Woolworths</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-courts-middle-eastern-supermarket-giant/fr23o8co1</link><description>As Australia grapples with a supermarket monopoly, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese hopes the expansion of this Emirati &amp;quot;hypermarket&amp;quot; might bring in some competition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">502127dd08d1fa8a44e6a84c3eb9bf1e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Hearts are aching&amp;apos;: Family of missing preschooler release statement as search continues</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/search-for-missing-four-year-old-boy-enters-fourth-day-in-remote-south-australia/gtbtpegh8</link><description>Four-year-old Gus disappeared from his family&amp;apos;s remote South Australia property on Saturday afternoon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">59a738147164a3de6a3bb4bf377e93b7</guid></item><item><title>SBS News In Easy English 30 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-30-september-2025/jdhualamn</link><description>A daily 5 minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2b9a3cdb73d968e31be53f8812b1113</guid></item><item><title>Not the outcome Australians wanted, Chalmers says, as Reserve Bank holds cash rate</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rba-decision-cash-rate/nwdfe3zp2</link><description>The Reserve Bank of Australia board was widely tipped to hold the cash rate after inflation data showed successive rises.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edcaa0ba558c5d68fd1ac4541a30ade9</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Disappointing&amp;apos;: Critics say Riyadh Comedy Festival has an unfunny human rights problem</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/saudi-arabia-riyadh-comedy-festival-backlash/hw44zsdc5</link><description>Comedy heavyweights including Dave Chappelle, Jimmy Carr and Louis CK are on the bill of the Riyadh Comedy Festival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">832467142398885fd15650d23814716f</guid></item><item><title>New guidelines developed for helping people with dementia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-guidelines-developed-for-helping-people-with-dementia/03ev9eyth</link><description>A framework has been developed to track and improve the treatment options for dementia patients in aged care. The proposal come after the Australian Institute of Health and Welfare named dementia as the leading cause of death in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ea802cc61d8b0ad130cb82dc87abdef</guid></item><item><title>Key questions around the &amp;apos;tone deaf, very tricky&amp;apos; Trump-Netanyahu Gaza peace plan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-plan-for-gaza-peace-between-hamas-and-israel-explained/wmzir1eb0</link><description>A United States proposal for peace in Gaza has received endorsement from Israel and the Palestinian Authority, but its long-term success is on a knife-edge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa41b708580e8539fd7d807386cc3d99</guid></item><item><title>The PM&amp;apos;s new supermarket proposal might cut your bills, but it&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;no silver bullet&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-the-pms-new-supermarket-proposal-might-cut-your-grocery-bill-but-its-no-silver-bullet/mdb5fp6k9</link><description>The prime minister needs to consider preconditions, such as space and a break-up of Coles and Woolworths, if he wants a competing supermarket to thrive and bring down prices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fd78e743146c58f35bc9919d9bf8008</guid></item><item><title>RBA holds fire; energy stock sell-off</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/rba-holds-fire-energy-stock-sell-off/lsl4zdbqb</link><description>Despite solid gains by the gold miners, a sell-off in energy stocks – fuelled by a continued decline in oil prices – has dragged the Australian sharemarket. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Jonathan Shead, Head of Investment at State Street Investment Management. Plus, the Reserve Bank left interest rates unchanged at 3.6 percent, as expected, at its September board meeting. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Pradeep Philip from Deloitte Access Economics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0550cd1a89a7d892e7859770c95814b</guid></item><item><title>Decision to allow registered nurses to prescribe medicines solves many health service problems</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/decision-to-allow-registered-nurses-to-prescribe-medicines-solves-many-health-service-problems/jmvjlk8bw</link><description>Tens of thousands of registered nurses across the country will be able to up-skill to prescribe medications usually authorised by a doctor. It&amp;apos;s a reform that could change the medical landscape in Australia... and the lives of many patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93ace09bc523bf1c9d83859ab2095c04</guid></item><item><title>Pizza, porn, and getting high: Inside the grip of a severe tech addiction</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/how-talking-in-online-chat-rooms-as-a-teen-changed-quentins-life-as-an-adult/dl6a804ch</link><description>Technology seems a non-negotiable part of everyday life. For Quentin, it became an addiction. After years of trying different ways to break free, it was a 12-step program that helped her into recovery.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">021ecadbbe87617c73bac0a51ff36a19</guid></item><item><title>Fast entry or backwards step? What Labor&amp;apos;s new housing scheme means for you</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fast-entry-or-backwards-step-what-the-new-5-per-cent-deposit-scheme-means-for-you/l7zi865te</link><description>Analysis shows the government&amp;apos;s new First Home Guarantee scheme could slash years off savings times — but experts warn it could come at a cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fcc072a72eed8694761788337fdaa92</guid></item><item><title>Nicole Kidman files for divorce from Keith Urban, citing &amp;apos;irreconcilable differences&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nicole-kidman-files-for-divorce-from-keith-urban-after-19-years-of-marriage/cg9evz0sz</link><description>Oscar-winning star Nicole Kidman and Grammy-winning country musician Keith Urban had been living apart for some time, according to US media reports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">45ab256f4fbe8908a59896353472c35f</guid></item><item><title>A new push for peace: What part did Australia play in the 20-point plan for Gaza?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-part-did-australia-play-in-the-20-point-plan-for-gaza/ono1izwo7</link><description>Anthony Albanese&amp;apos;s stopover in the Middle East came after more lengthy engagements in the US — for the leaders&amp;apos; week at the United Nations — and the UK.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d53efcac4bd727814c78b8c53dbf7535</guid></item><item><title>The US government has shut down. What happens now?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-to-know-about-the-us-government-shutdown/ipl8gg8s0</link><description>The US government has entered a shutdown, meaning thousands of federal employees are being placed on leave or asked to work without pay until the government reopens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3d73438cbd8bfd61429a238bb9c93d1</guid></item><item><title>Albanese &amp;apos;concerned&amp;apos; over China&amp;apos;s reported BHP iron ore ban</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anthony-albanese-concerned-over-chinas-reported-bhp-iron-ore-ban/y9hjt8lcs</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese hopes a pricing dispute between China and the Australian mining giant will be resolved &amp;quot;very quickly&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ad1be6d97a325f8eebc4ca2935f9884</guid></item><item><title>SBS News In Easy English 1 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-1-october-2025/og0ij6kg9</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">634c7c07679bc14f068964ced9de631f</guid></item><item><title>Magnitude-6.9 earthquake kills more than 70 people in the Philippines</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/philippines-6-9-magniture-earthquake-kills-at-least-60/eexymigxd</link><description>The quake, which struck off the central island of Cebu, was the country&amp;apos;s deadliest in more than a decade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77b052b3a82d21bd7b5ba439b5f17230</guid></item><item><title>It happened &amp;apos;by accident&amp;apos;, but Mark is helping tackle a $2.7bn Australian problem</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-in-a-loneliness-crisis-research-suggests/ut4p7mu9o</link><description>Loneliness among men has been described as a &amp;quot;crisis&amp;quot; in Australia, and its estimated to cost the health system billions each year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edb259298a6eaedb69908518aa23d266</guid></item><item><title>BHP-China iron ore stand-off; house prices continue to rise</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/bhp-china-iron-ore-stand-off-house-prices-continue-to-rise/zflasuw75</link><description>The Australian sharemarket has fallen flat, as investors react to the US government shutdown and reports of China temporarily banning purchases of BHP’s iron ore. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Niv Dagan from Peak Asset Management. Plus, Australian house prices continue to rise, as the Albanese Government’s Home Guarantee scheme is expanded to all first home buyers. For more, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Tim Lawless, Asia-Pacific research director at Cotality.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">70dcf961fdca3dd7adda15e950311621</guid></item><item><title>A new First Nations voice to guide Australia&amp;apos;s public health sector</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-new-first-nations-voice-to-guide-australias-public-health-sector/tqvwcecqm</link><description>The Public Health Association of Australia has announced they will be establishing an Aboriginal and Torres-Strait Islander voice to help guide their work after a near unanimous vote by their members. Nearly two years after the failed referendum saw a First Nations voice to parliament shot down, NGOs like the PHAA and state governments have chosen to follow the wishes of the majority of Indigenous communities in Australia who voted for this special representation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8949dfecda1f4bb674fc5069c318ac17</guid></item><item><title>Man cleared of involvement after police swoop on property in search for Dezi Freeman</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/man-cleared-of-involvement-after-police-swoop-on-property-in-search-for-dezi-freeman/igl2yw2r6</link><description>Police hunting Australia&amp;apos;s most wanted fugitive have targeted an area far away from where he was last sighted after he allegedly shot dead two officers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">556a09f354709d0d686cfd8197cc9bb8</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;No more signs of life&amp;apos;: Dozens remain missing after Indonesian school collapse</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/91-children-still-missing-after-indonesian-school-building-collapse/l4aps5xg5</link><description>After days of rescue operations, 59 people were still feared buried under the rubble after at least five people had been confirmed dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">10c1787f60aefe5ecf75c329a17da7a8</guid></item><item><title>Is your sunscreen safe? What to know amid Australia&amp;apos;s SPF ratings storm</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-sunscreen-tga-recall-explainer/rz9nt85bm</link><description>Eighteen sunscreens have either been recalled or had their sale paused in Australia. Here&amp;apos;s what you need to know as the weather gets warmer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39b79060ee7e02aaab39b3a367f61d50</guid></item><item><title>In a battle to build, these five charts show Labor&amp;apos;s housing headache</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-two-year-question-in-labors-housing-battle/ji1yydwv5</link><description>There are doubts major inroads into Australia&amp;apos;s housing supply problem can be made in a couple of years and questions over the government&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;ambitious&amp;quot; 2029 target. So, what can be done?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da71e36dd57187d50283b30ed59ba3a0</guid></item><item><title>I started feeling sick making lunch — and never could&amp;apos;ve expected what came next</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/i-called-triple-zero-after-my-smartwatch-showed-something-unusual-it-saved-my-life/x26zfaffp</link><description>Corinne Laurent doesn’t believe she would still be alive if not for her smartwatch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02ca9d26e84779f88d214d4b0e3afbbd</guid></item><item><title>Wildlife advocate and primate expert Jane Goodall dies at 91</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/wildlife-advocate-and-primate-expert-jane-goodall-dies-at-91/i6ec7swnj</link><description>The renowned conservationist, scientist, and global activist Jane Goodall has died at the age of 91. The Jane Goodall Institute announced the primatologist&amp;apos;s death of natural causes on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">543c18495ebcda15eb2c82d8aec941e4</guid></item><item><title>See the full list: The biggest Australian companies paying the least tax</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/see-the-full-list-the-biggest-australian-companies-paying-the-least-tax/kdgh1o7wg</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s largest companies paid $95.7 billion in taxes, with those paying zero dropping to an 11-year low.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1fe1d3fada847653e05eca180847932d</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 2nd October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-2nd-october-2025/98pmdmae7</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2960dd08a4922185aa54540a6215bbed</guid></item><item><title>Albanese welcomes PNG&amp;apos;s decision to sign landmark defence pact</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-png-defence-pact-gets-green-light-following-cabinet-delay/nt085b3mc</link><description>The pact will elevate the Pacific partnership, ensuring an attack on one would be a &amp;quot;danger to the peace and security of both countries&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a92f04b61fa6d04c67d70b78d7e9ba4d</guid></item><item><title>Albanese welcomes PNG&amp;apos;s decision to sign landmark defence pact</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-welcomes-pngs-decision-to-sign-landmark-defence-pact/nt085b3mc</link><description>The pact will elevate the Pacific partnership, ensuring an attack on one would be a &amp;quot;danger to the peace and security of both countries&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d26cacb840ff16f519299547599c3165</guid></item><item><title>Animal shelter accused of having &amp;apos;blood on its hands&amp;apos; after euthanising 12-week-old puppy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/blood-on-their-hands-row-erupts-over-lost-dogs-homes-puppy-euthanasia-decision/x1ndqdphz</link><description>A couple who had fostered the dog, Murphy, had called Victoria&amp;apos;s Lost Dogs Home to ask how he was going, only to be told he would be put down.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cae637382778e0ba4c6cc697d819a617</guid></item><item><title>Australian men face loneliness crisis: what’s driving it and how to fix it</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australian-men-face-loneliness-crisis-whats-driving-it-and-how-to-fix-it/k47gy4q99</link><description>Loneliness among men has been described as a &amp;quot;crisis&amp;quot; in Australia, and it appears to be on the rise. This social isolation can not only hurt mens mental health and overall wellbeing, it is also costing the Australian economy billions of dollars. A recent Australian study could hold the answer as to why men appear to be stuggling more with loneliness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2699cdf7843c4ff11fd65a92f917da1b</guid></item><item><title>Gaza peace plan, US shuts down &amp;amp; China combats whingers</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gaza-peace-plan-us-shuts-down-china-combats-whingers/sy8wo6r3a</link><description>A new 20-point plan for peace in Gaza gains support among the international community. Trump warns the US military of the enemy from within as Hegseth tells Generals to slim down for the war on woke. Plus, Democrats and Republicans point the finger at each other as the US government shuts down. Also, Moscow warns of a new red line in the war in Ukraine. And, China launches a campaign to stamp out online negativity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cae9b3556147066c2d14b3ea166cca48</guid></item><item><title>Nuclear energy sank the Coalition at the election — can it power their comeback?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nuclear-energy-sank-the-coalition-at-the-election-can-it-power-their-comeback/eqd6mzqsd</link><description>The coalition are revamping their proposal for nuclear energy, despite suffering an election loss with this policy. The details are yet to be confirmed, but the Opposition Energy Minister says they will adapt their plan to meet developments in the space.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ce95ff0c869a7707f7ba7c89bf33d0ea</guid></item><item><title>NIMBYs, YIMBYs — and BIMBYs: The new group in Australia&amp;apos;s housing stoush</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/yimbys-nimbys-and-bimbys-in-australias-housing-stoush/684pjcwmn</link><description>As state governments roll out plans to battle Australia&amp;apos;s housing crisis, community groups are mobilising to have a say in how their suburbs are — or are not — changed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac71bb540a7137e724f30e60564c8b9e</guid></item><item><title>ASX rallies despite US government shutdown</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asx-rallies-despite-us-government-shutdown/ln743tnhv</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Callam Pickering about the latest household spending data and what it means for interest rates, plus Henry Jennings from Marcus Today on the days market action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1c37f8b542f20920bc0294ef6e85ada</guid></item><item><title>Police say they &amp;apos;will not rest&amp;apos; despite scaling back search for boy missing in outback</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/they-just-dont-disappear-into-thin-air-hopes-fading-for-boy-missing-in-south-australian-outback/hhegfsq12</link><description>No significant evidence was found to indicate where Gus may have gone during the massive search involving police, defence force personnel and large numbers of volunteers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e77e1a1ad583bb9fcdf9b59eba347a7</guid></item><item><title>Why experts are &amp;apos;rewriting&amp;apos; Australia&amp;apos;s bushfire risk this summer</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-experts-are-rewriting-australias-bushfire-risk-this-summer/cm2ns4rb1</link><description>Unusual weather patterns and climate change are raising concerns for parts of Australia, as well as popular travel destinations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74b84ba4c6053b03df899ae3bf840b38</guid></item><item><title>New trick Australians are using to &amp;apos;maximise&amp;apos; tax returns — but beware of the risks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-turning-to-ai-to-maximise-tax-returns-research-suggests/cxv17n2n4</link><description>It might be free to use and readily available, but it could also be giving incorrect advice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">18fb8425575513f0bd3949ff904ed080</guid></item><item><title>UK government promises greater security for Jewish community after deadly synagogue attack in Manchester</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/uk-government-promises-greater-security-for-jewish-community-after-deadly-synagogue-attack-in-manchester/bdghdduln</link><description>A WARNING THAT THE FOLLOWING STORY CONTAINS CONTENT THAT MAY BE DISTRESSING FOR SOME LISTENERS Two people have been killed and three others seriously hurt after an assailant drove a car into pedestrians and stabbed a security guard near a synagogue in Manchester in northern England. Greater Manchester Police say officers shot and killed the suspect, who investigators say attacked just as Jewish communities around the world mark Yom Kippur, the holiest holiday in the Jewish calendar.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">78e356f2781e4148efa5ab88aa031d58</guid></item><item><title>Organisers vow to fight police bid to stop pro-Palestinian Opera House rally</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nsw-police-to-fight-pro-palestine-protesters-march-to-sydney-opera-house/9wu8ucyud</link><description>Organisers said banning the rally would violate fundamental rights and set a &amp;quot;dangerous precedent&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a54fc1c86a081a687594ef8d2860c119</guid></item><item><title>What is the Global Sumud Flotilla - and why has Israel intercepted it?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/what-is-the-global-sumud-flotilla-and-why-has-israel-intercepted-it/zj4jw42vi</link><description>Israeli naval forces have intercepted the Global Sumud Flotilla, seizing more than 40 civilian boats and hundreds of activists - including Australians. The action has sparked global protests and condemnation, with Israel saying it is necessary for its own security.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c69b95d6469a538fd67e1752dcdbd87b</guid></item><item><title>New twist in &amp;apos;offensive&amp;apos; pamphlet saga targeting teal MP Allegra Spender</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/new-twist-in-offensive-pamphlet-saga-targeting-teal-mp-allegra-spender/634jez0un</link><description>Legal action follows an investigation by the electoral watchdog into allegedly unauthorised pamphlets targeting the independent MP that she had said were part of a campaign of &amp;quot;dirty tricks&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8f41bd9dd226c3d6871f0a96dffbbb75</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 3 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-3-october-2025/yloxqghu5</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">768b0278ce23523b8b3fabba58bc3ec3</guid></item><item><title>Footy, culture, and so much more: welcome to the Koori knockout</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/footy-culture-and-so-much-more-welcome-to-the-koori-knockout/ardx4qeqz</link><description>This weekend will see the largest annual gathering of Indigenous people in the country at the New South Wales Koori knockout rugby league tournament. It&amp;apos;s a sporting competition... but also, so much more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1aa459fcf3b03e862c3e2aed8b15fe8e</guid></item><item><title>Forwards or backwards? Daylight saving starts soon — here&amp;apos;s what to know</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/when-daylight-saving-time-starts-in-australia-in-2025/67t60uuqb</link><description>Here&amp;apos;s everything you need to know, including tips on how to adjust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f095370d70d3af25e324360142a0835</guid></item><item><title>When do the 2025 NRL and NRLW grand finals start? Here&amp;apos;s everything you need to know</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/when-do-the-2025-nrl-and-nrlw-grand-finals-start/fdj88sefp</link><description>It will be a busy day of footy on Sunday with both the NRL and NRLW grand finals taking place. Here&amp;apos;s what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46d15fe9fc47865d6df86970a318c2c9</guid></item><item><title>Oil prices tumble to 4 month low as ASX edges closer to record high</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/oil-prices-tumble-to-4-month-low-as-asx-edges-closer-to-record-high/ee4eoyhss</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Dianne Colledge from Morgans Financial Limited about the days sharemarket action including the opportunites for investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa53c66df7caad74aee6a6f6ac9017d0</guid></item><item><title>How the Dezi Freeman search could wind down — and how major Australian manhunts ended</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dezi-freeman-police-manhunt/h9o270lc9</link><description>While the operation to find Dezi Freeman is the biggest manhunt in Australia to date in terms of resources, it is far from the longest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3acb245cf6e9c9d2be5a7aeff339c82</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The 99 per cent are not your enemy&amp;apos;: Genesis Owusu on power, politics and racism</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/some-things-need-to-be-said-genesis-owusu-on-speaking-truth-in-a-divided-world/vnmtwxihp</link><description>Genesis Owusu has battled racism, depression and industry pressures — but his third album is his most direct yet. He says it’s a blunt call for truth in an era of division.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d57c833150ae3b366294ff78e399fa4</guid></item><item><title>700 Australians were recruited for a yoga study. What researchers found surprised them</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/yoga-study-older-people-falls/s4gqz30zo</link><description>Many older Australians who practice yoga say it gives them strength and confidence, but a new study suggests one particular type of yoga could be associated with a higher risk of falls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">766326cb3fadeacdbd152085fa484ad8</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Could a First Nations voice help tackle stubborn public health challenges?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-could-a-first-nations-voice-help-tackle-stubborn-public-health-challenges/9o1r5o95q</link><description>Nearly two years after the failed referendum saw a First Nations voice to parliament shot down, some NGOs and state governments have been taking the initiative to follow the wishes of the majority of Indigenous communities in Australia who voted for this special representation. Australia&amp;apos;s principal non-government organisation for public health, the Public Health Association of Australia, has announced they will be instituting an Aboriginal and Torres-Strait Islander voice to help guide their work after a near unanimous vote by their members. SBS spoke to Dr Summer May Finlay, a Yorta Yorta woman, an Associate Professor at the University of Wollongong and the Vice President (Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander) of the Public Health Association about the importance of a First Nations voice in helping to Close the Gap on healthcare outcomes between Indigenous and non-Indigenous Australians</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b72abcb3c66a7c1aa036143c6a6ed3c</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Everyone loves a ghost train: but why do we love being scared?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-everyone-loves-a-ghost-train-but-why-do-we-love-being-scared/u32c8730l</link><description>Scary movies, haunted houses and trick or treating, October is the unofficial start to “spooky season” - at least, that&amp;apos;s what you would think judging by what&amp;apos;s on the shelves in our local shops. Sarah Kollat, teaching professor of psychology at Penn State University in the US, says there are lots of reasons people like to be scared. At a chemical level, our brains and bodies are reacting to the jump scares in a movie and “surviving” a haunted house. But psychologists also say getting scared in a safe environment prepares us for real danger.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80dd3f386e756d22769ecab32573d2e2</guid></item><item><title>The major sticking points that could still upend the partially accepted Gaza peace deal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-major-sticking-points-that-could-still-upend-the-partially-accepted-gaza-peace-deal/r1v3u1nn3</link><description>One expert says a hostage-prisoner exchange between Israel and Hamas is &amp;quot;highly likely&amp;quot; to go ahead, but he and others remain wary about the prospects for other parts of a Gaza peace deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eafb2a9b36df924305576090a027935a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I passed out multiple times at work&amp;apos;: The health problem costing Australia billions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-health-problem-costing-australia-billions/g3usjolbe</link><description>Endometriosis affects one in seven Australian women, yet experts warn workplaces remain years behind in providing support for those living with this &amp;quot;invisible&amp;quot; condition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6dcadce6efd2c049bdf54d58ac15c0d</guid></item><item><title>Why Joel spends his evenings being stabbed in the head with skewers — for fun</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-is-deathmatch-wrestling-and-why-is-it-controversial/nj1sz5e5z</link><description>Blood, thumbtacks, fire, cactus plants and even whipper snippers. Welcome to the world of Australian deathmatch wrestling.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f61856630983c73041efd339266439b</guid></item><item><title>Yazidi refugees in Toowoomba find community through hockey</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/yazidi-refugees-in-toowoomba-find-community-through-hockey/j814wa3h1</link><description>The Queensland city of Toowoomba has become home to thousands of Yazidi refugees. A local hockey program is aiming to develop confidence and language skills for this community, with the help of retired locals on the field.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5f81e55f17530c791f21bcf7b4d475a</guid></item><item><title>Smooth Snake slithering its way back to life in the UK</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/smooth-snake-slithering-its-way-back-to-life-in-the-uk/epgsvimyj</link><description>Snakes may be ten a penny here in Australia but in the UK it&amp;apos;s a different story. Britain&amp;apos;s rarest reptile, known as the Smooth Snake, is thriving again after conservation efforts were introduced to save it in 2009. But monitoring exactly how many Smooth Snakes there are can be a challenge due to the reptile&amp;apos;s reclusive nature.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0577ac3c3db7bfe3fe5b9ffc9a5f20b</guid></item><item><title>Location-tracking apps: A harmful invasion of privacy or a great tool to keep loved ones safe?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/location-tracking-apps-a-great-tool-to-keep-loved-ones-safe-or-a-harmful-invasion-of-privacy/isma6nxvo</link><description>With consent, location-tracking can be immensely useful in some situations, experts say, but they warn that the technology is certainly not without potential harms and can lead to controlling and coercive behaviours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a5fa3dd319ea39f2d1f365c795522bf</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Determination and ingenuity&amp;apos;: Australia&amp;apos;s oldest man just turned 112</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australias-oldest-man-celebrates-life/p7v9yud7i</link><description>Ken Weeks was still walking into town for shopping after he turned 100 more than a decade ago.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bacbbd1941638773676ab40810dfdc13</guid></item><item><title>We now know when your HECS debt will be slashed, and by how much</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/millions-of-australians-to-see-their-student-debts-slashed-heres-what-you-need-to-know/jk27nb331</link><description>About three million Australians with a student debt will soon see their balance owed reduced.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ca91d2f5055b26f7ea83ab864b48208d</guid></item><item><title>A Thatcher-loving heavy metal drummer: Meet Japan&amp;apos;s first female PM-in-waiting</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/japan-woman-prime-minister-sanae-takaichi/31clccs47</link><description>Sanae Takaichi has repeatedly referred to former UK leader Margaret Thatcher as a source of inspiration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c735d6c116c76970cdae66146c730cd</guid></item><item><title>Trump authorises deployment of 300 national guard troops to Chicago</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-national-guard-troops-chicago/x87t47pvr</link><description>The state&amp;apos;s governor said it was &amp;quot;absolutely outrageous and un-American to demand a governor send military troops within our own borders and against our will&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d37794feb24eaed597e65f51d2396b84</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Heartbreaking&amp;apos;: The children Australia won’t bring home from a Syrian detention camp</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-children-australia-wont-bring-home-from-a-syrian-detention-camp/jwnozrffs</link><description>The women and children who recently smuggled themselves out of a Syrian detention camp and returned to Australia proved that the government could bring its citizens home if it had the will, advocates say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4bd65b9a2da97199f0fe974960967c6</guid></item><item><title>Israelis like Michal and Yarden act as &amp;apos;human shields&amp;apos; in the West Bank. They&amp;apos;ve been called traitors</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/israelis-like-michal-and-yarden-act-as-human-shields-in-the-west-bank-theyve-been-called-traitors/il4m5r6gi</link><description>As the second anniversary of October 7 and Israel’s war in Gaza approaches, settler violence in the West Bank is steadily escalating. A small number of Israelis like Yarden want to end the &amp;apos;status quo&amp;apos; — and they&amp;apos;re willing to act as human shields to achieve it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">974283754e15dfcfaddb901970f9ce39</guid></item><item><title>Government summons Optus, Telstra to Canberra over triple-zero failings</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/government-summons-optus-telstra-to-canberra-over-triple-zero-failings/tic2vlzkt</link><description>From 1 November, telcos will be required to provide real-time updates on network failures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1ed9f436ffaf8e337e494512a209a42</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We do not see any change&amp;apos;: Israel pounds Gaza despite Trump&amp;apos;s call for end to bombing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-says-gaza-deal-talks-to-go-on-couple-days-as-rubio-asks-israel-to-stop-bombing/kcyspcgfz</link><description>There was no let-up in Israeli attacks on Gaza over the weekend as planes and tanks pounded areas across the enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49494d7d2fb7fc0e2c5cb09883993f98</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy criticises world &amp;apos;silence&amp;apos; after yet another large-scale Russian attack</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/zelenskyy-criticises-world-silence-after-large-scale-russian-attacks-on-ukraine/0rwbgt2u2</link><description>Five people have died after the Russian military attacked Ukraine overnight with 53 missiles and several waves of drones.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">606b8824cc69c840c6e7dcfe55b0aa92</guid></item><item><title>Police charge alleged gunman with 25 offences after Sydney shooting spree</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sydney-croydon-park-inner-west-shooting-bullets-fired/ba3gob1zg</link><description>Numerous bystanders, cars and police were fired on during a two-hour window in Croydon Park on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40ecb8a44f1738fce9a8b85a3199def5</guid></item><item><title>Space monster: gas-guzzling rogue planet eats all in its path</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/space-monster-gas-guzzling-rogue-planet-eats-all-in-its-path/jd175wu8e</link><description>It sounds like the plot of a science fiction movie from the 1950s - a giant rogue planet, moving through the galaxy at a record-breaking speed, consuming vast quantities of dust and gas . But this isn&amp;apos;t the product of the fevered imagination of a Hollywood writer. This lone planet is very real.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfc4848bc0506bfd7161abd10b64d191</guid></item><item><title>It&amp;apos;s on Australia&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;do not travel&amp;apos; list. But influencers are promoting it anyway</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/its-on-australias-do-not-travel-list-influencers-are-promoting-it-anyway/l6ladosss</link><description>A surge of travel vloggers is putting Afghanistan back on the tourism map, even as the Taliban tightens restrictions on women and security risks remain high.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9739ed1e9708b066c8679a8ce0741373</guid></item><item><title>The Australians who think it&amp;apos;s fine to steal, and those who disagree</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-retail-theft-survey/b1yrp6vki</link><description>A new survey found a generational divide when it comes to rationalising retail theft behaviours, including scanning items incorrectly at self-checkout.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f73afe8aefb91168f2b15b3bcb87181</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 6 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-6-october-2025/22ssjf5lu</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">645ce9f66c6f1ad98a25360b9cd23743</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Equals, mates, and now allies&amp;apos;: What is the new treaty between Australia and PNG?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/pukpuk-treaty-australia-png-defence-pact/snprmvu55</link><description>Australia has signed its first alliance in 70 years. In a battle for Pacific influence, is it a threat to China?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a96a757a06cea19c022013e7239c935</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Undignified&amp;apos;: Albanese criticises Greens leader over Manchester attack comments</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/undignified-albanese-criticises-greens-leader-over-manchester-attack-comments/y63za8lal</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese said he watched the interview with the Greens leader, Larissa Waters, and was left &amp;quot;stunned&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a19a6396495d336e002dc87ac044c62e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;quot;Excitement, then everything changed&amp;quot;: survivors remember October 7 attack as calls grow for end to Gaza war</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/excitement-then-everything-changed-survivors-remember-october-7-attack-as-calls-grow-for-end-to-gaza-war/gcgwne2p3</link><description>Thousands of Australians are joining vigils across the nation to mark the second anniversary of the deadly Hamas attack on Israel. Around 1200 people were killed and 250 taken hostage during the designated terror group&amp;apos;s attack on October 7, 2023, which triggered a brutal military response from Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90e3b1dc68c0fb2458a0b763135949f9</guid></item><item><title>Australian claims dislocated arm from soldiers in prison called Israel&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;worst&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-prison-thunberg-australians-flotilla-ketziot-prison/4k67kxy2j</link><description>Ketziot prison was once called the &amp;quot;largest and the worst&amp;quot; of Israel&amp;apos;s prisons by Human Rights Watch. There are welfare concerns for Australians detained there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3479ab3351f4cc7f88d1ea8e3eb0dcfd</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Manifestly inadequate&amp;apos;: Prosecutors to appeal Erin Patterson&amp;apos;s sentence</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/prosecutors-appealing-erin-patterson-mushroom-murders-sentence/aso8ou568</link><description>The 51-year-old was sentenced to life in prison for the murder of three relatives.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f8c554efb5ea2d7d46ee2ca47ba8c60</guid></item><item><title>Gold and copper prices surge and why you shouldn’t ignore your annual super statement</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gold-and-copper-prices-surge-and-why-you-shouldnt-ignore-your-annual-super-statement/ycyf7efc7</link><description>The ASX-200 has started the week in the red, as a tech sell-off offset strong gains by gold and copper miners. Plus, Japanese stocks have hit a record high just a day after the country’s ruling Liberal Democratic Party named Sanae Takaichi as its leader. For more, Rena Sarumpaet spoke with George Boubouras from K2 Asset Management. As annual superannuation statements start to arrive in the mail, Australians are being urged to not ignore them with research from Canstar showing about a fifth of respondents only check their super once every few years - or never. For more on how a financial health check could benefit your nest egg, Stephanie Youssef spoke with Canstar Data Insights Director Sally Tindall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bf769f3e207d0282dbc7a810668680f0</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Fighting a war on two fronts&amp;apos;: Behind the rise of a new threat in Gaza</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hamas-influence-is-waning-in-gaza-palestinians-fear-armed-gangs-more/nz8wiwgfy</link><description>Newly released data shows a major spike in intra-Palestinian violent incidents this year, as well as a significant rise in stolen aid packages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e010bbb46bdb0e33ece03d84dbb1b80a</guid></item><item><title>The unseen impact of missing or damaged teeth — and the key to addressing it</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/unseen-impact-of-dental-issues/qxmy885wl</link><description>Why is it so shameful to have missing teeth or gum disease? And what can we do about it?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5c6536419384386081ada9d87c84a61</guid></item><item><title>Australians from Gaza aid flotilla deported by Israel to Jordan following detention</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/thunberg-greeted-by-cheering-crowd-in-athens-after-israel-expels-flotilla-activists/mf2qe8dj9</link><description>Some of the Australian activists recently detained by Israel have alleged violence and mistreatment at the hands of soldiers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79606fccfeaecb0d2ba332a2ba68edc8</guid></item><item><title>Gaza peace talks to continue as October 7 anniversary marked by commemoration, protests</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gaza-peace-talks-begin-as-october-7-anniversary-marked-by-commemoration-protests/08rf6jaqb</link><description>As Gaza marks two years under devastating Israeli bombardment, commemorations of the October 7 attacks and demonstrations in support of Palestinians are planned around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0633872b0d7cba4a7204b1bbac0fc2b0</guid></item><item><title>University students panicked after fraudulent emails &amp;apos;revoked&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;disqualified&amp;apos; degrees</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/western-sydney-university-hacks-scams-fraudulent-emails/9qa23rd0r</link><description>Western Sydney University said the emails are &amp;quot;not legitimate&amp;quot; and have been reported to police.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52ce0f86abd8ab03886197cfd7efdcee</guid></item><item><title>Advocates alarmed as major change for autistic kids looms</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/advocates-alarmed-as-major-change-for-autistic-kids-looms/n2rj2ev77</link><description>There are fears that many children with autism or learning difficulties will fall between the cracks of a new support system that aims to limit access to the National Disability Insurance Scheme. The Thriving Kids initiative will be rolled out from the middle of next year, with a focus on providing support to children with so-called mild to moderate autism within community and mainstream settings. But disability advocates have told a parliamentary inquiry it is these children that are most often overlooked or misunderstood.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbcbfc97c8481df7a17e0c2a379464dc</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 7 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-7-october-2025/pj6h2owkh</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76159309e4392687a2c1f21694cde629</guid></item><item><title>Federal government admits handballing truth-telling process as only &amp;apos;half a person&amp;apos; employed</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/federal-government-admits-handballing-truth-telling-process-as-only-half-a-person-employed/6yvl7nghg</link><description>The Greens have questioned what progress is being made on truth-telling and treaty at a federal level.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c089253e246d0c2480ff6db83e911471</guid></item><item><title>Talks on Gaza peace plan progress - but can the sticking points be overcome?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/talks-on-gaza-peace-plan-progress-but-can-the-sticking-points-be-overcome/wr735q857</link><description>Israeli and Hamas officials are meeting in Egypt this week in hopes of progressing a deal for a potential ceasefire in Gaza. It comes as the world marks two years of intense war in the enclave.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c390c44c2c1c13e6a5aa05e92f9c6b6</guid></item><item><title>France plunges into chaos as anger mounts over political deadlock</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/france-plunges-into-chaos-as-anger-mounts-over-political-deadlock/qk99nmupt</link><description>French politics has been in disarray since President Emmanuel Macron called an early legislative election last year, producing a deeply fragmented National Assembly. Now, with Prime Minister Sébastien Lecornu resigning after less than a month in the job, there are fears the French parliament has plunged into political deadlock.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b4bcbb17803c79ddd415ae773e8c258b</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;You are not alone&amp;apos;: PM and Ley recall horrors of Hamas attack, commemorating October 7</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/you-are-not-alone-pm-and-ley-recall-horrors-of-hamas-attack-commemorating-october-7/upzbe0n52</link><description>Both major party leaders have stood in solidarity with Australia&amp;apos;s Jewish community as it remembers the Hamas-led attack on Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d6219dd60cc721c68945832cd80d23f</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The purpose of my voice is to teach history&amp;apos;: Survivor tells how a party turned to trauma</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jewish-community-groups-mark-7-october-but-remain-divided-over-israels-response/8wbljra59</link><description>Nova Festival attack survivor Natalie Sanandaji shares her ordeal escaping the massacre on 7 October 2023 in southern Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f54ac3b662d720cf0b52eb64f2f47c7</guid></item><item><title>GP snapshot reveals why the job has become more complicated</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gp-snapshot-reveals-why-the-job-has-become-more-complicated/qpql0lgde</link><description>A snapshot of Australian general practice has revealed that GPs are having to see patients for longer appointments to treat more complex medical needs. The Health of the Nation industry survey of almost 2,500 GPs also shows a growing number of general practitioners are managing patient conditions typically handled by specialists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c160cb3c86a6aded30a18e7d0e9289a</guid></item><item><title>ASIC approves ASX listing market competitor; is AI in a bubble? and gold approaches US$4,000</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asic-approves-asx-listing-market-competitor-is-ai-in-a-bubble-and-gold-approaches-us-4-000/15pn8lg7y</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Todd Hoare from LGT Wealth Management Australia Management about the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action, including ASIC&amp;apos;s approval of Cboe Australia&amp;apos;s listing market.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a14fecba3f407f02c5f75ddaca796de3</guid></item><item><title>Government fast-tracks legislation to strengthen 000 call system</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/government-fast-tracks-legislation-to-strengthen-000-call-system/w83hkwzos</link><description>The government has fast-tracked legislation into parliament aimed at strengthening the 000 call system after failures by Optus to ensure access to emergency calls. As parliament resumed, the nation&amp;apos;s leaders made time to commemorate the second anniversary of the October 7 attack on Israel by Hamas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5eae27ff927fc8446f700e60af6c28d2</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Israel marks October 7 anniversary</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-marks-october-7-anniversary/7nytd3mxs</link><description>Bereaved friends and family members gathered at the site of the Nova music festival, while others came together in Tel Aviv and held ceremonies across the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f40f4967660e93d469c317547818f0e</guid></item><item><title>Minister urged to &amp;apos;come clean&amp;apos; on NDIS changes, as advocates fear &amp;apos;degrading&amp;apos; treatment</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/minister-urged-to-come-clean-on-upcoming-ndis-changes/6rtqr6kj3</link><description>Disability advocates are demanding clarity on upcoming NDIS changes, warning that the new system could be &amp;quot;traumatising&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35ef37fb66b60de2f07e0b9551334b12</guid></item><item><title>Trump threatens to invoke centuries-old anti-insurrection law to militarise US cities</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-threatens-to-invoke-insurrection-act-to-deploy-military/6g0b7x1n5</link><description>Donald Trump has said he would use the law to sidestep court rulings restricting orders to send National Guard troops into cities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2fd3ebac03c4a2285999cce9553fa08</guid></item><item><title>Trump threatens to invoke centuries-old anti-insurrection law to militarise US cities</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-threatens-to-invoke-insurrection-act-to-deploy-military-2/6g0b7x1n5</link><description>Donald Trump has said he would use the law to sidestep court rulings restricting orders to send National Guard troops into cities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72a0ed269fc7270b4c3aee326c3e94f9</guid></item><item><title>Kneecap member vows to fight and win again as prosecutors appeal terrorism charge</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/kneecap-vows-to-fight-and-win-uk-terrorism-charge-appeal/8d3xtw0yc</link><description>UK prosecutors will appeal a court&amp;apos;s decision to throw out a terrorism case against a member of the Irish rap trio.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38229a85ca8146e408f60d190f6a51bd</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: The AFP&amp;apos;s new commissioner, Krissy Barrett</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-the-afps-new-commissioner-krissy-barrett/3bm6lw2eg</link><description>The new Commissioner of the Australian Federal Police says her leadership will be characterised by a focus on social cohesion. Krissy Barrett, the first woman to lead the A-F-P, has amended the agency&amp;apos;s mission statement to include &amp;quot;defend&amp;quot; and protect Australia from domestic and global security threats. In a wide ranging interview with SBS&amp;apos;s Sara Tomevska, Commissioner Barrett says the agency will have a laser focus on disrupting crimes that impact Australia&amp;apos;s sovereignty, democracy and social cohesion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a0363e98313dddbea1eb00804b7aa02</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;State sponsors of terrorism&amp;apos; to be brought into Criminal Code</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/state-sponsors-of-terrorism-to-be-brought-into-criminal-code/rr8oox88l</link><description>New laws will target state entities that &amp;quot;fuel division, create fear and erode social cohesion&amp;quot; in Australia, the government said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9dc35cef4ada0ab2ecbe2b18e2d1d47c</guid></item><item><title>Optus sent triple-zero outage notification to the wrong email address, department says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/optus-sent-triple-zero-outage-notification-to-the-wrong-email-address-department-says/51cqm1wqr</link><description>Companies had been told &amp;quot;a number of times&amp;quot; the email address was not to be used for notifications, a departmental staffer said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f464b043ea3c17cbbb73f48b3d98a71</guid></item><item><title>Home Affairs knew for months &amp;apos;ISIS brides&amp;apos; were returning; granted children citizenship</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/government-reveals-it-knew-for-months-that-women-children-were-returning-from-syria/25rhks9h4</link><description>The federal government says the group, who arrived in Australia recently, are being monitored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7be85bee82432c5f464de873b190365f</guid></item><item><title>Home Affairs knew for months &amp;apos;ISIS brides&amp;apos; were returning; granted children citizenship</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/government-reveals-it-knew-for-months-that-women-and-children-were-returning-from-syria/25rhks9h4</link><description>The federal government says the group, who arrived in Australia recently, are being monitored.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1dfc8ba7d909fded36d095142372720</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 8 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-8-october-2025/whwmm56t5</link><description>A daily news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2117dd9198b3e40c0ee5a7ff6776e2e4</guid></item><item><title>Australian Gaza aid flotilla activists deported by Israel amid claims of abuse</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australian-gaza-aid-flotilla-activists-deported-by-israel-amid-claims-of-abuse/clunej4cm</link><description>More ships are sailing towards Gaza as part of an international aid flotilla. It comes as Israel deports Australians who were part of the Global Sumud Flotilla.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dfaf8766dcf1cc93d5dbca6760f99a67</guid></item><item><title>Australian flotilla activist accuses government of &amp;apos;shameful&amp;apos; Israel extraction effort</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-gaza-aid-flotilla-detained-israel-government-response/k0z6te9ta</link><description>Australians were detained at what has been called an &amp;quot;outrageous&amp;quot; prison.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1257d9945cbeacdd1dfcb0ead12bf2fb</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s cancer survival rates are improving — but there are also some &amp;apos;concerning&amp;apos; trends</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cancer-survival-rates-increasing-concerning-trends/2pv0jmxyg</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s latest snapshot of cancer incidence and deaths has been released.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">107c68cb639ee7a8a33619366761bd82</guid></item><item><title>Gold breaks US$4,000 &amp;amp; is NZ becoming a better value tourist destination?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gold-breaks-us-4-000-is-nz-becoming-a-better-value-tourist-destination/4wphc7m2n</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Armina Rosenberg from Minotaur Capital about the day&amp;apos;s market action, including gold&amp;apos;s new milestone and how her firm is using AI to invest; plus Nick Tuffley from ASB Bank goes through why the RBNZ cut interest rates more than expected and what it means for Australian travellers going to New Zealand.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">075d064fad7859a126dc1ae41b3a59f0</guid></item><item><title>Communications minister accused of misleading parliament over Optus notification</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/communications-minister-accused-of-misleading-parliament-over-optus-notification/esnv5jsxx</link><description>The federal opposition has accused Communications Minister Anika Wells of misleading parliament over when her office was notified of the Optus Triple-Zero outage that has been linked to four deaths. It comes as emails that Optus sent to notify the government and the regulator of the outages, which ultimately affected more than 600 people last month, are scrutinised in Senate estimates. Meanwhile, legislation creating a triple-zero custodian has passed the lower house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f7070d12aef1f94469b2c63613df90df</guid></item><item><title>There&amp;apos;s a difference between hot and cold sweat — and one tends to smell more distinctive</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hot-cold-sweat-whats-the-difference/zqv96pzqv</link><description>Cold sweat is known as psychological sweat, while hot sweat is often the body&amp;apos;s response to physical exertion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b581aa783d42878f5bfb52f06e2a6573</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Deeply harmful&amp;apos;: Autism advocates fear major change for some Australian children</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/kids-autism-program-challenged-during-inquiry/1ql3ja1au</link><description>The government is pushing ahead with a new program — and there are concerns it could leave some children falling between the cracks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f6ec8ef5e7935117bfb77b92878c052</guid></item><item><title>Prison guards thought TJ was &amp;apos;playing possum&amp;apos;. Hours later, he was dead</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/inquest-into-tian-jarrah-denniss-death-in-prison-custody/d1zj2u0aw</link><description>TJ&amp;apos;s death in custody prompted an apology by Corrective Services NSW. But did he ever stand a chance of leaving?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">81fa8ce117eb05e7e0ae7de6f3e50dce</guid></item><item><title>Former FBI chief James Comey pleads not guilty in case pushed by Trump</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/former-fbi-chief-james-comey-pleads-not-guilty-in-case-pushed-by-trump/vk3x08kaj</link><description>Donald Trump has threatened to imprison his political rivals since the start of his 2016 presidential campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">665c0bf556497e3b0c0c314ea824a640</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Light at the end of the tunnel’: Darfur victims welcome ICC verdict</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/light-at-the-end-of-the-tunnel-darfur-victims-welcome-icc-verdict/0uv537aqj</link><description>The International Criminal Court has convicted Sudanese militia commander Ali Muhammad Ali Abd-Al-Rahman of war crimes and crimes against humanity for leading attacks in Darfur over 20 years ago. The conviction marks the ICC&amp;apos;s first conviction for atrocities in the Darfur conflict which killed an estimated 300,000 people and forcibly displaced around 2.7 million.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a65e2818a74c8049c6f19050d3595e41</guid></item><item><title>Senior US officials arrive in Egypt for Gaza peace talks as Israeli assault dials down</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-officials-gaza-peace-talks-in-egypt/ioj1mhemm</link><description>Donald Trump said a deal was &amp;quot;very close&amp;quot; and that he may travel to the Middle East this weekend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acf08b1fc5e9d0202db0f22b5875a723</guid></item><item><title>Could Donald Trump win the 2025 Nobel Peace Prize?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/can-donald-trump-win-2025-nobel-peace-prize/jd8qsc5o2</link><description>Leaders seeking to curry favour with Trump have been quick to talk up the US president&amp;apos;s chances, but experts aren&amp;apos;t so sure.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0a4240ebbb17289ba0358cae532feac</guid></item><item><title>Pro-Palestinian marchers plan new route after court blocks Opera House rally</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/opera-house-protest-banned-by-court/f87xn5r5c</link><description>Organisers said their right to protest was &amp;quot;paramount&amp;quot; after their initial plan was blocked following a court challenge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7292b4de0e238502babf75fd9bc0cbc9</guid></item><item><title>Trump says &amp;apos;first phase&amp;apos; of Gaza peace deal reached; hostages to be released within days</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-hamas-signed-off-on-gaza-deal-trump-says/fob44vchm</link><description>Arab countries backing the plan say it must lead to eventual independence for a Palestinian state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dc34357c365ce7c52421528686fbc0f</guid></item><item><title>What we&amp;apos;ve learnt about the &amp;apos;ISIS brides&amp;apos;, as federal police anticipate more returns</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-weve-learnt-about-the-isis-brides-as-federal-police-anticipate-more-returns/azsbkp5dj</link><description>The Australian Federal Police said the group, which has returned from Syria, was being monitored as part of an ongoing operation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">095473ab291891ba39d99c9b49418bbc</guid></item><item><title>Trump says Gaza peace plan first phase agreed to by Israel and Hamas | Midday News Bulletin 9 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trump-says-gaza-peace-plan-first-phase-agreed-to-by-israel-and-hamas-midday-news-bulletin-9-october-2025/ye60wog0y</link><description>Donald Trump says Israel and Hamas have agreed to the first phase of a Gaza peace plan; an Australian scientist wins the Nobel Prize in Chemistry; and Cristiano Ronaldo becomes the first footballer to reach billionaire status.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">61ff8281bebd8b15eaa373a7fe4f116a</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: What does the Middle East peace deal mean?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-what-does-the-middle-east-peace-deal-mean/kcb42zhl7</link><description>US President Donald Trump says Israel and Hamas have agreed on the first phase of a peace framework that will allow for the release of all hostages. In a post on social media, he said the release of hostages is imminent, adding that &amp;quot;All Parties will be treated fairly!&amp;quot;. The exchange of the remaining hostages held by Hamas for Palestinian prisoners could happen within 72 hours of the deal&amp;apos;s implementation. Dr Eyal Mayroz is a lecturer in Peace and Conflict Studies at the University of Sydney, and he gave SBS&amp;apos;s Cameron Carr his reaction to the agreement</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5e7f8c4f3c51e8fecc5c714da859ebf</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 9 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-9-october-2025/smjkdc3tt</link><description>A daily news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f36918c138d94a0d8745616a3fb46ba</guid></item><item><title>The Gaza peace deal&amp;apos;s first phase has been agreed to. But there are still many questions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-is-left-to-work-out-in-the-gaza-peace-plan/z86yn49de</link><description>Despite the hopes raised for ending the war, crucial details are yet to be spelled out.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e0393a92f821e6c0dbee3b0dc02d076</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;A ray of light&amp;apos;: Albanese, Ley applaud delivery of Trump&amp;apos;s Gaza peace plan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/a-ray-of-light-albanese-ley-applaud-delivery-of-trumps-gaza-peace-plan/3emcoceam</link><description>Both major party leaders say the breakthrough in Gaza gives &amp;quot;hope&amp;quot; to the world that Donald Trump&amp;apos;s peace plan is &amp;quot;the start of the end of this war&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">74c62c98bd0feef8cc1171429044c719</guid></item><item><title>New workplace laws aim to remove extra pain burden on parents arising from stillbirth</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-workplace-laws-aim-to-remove-extra-pain-burden-on-parents-arising-from-stillbirth/yxxby73uk</link><description>Laws have been introduced into federal parliament to stop employers from scrapping leave entitlements when families face the tragedy of a stillbirth or death of their baby.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e463603d4aa7c01baf13de3111cf7ff7</guid></item><item><title>Sign off on first phase of Gaza peace deal welcomed | Evening News Bulletin 9 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sign-off-on-first-phase-of-gaza-peace-deal-welcomed-evening-news-bulletin-9-october-2025/6ito03gxl</link><description>Australia welcomes Israel and the Hamas signing the first phase of peace deal; India&amp;apos;s Defence Minister visits Australia, as both countries deepen defence ties; and in sport, Matildas coach Joe Montem calls for more investment in A-League Women teams.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d04f0a897c674a55550ca2c827aefbc5</guid></item><item><title>The common mortgage feature that could be leaving you &amp;apos;worse off&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-common-mortgage-feature-that-could-be-leaving-you-worse-off/353pu5cpx</link><description>Mortgage offset accounts have helped many Australians wipe interest off their home loan. But they don&amp;apos;t always offer a benefit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ee442e3b846b3c3009e9a69f6380e9a2</guid></item><item><title>Gaza peace deal market impacts &amp;amp; Gemini crypto exchange enters Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gaza-peace-deal-market-impacts-gemini-crypto-exchange-enters-australia/cn4wgwr7z</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Robert Talevski to see how the Gaza peace deal has impacted markets; and Ricardo takes a look at Australia&amp;apos;s crypto regulatory space with Gemini&amp;apos;s Saad Ahmed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">32dadee138ba4452c8f55df884a185c7</guid></item><item><title>Israel and Hamas have agreed on the first phase of a Gaza peace deal. Now what?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israel-and-hamas-have-agreed-on-the-first-phase-of-a-gaza-peace-deal-now-what/0q53t5h5m</link><description>Israel and Hamas have agreed to the first phase of United States President Donald Trump&amp;apos;s plan for Gaza. The ceasefire and hostage deal could be a first step toward ending a bloody two-year-old war that has roiled across the Middle East.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">365e8bc7ed55d46044888698306e272f</guid></item><item><title>A Gaza peace deal signed; au revoir to yet another French PM; &amp;amp; Australia&amp;apos;s new security alliance</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-gaza-peace-deal-signed-au-revoir-to-yet-another-french-pm-australias-new-security-alliance/qpvku4bvv</link><description>Hamas and Israel sign up for Phase One of Trump&amp;apos;s new 20-point plan for peace in Gaza. France&amp;apos;s revolving door on its prime ministerial office takes another spin. Plus Australia and PNG sign on to an expanded alliance for regional cooperation. And how desperate for $5,000 are you? Take a job at a haunted hotel desperate?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8242392b02a0cd65357a0346f8e7e0dc</guid></item><item><title>In pictures: Palestinians and Israelis celebrate after news of ceasefire deal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/in-pictures-palestinians-and-israelis-celebrate-after-news-of-ceasefire-deal/2tn21mxlb</link><description>Israel and Hamas are expected to sign the agreement at the Egyptian beach resort of Sharm el-Sheikh on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">57ba00d9399367bc75535899924611c2</guid></item><item><title>Fear drove Fouad to Australia. Even after a major milestone, his hopes are dim</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/syrians-in-australia-react-to-recent-elections/abrnu5ip9</link><description>Fouad Berzghal&amp;apos;s home country had its first election since the fall of its dictator. But there are questions over how much will change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27787313fa317cc17ce5162a28bb9d06</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;It felt like home&amp;apos;: Why generations of migrant Australians love the NPL</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-championship-2025-npl-clubs-vying-for-a-league/e8w984a52</link><description>Once the lifeblood of migrant communities, suburban football clubs are back on the national stage for the Australian Championship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d609837651a1452d9f46ac7ed2f3256</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump says Israeli hostages should be home early next week | Morning News Bulletin 10 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/donald-trump-says-israeli-hostages-should-be-home-early-next-week-morning-news-bulletin-10-october-2025/u3hj3ty68</link><description>Donald Trump says Israeli hostages should be home early next week as the world welcomes a Gaza ceasefire deal; The government under pressure over FOI laws; And in sport, Novak Djokovic through to semi-finals of Shanghai Masters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80ac40c6ada2c3bc3660a81272581802</guid></item><item><title>What’s the Senate actually estimating? Ft. David Pocock</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/whats-the-senate-actually-estimating-ft-david-pocock/mh2g41en3</link><description>The first senate estimates of the 48th Parliament have arrived – where the Albanese Labor Government and representatives from the Australian Public Service and government agencies are quizzed for up to 14 hours a day about pretty much anything. It’s tedious, it’s long, but it’s all about accountability, and Independent Senator for the ACT David Pocock takes us behind the scenes. Plus Bob Katter has a suggestion for the footy off-season, and Andrew Hastie has left the Coalition front bench.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf65a9ae21431245bb073149e8e14804</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Safe beds save lives&amp;apos;: Calls for urgent action to address rising number of homeless women</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/calls-for-urgent-action-to-address-rising-rates-of-homeless-women/guxjs58zb</link><description>Australians are being urged to recognise the link between domestic violence and homelessness, as more women face sleeping rough.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4c2cda473f27360e0af7ffd236102d0</guid></item><item><title>Phase one of Gaza peace deal set to begin after approval by Israeli cabinet</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-says-all-parties-have-now-signed-phase-one-of-gaza-peace-deal/cg3mvrghn</link><description>Despite celebrations in Israel and Gaza and a flood of messages from world leaders hailing the deal, numerous issues remain unsettled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a83608dc7c3725b7ae939afb7abe63c6</guid></item><item><title>Phase one of Gaza peace deal set to begin after approval by Israeli cabinet</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gaza-peace-deal-set-to-begin-after-approval-by-israeli-cabinet/cg3mvrghn</link><description>Despite celebrations in Israel and Gaza and a flood of messages from world leaders hailing the deal, numerous issues remain unsettled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">449af5463a6d312a1f266c15e3f5d7bd</guid></item><item><title>Australia welcomes Gaza peace plan, urges two-state solution | Midday News Bulletin 10 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/midday-news-bulletin-10-october-2025/u1q3z4kqr</link><description>Israel&amp;apos;s cabinet approves phase one of a Gaza peace plan; Indigenous artists celebrated at the Australian Women in Music Awards; And in sport, Australia remain top of the Women&amp;apos;s Cricket World Cup League standings</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aace9461961b5cb66705237b824308c9</guid></item><item><title>Australia welcomes Gaza peace plan, urges two-state solution | Midday News Bulletin 10 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australia-welcomes-gaza-peace-plan-urges-two-state-solution-midday-news-bulletin-10-october-2025/u1q3z4kqr</link><description>Israel&amp;apos;s cabinet approves phase one of a Gaza peace plan; Indigenous artists celebrated at the Australian Women in Music Awards; And in sport, Australia remain top of the Women&amp;apos;s Cricket World Cup League standings</description><guid isPermaLink="false">35e7c5e26db28467143b7ce75d47fd8f</guid></item><item><title>Are Syria’s first post-Assad elections strengthening or weakening democracy?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/are-syrias-first-post-assad-elections-strengthening-or-weakening-democracy/ba0rd6man</link><description>Syria&amp;apos;s first parliamentary elections since the fall of Bashar al-Assad have sparked criticism for how they were run. The election was seen as a key step in the shift away from the al-Assad regime, but one that has sparked concerns about inclusivity and fairness under the country&amp;apos;s new leaders. Syrians here in Australia say their relatives at home do not feel represented by the new Government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1324997c4daa234662dcdf368f87293c</guid></item><item><title>Pocock won&amp;apos;t rejoin parliamentary sports club despite ban reversal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/parliamentary-sports-club-drops-senator-over-cheap-shot-gambling-lobby-complaints/ni07m8rcy</link><description>The former Wallabies captain says he won’t take part in Parliament’s friendly sporting matches unless the club rethinks its corporate ties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5d780167cc8bd777c6b16f620aa7162d</guid></item><item><title>Peace in the Middle East greeted with joy across the divide</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/peace-in-the-middle-east-greeted-with-joy-across-the-divide/f6r5yfx3w</link><description>After two years of devastating conflict, there are scenes of cautious celebration across the Middle East. A historic ceasefire deal between Israel and Hamas, brokered by US President Donald Trump, has been reached, in effect, marking what some are calling a new chapter of peace.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4091d5c843b7e47882f975b4d3b36f69</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 10 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-10-october-2025/ox4745edi</link><description>A daily news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">461f5ff0895d21df54b3565c645bef89</guid></item><item><title>Australian flotilla activist faces indefinite Israeli detention &amp;apos;threat&amp;apos;, as others return home</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/deported-australian-gaza-flotilla-activists-vow-to-return/r5ng7dpgj</link><description>The returned activists have concerns for Madeline Habib, who is said to be in &amp;quot;good health&amp;quot; while detained in Israel.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">267ed924408cd9b6bd7f759e3a861ac5</guid></item><item><title>Tsunami threat passes after powerful earthquake strikes Philippines</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tsunami-warning-issued-after-magnitude-7-4-earthquake-strikes-philippines/rojk438gt</link><description>A tsunami alert for the Philippines, Palau and Indonesia has been lifted following a magnitude 7.4 earthquake south of the Philippines.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eae9b3947c5305856ff6eafe0f99b2be</guid></item><item><title>Unveiled: New 60-day plan for Gaza after ceasefire begins</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/new-60-day-plan-for-gaza-after-ceasefire-begins/sd9iqjpa8</link><description>The United Nations says it&amp;apos;s prepared for a humanitarian aid &amp;quot;surge&amp;quot; once the Gaza ceasefire begins.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ecc5e450c0f48e654576e73150d41b7</guid></item><item><title>How a &amp;apos;deeply-embedded&amp;apos; part of Australian culture could change forever</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-young-people-drinking-less/5evzgqh3h</link><description>Young Australians are leading this emerging generational shift, according to a new study.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37ff3efc37c81ed4a2b915dfbbae5f8c</guid></item><item><title>US troops deployed to help monitor Gaza ceasefire deal | Evening News Bulletin 10 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-troops-deployed-to-help-monitor-gaza-ceasefire-deal-evening-news-bulletin-10-october-2025/jdtq06z14</link><description>US troops deployed to Israel to help monitor the Gaza ceasefire deal; an earthquake triggers a tsunami warning for the Philippines and neighbouring regions of Indonesia; and in football, Sam Kerr returns to the Matildas squad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3b96d2229965401e77275fd7b20addce</guid></item><item><title>The looming Europe travel change that will affect Australians</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-looming-europe-travel-change-that-will-affect-australians/vcw4eeb3k</link><description>New personal data collection rules are about to come into effect in Europe&amp;apos;s Schengen area. Here&amp;apos;s what you need to know.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8915e4cc6bb110563107cac201a2909</guid></item><item><title>Silver at highest since 1980 &amp;amp; how markets are reacting to Gaza peace deal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/silver-at-highest-since-1980-how-markets-are-reacting-to-gaza-peace-deal/629kn57mq</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Zoran Kresovic from Blueberry Markets about the day&amp;apos;s market action, including how investors are feeling following the potential Gaza peace deal, the future for gold and the outlook for silver, which hit a near 45 year high.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d1d05bfb6622d4a8698efb5d64f8f82</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan opposition figure María Corina Machado awarded Nobel Peace Prize</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/awarded-nobel-peace-prize-as-trump-misses-out/1mib232vu</link><description>Machado had been forced into hiding but remained in Venezuela, a choice that &amp;quot;inspired millions&amp;quot;, the Nobel Committee chair said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da4d3d7f412d47df82feb324ffda31e5</guid></item><item><title>Venezuelan opposition figure María Corina Machado awarded Nobel Peace Prize</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/venezuelan-opposition-figure-maria-corina-machado-awarded-nobel-peace-prize/1mib232vu</link><description>Machado had been forced into hiding but remained in Venezuela, a choice that &amp;quot;inspired millions&amp;quot;, the Nobel Committee chair said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d5e492e919ad601ea5669d16343048c1</guid></item><item><title>Displaced Gazans stream back to their destroyed homes after ceasefire comes into effect</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gaza-ceasefire-in-effect-gazans-return/47a4beep2</link><description>A massive column of displaced Gazans filed north through the dust towards Gaza City after the ceasefire came into effect at midday Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8fa4b0c30e87f775a6a0bd207e3bf44c</guid></item><item><title>Displaced Gazans stream back to their destroyed homes after ceasefire comes into effect</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gaza-ceasefire-in-effect-israeli-military-announcement/47a4beep2</link><description>A massive column of displaced Gazans filed north through the dust towards Gaza City after the ceasefire came into effect at midday Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b44e6dde49b4c4379129b993fbe76866</guid></item><item><title>Thousands of displaced Palestinians return home following ceasefire | Morning News Bulletin 11 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/thousands-of-displaced-palestinians-return-home-following-ceasefire-morning-news-bulletin-11-october-2025/zr00smqi2</link><description>Displaced Palestinians return to ruins after ceasefire takes effect in Gaza; Nobel Peace Prize goes to Venezuelan opposition leader; Andrew McDonald optimistic Pat Cummins will play the first Ashes Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">264f16783c7afcc885877fb4f794a6a8</guid></item><item><title>Saving money and packing &amp;apos;go bags&amp;apos;: How Australians in the US are preparing for the worst</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-living-in-america-anxiety/p88o60wos</link><description>With changes to visas and growing scrutiny of foreign nationals, Australians in the US say they feel uncertain about their futures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d92df2c543967f34a3a2a80e74842b9</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s potato capital is facing a threat never-before-seen in the country</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/potato-mop-top-virus-management/hsbsfzew1</link><description>With eradication off the table, Australia is looking to New Zealand for lessons on how to manage potato mop top virus as planting begins in Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c375078453cf75cec49b0f1ccf3cd88e</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s potato capital is facing a threat never-before-seen in the country</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/template/hsbsfzew1</link><description>With eradication off the table, Australia is looking to New Zealand for lessons on how to manage potato mop top virus as planting begins in Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e22de1eea49a41dd6bf76751dd071b24</guid></item><item><title>US aid cuts start to bite for Myanmar&amp;apos;s refugees</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-aid-cuts-start-to-bite-for-myanmars-refugees/jozn5d7v2</link><description>Earlier this year, US President Donald Trump ordered steep cuts to the US foreign aid budget, a move that sparked concerns it would cause widespread harm and even deaths for the millions that relied on the programs delivered or funded by the USAid office. Now, refugees and advocates say the cuts are starting to bite, with 85 per cent of residents in refugee camps along the Myanmar-Thai border living without USAid food rations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2a532cc132b4c5770d1b855534a7097</guid></item><item><title>Trump hikes tariffs on China by extra 100 per cent, threatens to cancel talks with Xi Jinping</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-threatens-to-cancel-talks-imposes-100-per-cent-tariffs-on-china/sxmr7930k</link><description>There was no immediate reaction from Beijing after Trump said China should not &amp;quot;be allowed to hold the world &amp;apos;captive&amp;apos;&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d401645600cd1cbcbc6079c8b41747c</guid></item><item><title>Trump hikes tariffs on China by extra 100 per cent, threatens to cancel talks with Xi Jinping</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-threatens-to-cancel-talks-impose-massive-tariffs-on-china/sxmr7930k</link><description>There was no immediate reaction from Beijing after Trump said China should not &amp;quot;be allowed to hold the world &amp;apos;captive&amp;apos;&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4aafafecdaf34fc1ca75d5263663b29e</guid></item><item><title>French president reappoints prime minister just days after he quit the job</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/french-president-reappoints-prime-minister-just-days-after-he-quit-the-job/rpa8d83zc</link><description>Newly reappointed French Prime Minister Sebastien Lecornu&amp;apos;s most pressing task will be to deliver a budget to parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">858c65f7f3f1fb0a683cc6367166a185</guid></item><item><title>French president reappoints prime minister just days after he quit the job</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/french-president-reappoints-prime-minister-just-days-after-he-quit-the-job-2/rpa8d83zc</link><description>Newly reappointed French Prime Minister Sebastien Lecornu&amp;apos;s most pressing task will be to deliver a budget to parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb612290ce62465ba2a75d1fdd89834a</guid></item><item><title>Hopes Gaza ceasefire will lead to drop in &amp;apos;dehumanisation and othering&amp;apos; in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/hope-gaza-ceasefire-will-drop-dehumanisation-and-othering/ergaf1xko</link><description>The race discrimination commissioner hopes the Gaza ceasefire will lessen division at home but says &amp;quot;problems will remain&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">79ef9413da5d1e22c283740b8f1a8ca0</guid></item><item><title>Midday News Bulletin 11 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/midday-news-bulletin-11-october-2025/9kk6zyi5w</link><description>French PM Sebastien Lecornu reinstated just days after shock resignation; deadline looms for release of sensitive information by hacking collective; Alex de Minaur&amp;apos;s prospects at the Shanghai tournament come to a halt.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c11d7bd6f6a4bedaf2bb042f582bc52</guid></item><item><title>Three dead as light plane crashes just after take-off near Wollongong</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/three-dead-as-light-plane-crashes-just-after-take-off-near-wollongong/i2f2q6bfa</link><description>Three people have been killed in a light plane crash shortly after take-off, in what first responders have described as a &amp;quot;gruesome&amp;quot; scene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">120b6304d5fde73aee6b4298f56982c6</guid></item><item><title>Three dead in light plane crash south of Sydney | Evening News Bulletin 11 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/three-dead-in-light-plane-crash-south-of-sydney-evening-news-bulletin-11-october-2025/js6m1zjfs</link><description>Three people dead after light plane crash south of Sydney... new laws introduced to target aggressive behaviour and sexual assault outside venues in New South Wales... and the Socceroos beat Canada, one goal to nil</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0adbcd4003f8ba079d307a2f313871d</guid></item><item><title>Clean-up begins in Philippines after at least eight killed in twin earthquakes</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/clean-up-begins-in-philippines-after-at-least-eight-killed-in-twin-earthquakes/hlog6tmyu</link><description>Some residents in Mindanao slept outdoors in fear of aftershocks after 7.4 and 6.7-magnitude earthquakes struck off the coast on Friday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26a55f5ff6d8ae561174db3023b2e9f5</guid></item><item><title>North Korea shows off its &amp;apos;most powerful&amp;apos; missile at parade with Russian, Chinese top brass</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/north-korea-parades-its-most-powerful-missile-at-a-military-parade-attended-by-top-russian-and-china/22aulkt16</link><description>Kim Jong Un welcomed top Russian and Chinese officials to the event marking 80 years of North Korean rule under the Workers&amp;apos; Party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c8c3dcc4004306661593f57b1a5ce32c</guid></item><item><title>Casper takes a drug that helps him grow. But the treatment is controversial</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/casper-takes-a-drug-that-helps-him-grow-but-the-treatment-is-controversial/72242cs13</link><description>A controversial drug Australia had a key role in developing continues to bring hope - and frustration – for the short-statured community.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f6752e3ad0558ffcc086d892ca1397b</guid></item><item><title>Not just magpies: The other birds swooping you this season — and why they do it</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/swooping-birds-magpies-spring/rjw9tyy7h</link><description>Magpies may have perfected the art of swooping, but they&amp;apos;re not the only Australian bird diving on unsuspecting humans this spring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac2a97d7785b3c241eafd24952f2dad4</guid></item><item><title>Morning News Bulletin 12 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/morning-news-bulletin-12-october-2025/gguy7l2lb</link><description>The United Nations says it is preparing to deliver large amounts of vital aid in Gaza; an investigation underway after a deadly plane crash in New South Wales; and in Tennis, two cousins, Arthur Rinderknech and Valentin Vacherot, to play against each other in the finals of the Shanghai Masters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c648ec3fe887b52595c0054a3ea9a51f</guid></item><item><title>Morning News Bulletin 12 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/morning-news-bulletin-7-october-2025/gguy7l2lb</link><description>The United Nations says it is preparing to deliver large amounts of vital aid in Gaza; an investigation underway after a deadly plane crash in New South Wales; and in Tennis, two cousins, Arthur Rinderknech and Valentin Vacherot, to play against each other in the finals of the Shanghai Masters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">84c16dcbfe676b7bccd4a163e490f027</guid></item><item><title>California sends ultraprocessed school meals to the sin bin</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/california-sends-ultraprocessed-school-meals-to-the-sin-bin/oqmx7iqdc</link><description>California is to phase out certain ultraprocessed foods from school meals over the next decade under a first-in-the-nation law signed by Governor Gavin Newsom. Schools will have to start removing those foods from their menus by July 2029, and districts will be barred from selling them for breakfast or lunch by July 2035.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e29626fd5f4127e4148022381379bafd</guid></item><item><title>Lostprophets singer Ian Watkins dies in prison attack</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lostprophets-singer-ian-watkins-dies-in-prison-stabbing-attack/zilz3kk5c</link><description>Lostprophets singer Ian Watkins was sentenced to 29 years in prison for child abuse in 2013.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bf9903b808391ca4c4d69a083b7cf25</guid></item><item><title>Diane Keaton, star of Annie Hall and The Godfather, dies at 79</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/oscar-winning-actress-diane-keaton-dies-at-79/c5xrom26x</link><description>Diane Keaton, the Oscar-winning star of Annie Hall, The Godfather films and Father of the Bride, has died at the age of 79.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f54b501fd3a6c497c0924eb42a6bd7d5</guid></item><item><title>Midday News Bulletin 12 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/midday-news-bulletin-12-october-2025/rn35t8w4z</link><description>Final preparations made for the exchange of hostages in Gaza for Palestinians held in Israeli prisons; rare earth minerals on the agenda when Anthony Albanese meets with Donald Trump; and in cricket, Australia to face India in a sold-out O-D-I World Cup blockbuster.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba01124f30d3b3e8f547dfe6bee2a43f</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;All over the place&amp;apos;: Concerns over Qantas hacked data access as airline investigates</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/its-all-over-the-place-qantas-customer-data-leaked/yfa1yeucc</link><description>One cybersecurity expert says the stolen data might be available not just on the dark web, but also on the clear web.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e041d61ae2264ebcb23c839e668acd6c</guid></item><item><title>Families await hostage release as Palestinians return to &amp;apos;ghost town&amp;apos; during Gaza ceasefire</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/families-await-hostage-release-as-palestinians-return-to-ghost-town-during-gaza-ceasefire/q6o2ag6ps</link><description>The ceasefire between Israel and Hamas is in its second day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">98d504f79bc84c9f7d023482bc16b8a9</guid></item><item><title>Made famous by Steve Irwin, this croc&amp;apos;s now been &amp;apos;wrongfully accused&amp;apos;, advocates say</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-theres-concern-over-iconic-crocodile-old-faithful-detention/b36fd948z</link><description>Old Faithful is being held in a government facility for displaying problematic behaviour towards humans, but environmental activists say it&amp;apos;s a case of mistaken identity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0bed6c1b16fd51aef971771dd633ee04</guid></item><item><title>Evening News Bulletin 12 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/evening-news-bulletin-12-october-2025/g1demqpqz</link><description>Pro-Palestinian protests take place across the country, Human trafficking rates skyrocket in Australia, Portugal beats Ireland in stoppage time in their World Cup qualifier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dbd44b6ef4136c594db2c6cc82bab8ed</guid></item><item><title>Who are the hostages Israel believes are still alive and when will they be released?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/who-are-the-hostages-israel-believes-are-still-alive-and-when-will-they-be-released/ywua8sqxi</link><description>A condition of the peace deal between Israel and Hamas is the return of 48 hostages held in Gaza, 20 of whom are believed to be alive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">585053a1c521b656c9dfa58fbfaa7d21</guid></item><item><title>Why pro-Palestinian protesters say they will continue to march despite Gaza ceasefire</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-protesters-in-support-of-palestinians-say-theyll-continue-to-march-amid-a-gaza-ceasefire/irzowzg40</link><description>Dozens of rallies took place across the country on Sunday, with some protesters expressing concern the ceasefire would not hold.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d12ea31494d7af73188787790b379c7</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Tip of the iceberg&amp;apos;: Human trafficking reports in Australia reach all-time high</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tip-of-the-iceberg-human-trafficking-reports-reach-all-time-high/6fgetvo7v</link><description>Police say the increase was likely the result of the community becoming better at recognising indicators.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d917fab9081154253a02470d11373466</guid></item><item><title>Afghanistan says 58 Pakistani troops killed as border tensions erupt after airstrikes</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/afghanistan-says-58-pakistani-troops-killed-as-border-tensions-erupt-after-airstrikes/ez374mu6q</link><description>Pakistan closed several border crossings with Afghanistan after fierce overnight fighting left dozens dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3be84e506dab4d251f8787506dab489</guid></item><item><title>I asked a mortgage broker what median first home buyers can get with a 5% deposit (not much)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/i-asked-a-mortgage-broker-what-median-first-home-buyers-can-get-with-a-5-deposit-not-much/986cxo8k6</link><description>First home buyers can get into the housing market with a 5 per cent deposit - but are there hidden pitfalls they may not be aware of? We asked an expert to crunch the numbers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4ae1e8af7eaf6e3e9f25e9709f3e610</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I felt alone&amp;apos;: Inside the &amp;apos;invisible&amp;apos; loss one in three Australian women endure</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/i-felt-alone-inside-the-invisible-loss-one-in-three-australian-women-endure/d97d2me8d</link><description>Organisations that help women through miscarriages are looking forward to seeing a national pregnancy loss register to address what they say is an invisibility around the true scale of the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cc6a40abb4cdb96b172f7ec1cb137a5</guid></item><item><title>Gaza: Aid begins to roll in | Morning News Bulletin 13 October 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gaza-aid-begins-to-roll-in-morning-news-bulletin-13-october-2025/83js4v53r</link><description>Aid trucks enter Gaza as hostages expected to be freed under ceasefire deal; Taliban says 58 Pakistani soldiers killed in border clashes amid rising tensions; Socceroos eye 11-game unbeaten streak ahead of clash with United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3381331d8fee2219d39129220b32eaf5</guid></item><item><title>Gaza ceasefire holds ahead of hostage release and Trump&amp;apos;s visit to Israel</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ceasefire-holds-in-gaza-ahead-of-hostage-release-and-trumps-visit-to-israel/7ts6fyvou</link><description>Israeli officials said they expect the hostage release to start around 2-3pm AEDT.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8c86e44218186db43d220557d42373f</guid></item><item><title>The miscarriage data gap and &amp;apos;invisible loss&amp;apos; leaving Australian women behind</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-miscarriage-data-gap-and-invisible-loss-leaving-australian-women-behind/y56quko28</link><description>A new report is calling for a national database on miscarriage to address ongoing invisibility around miscarriage and early pregnancy loss in Australia, particularly for First Nations women and in rural and regional communities. This comes as the government announced a $9.5 million funding package in May last year to improve awareness and support for early pregnancy loss.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">012a9e93267514f189f40d33c4787b7d</guid></item><item><title>Madagascar president says coup attempt &amp;apos;underway&amp;apos; as protesters install new army chief</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/madagascar-president-says-coup-attempt-under-way-as-anti-government-protesters-install-new-army-chief/eq8vb1jxq</link><description>Anti-government demonstrations erupted in Madagascar on 25 September.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3beb9f07d7823eee92b18fd94768e67e</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump softens tone on China after tariff tensions flare</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/donald-trump-softens-tone-as-china-us-trade-tensions-flare/3mxy3fa5w</link><description>Trump has taken a less confrontational approach in his latest social media post on trade tensions with China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3b5920f3cfcf1b4d5b76ade1743c953</guid></item></channel></rss>