<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>SBS English News (Unofficial Aggregation)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 22:10:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>ANZ says AUD heading for US $0.73 as Cochlear warns of currency impacts</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/anz-says-aud-heading-for-us-0-73-as-cochlear-warns-of-currency-impacts/wsgwt9wkq</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Cochlear CEO Dig Howett about the hearing implant maker&amp;apos;s latest results, the link between hearing loss and dementia and the impact the higher Australian dollar will have on its earnings. Plus Mahjabeen Zaman from ANZ looks at the drivers of the surging currency and market implications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42f8e2c561a9ae5cf39a98c24d17d495</guid></item><item><title>Australians&amp;apos; personal data could soon be accessible by US agencies. Here&amp;apos;s why</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trumps-america-wants-access-to-australian-biometric-data/ftomgcy5j</link><description>Speculation over a proposal to hand Australians&amp;apos; biometric data to the US is raising concerns among privacy experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">987aeea1bfcfee4bb17c2ec2db139020</guid></item><item><title>The Lunar New Year DIY dumpling event putting a new spin on a centuries-old tradition</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-lunar-new-year-diy-dumpling-event-putting-a-new-spin-on-a-centuries-old-tradition/9v84r6nfv</link><description>Dumplings are popular dish for families celebrating Lunar New Year. In Melbourne, one restaurant is challenging tradition, with a make-your-own approach and a range of exotic flavours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eedc6ad00fdae68b5bc59e344ab07f51</guid></item><item><title>Tears of joy as snowboarder Josie Baff scores Australia&amp;apos;s second Winter Olympics gold</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/josie-baff-australian-gold-medal-winter-olympics/zn3rfx836</link><description>Baff knew fellow Aussie gold medalist Cooper Woods growing up, and said his victory a day earlier &amp;quot;sparked a little fire in me&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05a9a84da360fb12e66d2adfb4c3997c</guid></item><item><title>Gary wasn&amp;apos;t impressed by Australia&amp;apos;s dumpling scene. Now he&amp;apos;s selling thousands a day</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/gary-wasnt-impressed-by-australias-dumpling-scene-now-hes-selling-thousands-a-day/6cqp6gbvw</link><description>Dumplings are a popular dish for Lunar New Year celebrations. However, one Australian restaurant is bringing a twist to the tradition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb7b517bfea453ff19d2afdbddc7b828</guid></item><item><title>Mariam&amp;apos;s story of survival amid a &amp;apos;war on women&amp;apos; in Sudan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sudan-gender-based-violence-crisis/pq1retgcu</link><description>Nearly three years into a civil war, Sudan is facing a hunger crisis. It&amp;apos;s also facing a crisis of violence against women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b43f4f5700f9567aeaa6bd8cc8cc4164</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Can a souffle rise once?&amp;apos;: Albanese takes first swipe at new Opposition leaders</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anthony-albanese-angus-taylor-criticism/0nhyfq7cc</link><description>The prime minister has made his first comments about the ouster of Sussan Ley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6e3b267d66d4b53d17f4a08e214f20c</guid></item><item><title>With their first female leader gone, can the Liberals shake their &amp;apos;women problem&amp;apos;?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/liberals-women-problem-after-sussan-ley-dumped-as-first-female-leader/bamdvwqf3</link><description>Senior Liberals say Sussan Ley&amp;apos;s removal was about polling, not gender. But experts warn it may reinforce doubts about the party&amp;apos;s appeal to women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d355396c4df18a1ae16f181a7a00f27c</guid></item><item><title>Injured Australian aerials champion ruled out of Winter Olympics</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/injured-australian-aerials-champion-ruled-out-of-winter-olympics/w5why8969</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s two-time aerials world champion Laura Peel is the fourth Australian to withdraw from the Milano Cortina Winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b140b89691e7f3863e108be05c33b55e</guid></item><item><title>How a hairdressing client list became a campaign to help Jay and Jeremy become dads</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/how-a-hair-stylists-client-list-became-a-campaign-to-change-surrogacy-laws/68mzq9pv6</link><description>Jay always wanted to be a dad, but WA&amp;apos;s surrogacy laws meant significant barriers. So he became the face of a campaign to change them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53732ac447f6e05155105724ced5769a</guid></item><item><title>Mariam&amp;apos;s story of survival amid a &amp;apos;war on women&amp;apos; in Sudan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/mariams-story-of-survival-amid-a-war-on-women-in-sudan/559hvyz8u</link><description>Women and girls are bearing the brunt of Sudan’s nearly three-year-old civil war, facing widespread gender-based violence, displacement and deepening hunger as the conflict intensifies. 18-year-old Mariam, a survivor of sexual violence has had to flee escalating violence to an under-resourced displacement camp where food and medicine is in limited supply. With famine spreading and humanitarian access shrinking, organisations like Plan International warn the needs of survivors far exceed the support available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccb165ec3003c083b17779b613cc8301</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: What needs to happen to bring the Murray Darling Basin back to health?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-what-needs-to-happen-to-bring-the-murray-darling-basin-back-to-health/flm7l3sho</link><description>The Murray Darling Basin management plan is currently under review. Public submissions on a discussion paper [[see it here: https://www.mdba.gov.au/publications-and-data/publications/2026-basin-plan-review-discussion-paper]] are being accepted until 1 May 2026, as authorities determine their next steps in managing Australia&amp;apos;s biggest river ecosystem. SBS has spoken with the national director of the Murray Darling Conservation Alliance, Craig Wilkins, about what those next steps should be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">107ced71972b7468aa2d561b3496af10</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Unprecedented times&amp;apos;: Jakara Anthony&amp;apos;s Winter Olympic gold secures record medal haul for Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jakara-anthony-winter-olympics-gold-medal/dbfe6nwgy</link><description>The 27-year-old skier has become Australia&amp;apos;s first ever two-time Winter Olympic gold medallist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e192cf53d0b05c84d9e8b1713d704f8</guid></item><item><title>Which states get an Anzac Day public holiday this year?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anzac-day-public-holiday-which-states/0nax12a1k</link><description>With Anzac Day falling on a weekend this year, an extra public holiday has been announced for the people of NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">936e15ece260f9f695fc5dad08385b7d</guid></item><item><title>Weet-bix kimchi: Glynn&amp;apos;s experiment with Australian and Korean favourites may be a hit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/weet-bix-fermented-australian-kimchi-from-regional-tasmania/a2mc6iuwy</link><description>Through Weet-Bix kimchi, Sue Glynn is connecting Australia and Korea in regional Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ec4b8c1f091ad0d6e73233d81175b3d</guid></item><item><title>Darren&amp;apos;s hunted zebras and bears overseas. Now a &amp;apos;trophy&amp;apos; ban is in Australia&amp;apos;s sights</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/killing-or-conservation-inside-australias-trophy-hunting-fight/gwb6i8s0o</link><description>Supporters say trophy hunting is misunderstood. But critics call it cruelty dressed up as conservation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28ca3e1d648592f5b5689d3046457eb0</guid></item><item><title>What fasting for Ramadan is like for a sailor, a midwife and a miner</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-ramadan-fasting-is-like-in-australian-workplaces/afrnkk8oh</link><description>Australians in high-stakes workplaces — from ships to hospitals to mine sites — reveal the realities of observing Ramadan while on the job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c1bbaf3d65d4ea06f7ee15a701863a9</guid></item><item><title>Israel&amp;apos;s approval of West Bank land registration condemned as &amp;apos;de facto annexation&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/de-facto-annexation-israel-approves-proposal-to-register-land-in-west-bank-as-state-property/rregk7fxr</link><description>The land registration adds to a series of measures taken earlier this ⁠month to expand control.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">477e43337d5c4334ee3182e76cb3db93</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Not fair dinkum&amp;apos;: ACCC rejects Coles&amp;apos; arguments in landmark &amp;apos;illusory&amp;apos; discounts legal case</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/accc-coles-misleading-discounts-allegations-federal-court-case/92p7elywx</link><description>The consumer watchdog&amp;apos;s barrister said increased costs are irrelevant to whether products are promoted to customers as genuine discounts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90cb79de359ce0e690dcb4531d1e24e4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Iran is my home as well&amp;apos;: Worldwide turnout of hundreds of thousands in solidarity with Iranian protesters</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/iran-is-my-home-as-well-worldwide-turnout-of-hundreds-of-thousands-in-solidarity-with-iranian-protesters/4wlnbwj7e</link><description>From Munich to Melbourne, hundreds of thousands have turned out to oppose Iran&amp;apos;s clerical leadership in the wake of a brutal crackdown on protesters inside the country. While opinions differ over who should take over the current regime, protesters all voiced their desire for an Iran free from oppression.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acab2944d9da356f03fbe9dad0de4b16</guid></item><item><title>Court appearance for alleged Bondi shooter | SBS News In Easy English 16 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/court-appearance-for-alleged-bondi-shooter-sbs-news-in-easy-english-16-february-2026/b9qdml1j4</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d542eef3447d36c32b21b79b6eb568</guid></item><item><title>Opposition was preparing widespread immigration bans under Sussan Ley&amp;apos;s leadership</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/opposition-was-preparing-widespread-immigration-bans-before-liberal-leadership-spill/z89xa831g</link><description>The Opposition&amp;apos;s immigration spokesperson under Ley has said he never proposed nor agreed to the policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75fc8909326c7874899db49ff85e3b52</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s history-making Winter Olympics — and how it compares to previous years</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-is-making-winter-olympics-history-how-does-2026-compare-to-previous-years/ln49ommb3</link><description>There&amp;apos;s still one week to go in this year&amp;apos;s Winter Games, which are shaping up to be record-breaking for Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b02d46a7af3d40aa5d99e5278d021402</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians look to salvage Gaza&amp;apos;s history from the ruins of war</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/palestinians-look-to-salvage-gazas-history-from-the-ruins-of-war/fsx3yp0sc</link><description>.The Gaza Strip is home to some extraordinary remnants of human history, dating from the Bronze Age through to the Ottoman and British empires.Many historic sites suffered from neglect before the war - but the United Nations cultural agency, UNESCO, says it has verified damage to at least 150 historic heritage sites since the start of the Israel-Hamas conflict. Palestinians in the Gaza Strip are reckoning with how to save their historical monuments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60ffd6545c3d500ffc25cd320e0fadbe</guid></item><item><title>Tech stocks recover and IMF warns Australian states on spending</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/tech-stocks-recover-and-imf-warns-australian-states-on-spending/0s02gxzdv</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Alex Pikoulas from Munjarra Capital about the day&amp;apos;s market action including the latest profit results and the turn around in the tech sector; plus Anthony Walker from SP Global Ratings after the IMF warned Australian states to reign in spending.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43b0fbadbee53b48850dfbcc9b34ad5a</guid></item><item><title>Australians sent back to Syrian camp holding suspected IS families after being released</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-released-from-syrias-roj-camp-of-is-affiliated-families/1rgyuwnlg</link><description>The women and children had been released from Roj camp in Syria for repatriation to Australia but were then forced to turn back.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">26322fb548e3176acc02e121375f569a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I want to taste everything&amp;apos;: Why millions of people make this annual pilgrimage</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lunar-new-year-2026-asian-australian-pilgrimage-to-asia/zvkose308</link><description>As many Asians living in Australia return to their ancestral homes for Lunar New Year, what awaits them can be surprising.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3ee4356f8a27e52978c2ac52cefcc3e</guid></item><item><title>Kath hosted her late partner Nigel&amp;apos;s wake while he was still alive</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/living-funerals-living-wakes-australia/9pst1yh9d</link><description>Living funerals are an emerging practice in Australia, allowing people to say goodbye to loved ones before they die.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fecd296f29f559aafdc724b93616899a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Very rare&amp;apos;: Israeli prosecutors to charge West Bank settler over killing of Palestinian activist</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-prosecutors-west-bank-settler-palestinian-activist-killing/gjsv4v806</link><description>The decision is an uncommon legal step amid mounting criticism over accountability for violence in the occupied territories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c918705833496bb27912438ce6db9d46</guid></item><item><title>Who are the Australians with alleged IS links seeking to return from a Syrian camp?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/who-are-the-australians-with-is-links-seeking-to-return-from-a-syrian-displacement-camp/kteqt8i8c</link><description>The government says it won&amp;apos;t help repatriate a group of Australian women and children with links to the self-proclaimed Islamic State group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d56243d1db928e888eafea40e2204ee1</guid></item><item><title>Protest restrictions eased in Sydney after nearly two months</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/protest-restrictions-eased-sydney-after-nearly-two-months/dxgzax77y</link><description>The restrictions were rushed through NSW parliament after the Bondi terror attack in December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f704a31ecfe8e3085c759370a6358abc</guid></item><item><title>The Year of the Horse welcomed around the world</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-year-of-the-horse-welcomed-around-the-world/3lq7ejito</link><description>The Lunar New Year has begun with vibrant celebrations welcoming the Year of the Horse, from fireworks in Vietnam and bustling Hong Kong markets to festive streets in Malaysia and Peru. Families gather for symbolic meals, travellers embrace cultural traditions, and global leaders send messages of unity, marking a holiday that connects communities across Asia and around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ba4953eddbb2b1db8473ffe2f3cc2b2</guid></item><item><title>How the tale of one possum reveals threats to thousands of Aussie species</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/how-the-tale-of-one-possum-reveals-threats-to-thousands-of-aussie-species/udv2e0mic</link><description>Australia’s unique wildlife is facing an escalating extinction crisis, driven primarily by climate change and compounded by habitat loss. 34 new species of plants and animals have been added to the government&amp;apos;s threatened species list this February, including the lemuroid ringtail possum - native to north Queensland&amp;apos;s Wet Tropics region. Researchers say urgent climate action and stronger environmental protections are critical to prevent further irreversible loss of Australia&amp;apos;s signature biodiversity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">722b1ba0b95aff16d1dbd79f09844c98</guid></item><item><title>PM rules out repatriation for Australians with alleged IS links in Syria | SBS News In Easy English 17 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pm-rules-out-repatriation-for-australians-with-alleged-is-links-in-syria-sbs-news-in-easy-english-17-february-2026/bmscm041v</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da9a73967005936c2a608aaffb513308</guid></item><item><title>See the full list: Opposition leader Angus Taylor unveils fresh shadow ministry</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/opposition-leader-angus-taylor-unveils-fresh-shadow-ministry/411rnsatg</link><description>The Opposition has unveiled its shadow ministry, with a mix of new and old faces taking up frontbench positions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30c8a6673f858a86346eda8d60d5c4d6</guid></item><item><title>Do migrants feel they belong in Australia? The answer is complicated</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/do-new-migrants-feel-they-belong-to-australia-the-answer-is-complicated-study-shows/x8hre58vx</link><description>Interviews with migrants from Australia&amp;apos;s fastest growing communities show only 32 per cent feel a great sense of belonging.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a0880652b41e2492d333b9fd92a951b</guid></item><item><title>BHP CFO on copper growth opportunties, iron ore future and growing dividends</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/bhp-cfo-on-copper-growth-opportunties-iron-ore-future-and-growing-dividends/02zrgxnfj</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with BHP CFO Vandita Pant following the miner&amp;apos;s US$5.6bn half-year profit to find out more about its growing copper business and future dividend policy; plus Jonathan Shead from State Street Investment Management on the investment environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2824a48dbba0de5f40c6e4e216eaeaea</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;It was a no-brainer&amp;apos;: The baby boomer retirement myth being upended</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/no-brainer-why-more-young-people-like-zoe-are-rethinking-their-australian-dream/4mdmrz8w2</link><description>You might think it&amp;apos;s boomers and empty nesters moving to these parts of Australia, according to an expert. New data tells a different story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62fd14a4e7eefeaebde2c93bd0fd52d4</guid></item><item><title>Sabina quit snacking after monitoring her sugar levels. Is the data that simple?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/sabina-quit-snacking-when-she-started-monitoring-her-sugar-levels-but-is-the-data-that-simple/pbtwrxi7s</link><description>Continuous glucose monitors provide live data for blood sugar levels. But is access to this health data a good thing for non-diabetics?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9949b35d971804969c78494c20b22ba6</guid></item><item><title>Government stands firm on not assisting or repatriating IS families in Syria</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/government-stands-firm-on-not-assisting-or-repatriating-is-families-in-syria/wpbepaasa</link><description>The last remaining Australian women and children with links to the IS Group have been sent back to a Syrian camp after attempting to repatriate themselves home. The group of 34 left al-Roj in the country&amp;apos;s northeast overnight - but a communications issue with Damascus forced their return to the camp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e9e14d59c3df3ef6949b17a1d9b7674</guid></item><item><title>Tilda Swinton, Javier Bardem and others criticise Berlin Film Festival&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;silence&amp;apos; on Gaza</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dozens-condemn-berlin-film-festival-silence-on-gaza/zojo9eirv</link><description>An open letter signed by film industry figures condemned the Berlin Film Festival&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;neutral stance&amp;quot; on Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc759321283e6cb70c28b7731efe316c</guid></item><item><title>Man with shot gun arrested in Capitol Hill | SBS News in Easy English 18 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/man-with-shot-gun-arrested-in-capitol-hill-sbs-news-in-easy-english-18-february-2026/ksyu4ody4</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English Language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f849dc5eb6244900f98042f437307a52</guid></item><item><title>Government bans woman with alleged IS links from returning to Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/government-bans-woman-with-alleged-is-links-from-returning-to-australia/2tt852ezp</link><description>Human rights advocates say the move could render the Australian &amp;quot;stateless&amp;quot;, stressing the government&amp;apos;s duty under international law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba7219fc6a23c8927aaaa3908ee5b737</guid></item><item><title>No, not even water: A guide to Ramadan for non-Muslims</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/no-not-even-water-a-guide-to-ramadan-for-non-muslims/tnccci4jz</link><description>Wonder what Ramadan is all about? Here&amp;apos;s why many Muslims fast during the holy month, and how to best support your practising friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ea3cf88301b12b1bfbbbb35758ee3ad</guid></item><item><title>No, not even water: A guide to Ramadan for non-Muslims</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ramadan-guide-for-non-muslims/54526knpd</link><description>Wonder what Ramadan is all about? Here&amp;apos;s why many Muslims fast during the holy month, and how to best support your practising friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">008bc76385c6c58b7e095e90dbcc82a6</guid></item><item><title>Muslim leaders&amp;apos; three requests as Australia&amp;apos;s largest mosque receives new threatening letter</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ramadan-islamophobia-concerns-australia-lakemba-mosque/pacrzf7gp</link><description>It comes amid unease and safety concerns in Muslim communities across the country ahead of Ramadan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df5d22a74566b2b2d3754aab27911afa</guid></item><item><title>Racism revealed to be widespread and systemic in Australian universities</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/racism-revealed-to-be-widespread-and-systemic-in-australian-universities/fwtgzu973</link><description>The first national report on racism at universities in Australia has found it is a problem that is widespread and systemic. The report found 70 per cent of students and staff from 42 universities had witnessed racism. Levels of racism were higher among Indigenous, Chinese, African, Jewish and Middle Eastern students and staff; with only six per cent of those who experienced racism making a complaint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">102a45d8a073aa7a6d8fcded2bf39b88</guid></item><item><title>Inflation eats into wages as cost of living worsens</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/inflation-eats-into-wages-as-cost-of-living-worsens/wwh0xx8vk</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Devika Shivadear from RSM Australia about the latest Wage Price Index which shows real wages has gone backwards; plus a look at the day on the sharemarket with Jun Bei Lui from Ten Cap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8cf63144fa527125134c8d48ec0ae0c</guid></item><item><title>What makes people proud to be Australian? The answer might surprise you</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-national-pride-pew-report/0nv0le4l0</link><description>These are the factors that influence Australians&amp;apos; sense of pride in their country — and those that don&amp;apos;t, according to a new report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eed3ed5fe8f7c27b6189a11768778941</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Means everything&amp;apos;: Australian Danielle Scott claims aerial skiing silver at the Olympics</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/aussie-danielle-scott-claims-aerial-skiing-silver-at-the-olympics/gmb3ohoav</link><description>Freestyle skier Danielle Scott is officially an Olympic medallist, breaking through to win silver in the aerials in her fourth Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2117ad285a4427987359e3f96bdfbf2c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Means everything&amp;apos;: Australian Danielle Scott claims aerial skiing silver at the Olympics</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-danielle-scott-claims-aerial-skiing-silver-at-the-olympics/gmb3ohoav</link><description>Freestyle skier Danielle Scott is officially an Olympic medallist, breaking through to win silver in the aerials in her fourth Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edd808832cf6c806fdb57e97bded519e</guid></item><item><title>The super mistake that could cost you more than $120,000 at retirement</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-not-checking-your-super-could-cost-you-over-120-000-at-retirement/pnthrysuz</link><description>One in four Australians couldn&amp;apos;t answer a key question about their super, a new survey found, prompting a warning from a peak body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c2cbb25ea15d4fc5be17bfee32b7415</guid></item><item><title>Eight skiers found dead after California avalanche, one still missing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/california-avalanche-skiers-found-dead/q7villp8m</link><description>Rescuers had earlier reached six survivors in &amp;quot;extreme&amp;quot; conditions near Lake Tahoe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72c5ca3a4fa51756bcac700262330541</guid></item><item><title>How Palestinians in Gaza are marking their first Ramadan since fragile truce took hold</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/first-ramadan-after-israel-truce-gaza/gf29g2o4e</link><description>Amid the devastation, some in Gaza City are working to revive Ramadan festivities as Palestinian Muslims celebrate the holy month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c4961f773fd6e01153ce818fa021e04</guid></item><item><title>Local dog goes for gold as he gatecrashes Olympic sprint</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dog-winter-olympics/llc8znnnb</link><description>The unexpected competitor, a &amp;quot;stubborn, but very sweet&amp;quot; resident of a nearby bed-and-breakfast, joined skiers down the home stretch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8d82bece2ee1785100b99c7809eab33</guid></item><item><title>Zuckerberg on the stand: Why this new social media trial could be a turning point</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/mark-zuckerberg-on-the-stand-why-this-new-social-media-trial-can-be-a-turning-point/te9xkchob</link><description>It&amp;apos;s the first time Mark Zuckerberg has addressed child safety on his platforms before a jury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2184b06c5ed621e76c003020623d848</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Outrageous decision&amp;apos;: Why are Ukrainian officials boycotting the Paralympics?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ukraine-officials-boycott-russia-competing-in-paralympics/ri4di1uft</link><description>Paralympians from Russia and Belarus have been given the green light to compete — and not as neutral individuals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba50d0ec60fa8cc4d3315a1ffa2193e3</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Need to do more of everything&amp;apos;: Australia&amp;apos;s 2030 goal that&amp;apos;s at risk</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australias-2030-goal-thats-at-risk/i1kn803tk</link><description>The figures are heading in the wrong direction — but some believe simple changes could make a difference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7305d7db5413037867e238b7819dc3b2</guid></item><item><title>Eight skiers die California avalanche |SBS News in Easy English 19 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/eight-skiers-die-california-avalanche-sbs-news-in-easy-english-19-february-2026/9hywmdxd9</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28f9ca11622df7f0d0a45d4b55e7c3bb</guid></item><item><title>Is Australia facing an economic reality not seen since World War Two?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-government-debt-analysis/b7ibrbt13</link><description>As debt climbs, some economists warn Australia may face difficult choices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06199b7b66ecd598be892af76a920d60</guid></item><item><title>Latest labour data increases chance of a rate rise, experts warn</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/labour-data-rate-rise-rba/if516z32w</link><description>A historically strong jobs market has raised the chances of another rate rise in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2d56251cd2d54094dad9985d944d963</guid></item><item><title>Is the US approach to Europe softening? Israel moves in the West Bank and, well, cocaine sharks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/is-the-us-approach-to-europe-softening-israel-moves-in-the-west-bank-and-well-cocaine-sharks/eedp75dnt</link><description>Marco Rubio sends mixed messages to Europe, Israel starts registration of large areas of the occupied West Bank and how new is Bangladesh’s new government? Plus, Chinoys celebrate lunar new year in the Philippines and Cocaine Sharks coming to waters near you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eedbad5d2a38d20b772a580700fdb5a9</guid></item><item><title>Government blocks return of Australian woman from Syrian refugee camp for IS Group families</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/government-blocks-return-of-australian-woman-from-syrian-refugee-camp-for-is-group-families/ajfnnky6u</link><description>Home Affairs Minister Tony Burke has blocked the immediate return of an Australian woman from Syria via a temporary exclusion order. It follows what the government is calling its no assistance policy for 34 citizens recently turned back by Syrian authorities. While the Prime Minister insists those who joined the IS Group must live with their choices, legal and human rights experts argue that abandoning children and coerced women in detention camps poses a greater long-term radicalisation risk than bringing them home to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3c7d83f825ac86c4f3bcad4447fa48a</guid></item><item><title>Jobless rate stays at 4.1% and ASX hits another record</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/jobless-rate-stays-at-4-1-and-asx-hits-another-record/novh8uo7s</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Hugh Lam, CFA from Betashares for his take on the markets as the ASX200 hits another record high, the jobless rate remains at 4.1% and takes a look at the latest company profit reports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7f72580089b8a17545290d15b3f2f46</guid></item><item><title>They&amp;apos;re &amp;apos;devastated&amp;apos;: Fresh plea for Australian children in Syrian detention camps</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fresh-plea-for-australian-children-in-syrian-detention-camps/qb9z6g3xw</link><description>Child welfare advocates are calling for the return of Australians from a detention camp in Syria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6de4d7e72a9be526b4f3ca30a9a13cc1</guid></item><item><title>Calls for major change after deadly mental health escapes in Sydney</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/calls-for-major-change-after-deadly-mental-health-escapes-in-sydney/ta8d6md7r</link><description>A WARNING THAT THIS STORY MAY BE DISTRESSING FOR SOME LISTENERS The New South Wales government is investigating the circumstances surrounding the escape of two patients from the same hospital, who days later were allegedly involved in separate incidents where three people died. Mental health professionals say it&amp;apos;s again thrown the state&amp;apos;s mental health care crisis into the spotlight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94250522597c5c31ef86bfbb52a828e3</guid></item><item><title>See the full list: Private insurer price hikes — and how to save cash</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/private-health-price-hikes-list/4y8b9j6s8</link><description>The 4.41 per cent increase announced this week is an industry average, and some insurers will raise premiums by more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f65163aacd735aac03c65c61161e7e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Canary in the coal mine&amp;apos;: The possum on the frontline of Australia&amp;apos;s extinction crisis</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/possum-threatened-species-australia/mar3m3qe5</link><description>The lemuroid ringtail possum is one of 34 species that have just been added to Australia&amp;apos;s threatened species list.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">419030bdf41553d86ad5248dc27e49c8</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Hallmarks of genocide&amp;apos; found in Sudan, UN says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sudan-civil-war-genocide-united-nations/9ci878kco</link><description>A UN fact-finding mission concluded that the RSF paramilitary group had acted &amp;quot;with genocidal intent&amp;quot; during the seizure of Al-Fasher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e1b4ca051ed27b50ee05ddef3b60928</guid></item><item><title>How former prince Andrew went from pilot to fallen figure</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/prince-andrew-arrested-after-decades-controversies-epstein/9okjjpkjc</link><description>Former prince Andrew has left the police station after 10 hours of questioning by UK Police for alleged misconduct in public office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c7dbdc38ac27aea868883da9adb3335</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 20 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-20-february-2026/7a0chyaxj</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38c904a9171b7a08a6f889f720a2501e</guid></item><item><title>Trump&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;Board of Peace&amp;apos; flags billions in Gaza aid, US issues fresh threats against Iran</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trumps-board-of-peace-flags-billions-in-gaza-aid-us-issues-fresh-threats-against-iran/61ija714i</link><description>United States President Donald Trump has held the inaugural meeting of his so-called &amp;quot;Board of Peace&amp;quot;, pledging AU$14.2 billion for the reconstruction of Gaza. Boasting his role as a peacemaker while leveling fresh threats against Iran, Donald Trump says the board will help achieve peace in the Middle East.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f393c32b05fef7a8e3c624c14447a91d</guid></item><item><title>Australian Federal Police says reports of crime received over Pauline Hanson&amp;apos;s remarks on Muslims</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australian-federal-police-says-reports-of-crime-received-over-pauline-hansons-remarks-on-muslims/gu8yllg4m</link><description>The fallout continues after One Nation leader Pauline Hanson suggested earlier this week that there are no &amp;quot;good&amp;quot; Muslims. The Australian Federal Police says it has received reports of a crime in relation to comments made by Ms Hanson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8af3d4854dd2454e826f3cfc83a7b91c</guid></item><item><title>UN says siege at el-Fasher shows evidence of genocide</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/un-says-siege-at-el-fasher-shows-evidence-of-genocide/dn8pk0jel</link><description>A United Nations fact-finding mission in Sudan has found the 18-month long siege and subsequent capture of El-Fasher in the Darfur region, last October, bears evidence of genocide. The United States, in response, has imposed sanctions on paramilitary commanders. But experts are calling for far stronger global response, to stop the violence from continuing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67b44c87ccd5592d6997297d773fd5d8</guid></item><item><title>US goods deficit widens despite tariffs and market reacts to QBE and Rio results</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-goods-deficit-widens-despite-tariffs-and-market-reacts-to-qbe-and-rio-results/hw7rv3gfm</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Marcus Bogdan from Blackmore Capital on the day&amp;apos;s market action, including a wrap of the major profits and a look at the latest US trade figures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">580e857a3f35ad08877c8838004e7915</guid></item><item><title>Dreams of being a ballerina: Hopes of Australian child in Syrian camp for IS-linked families</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/dreams-of-being-a-ballerina-hopes-of-australian-child-in-syrian-camp-for-is-linked-families/cirb1lqi9</link><description>An Australian child in a camp for families with links to IS fighters says she wants to come to Australia, a family member told SBS.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39a2a8627a39f3a12dbf41b107665041</guid></item><item><title>Is there a &amp;apos;sweet spot&amp;apos;? These five charts are key to the migration debate</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/migration-sweet-spot-these-five-charts-are-key-to-the-migration-debate/69sydxzau</link><description>The government&amp;apos;s opponents have fuelled debate over Australia&amp;apos;s migration numbers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">497fbfd7c4bac40ce6fd64181e9e7f19</guid></item><item><title>Cafes and restaurants are closing in record numbers. This couple is bucking the trend</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/cafes-and-restaurants-are-closing-in-record-numbers-this-couple-is-bucking-the-trend/idmdixlzv</link><description>Australian restaurants and cafes are in crisis, according to a new report. Rising costs and falling revenue have forced one in ten food service outlets to close over the past year. However, one Australian couple has found ways to survive and thrive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a756f557c58c219c62ff4af75d746bf0</guid></item><item><title>It scares me all the time&amp;apos;: Exploring new ways to improve water safety</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/it-scares-me-all-the-time-exploring-new-ways-to-improve-water-safety/tv4tmgse9</link><description>Australian and Indian drowning prevention experts have come together for a two-day workshop to explore new ways to reduce drowning deaths in both countries. Drowning causes tens of thousands of deaths a year in India, and in Australia, experts say the Indian diaspora is among groups that are worryingly over-represented in the country&amp;apos;s drowning fatalities. Through exchanging ideas and building stronger cultural knowledge, workshop participants have explored new, sustainable ways to improve water safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f549fe883614f2768571cddb913e4298</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: New project explores power of language and shared histories</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-new-project-explores-power-of-language-and-shared-histories/1049wei0n</link><description>The Acknowledgement of Country has been translated into 40 languages as part of a project led by Dr Elaine Laforteza. She explains how it started and the vision for what comes next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5753be9e2251151328da43f539855b9d</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: How students are combating racism at Australian universities</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-how-students-are-combating-racism-at-australian-universities/k7nspp61k</link><description>The University of Melbourne Student Union is preparing to release the findings of its fourth report on racism on campus. The union&amp;apos;s president, Lushy Chinganya, explains what it found and how it connects with the latest Human Rights Commission report on the same issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c5f20cdcd4f55b023a69a7b832ab919</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We nearly gave up&amp;apos;: These pizza chefs bought their first home. It hasn&amp;apos;t been easy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/we-nearly-gave-up-these-pizza-chefs-bought-their-first-home-it-hasnt-been-easy/ksabcq74o</link><description>Australian restaurants and cafes are in crisis, according to a new report. One Melbourne couple has found ways to survive and thrive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ecdd8b9f5ae06d381bd74defdd7d84d</guid></item><item><title>Daylight upon the magic: How former prince Andrew&amp;apos;s arrest could impact the royal family</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/daylight-on-the-magic-how-former-prince-andrews-arrest-can-impact-the-royal-family/chs8quqrz</link><description>The last time a British royal was arrested, it led to the fall of the crown. Could it happen again?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d74a4ba28cf2fe646313cecb9f3b6318</guid></item><item><title>What is the rules-based order and is Trump really threatening it?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rules-based-order-donald-trump/tucqu8dcw</link><description>Global leaders warn that the post-war rules-based order is unravelling. But is the system collapsing or just under strain?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8d1fd3bb13d216660cf4b2883624bfb</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I knocked on every single farm&amp;apos;: How Sammy Jeon went from backpacker to restaurateur</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/chef-sammy-jeon-on-bringing-east-asian-food-to-orange-nsw/icytsfkn8</link><description>Renowned Korean Australian chef Sammy Jeon&amp;apos;s culinary journey started when one regional winery took a chance on him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8827a22c10d88044d2e8cd199143fc5f</guid></item><item><title>Experts say Russia&amp;apos;s government ensures its longevity by crushing dissent</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/experts-say-russias-government-ensures-its-longevity-by-crushing-dissent/kb1o3ujsw</link><description>This week will mark four years since Russia began its full scale invasion of Ukraine. Since then, experts say President Vladimir Putin has intensified efforts in his ongoing campaign to quash dissent and political opposition - many resistance leaders and activists inside Russia, jailed - or dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76c7d3302660ad4d5c96fb94e6012f20</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s underground hardcore scene just went global — you can thank a flute for that</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-hardcore-band-speed-on-making-community-from-chaos/ejqim6r47</link><description>Australian hardcore band SPEED started out playing for a room of 60 people. Now they&amp;apos;re fronting thousands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72750f856a2e2bfa9bc6010676c69b93</guid></item><item><title>No advice from ASIO to block passports of women with alleged IS links, Burke says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/no-advice-from-asio-to-block-passports-of-women-with-alleged-is-links-burke-says/dzan5s9gi</link><description>The home affairs minister said the government had not received advice that would require any further temporary exclusion orders to be issued.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6a31e58e0e58b09d74b4d7eacb1d35d</guid></item><item><title>Burke reveals process has begun to ban Islamist group Hizb ut-Tahrir</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tony-burke-reveals-process-has-begun-to-ban-islamist-group-hizb-ut-tahrir/lbridgo4j</link><description>The home affairs minister revealed his department had received advice from ASIO that the group met the legal threshold to be banned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c986cb3aca8526b992992a80c29a1b96</guid></item><item><title>A Chinese museum comes to life in the year of the fire horse</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-chinese-museum-comes-to-life-in-the-year-of-the-fire-horse/76zqqjzx6</link><description>The first museum in New South Wales dedicated to the history of Chinese people in Australia has opened in the heart of Sydney&amp;apos;s Chinatown. The Museum of Chinese in Australia [[MOCA]] dedicates its stories to some of Australia&amp;apos;s earliest migrants - preserving Chinese history and culture in the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dcb79913d49b0f05ca9f2920077a335</guid></item><item><title>Middle East states denounce US diplomat&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;inflammatory&amp;apos; backing of Israeli expansion</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/middle-east-states-denounce-us-diplomats-inflammatory-support-for-israeli-expansion/xcz0nzfp1</link><description>More than a dozen countries condemned Mike Huckabee&amp;apos;s suggestion that Israel had a right to large parts of the Middle East.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb48cd413838cff90538ae4aa515c965</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;What&amp;apos;s fair?&amp;apos;: The wages problem that&amp;apos;s led to some roles being &amp;apos;massively overpaid&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-professions-that-work-the-least-but-are-paid-the-most/0awq6v23l</link><description>Some occupations are very well paid, and here&amp;apos;s why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91069aa3eeafdf56aa0c8f9f1502c851</guid></item><item><title>Armed intruder shot dead at Donald Trump&amp;apos;s Mar-a-Lago resort</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/police-fatally-shoot-armed-intruder-at-mar-a-lago/6i7ta9mub</link><description>Police have fatally shot a man armed with a shotgun and fuel can at US President Donald Trump&amp;apos;s Florida resort.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd3462e366483d24b8cc38d6d2eb6fe0</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;No thanks&amp;apos;: Greenland, Denmark reject Donald Trump&amp;apos;s offer of medical aid</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/no-thanks-greenland-denmark-reject-donald-trumps-offer/caz3rgmq8</link><description>Greenland&amp;apos;s prime minister says US President Donald Trump should talk to him instead of making &amp;quot;random outbursts on social media&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e17d064e479a5fc99d6ba16c1b15ad70</guid></item><item><title>Furious Iranian students hold anti-government protests for second day as US threats loom</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/furious-iranian-students-hold-anti-government-protests-for-second-day-as-us-threats-loom/exyghy3fg</link><description>The anti-government protests have led to more clashes at several Iranian universities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55a40f051f476b08c5cd5eae215990ea</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Unintended consequences&amp;apos;: Coalition&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;terrorist hotspot&amp;apos; proposal raises questions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/terrorist-hotspot-key-question-in-coalitions-plan-to-criminalise-help-to-returning-australians/f6htmey7b</link><description>An element of the plan is &amp;quot;not really known to Australian law&amp;quot;, a legal expert says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbcd319cd1b1ecf6ef79c885f62bee9f</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Unintended consequences&amp;apos;: Coalition&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;terrorist hotspot&amp;apos; proposal raises questions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/coalitions-plan-to-criminalise-assistance-to-australians-with-alleged-is-links/f6htmey7b</link><description>An element of the plan is &amp;quot;not really known to Australian law&amp;quot;, a legal expert says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">930921b7960565525b1e9a844475df2c</guid></item><item><title>As rate hikes loom, Australians scramble to take on increasing amounts of debt</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-reactions-to-interest-rate-hikes-take-on-more-debt/fgp5t4ov2</link><description>Instead of tightening their belts, Australians are taking on more and bigger home loans, while demand for credit cards is soaring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6deb9a05b3d40701db2ceb6952a8742</guid></item><item><title>Man shot dead attempting to enter Trump estate | SBS News in Easy English 23 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/man-shot-dead-attempting-to-enter-trump-estate-sbs-news-in-easy-english-23-february-2026/u1vykusqp</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dae983213250d25a788a97282880640</guid></item><item><title>Australia faces drenching as storm system set to bring heavy rain and flash floods</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-faces-drenching-as-storm-system-set-to-bring-heavy-rain-and-flash-floods/882zlhxny</link><description>Heavy rain and severe storms are expected across multiple states, with flash flooding, damaging winds and travel disruptions possible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9084d5c9c5c15abb63d0d3c745d8ad0f</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Abhorrent&amp;apos;: Players targeted with racist abuse after Premier League games</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/premier-league-racist-abuse/e24gullm2</link><description>Just days earlier, an investigation was opened into a Real Madrid player&amp;apos;s claim he was racially abused by another player.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a82d9c87bc1a59019486c9d66df8a26d</guid></item><item><title>Travelling to the UK? Some dual nationals say passport changes have thrown their plans into chaos</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/travelling-to-the-uk-some-dual-nationals-say-passport-changes-have-thrown-their-plans-into-chaos/00rb0iam3</link><description>Travel experts have raised concerns about new border rules for Australian travellers who hold dual British or Irish nationality. From February 25, dual citizens who can&amp;apos;t present a valid British or Irish passport are at risk of being refused entry to the UK. The new regulations are causing widespread confusion, with many not even aware of their links to the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">499223419b6869bb02d49b2697b1024c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Not an empty threat&amp;apos;: Trump builds military presence as US and Iran&amp;apos;s views on talks differ</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/iran-us-talks-differing-views-explained/pnvu2wuvd</link><description>Iran and the United States are set to hold talks in Geneva on Thursday, but an expert says it&amp;apos;s hard to predict the outcome.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">460cbc305adc05c34057618769d77418</guid></item><item><title>Are loopholes undermining Australia&amp;apos;s support for Ukraine?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/loopholes-undermining-australia-ukraine-support/uk9esxhgh</link><description>Australia has slapped nearly 2,000 sanctions on Russia — but some have questioned the effectiveness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b29a226425129e9b87deb4fcf948ce03</guid></item><item><title>Trump Tower planned for Gold Coast would be Australia&amp;apos;s tallest building, developer says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-tower-gold-coast-surfers-paradise/qt2vu2u50</link><description>The skyscraper will reportedly be 91 storeys high and contain a six star resort, but the proposal is far from a done deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a33f18a208d79877ce2b7e970898d87</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Grave allegations&amp;apos;: Albanese writes to Starmer backing Andrew&amp;apos;s succession removal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-backs-removal-of-former-prince-andrew-from-succession/8ywwv101r</link><description>The New Zealand government has since become the second Commonwealth country to voice support for the move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94a58535e2f79b934d018136eb22840d</guid></item><item><title>Australians urged to share their stories as royal commission begins after Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/antisemitism-royal-commission-explained/hr78vjaq0</link><description>Australians are being encouraged to submit their experiences to assist the royal commission into antisemitism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a0ba156f62b5810fb596e0030e76746</guid></item><item><title>UK police arrest ex-ambassador Peter Mandelson after Epstein revelations</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/uk-police-arrest-peter-mandelson-amid-probe-into-allegations-over-ties-to-epstein/xsajzb0di</link><description>British police have arrested a former UK ambassador to the US in a misconduct investigation stemming from his ties with Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2321d8a56575694645a50f31bd200f3a</guid></item><item><title>Russia-Ukraine peace talks continue, but will they ever conclude?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/russia-ukraine-peace-talks-continue-but-will-they-ever-conclude/6bhzbo12o</link><description>As Ukraine enters its fifth year of war, another round of talks aimed at ending the war in Ukraine could be held at the end of this week. Ukraine, Russia and the United States have held several rounds of talks in Abu Dhabi and Geneva; as Washington seeks an end to four years of war since Moscow&amp;apos;s 2022 full-scale invasion. But how close is a real peace deal?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e0b0594d425d73b5479306d49968609</guid></item><item><title>UK government updates rules for dual citizens under new passport laws</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/uk-government-updates-rules-for-dual-citizens-under-new-passport-laws/bvjyg2egh</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1984283d484a10683fd2cf360666354f</guid></item><item><title>Iran would react &amp;apos;ferociously&amp;apos; to US aggression, as student protests continue across the country</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/iran-would-react-ferociously-to-us-aggression-as-local-protests-continue-across-the-country/2unvhn2l2</link><description>Iranian student protesters have defied authorities for a third day, weeks after security forces crushed mass unrest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0d9b26f79738a9ab2d9fce078dd6e43</guid></item><item><title>Severe storms sweep Victoria, leaving thousands without power as &amp;apos;danger&amp;apos; warnings continue</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dangerous-very-quickly-states-flash-flood-warning/pg6stgrif</link><description>Wild storms swept across Victoria on Tuesday night, leaving thousands without power and the SES responding to hundreds of emergency calls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc0d71808754116d9178dff70e27ea7b</guid></item><item><title>Severe storms sweep Victoria, leaving thousands without power as &amp;apos;danger&amp;apos; warnings continue</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/victoria-flash-flood-warning/pg6stgrif</link><description>Wild storms swept across Victoria on Tuesday night, leaving thousands without power and the SES responding to hundreds of emergency calls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41f6bc9f08871eb4c3fdd28276c7510d</guid></item><item><title>Capital gains tax concessions slammed as unfair and cruel to younger generations</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/capital-gains-tax-concessions-slammed-as-unfair-and-cruel-to-younger-generations/e8f2opgor</link><description>A Senate inquiry into housing affordability has heard urgent calls for tax reform, with advocates warning that current capital gains concessions favour wealthy investors while locking the younger generation out of the property market. The Australian Council of Trade Unions argues that reducing these tax breaks could boost home ownership by four per cent. The Grattan Institute maintains the primary benefit would be a $6.5 billion budget windfall to fund public housing and support struggling renters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">082d057206771bce5f2e0e85719856a2</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Buyer Beware&amp;apos;: Europe halts US trade deal after Trump tariffs ruled illegal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/buyer-beware-europe-halts-us-trade-deal-after-trump-tariffs-ruled-illegal/ppz9ikodw</link><description>The European Union has paused the ratification of a US-EU trade agreement after a US Supreme Court ruling and new tariff threats cast doubt on the deal. As Donald Trump threatens new sweeping tariffs, European politicians say they can&amp;apos;t move forward until clarity is provided.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff1eb35c8a29a96b1fe9a971df2cde06</guid></item><item><title>Trump&amp;apos;s tariffs spark fresh round of market uncertainty</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trumps-tariffs-spark-fresh-round-of-market-uncertainty/qa0u4gk2a</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with David Scutt from StoneX Group Inc. about the day&amp;apos;s market action, including how Trump&amp;apos;s tariffs are causing a fresh wave of uncertaintly, plus why investors are keeping a close eye on the private credit markets</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab689e68504d6c2658ead1971ce8cdb9</guid></item><item><title>Police believe remains may belong to missing grandfather | SBS News in Easy English 24 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/police-believe-remains-may-belong-to-missing-grandfather-sbs-news-in-easy-english-24-february-2026/mh82bnmvg</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">002eacb46bff4f4abdc6e443034035a8</guid></item><item><title>Politicians urged to tackle &amp;apos;monopoly-like&amp;apos; issue with iPhone payments</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/apple-wallet-accused-of-freeriding-by-australian-banks/8oxwxsx2l</link><description>Banks and fintech representatives are accusing tech platforms such as Apple of free-riding amid the rapid growth of digital payments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c158fa3056e3bfc4f20a031a574a35b8</guid></item><item><title>BAFTAs scandal: What is Tourette syndrome, what are tics, and why are people angry?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/baftas-scandal-what-is-tourette-syndrome-what-are-tics-and-why-are-people-angry/j5ckaimhc</link><description>Tourette syndrome activist John Davidson says he left the BAFTAs ceremony &amp;quot;aware of the distress my tics were causing&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5477a6fb536c5990592291becdb0f8c1</guid></item><item><title>Human remains found by police in search of kidnapped grandfather | Evening News Bulletin 24 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/human-remains-found-by-police-in-search-of-kidnapped-grandfather-evening-news-bulletin-24-february-2026/ae3iqzknm</link><description>Human remains discovered in Sydney&amp;apos;s north-west suspected to be those of an elderly man who was abducted; Police to investigate a gynaecologist accused of performing unnecessary surgery; And in the AFL, Carlton has signed a player to the longest contract in its history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8ed1137d7cfd76f1e5e73b59f7b8767</guid></item><item><title>$831 billion rebuild cost reveal as Ukrainians in Australia stuck on &amp;apos;hope and heartbreak&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/after-four-years-of-war-ukrainians-in-australia-are-stuck-between-hope-and-heartbreak/a0r6misaf</link><description>As the Russia-Ukraine war enters its fifth year, Ukrainians are exhausted by protracted peace talks and ongoing violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6270cdcd98851c6e95e0ff95a30633ea</guid></item><item><title>How much you need for a comfortable retirement &amp;amp; AI fears continues to spook investors</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/how-much-you-need-for-a-comfortable-retirement-ai-fears-continues-to-spook-investors/k1u6stuw8</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Mike Jenneke from UBS Wealth Management about the day&amp;apos;s market action including investors’ renewed AI fears; plus Stephanie Youssef talks with Jame Koval from ASFA to find out how much you need for a comfortable retirement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d920c74970fda10d35a478a6e1f63e4</guid></item><item><title>Australian jailed in Syria now feared lost in Iraqi prison system</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-leading-bid-to-return-isis-linked-families-says-syrian-authorities-spooked/hzfy2c98i</link><description>A Sydney doctor leading a bid to return IS-linked families said Australia has &amp;quot;failed&amp;quot; Yusuf Zahab.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96aa49e7b8945c850a3e31fd0993e5e1</guid></item><item><title>China responds after banned dance troupe linked to threat that forced PM&amp;apos;s evacuation</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anthony-albanese-evacuated-safety-threat/r8jttzhxl</link><description>The threat referenced Shen Yun — a cultural show linked to the spiritual movement Falun Gong, both of which have been banned by China.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12ec046c054a2d9e13ee822e61abd9aa</guid></item><item><title>Can Australia stop a citizen&amp;apos;s return? The legal situation facing IS-linked cohort in Syria</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/can-australia-stop-its-citizens-from-coming-home-this-is-what-the-law-says/lvt5vwe9u</link><description>The government wants to block the return of 34 IS-linked women and children to Australia. This is what the law says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb519ab659f84b8a092141dbcc93fb21</guid></item><item><title>I&amp;apos;ve been goth for almost 40 years. Here&amp;apos;s what I learned about fitting in</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/ive-been-a-goth-for-almost-40-years-the-subculture-saved-my-life/i70vulstm</link><description>Emma Baird entered the Perth goth scene in the late 1980s. She believes it was pivotal in relieving her feeling of social isolation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b25140516cb6d2a8dce56edb273de12a</guid></item><item><title>Are you on track to retire comfortably? Australia&amp;apos;s new super benchmark released</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/new-superannuation-target-released-comfortable-retirement/u5nkrhcnk</link><description>Despite the increased benchmark, a superannuation expert says one group of Australians are right on track for a comfortable retirement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dea7fc972c0999f2d862f4b075a0d6e</guid></item><item><title>Putin &amp;apos;did not break&amp;apos; Ukraine, Zelenskyy says on fourth anniversary of Russian invasion</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/zelenskyy-speaks-as-ukraine-enters-fifth-year-of-russian-invasion/wadx0ngak</link><description>The Ukrainian president said the country was ready for peace with Russia, but any deal must not &amp;quot;betray&amp;quot; the price paid by his people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b603e2c99450bf279291ca3f21c879d</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Our lives have been shattered&amp;apos;: Gus Lamont&amp;apos;s parents issue fresh plea for missing boy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gus-lamonts-parents-issue-fresh-plea-for-missing-boy/wzssdbikd</link><description>The parents of the missing four-year-old have pleaded for anyone with information about his disappearance to come forward.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fb062d44e916f20d542d57fa7603f22</guid></item><item><title>PM evacuated from The Lodge after safety threat | Morning News Bulletin 25 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pm-evacuated-from-the-lodge-after-safety-threat-morning-news-bulletin-25-february-2026/sozjin8r9</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese evacuated from Canberra residence due to a safety threat, US President Trump&amp;apos;s new global tariffs come into effect, Matildas winger Hayley Raso says the side is determined to do well in the Women&amp;apos;s Asian Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">54473e40a0636328d66a16700404caf1</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Dr Jamal Rifi on efforts to being home Austalian women in an IS group detention camp</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-dr-jamal-rifi-on-efforts-to-being-home-austalian-women-in-an-is-group-detention-camp/ftjdnse63</link><description>Dr Jamal Rifi is an Australian doctor who has travelled to Syria to try and bring home a group of Australian women and children being held in an IS-group detention camp. The federal government has been adamant it will not help with the group&amp;apos;s repatriation, and Prime Minister Anthony Albanese has said any of those who do return will face charges if they are found to have broken Australian law. Dr Rifi has with him passports for the cohort of women and children which have been issued by Australian authorities. He also has another passport in his possession-- for an Australian man Yusuf Zahab, who was thought to be dead, until the SBS Dateline program revealed in 2024 he was alive and in a Syrian prison. Dr Jamal Rifi spoke with SBS Chief Political Correspondent Anna Henderson from an undisclosed location.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec23a95cb1b1fb2f1312257f733a248e</guid></item><item><title>PM evacuated from The Lodge after safety threat | Morning News Bulletin 25 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pm-evacuated-from-the-lodge-after-safety-threat-morning-news-bulletin-25-february-2026/km1z7zc1m</link><description>Prime Minister Anthony Albanese evacuated from Canberra residence due to a safety threat, US President Trump&amp;apos;s new global tariffs come into effect, Matildas winger Hayley Raso says the side is determined to do well in the Women&amp;apos;s Asian Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9e3acc524516037a08fc54b2fd28618</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Never hurt a fly&amp;apos;: Chris Baghsarian&amp;apos;s family pay tribute as accused killers face court</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/arrests-made-over-death-of-kidnapped-grandfather-chris-baghsarian/mmvk03dbu</link><description>The 85-year-old went missing from his Sydney home nearly two weeks ago, in what police believe was a mistaken identity kidnapping.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd28771003ad23c3945e6e975f308fbc</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Rude, arrogant and entitled&amp;apos;: British MPs line up to lash former prince Andrew</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rude-arrogant-and-entitled-british-minister-lashes-former-prince-andrew/tn2ifywll</link><description>The criticisms came during a parliamentary debate about the release of documents related to the former prince&amp;apos;s time as a trade envoy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c3e464f2a8f9065647497be0a1619e67</guid></item><item><title>New permanent anti-terror and hate unit in Australia&amp;apos;s biggest police force | Midday News Bulletin 25 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-permanent-anti-terror-and-hate-unit-in-australias-biggest-police-force-midday-news-bulletin-25-february-2026/8l0016d9e</link><description>A new permanent unit in the country&amp;apos;s biggest police force to combat terrorism and hate crimes... The U-N chief calls the Ukraine war a stain on the world&amp;apos;s conscience...and Bodo/Glimt knock Inter out of the Champions League.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a90c787db9224de59cd0003c1aa7a357</guid></item><item><title>Trump boasts about economy, clashes with Democrats in longest ever State of the Union</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tariffs-tax-cuts-and-iran-what-to-expect-from-trumps-state-of-the-union-address/mjrqusrp2</link><description>The US president&amp;apos;s address to Congress lasted around two hours and touched on everything from inflation to immigration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9e91414a570d7147f16f0f997423783</guid></item><item><title>Full steam ahead: Federal Government launches plans for first high-speed Sydney to Newcastle train service</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/full-steam-ahead-federal-government-launches-plans-for-first-high-speed-sydney-to-newcastle-train-service/7ak0h5p9x</link><description>The Federal Government has moved to the next stage of Australia&amp;apos;s inaugural high-speed rail project, launching a two-year development phase for the Sydney-to-Newcastle link. Construction is slated to begin in 2028. While the project faces a nearly $90 billion price tag and public scepticism over its long history of delays, proponents argue the 180-kilometre network will eventually transform regional housing and productivity across the entire East Coast.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4553ff23537bd8e5b85bad388d48ac10</guid></item><item><title>The UK&amp;apos;s new entry rules are here. What do they mean for you?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-uks-new-entry-rules-are-here-what-do-they-mean-for-australians/7jund0l8f</link><description>UK citizens will need a valid British or Irish passport to enter the country. The decision has spelled chaos for Australian dual citizens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffb07714d0d712be5bd32a87333dacb9</guid></item><item><title>The UK&amp;apos;s new entry rules are here. What do they mean for you?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-uks-new-entry-rules-are-here-what-do-they-mean-for-you/7jund0l8f</link><description>UK citizens will need a valid British or Irish passport to enter the country. The decision has spelled chaos for Australian dual citizens.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd426b2f6160f8af7d5dd5b6218a0e8d</guid></item><item><title>Allies reinforce support for Ukraine on fourth anniversary of Russian invasion</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/allies-reinforce-support-for-ukraine-on-fourth-anniversary-of-russian-invasion/opb0xlphm</link><description>As Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine enters its fifth year, international pressure is intensifying to end the conflict. The European Union is finalising its 20th sanctions package against Russia, while the United Nations General Assembly has overwhelmingly backed a resolution supporting Ukraine’s territorial integrity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24cf5e395b365cf9a4a25befe3fd5964</guid></item><item><title>Could Andrew become the first Royal removed from the line of succession in 90 years?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/could-andrew-become-the-first-royal-removed-from-the-line-of-succession-in-90-years/5c6gnq45j</link><description>Questions over the British Royal line of succession are emerging after the UK government pledged to introduce laws to remove ex-prince Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor from the line. However, as the potential future King of 14 Commonwealth countries, the process to remove the former prince is not as simple as stripping his title.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43c656646a6e2a92dcbd26055b0a6791</guid></item><item><title>SBS News In Easy English 25 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-25-february-2026/s4y9gv2na</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">837bc6f94c07a5e271c23bb4ab03e91c</guid></item><item><title>Inflation rate remains the same, but unlikely to go down soon | Evening News Bulletin 25 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/inflation-rare-remains-the-same-but-unlikely-to-go-down-soon-evening-news-bulletin-25-february-2026/d46xtnhw5</link><description>Inflation remains the same, but the Treasurer admits it won&amp;apos;t come down soon... Angus Taylor proposes tough laws against Australians linked to I-S... and Australian Open tournament director Craig Tiley leaves to run the US Open instead</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3321f1de57c5a7b6e69e22ba1e3b0c22</guid></item><item><title>AI blamed for mass Wisetech job cuts &amp;amp; Woolies CEO on reputation rebuild</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ai-blamed-for-mass-wisetech-job-cuts-woolies-ceo-on-reputation-rebuild/ox7zr2fyk</link><description>Hear from Wisetech CEO Zubin Appoo as he explains why 2000 jobs will go at the company as AI hits its workforce; SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Francesco De Stradis from Ord Minnett to find out the implications for the broader market; plus Woolworths CEO Amanda Bardwell on how the supermarket operator is winning back consumer trust.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d192e274a3fa9936ef678a572c88ed9f</guid></item><item><title>Cheers and jeers at State of the Union as Donald Trump tries to win back voters</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/cheers-and-jeers-at-state-of-the-union-as-donald-trump-tries-to-win-back-voters/wtkw454b9</link><description>During the longest State of the Union address in history, United States President Donald Trump has declared the U-S is in its &amp;quot;golden era,&amp;quot; with him at the helm. The almost two-hour long speech was filled with dramatic moments, as the President boasted about his successes and outlined his agenda for the coming year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b472da34b7b0fa265449d26330d6a63f</guid></item><item><title>From immigration to Iran: The key moments from Trump&amp;apos;s State of the Union address</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/donald-trump-state-of-the-union-speech-2026-summary-need-to-know/v5h3gmc4l</link><description>The US president has delivered his annual national update, using the opportunity to burnish his achievements during a difficult period.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5476432e02b0497dbf6c5a77f1b4168b</guid></item><item><title>Poet Evelyn Araluen wins Victoria&amp;apos;s highest literary award for &amp;apos;uncompromising&amp;apos; collection</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/template/7j4fyq4hu</link><description>The Goorie/Koori poet has won the $100,000 Victorian Prize for Literature for her poetry collection The Rot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3871c5f9c5ee6a1d745bedfd90361d9</guid></item><item><title>Poet Evelyn Araluen wins Victoria&amp;apos;s highest literary award for &amp;apos;uncompromising&amp;apos; collection</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/poet-evelyn-araluen-victoria-literary-prize-uncompromising-collection/7j4fyq4hu</link><description>The Goorie/Koori poet has won the $100,000 Victorian Prize for Literature for her poetry collection The Rot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f4d6c2867b8e21a65a68680ca5a90245</guid></item><item><title>Australian diplomats&amp;apos; families in Middle East told to leave as US-Iran tensions rise</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-embassy-lebanon-israel-leave-amid-regional-tensions/igiofgu5p</link><description>DFAT said it had updated its advice in response to the &amp;quot;deteriorating security situation in the Middle East&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">304defd4d1a83aa5a3958a039fe73777</guid></item><item><title>Syrian Kurdish official fears IS-linked cohort will &amp;apos;become radicals&amp;apos; if not taken in</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/syrian-authorities-fear-is-linked-cohort-will-become-radicals-if-not-taken-in/ioyuv65ze</link><description>An official overseeing a Syrian detention camp says Australia must take responsibility for the 34 women and children living there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">956480bcf8ab04d1f25f4665c57e9bf6</guid></item><item><title>Want your property &amp;apos;pinch me&amp;apos; moment? Here&amp;apos;s how long it will take</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/pinch-me-moment-as-prices-soar-nationwide-patricia-has-bought-her-first-home/4gb500aoh</link><description>The time it takes to save a deposit to buy a home has blown out, according to a new report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">434800f2c3ca1dd4ef305548486b3731</guid></item><item><title>Killed, jailed, exiled: How Putin crushes his opponents from within</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/four-years-after-putins-invasion-of-ukraine-where-is-russias-opposition/ifaxxumoo</link><description>Experts say the Kremlin&amp;apos;s campaign to quash opposition has intensified, with many Russian activists either jailed or killed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44db8bbcdd6b0577e0af6815778c6309</guid></item><item><title>Two men charged over the alleged murder of Chris Baghsarian | Morning News Bulletin 26 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/two-men-charged-over-the-allegedmurder-of-chris-baghsarian-morning-news-bulletin-26-february-2026/qemwzj9jr</link><description>Two men charged over the alleged kidnapping and murder of 85-year-old Chris Baghsarian ... Australia tells families of diplomats in Lebanon and Israel to leave amid &amp;quot;regional tensions&amp;quot; ... and test cricket returns to Darwin the first time in more than two decades.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3abb559370907347d51c445fedea6c06</guid></item><item><title>Israel responsible for two-thirds of record 129 journalist deaths in 2025, watchdog finds</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/record-number-of-journalists-killed-on-the-job-in-2025-two-thirds-killed-by-israel/jgtfdn7z8</link><description>Most journalist deaths last year were from armed conflict, making it the second consecutive record-breaking year for fatalities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e357bf0aa7348f2b4658bc7d962504cb</guid></item><item><title>New website and app to safeguard international students in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-website-and-app-to-safeguard-international-students-in-australia/7edz3u8zp</link><description>For international students studying in Australia, accessing healthcare is often seen as too expensive - or too confusing to navigate. But a new initiative - designed by international students FOR international students - aims to make services easier to find, while breaking down taboos around sexual and mental health.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6f1355bcda66b9e116754bbf14d04a0</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Dial down the rhetoric&amp;apos; PM says, amid jump in threats to MPs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/dial-down-the-rhetoric-pm-says-amid-jump-in-threats-to-mps/xob5fm970</link><description>The emergency evacuation of the Prime Minister from his Canberra home due to a targeted bomb threat has prompted warnings of a heightened security environment, where online hostility is increasingly manifesting as high-harm physical threats. It follows comments by the Federal Police Commissioner late last year, noting a trend of escalating violence against public officials.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80e4849c979a8da00d0271e4d723aebf</guid></item><item><title>South African men allegedly lured to fight for Russia in Ukraine return home</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/south-african-men-allegedly-lured-to-fight-for-russia-in-ukraine-return-home/q4z4z07nj</link><description>South African President Cyril Ramaphosa thanked his Russian counterpart, Vladimir Putin, for helping to secure the group&amp;apos;s return.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b0e345b6df0a85bcf9fa64fd98f76ae</guid></item><item><title>Inflation pressures to dominate federal Budget | Midday News Bulletin 26 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/inflation-pressures-to-dominate-federal-budget-midday-news-bulletin-26-february-2026/llv0ik5s4</link><description>The Treasurer says Inflation to be the central challenge of this year&amp;apos;s federal budget; the iconic Mardi Gras parade route to be heritage listed; Gold medallist Cooper Woods reflects on his Winter Olympics campaign.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bdf463fa5bb0ce247a29a056bf7c28cb</guid></item><item><title>What Aussies should do after $450 energy bill &amp;apos;shock absorber&amp;apos; axed</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-you-can-do-about-increasing-electricity-prices/prviuvhqw</link><description>The first quarterly energy bills of the year are arriving — and you might notice something is missing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e1107210a3827f3619ccb97eec812ed9</guid></item><item><title>Albanese addresses &amp;apos;difficult&amp;apos; Grace Tame comment as Tame compares him to Morrison</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-addresses-grace-tame-difficult-comment-after-calls-for-apology/6slxu9296</link><description>The prime minister said his comments were misrepresented following criticism on social media.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0e19d5b085bb0569e8eccd7c0987276</guid></item><item><title>Why 90 per cent of Australians will receive the same emergency alert in July</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/texts-and-sirens-to-be-sent-to-australians-as-part-of-emergency-alert-overhaul/0yvcxy4eo</link><description>A long-awaited system will come online this year, with most Australians set to receive identical messages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">30dc42924c3640dfb8919f865f9392e9</guid></item><item><title>The world watches - and waits - on the eve of US and Iran nuclear talks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-world-watches-and-waits-on-the-eve-of-us-and-iran-nuclear-talks/or0rm61eu</link><description>As the United States amasses more warships and aircraft in the Middle East than the world has seen in decades, the possibility of a regional war appears ever-more threatening. There are fears the dispute between the two nations could flare up into a far-reaching conflict, on the eve of a third round of talks between the United States and Iran in Geneva over the Islamic Republic&amp;apos;s nuclear program.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3f03576d79fbddc39916db4079b47a4f</guid></item><item><title>Talks continue between Iran and the US | SBS News in Easy English 26 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/talks-continue-between-iran-and-the-us-sbs-news-in-easy-english-26-february-2026/4b3rw656q</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1cfea73e7ec63b04b9326adaac8cdcb</guid></item><item><title>PM apologises to Grace Tame over &amp;apos;difficult&amp;apos; comment | Evening News Bulletin 26 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pm-apologises-to-grace-tame-over-difficult-comment-evening-news-bulletin-26-february-2026/hnu12rdk4</link><description>Voluntary departures offered to more diplomat families in the Middle East; The Prime Minister apologises for calling former Australian of the year Grace Tame difficult; Mohamed Toure racing to regain fitness for the Socceroos.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1684137e76d7c24ed1a4049dd2e4b806</guid></item><item><title>Syria confirms mass escape of detainees with alleged IS links from al-Hol camp last month</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/syria-confims-mass-escape-from-al-hol-camp-in-january/wx8hqh97m</link><description>Syria has confirmed that &amp;quot;more than 138 breaches&amp;quot; have been discovered in the camp&amp;apos;s 17km perimeter wall.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c35973f27f296573573a6774a2693939</guid></item><item><title>The Chinese dance group at the centre of the Albanese bomb threat — and its link to Trump</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/shen-yun-falun-gong-chinese-dance-troupe-albanese-bomb-threat-trump/ctw1g8318</link><description>A threat that forced the prime minister to temporarily evacuate his official residence was directed at the Shen Yun company.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b8189cc723bfef3496f98b2cc83c2ea</guid></item><item><title>Two patients have died after a fungal outbreak at Sydney hospital</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/two-patients-have-died-after-a-fungal-outbreak-at-sydney-hospital/cosmpgk72</link><description>The outbreak occurred between October and December 2025, and the hospital is currently under redevelopment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52a0b944d507949111064489dd87929f</guid></item><item><title>How the US created a vacuum for the IS-linked cohort trying to return to Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-the-us-created-a-vacuum-for-is-linked-cohort-trying-to-return-to-australia/oh8w5pdba</link><description>The US is halting support of two IS-linked camps in Syria, saying their help &amp;quot;cannot last forever&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf58823d73a5d1cce2a2228601be41c2</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine’s grim anniversary, ‘El Mencho’ killed &amp;amp; SOTU, Trump’s very, very long speech</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ukraines-grim-anniversary-el-mencho-killed-sotu-trumps-very-very-long-speech/9sic7urtw</link><description>Can Ukraine hold the line as US support wavers going into a fifth year of fighting Russia’s full-scale invasion? Plus, an explosion of violence in Mexico after the killing of brutal cartel boss ‘El Mencho’ - will calm be restored in time for the World Cup? The US Supreme Court takes down Trump’s tariffs and POTUS uses his high-stakes State of the Union address to accuse Somalis of fraud</description><guid isPermaLink="false">776c460c1890eab8e4fd4058f1a0a2ad</guid></item><item><title>A global spectacle, a local crisis: Cartel violence and Mexico&amp;apos;s World Cup moment</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fifa-2026-world-cup-cartel-violence-mexico-safety/b192z3js7</link><description>Cartel violence has swept through parts of Mexico in recent days, raising questions over the country&amp;apos;s ability to host football&amp;apos;s biggest tournament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c45fcf9f306c26b0d30b6ecb43f4580</guid></item><item><title>Nvidia results spur AI tech recovery &amp;amp; why most borrowers will cope with rate rise</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nvidia-results-spur-ai-tech-recovery-why-most-borrwers-will-cope-with-rate-rise/3r087bdcf</link><description>Hear from Nvidia CEO Jensen Huang on why he thinks huge capital expenditure on AI technology will continue as SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Heath Moss from HLM Investments about the days market action including a recovery in tech stocks and a look at Qantas&amp;apos; half-year results. Plus Erin Kitson from S&amp;amp;P Global explains how borrowers are likely to cope with rising interest rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bd12e8ece1f624b16c22457e7cf91fb</guid></item><item><title>Teenager confirmed as first Australian to have died from tick-induced red meat allergy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jeremy-webb-teen-death-tick-induced-meat-allergy/dlcgl6blx</link><description>A coroner has found that an Australian teenager&amp;apos;s death in 2022 was the result of a rare condition called mammalian meat allergy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">843465a13bb7476160381359dc886349</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Tip of the iceberg&amp;apos;: Australia faces a rising threat</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/political-violence-threats-australia/x49u1wbhr</link><description>In a more polarised world, political threats and violence are on the rise — and Australia is not immune.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">046a7ed8e5f5dc36b6fb0c2a3ac91952</guid></item><item><title>Your guide to the Women&amp;apos;s Asian Cup 2026, as the Matildas chase redemption</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/heres-what-you-need-to-know-about-the-womens-asian-cup/ncwednd4f</link><description>The Matildas will be hoping for a better result at the home tournament, after a shock early exit last time around.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeb869edbf3b8d6468a4f7874ba0aef5</guid></item><item><title>Dateline returns with stories of the people caught in Trump&amp;apos;s immigration crackdown</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/dateline-returns-for-2026-season/zgy4kdf95</link><description>Dateline&amp;apos;s new season sees reporter Darren Mara meet ordinary Minnesotans who&amp;apos;ve found themselves at the heart of US President Donald Trump&amp;apos;s crackdown on immigration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f71c6a8a2b54c2cfacb708ed139a6bdf</guid></item><item><title>I run a gay sauna in Australia. You&amp;apos;d be surprised who comes through the door</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-gay-saunas-are-more-than-just-a-place-for-sex/eje1vbghy</link><description>Once stigmatised — and illegal — gay saunas like the one Glenn McNamara runs hold a special place in LGBTQI+ history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34bf519bfdf4a92f38c3e1310c0ae978</guid></item><item><title>NSW Protest laws challenged in court | Morning News Bulletin 27 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nsw-protest-laws-challenged-in-court-morning-news-bulletin-27-february-2026/jlq84erog</link><description>The New South Wales premier defends the state&amp;apos;s protest laws; US Justice Department looking into allegations it withheld Epstein files; and in sport, the Matildas in training ahead of their first Asian Cup game on Sunday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ac5c74af693dd2e36a1750705260f2d</guid></item><item><title>Last-minute apology for &amp;apos;racist&amp;apos; posts &amp;apos;doesn&amp;apos;t change anything&amp;apos; for NT administrator, Elder says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/incoming-nt-administrator-david-connollys-racist-posts-still-under-fire/jy5pq7awh</link><description>The incoming administrator&amp;apos;s apology for widely criticised social media posts has not been accepted by some of his critics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">05beab27ad0539a0103b9b160c6998cc</guid></item><item><title>Clinton says she doesn&amp;apos;t recall ever meeting Epstein, has no information about his crimes</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/clinton-says-she-doesnt-recall-ever-meeting-epstein-has-no-information-about-his-crimes/s6h9k7wl9</link><description>&amp;quot;I do not recall ever encountering Mr Epstein ... I have nothing to add to that,&amp;quot; the former first lady said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0824ff5922f14afd7e9d23fa2243ca60</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Fractured trust&amp;apos;: Veteran Navy officer sacked from multicultural board after Israel posts</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/mona-shindy-veteran-muslim-navy-officer-sacked-multicultural-board-israel-posts/v0n1iedq1</link><description>Mona Shindy was dumped by Multicultural NSW from its advisory board this week after she shared posts on LinkedIn about Israel and Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f58cbd1b1a3cde6cb7a862eeeceb4738</guid></item><item><title>US democrats vow to have all Epstein files released | Midday Bulletin 27 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-democrats-vow-to-have-all-epstein-files-released-midday-bulletin-27-february-2026/5kartsron</link><description>US democrats vow to have all Epstein files released, after reports key records were knowingly withheld, Key childcare safety reforms come into effect today, across Australia, Australians gather in Las Vegas for the NRL season opener.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c687f48ab87fa9307aaa57e67999c635</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley won&amp;apos;t return to parliament for farewell but is &amp;apos;proud&amp;apos; of leadership milestone</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sussan-ley-hands-in-resignation-letter-says-proud-of-being-first-female-leader/aw2x6yigp</link><description>Becoming the first woman to lead any federal Opposition in Australia was &amp;quot;a milestone for all women to be proud of&amp;quot;, Ley said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5476495040a054bb5da539c0c5c95d75</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Lured in&amp;apos;: The Russian recruitment scam sending Africans to fight in Ukraine</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/lured-in-the-russian-recruitment-scam-sending-africans-to-fight-in-ukraine/tkvbi10hc</link><description>With the Russian Army losing an estimated 30 to 50,000 ((30,000 to 50,000)) soldiers per month, Russia is reportedly using recruitment scams to lure in men from across Africa. Offered enticing salaries and told to sign a contract in Russian, officials say economic incentives and the exploitation of vulnerable people are driving recruitment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0b86ec4e0e55d9bc9db1235ce44089af</guid></item><item><title>IRGC terrorism listing welcomed by Kylie Moore-Gilbert</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/irgc-terrorism-listing-welcomed-by-kylie-moore-gilbert/k6yna3432</link><description>The Australian government is reviewing its formal designation of the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) as a terrorist organisation, following the expulsion of Iran&amp;apos;s ambassador over allegations of foreign interference and state-sponsored violence. Testimony from experts and former detainees highlights a catastrophic human rights situation, including systematic repression of universities and a nationwide death toll reported to be in the tens of thousands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1d0a75c627a640d87cb93bbc974fba5</guid></item><item><title>Hillary Clinton testifies in Epstein investigation as Democrats claim cover up</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/hillary-clinton-testifies-in-epstein-investigation-as-democrats-claim-cover-up/hmrrcdx44</link><description>Political pressure is intensifying over the release of Jeffrey Epstein investigation files as Hillary Clinton appears before U-S leaders, and Democrats accuse the Justice Department of withholding key records.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a9640027b3503300c4963f95bc89d1d2</guid></item><item><title>New measures to protect children in childcare | SBS News in Easy English 27 February 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-measures-to-psbs-news-in-easy-english-27-february-2025/rr8zpyllw</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">032e2e4e6fa8eef0e8886f0c7ddfd66a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Significant progress&amp;apos; made during US and Iran talks — but no sign of a deal yet</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/iran-us-talks-geneva-progress-no-deal/w6rp4urxi</link><description>The discussions about the decades-long dispute over Iran&amp;apos;s nuclear work come amid growing tension in the Middle East.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfa972b969494ed9490f181f55947df7</guid></item><item><title>Magda Szubanski says she&amp;apos;s in remission after completing chemotherapy for cancer</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/magda-szubanski-remission-cancer/287sja5sb</link><description>The comedian said she was &amp;quot;eternally grateful&amp;quot; to her medical team and those who&amp;apos;ve wished her well over the past nine months.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2872605145e953a212b6318fa612ef3</guid></item><item><title>A troubling new record as Australians&amp;apos; financial woes surge</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/a-troubling-new-record-as-australians-financial-woes-surge/mqh6llh4i</link><description>Last year, a record 111,373 Australians lodged complaints with the financial watchdog — a 14 per cent rise from 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fa38a2e94fd8b5df9f8ab120515299d</guid></item><item><title>Sussan Ley formally leaves federal parliament | Evening News Bulletin 27 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sussan-ley-formally-leaves-federal-parliamentevening-news-bulletin-27-february-2026/opven5u6a</link><description>Sussan Ley formally leaves federal parliament, triggering a by-election in Farrer, New standards for childcare centres introduced, Mary Fowler returns from an ACL injury, ready for the Matildas&amp;apos; Asian Cup kickoff.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">947a7b55807056f9e2eefbf6e0440e3e</guid></item><item><title>Pakistan says it&amp;apos;s in &amp;apos;open war&amp;apos; with Afghanistan after launching airstrikes in multiple cities</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/pakistan-afghanistan-open-war-airstrikes/wdzagba11</link><description>It comes after months of clashes between the two neighbours along the frontier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">758ca24ac0b50ce5376f08647b7cae93</guid></item><item><title>Calls for better support for LGBTIQ+ community on substance abuse issues</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/calls-for-better-support-for-lgbtiq-community-on-substance-abuse-issues/rypgwt5az</link><description>Mardi Gras is an occasion for celebration - a time to party for LGBTIQ+ communities. But Mardi Gras events can also invite risky behaviours. There are higher rates of substance use in LGBTIQ+ communities compared to the general population, coupled with a reluctance to seek help from healthcare professionals. Experts are calling for stronger investment in culturally safe care to improve access to appropriate support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90d69df21293ec056e0251f30a14023d</guid></item><item><title>Man charged with preparing for a terrorist act in Western Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/man-charged-preparing-terror-act-western-australia/kljfqkc31</link><description>Police allege the 20-year-old planned a &amp;quot;mass casualty event&amp;quot; at public buildings in Perth, including Muslim places of worship.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba20dca5f9c92925a7bd5a5b5d83791c</guid></item><item><title>AI-related job cuts continues as Block slashes 4,000 roles &amp;amp; Australia Post&amp;apos;s digital transformation</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ai-related-job-cuts-continues-as-block-slashes-4-000-roles-australia-posts-digital-transformation/chf8isod2</link><description>Hear from Block CEO Jack Dorsey as he explains why the company is cutting nearly half of its workforce; SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Omkar Joshi from Opal Capital Management about the future of AI and the impact on stocks. Plus Australia Post CEO Paul Graham details the group&amp;apos;s digital transformation plan as it records a fall in profit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b5d1881af92e886c2b0a9c2e5e867658</guid></item><item><title>Worse than a prison sentence: The stateless British schoolgirl with lessons for Australia&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;ISIS brides&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/shamima-begum-australia-isis-brides-al-roj-refugee-camp/hcowxrqmv</link><description>Could the Australians trying to come home from a Syrian refugee camp face a similar fate to that of al-Roj&amp;apos;s most famous resident?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a82fd3449487f7da46cb9116468333b6</guid></item><item><title>Ali&amp;apos;s friend died awaiting a visa. A new pathway could help LGBTQI+ refugees like him</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/new-australian-visa-pathway-could-help-lgbtqi-refugees/ta0u3r817</link><description>With resettlement options collapsing worldwide, a new community-led initiative will help LGBTQI+ people get to safety in Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ce45bf92c0c9665766906251e476847</guid></item><item><title>A man in WA charged with planning a terrorist act | Morning News Bulletin 28 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-man-in-wa-charged-with-planning-a-terrorist-act-morning-news-bulletin-28-february-2026/hrf8i5uz0</link><description>A man in Western Australia charged with planning a terrorist act; Pakistan&amp;apos;s defence minister says his country is in an &amp;quot;open war&amp;quot; with Afghanistan; and in sport, the Matildas face goalkeeper trouble ahead of their Asian Cup opener.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1466f25631b2d4e8fc3e054971bd893b</guid></item><item><title>The detectors on guard 15 years after New Zealand&amp;apos;s devastating earthquake in Christchurch</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-detectors-on-guard-15-years-after-new-zealands-devastating-earthquake-in-christchurch/8sl4jr4fa</link><description>Fifteen years after a devastating earthquake in New Zealand left 185 people dead, scientists are on guard, ready to spot an impending disaster. In the control rooms at Earth Sciences New Zealand headquarters, seismologists are continuously analysing data from a network of 700 detectors looking for warning signs of an imminent quake.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88289d738df593d588f9b606fb58a69a</guid></item><item><title>Mona fled war but remains haunted by the memories. This Australian hotline takes her calls for help</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/mona-fled-war-but-remains-haunted-by-the-memories-this-australian-hotline-takes-her-calls-for-help/ncu8sn3ve</link><description>A hotline offering multi-lingual support for refugees who’ve fled war, violence and persecution has expanded nationwide. As global conflicts grind on, experts say demand is soaring. A warning: the following story contains details that may distress some listeners.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d68defcd0112658d2c960ba95a21f40f</guid></item><item><title>Queen Mary to begin Australia state visit next month in Uluru</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/queen-mary-to-begin-her-homecoming-trip-next-month-in-uluru/s30oxbpq7</link><description>Queen Mary of Denmark is leading an enormous green energy-focused business delegation with her when she and husband, King Frederik visit next month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c59299253d4186749d194e4b7d508a9</guid></item></channel></rss>