<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>SBS English News (Unofficial Aggregation)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 19:09:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s spy boss warned of a Russian threat — and it&amp;apos;s unfolding in real time</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-russia-uses-ai-to-spread-disinformation/h4kf3947p</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s spy chief has expressed concern about the potential for AI to take online radicalisation and disinformation to new levels.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7c0a67f14545bb85891113cf9ce62639</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: BBC is facing an orchestrated campaign to undercut public trust says analyst</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-bbc-is-facing-an-orchestrated-campaign-to-undercut-public-trust-says-analyst/rflxsczy4</link><description>The director for the International Centre for Journalists says the resignation of two senior figures at the BBC is a result of an &amp;quot;orchestrated campaign to undercut public trust&amp;quot; in the broadcaster. The head of the BBC, director-general Tim Davie and news CEO Deborah Turness both resigned after criticism of the broadcaster’s editing of a speech by US President Donald Trump. Critics said the way the speech was edited for the BBC&amp;apos;s flagship documentary program Panorama last year was misleading and cut out a section where Donald Trump said that he wanted supporters to demonstrate peacefully. Mr Trump has threatened legal action against the BBC over the way the speech he made was edited. Julie Posetti is a professor of journalism at City St George&amp;apos;s University of London and director for the International Centre for Journalists and she&amp;apos;s speaking here to AP.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c6f82c58ef8334b8925097a9cb7b8c37</guid></item><item><title>Shock resignations, $1.5bn threat: How a 12 second clip of Donald Trump could cost the BBC</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-trump-scandal-could-cost-bbc/xcst7jizw</link><description>The BBC&amp;apos;s director general and head of news have both quit over a documentary that misleadingly edited clips of US President Donald Trump.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4db69788311dcca36c5a3cb1fe7f76e0</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 11 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-11-november-2025/0v13l4byz</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English Language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eb987a294973d29c8f81584d464e52f2</guid></item><item><title>Why consumers are optimistic despite inflation &amp;amp; CBA Q2 profit rises 2%</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/why-consumers-are-optimistic-despite-inflation-cba-q2-profit-rises-2/2fb8jxq6d</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Westpac&amp;apos;s Matt Hassan about a dramatic rise in consumer confidence, despite reaccelerating inflation and diminishing prospects of lower interest rates; plus the day on the sharemarket with Jamie Hannah from VanEck, including a closer look at the Commonwealth Bank&amp;apos;s latest profit result.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c275cd63eca036d04507c1dab7b3eb9</guid></item><item><title>The Dismissal: how it all played out</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-dismissal-how-it-all-played-out/1s5ql15ph</link><description>On November 11, 1975, Australia experienced its most dramatic constitutional crisis when Governor-General Sir John Kerr dismissed Prime Minister Gough Whitlam 50 years ago. We examine the full story of the Dismissal, from the political deadlock and the Loans Affair to Prime Minister Anthony Albanese&amp;apos;s recent claim of a &amp;quot;partisan political ambush&amp;quot; and new evidence suggesting foreign interference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c56cddfd12fbe9f0069c9be5572305cb</guid></item><item><title>The &amp;apos;incredibly toxic&amp;apos; hidden ingredient experts want banned from our supermarkets</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/calls-to-ban-industrial-trans-fats-in-food-products/4ycgwslw4</link><description>Researchers analysed 28,000 products stocked in Australian supermarkets. Here&amp;apos;s what they found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c7a10fbf0428963e6187fa51e2b39e5</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;God&amp;apos;s not making any more land&amp;apos;: Price gap between homes and apartments growing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gap-between-home-and-apartment-prices-growing-due-to-undersupply-domain-report-finds/32e5uklgm</link><description>On average, houses in capital cities are nearly 50 per cent more expensive than apartments. Five years ago, the gap was only 20 per cent.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dd7ccb3c2e66b57638b33cb76ce810a</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s dispute with Türkiye over COP31 hosting rights could see both miss out</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ethiopia-announced-as-cop32-host-as-australia-and-turkiye-vie-for-cop31/ptxfop4gk</link><description>Ethiopia will host the UN&amp;apos;s COP32 climate summit in 2027, but next year&amp;apos;s COP31 remains a contest between Türkiye and Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">37598ea11a910280016936b6f971c974</guid></item><item><title>Victoria to introduce &amp;apos;adult time for violent crime&amp;apos; reform in response to rising crime</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/victoria-to-introduce-adult-time-for-violent-crime-reform-in-response-to-rising-crime/rn01525p0</link><description>Children as young as 14 could face possible life sentences under the proposed changes to be announced by the Victorian premier on Wednesday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b0c3dafa5f175702b2a40e5aa9e14920</guid></item><item><title>At COP30, Indigenous leaders demand greater powers to protect their land.</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/at-cop30-indigenous-leaders-demand-greater-powers-to-protect-their-land/l1zpibmif</link><description>Indigenous leaders in the Amazon are urging leaders at the UN Climate Summit to empower First Nations people to protect their land and rainforests. As world leaders gather in the Amazonian city of Belem, pressure is on to go beyond words and ideas and start implementing meaningful policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d77edf4a873699a2063777d022cc2f8</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 12 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-12-november-2025/oimrouj1f</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02e13009faebf374bf0de6b24ef1591a</guid></item><item><title>As ADHD medications cause a rise in poisonings, experts call for a key change</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/adhd-medications-are-poisoning-more-australians/62fnke95i</link><description>ADHD medication poisonings have quadrupled in the last decade, according to new data, with children most at risk of adverse exposures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1d5654878ab8c6e8487f166c7f8b8d01</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Punishing trauma&amp;apos;: Experts say proposal to fix &amp;apos;crime capital&amp;apos; could have opposite effect</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/victoria-jail-plan-young-offenders/otrb671kk</link><description>Young offenders in Victoria could face life imprisonment under proposed reforms, but advocates say the move won&amp;apos;t make communities safer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">112603308bbb11e1921d1c459e97c1a0</guid></item><item><title>Property investor loans at record &amp;amp; market sentiment bullish despite down day</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/property-investor-loans-at-record-market-sentiment-bullish-despite-down-day/zzimwrjub</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Maree Kilroy from Oxford Economics Australia about the latest home loan data which shows lending to investors hit a record high to find out what it means for supply; plus James Gerrish from Market Parters takes a look at the day&amp;apos;s market action and reveals what he&amp;apos;s telling his clients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">82ea05a166fc57ac9376c7872342165f</guid></item><item><title>Why young, child-free men like Trent are choosing permanent contraception</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/why-more-younger-men-like-trent-are-choosing-permanent-contraception/hp2qzhz9b</link><description>Trent is among the men choosing a vasectomy, challenging ideas around contraception and rethinking having kids in a world of rising costs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd2f067faa37fc1a69a9e71429f58a65</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Demands urgent attention&amp;apos;: Study finds widening disparities in cancer survival rates</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cancer-survival-rates-disadvantaged-patients-study/p1od389mp</link><description>The equity gap has swelled since four decades ago, according to analysis of data from almost one million cancer patients.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">328713eca21d95678fc85c12603bda88</guid></item><item><title>The record-breaking US shutdown has finally ended, as bill heads to Trump&amp;apos;s desk</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-record-breaking-us-shutdown-may-finally-be-ending-what-still-needs-to-happen/2ev3uju71</link><description>The House passed a spending bill that will end the longest government shutdown in US history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b69f0fde7b4d9740c79c9223a3cbd1b3</guid></item><item><title>The record-breaking US shutdown has finally ended, as bill heads to Trump&amp;apos;s desk</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-record-breaking-us-shutdown-is-finally-ending-as-bill-heads-to-trumps-desk/2ev3uju71</link><description>The House passed a spending bill that will end the longest government shutdown in US history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c1eb10b354fad6beabb788525dd9e284</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Side by side&amp;apos;: Australia&amp;apos;s first treaty with Aboriginal people signed into law in Victoria</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/victoria-aboriginal-treaty-agreement-signed-into-law/qy0tg1sv2</link><description>Before today, Australia was one of few Commonwealth countries without any treaties in place with its First Nations peoples.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48829ec8e79affa0c245362bd2fe4932</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 13 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-13-november-2025/abkrr0bh3</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4639cdfb659722124c7cc41a2947c699</guid></item><item><title>What is next for the Liberals now they have scrapped their net zero commitment?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/what-is-next-for-the-liberals-now-they-have-scrapped-their-net-zero-commitment/0wpdb6fjq</link><description>The Liberal Party has voted to officially abandon its net zero by 2050 emissions reduction target, following a contentious internal meeting. This dramatic policy reversal, which will also seek to remove the target from the Climate Change Act, has triggered fierce internal debate among senior members and drawn criticism from the government and independents.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbe966d91f27e2db4a18970970eddf29</guid></item><item><title>Philippines in tatters, Trump taps a former terrorist and, well, Bob Ross</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/philippines-in-tatters-trump-taps-a-former-terrorist-and-well-bob-ross/sbweyrlv1</link><description>Typhoon Fung Wong leaves a vast trail of destruction in the Philippines, Syrian President Al-Sharaa shoots hoops before meeting Trump and Trump COPs it in Brazil. Also Zelenskyy under fire from corruption allegations, why AI is spreading Russian propaganda, and Bob Ross makes a splash.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b4aa2dac9a2fef38e6230d1c2e65c2f</guid></item><item><title>CEO Series: Xero&amp;apos;s Sukhinder Singh Cassidy &amp;amp; ASX tumbles on jobs gain</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ceo-series-xeros-sukhinder-singh-cassidy-asx-tumbles-on-jobs-gain/ehl367j13</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Xero CEO Sukhinder Singh Cassidy following the accounting software group&amp;apos;s 42% rise in half-year profit to find out where growth is coming from and how it is using AI; Devika Shivadekar from RSM Australia goes through the better-than expected labour force report to explain what it means for interest rates; plus the market reaction with Zoran Kresovic from Blueberry Markets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95f1ea75c6d424498affe771fdb4d075</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Cigars and champagne&amp;apos;: The Netanyahu corruption case at the centre of Trump&amp;apos;s pardon plea</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/netanyahu-corruption-case-trump-pardon/v4gxdetkv</link><description>The Israeli prime minister has faced a years-long trial over allegations of fraud and accepting bribes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1750883f232dae4f7e801aeaccea802</guid></item><item><title>Historic Victorian treaty the start of a new era, Indigenous leaders say</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/historic-victorian-treaty-the-start-of-a-new-era-indigenous-leaders-say/7ipkigzi4</link><description>It&amp;apos;s been hailed as a moment centuries in the making: the signing of Australia&amp;apos;s first ever state-wide treaty with Aboriginal people, described as something once thought impossible. The Australian-first treaty will take effect just before Christmas but will not be up and running until mid-2026. And for both sides signing the pact in Victoria, there&amp;apos;s recognition of more hard work that needs to be done.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ae4a4374684fe32c399b54720e3ad5b</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;flawed&amp;apos; health star ratings face criticism as they hit a deadline</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/health-star-rating-system-changes-criticism/g2el9r52i</link><description>A deadline for Australia&amp;apos;s contentious Health Star Rating system has arrived — and could spark big change.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9fe374081f72f80f4ecf16caeade36d</guid></item><item><title>How this rising star responded to men telling her she was &amp;apos;too pretty to do comedy&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/elouise-eftos-on-being-hot-and-funny/o9g7f07xl</link><description>Elouise Eftos is used to people judging her on her appearance. With her hit debut comedy show, she&amp;apos;s having the last laugh.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9c44e9f97a145f55d9c0b0d66b7dfb6</guid></item><item><title>Israel identifies deceased hostage returned by Hamas</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israel-receives-hostage-body-hamas/hn8fmz46m</link><description>Israeli authorities say the bodies of three hostages are still being held in the Gaza Strip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0f8f02fe00b8aa6aedde2b473d22ee2</guid></item><item><title>Having &amp;apos;a crack&amp;apos;: What&amp;apos;s the go with the social media ban?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/having-a-crack-whats-the-go-with-the-social-media-ban/einc5zepz</link><description>Weeks out from Australia&amp;apos;s world-first age restrictions being implemented, there are still plenty of questions about the platforms that will fall under the ban, the ones that won&amp;apos;t and how companies are actually going to figure out users&amp;apos; ages at all. This week, Elfy and Rania chat about what we know so far and how it&amp;apos;s all reflecting on the Albanese government right now.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cf8a3211a93d713ed815b19fff6d734</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Crushing waves&amp;apos;, not &amp;apos;shore dumps&amp;apos;: Are beach warnings failing overseas visitors?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fatal-risk-beach-signs-cause-confusion-for-international-visitors-and-australians-born-overseas/n881v9j9l</link><description>As summer approaches and many gear up for a swim at the beach, a study suggests unclear warning signs to non-English speakers are posing risks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8461982c271d3f7ba8c1b097c7088024</guid></item><item><title>The mystery of Australia&amp;apos;s deepest lake has finally been solved</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lake-st-clair-tasmania-depth-revealed-by-csiro/zghb92b9j</link><description>A CSIRO team spent nine days on Tasmania&amp;apos;s Lake St Clair, and they&amp;apos;ve finally answered one key question: how deep it really is.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8de106bf1d27dc4afd0c9c357ddb2fb6</guid></item><item><title>Settler attack on a mosque sparks international condemnation</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/settler-attack-on-a-mosque-sparks-international-condemnation/67vj1xmja</link><description>A fresh settler attack on a mosque in the occupied West Bank has drawn sharp international condemnation and intensified scrutiny of Israel’s handling of rising violence in the territory. The arson and vandalism at Deir Istiya, which left Korans burned and hate-filled graffiti on the walls, comes amid warnings from the United Nations that such assaults risk fuelling a wider regional crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9e0e5c73bbf34590a027b5e8f06b88e9</guid></item><item><title>Hopes dashed as global fossil fuel emissions increase in 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/hopes-dashed-as-global-fossil-fuel-emissions-increase-in-2025/k0id8j79i</link><description>For the second straight year, emissions from fossil fuels rose by slightly more than one per cent. Scientists at the COP30 climate conference in Brazil say it&amp;apos;s one of the smallest in recent non-pandemic years - but it means efforts to curb warming global temperatures by getting fossil fuel emissions to stop rising are still not meeting targets.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1bb89cf3af108eb31aae56f05e72fa63</guid></item><item><title>‘Popping champagne corks’: Climate change boss lashes Coalition for dumping net zero</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/climate-change-authority-criticises-coalition-net-zero/i7ygs99y5</link><description>Matt Kean said his former party is walking away from scientific evidence — and pandering to mining lobbyists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80e5ca7fad5fee5fdf12a2ef71eb66df</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 14 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-14-november-2025/zvuq0y2fb</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db5a251ad6708b93703da194f4c63cc4</guid></item><item><title>What does the treaty with Indonesia actually mean?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/what-does-the-treaty-with-indonesia-actually-mean/peupx11yr</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s leaders remain circumspect about the terms of a security agreement with a key northern neighbour after finalising the deal with Indonesia&amp;apos;s president. But Prime Minister Anthony Albanese says the deal commits the nations to consult regularly on matters of security, and consider possible measures should either&amp;apos;s security be threatened.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eecb989414f61d536de60c5697e054d7</guid></item><item><title>Dementia now Australia&amp;apos;s biggest killer, as leading causes of death revealed</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-causes-of-death-dementia-2024/h18jp7paz</link><description>Dementia deaths have risen steadily over the past decade, reflecting Australia&amp;apos;s ageing population, according to the ABS.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3887ae3583fd296d2201bed87229222a</guid></item><item><title>20,000 new Epstein documents just dropped. Here&amp;apos;s what we learned</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/20-000-new-epstein-documents-just-dropped-heres-what-we-learned/6107i153v</link><description>The White House criticised the Democrats&amp;apos; smaller document release, saying it was selectively chosen to make Trump look bad.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">85b5919cb62675f87990c7c9007d85ef</guid></item><item><title>This film starring Rose Byrne airs the unspeakable parts of motherhood</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/if-i-had-legs-id-kick-you-film-asks-what-if-a-mother-regrets-children/88i3o5x66</link><description>Motherhood is often seen as an idealised, glossy experience. But this new film from Rose Byrne aims to unpack the stigma that comes with regretting having children.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7eb1a186806a1035a3b69616bd323e80</guid></item><item><title>How David&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;game-changing&amp;apos; system saves him up to $50,000 a year</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/david-game-changing-system-saves-50000/opo8a2a37</link><description>Small business owner David Stuart was spending about $24,000 a year on electricity — until a solar overhaul changed everything.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2f27ef33f0ae96a3f14d50e0d659416</guid></item><item><title>April Le Sueur claims 2025 NATSI Sports Award</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/april-le-sueur-claims-2025-natsi-sports-award/clej1o01a</link><description>A young volunteer for a football club in central Victoria has won the National Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander (NATSI) Sports Awards this year. April Le Sueur has been volunteering at the Rumbalara Football and Netball Club in the Victorian town of Shepparton. She&amp;apos;s also the AFL Young Leader of the Year.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">88e329b65f1d649113dbe61ab844c0be</guid></item><item><title>As power prices surge, David has found ways to cut running costs by thousands</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/as-power-prices-surge-david-has-found-ways-to-cut-running-costs-by-thousands/b8175zrzi</link><description>Rising electricity prices are a major driver of headline inflation, putting pressure on households and Australia’s 2.6 million small business owners. Some are beating the odds – here’s how.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a65646c60d35224cd829b93c9f3bc12d</guid></item><item><title>Australia welcomes Trump&amp;apos;s backtrack on food-import tariffs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-cuts-tariffs-on-food-imports-including-australian-beef-amid-grocery-price-fears/n7710l8um</link><description>The new exemptions mark a sharp reversal for US President Donald Trump, who has long insisted that his import duties are not fuelling inflation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d4c895325469b89f8db6a2ccb2c7197f</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The worst possible situation&amp;apos;: This major city only has a few days of water left</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tehran-only-has-a-few-days-of-water-left/c7u3x80ig</link><description>Tehran&amp;apos;s main water sources are in a dire situation, with two major dams reaching what officials are calling &amp;quot;dead capacity&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8c3b76ca9d59ac5b161a4462d018f23</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: NITV Radio talks to Dr Harry Hobbs on Victoria&amp;apos;s treaty becoming law</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-nitv-radio-talks-to-dr-harry-hobbs-on-victorias-treaty-becoming-law/rj3bkrqua</link><description>This week a treaty between Victoria and the state&amp;apos;s First Nations people became law. Victorian Premier Jacinta Allan, First Peoples&amp;apos; Assembly of Victoria co-chairs Ngarra Murray and Rueben Berg signed the treaty at a formal ceremony at Government House on Thursday morning. Kerri-Lee Barry from SBS&amp;apos; NITV Radio has spoken with UNSW Law &amp;amp; Justice Associate Professor, Dr Harry Hobbs, about the historic agreement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">80e3e86b27c533cf6abd7572ba4ca693</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: The Great Koala Count and the citizen scientists involved</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-the-great-koala-count-and-the-citizen-scientists-involved/mlasfn4vm</link><description>Scientists in South Australia are asking the public to help count koalas - in a citizen science initiative that could have national implications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67813a585a5c73646fc792a677c17eed</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: The Great Koala Count and the citizen scientists involved</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-the-great-koala-count-and-citizen-scientists-involved/mlasfn4vm</link><description>Scientists in South Australia are asking the public to help count koalas - in a citizen science initiative that could have national implications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3d78b6d21cb55259b0dd82caaa181bc1</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians who &amp;apos;mysteriously&amp;apos; landed in South Africa had third-country approval, Israel says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gazans-palestinians-mysteriously-land-on-a-plane-in-south-africa/6yvrhb4w6</link><description>South African President Cyril Ramaphosa said it seemed like the Gazans &amp;quot;were being flushed out&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdeeb309b555a8e27576f088b69689ab</guid></item><item><title>Opposition presents its plan to put power prices at the centre of climate and energy policy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/opposition-presents-its-plan-to-put-power-prices-at-the-centre-of-climate-and-energy-policy/f2dnh0zl3</link><description>After a period of internal dispute over emissions reduction targets, the Coalition has presented a climate and energy plan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4aeb9a96b848c7f26a740e5246549466</guid></item><item><title>Need a new job? These are the top 10 skills Australian employers are looking for</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/top-job-skills-australian-employers-are-looking-for/ztg10usiz</link><description>Despite concerns about AI and job losses, there is enduring demand for uniquely human skills, new analysis suggests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90a8960348d06e42bb89c22ebd47fa2f</guid></item><item><title>I was abandoned as a baby. I want to ask my mother why</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/i-was-abandoned-as-a-baby-i-want-to-ask-my-mother-why/tzx5ywxvm</link><description>As a newborn, Caron Michelle Brown was left on the steps of a health clinic. She&amp;apos;s still searching for her mother — and her own identity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffb13f973cf24310f0a247ad8d4f107a</guid></item><item><title>Australia downplays co-hosting COP31 after Türkiye proposes sharing event</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/turkiye-proposes-co-hosting-cop31-with-australia-amid-deadlock-over-hosting-rights/63vhu2hdr</link><description>Australia and Türkiye both submitted bids in 2022 to host COP31, and neither has withdrawn, leading to an attention-sapping impasse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55e1703a2a61e505e375c7b217065e63</guid></item><item><title>Murder of anti-drug mayor sparks Gen Z protests in Mexico</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/gen-z-protests-against-crime-and-corruption-in-mexico-after-mayors-murder/3k1s8yra4</link><description>More than 100 people were injured in the protests, which were sparked by the assassination of the mayor of the western city of Uruapan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">666049af5b6bd247d603fc7ef5efc6f1</guid></item><item><title>Coalition cements climate policy: no net zero, more fossil fuel as a move towards nuclear</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/coalition-cements-climate-policy-no-net-zero-more-fossil-fuel-as-a-move-towards-nuclear/s3xi9d3di</link><description>The Coalition has formally solidified its dumping of the net zero emissions target in a party room meeting in Canberra. But it&amp;apos;s gone much further, with the Liberals and Nationals unveiling a plan to strip climate change from the national energy regulator&amp;apos;s list of objectives, while vowing to continue to reduce emissions by monitoring the progress of other countries.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2692039584d691af58407f93aa904a0</guid></item><item><title>Netanyahu voices opposition to Palestinian state ahead of UN Security Council vote on Gaza</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/netanyahu-voices-opposition-to-palestinian-state-ahead-of-un-security-council-vote-on-gaza/divvx2sje</link><description>The draft resolution would follow the US-brokered ceasefire deal between Israel and Hamas and mentions a possible future Palestinian state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb96222e77e937f2a6d00e8ab566b5ee</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We are heartbroken&amp;apos;: Australian cycling mourns Paralympian gold medallist Paige Greco</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-paralympic-gold-medallist-paige-greco-dies-aged-28/rfmq1rg8u</link><description>The para-cyclist died in her Adelaide home on Sunday after experiencing a &amp;quot;sudden medical episode&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2dbc9956691a27e1da9df00e46e0b1d7</guid></item><item><title>As the play sand asbestos scare continues to grow, here&amp;apos;s what we know so far</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/coloured-sand-asbestos-explainer-schools/yljs38aya</link><description>More recalls, more Canberra school closures, and the sand has been found at over 100 sites in South Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6684590fd0c1a90309a8a321afd34feb</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 17 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-17-november-2025/j3vw1spz1</link><description>A five minute bullet in for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">95d72df35870f7fa843e1ded3dfd0b8b</guid></item><item><title>Three day US government shutdown ends, but investors still nervous</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/three-day-us-government-shutdown-ends-but-investors-still-nervous/5h0s17ups</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with George Boubouras from K2 Asset Management Ltd about the day&amp;apos;s market moves including how the US government shutdown will impact the US Federal Reserve&amp;apos;s next interest rate decision, plus a preview of Nvidia&amp;apos;s quarterly results.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">075fc07c3cc023472110c4a78b7bf218</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Difficult territory&amp;apos;: What happens if we don&amp;apos;t reach net zero?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/difficult-territory-what-happens-if-we-dont-reach-net-zero/1b7jbom72</link><description>Failing to achieve net zero would &amp;quot;disproportionately&amp;quot; exacerbate the climate impacts projected for Australia, experts say. Here&amp;apos;s how.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89e1743eef401f185e4becb62ba7bfc8</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Gets under the skin&amp;apos;: The disadvantage shaping the future of 950,000 Australian kids</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/child-poverty-australian-children-future/c2lpnm276</link><description>A new report shines a light on how poverty is impacting a growing number of Australian kids.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73d1992197486863a9dc7bbb3f7bf626</guid></item><item><title>SBS News goes one on one with Federal Opposition Leader Sussan Ley</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-goes-one-on-one-with-federal-opposition-leader-sussan-ley/4fi9gxm9m</link><description>Just days after her party ditched its support of net zero emissions targets, federal Opposition Leader Sussan Ley talks to SBS Chief Political Correspondent Anna Henderson about that policy, immigration, and more in a lengthy one on one interview.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc16ecff020484dffd458bb692a50257</guid></item><item><title>UK cuts asylum seeker rights in major overhaul</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/uk-cuts-asylum-seeker-rights-in-major-overhaul/il4723ly1</link><description>Sweeping changes have been announced to Britain&amp;apos;s controversial asylum system as polls show immigration has overtaken the economy as voters&amp;apos; top concern. The Labour government has been hardening its immigration policies as it seeks to stem the surging popularity of the populist Reform UK party, which has driven the immigration agenda and forced Labour to adopt a tougher line.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">646b9363840b136f5c89df47f5fa9af2</guid></item><item><title>South African man&amp;apos;s Australian visa cancelled after neo-Nazi rally outside NSW parliament</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/neo-nazi-matthew-gruters-visa-has-been-cancelled/kotrcbjyg</link><description>Matthew Gruter was one of the 60 demonstrators who took part in a protest touting Hitler slogans outside NSW parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">938d721325ab77dd08ccb8b39392453b</guid></item><item><title>Ley downplays past net zero remarks, stops short of revealing personal view</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ley-confident-retains-liberal-support-leadership-speculation/owasmf1iq</link><description>The Opposition leader has said the Coalition&amp;apos;s new energy policy proves she still has the support of the party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8c92d3873214fa1486211d9f4b9a8be4</guid></item><item><title>Ley downplays past net zero remarks, stops short of revealing personal view</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sussan-ley-responds-to-2021-support-of-net-zero-after-liberal-policy-dump/owasmf1iq</link><description>The Opposition leader has said the Coalition&amp;apos;s new energy policy proves she still has the support of the party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3a1615af7caeab1506b5685c2f702fc4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Not just fear&amp;apos;: Why some Australians are sending their gold overseas</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-quiet-rush-to-hide-gold-safely-away/kd41rhi9c</link><description>Gold prices have been glimmering, keeping buyers and sellers busy. But for some Australians, it&amp;apos;s more than a market play.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d152439746e45f23ef623de63fa6ab1</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: SBS talks to Kaveh Madani on Tehran&amp;apos;s water crisis</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-sbs-talks-to-kaveh-madani-on-tehrans-water-crisis/qamlv6is5</link><description>Kaveh Madani warned Iran about water scarcity 20 years ago. He was called a &amp;quot;water terrorist.&amp;quot; Now Iran is experiencing an extreme water crisis, its like not seen for more than six decades. Tehran, famous for its surrounding snowy mountains, has had no rain in over 200 days. Its main water sources are in a dire situation; two major dams supplying the capital are at less than 10 per cent capacity. Kaveh Madani is the director of the United Nations University Institute for Water, Environment and Health, and warned of this situation back in the early 2000s, and he&amp;apos;s speaking here to SBS broadcaster Niv Sadrolodabaee.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4ad99199dbf18bd75ae633db846b1473</guid></item><item><title>UK&amp;apos;s planned overhaul of asylum system slashes key protections for refugees</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/uk-overhaul-of-asylum-system-slashes-key-protections-for-refugees/rhpwjwnvd</link><description>The UK government has called the proposed changes the &amp;quot;most sweeping reforms to tackle illegal migration in modern times&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1e3605152f06e656beaf3381b9d55f19</guid></item><item><title>What does the Gaza plan endorsed by the UN Security Council include?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/united-nations-security-council-united-states-gaza-plan/ed735kr26</link><description>The resolution endorses US President Donald Trump&amp;apos;s 20-point ceasefire plan, which calls for a transitional authority in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af8ccbfe44b383a788a21d4d942ff7d0</guid></item><item><title>How does your income compare? What Australians earned in a $1.3 trillion year</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-your-income-compares-australia/tm3jek6z5</link><description>Most Australians get their personal income from their jobs, but investments are also growing as a source of income for many.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">33f06d8da10363226a728c616238d12e</guid></item><item><title>Bangladesh&amp;apos;s former Prime Minister is sentenced to death</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/bangladeshs-former-prime-minister-is-sentenced-to-death/6kdukzmqd</link><description>Bangladesh has entered one of its most volatile political periods in decades after former prime minister Sheikh Hasina was sentenced to death after being convicted over last year’s student-led uprising. She strongly rejects the ruling as illegitimate and politically motivated, insisting she was denied a fair trial. The verdict has heightened fears of renewed unrest, deepening political polarisation, and uncertainty over who will lead the Awami League into future elections.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f06bf4766eb83d3cca1a1c467f3e4ef</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;FIFA Pass&amp;apos;: Donald Trump announces fast-tracked visas for World Cup ticket holders</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/donald-trump-visas-world-cup-2026-fifa/xwt5xd9yz</link><description>The US has promised a seamless experience for next year&amp;apos;s tournament despite concerns that Trump&amp;apos;s border crackdown could hurt fans.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8354ff99c5fc2c0e672c9f81920168e7</guid></item><item><title>Scammers &amp;apos;love&amp;apos; it: The $260 million reason Aussies are urged to be on alert</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/shopping-scams-black-friday-warning-australia/ewnlty0t2</link><description>Australians have lost nearly $260 million to scams this year, with shopping scams surging as sales season kicks off.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">49140d38fb6156d465bd4be7f89d6718</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 18 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-18-november-2025/tjoclbebj</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">97fe5ee049b60b7628a92bf70a12236e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;They hate modern Australia&amp;apos;: South African neo-Nazi detained after visa cancelled</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/south-african-neo-nazi-taken-into-detention-after-visa-cancelled/dgu2j4zl1</link><description>Matthew Gruter was one of 60 black-clad demonstrators who were allowed to assemble outside NSW parliament and yell Hitler youth chants on 8 November.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0da425d158ca0a70d0ed707659b69cce</guid></item><item><title>Ultra conservative expected to become Chile&amp;apos;s next president in December</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ultra-conservative-expected-to-become-chiles-next-president-in-december/nfruca8vj</link><description>Ultraconservative lawyer Jose Antonio Kast is the favourite to become Chile&amp;apos;s next leader, when he and rival Jeanette Jarra head to a second round of presidential elections next month. Neither candidate scored a majority of votes in the first round, triggering a run-off election that is expected to be dominated by votes for Chile&amp;apos;s conservative parties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5f95399167ab4da762934a425b2c3de8</guid></item><item><title>Hannah McGuire&amp;apos;s parents relieved after ex-boyfriend jailed for 28 years for murder</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ballarat-man-lachlan-young-jailed-for-nearly-three-decades-over-murder-of-hannah-mcguire/l36a8sc4l</link><description>Lachlan Young was midway through his trial when he changed his plea and admitted strangling his ex-girlfriend at their home in April 2024.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2bb97439163c00c5f00d6be1070e4e73</guid></item><item><title>$60bn wiped from ASX &amp;amp; scams rise ahead of Black Friday sales</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/60bn-wiped-from-asx-scams-rise-ahead-of-black-friday-sales/pn6vyu2mw</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with David Lane from Ord Minnett about why the ASX200 had its second worst day of the year as $60bn is wiped off the value of the local sharemarket; plus Angelica Waite discusses the rise of scams ahead of Black Friday with the ACCC&amp;apos;s Catriona Lowe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f9c9ffe521fe6abe5563ead97b278223</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Clearly bitter&amp;apos;: Liberal senator responds after ex-colleague&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;inept&amp;apos;, &amp;apos;lazy&amp;apos; claims</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/former-liberal-senator-hollie-hughes-lashes-ex-colleagues-as-inept-and-lazy-as-she-quits-party-live-on-radio/xjqprnvgj</link><description>Liberal senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price has responded to a former colleague&amp;apos;s claims she&amp;apos;s being used to undermine party leader Sussan Ley.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f48874979475bc07cbbc6a692ceb33e9</guid></item><item><title>The tiny island taking one of the world&amp;apos;s most valuable companies to court</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/pari-island-indonesia-taking-cement-giant-holcim-to-court/l8rhwbel5</link><description>The people of Pari Island have contributed minimally to climate change, but rising sea levels are threatening to swallow their home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dcde6720c56fc116063f45c59a481eaf</guid></item><item><title>eSafety commissioner says Roblox age restrictions come after negotiations, fine threats</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/roblox-to-introduce-age-guessing-tech-to-avoid-looming-social-media-ban-for-kids/8kgad5lie</link><description>Roblox said its age-checking technology would limit inappropriate conversations between children and adults on the platform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">66c92480e53165f83aab1503d01491d2</guid></item><item><title>The &amp;apos;quick cash&amp;apos; scams criminals are using to lure international students</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/afp-alerts-international-students-to-rising-identity-theft-risk/ses2d9qhs</link><description>Criminals are targeting international students with cash offers for access to their bank accounts and identity documents, police warn.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">51713a4340a600b0b14d8679d908c79d</guid></item><item><title>US Congress votes to force release of Epstein files</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-congress-votes-to-force-release-of-epstein-files/07lksfnlf</link><description>The US Congress has voted overwhelmingly to release the Department of Justice files on disgraced financier and convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein. After months of political pressure to release the files, survivors of Epstein&amp;apos;s abuse say they hope this can lead to some justice.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b854049ba25cd8d46905deb83697f156</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 19 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-19-november-2025/sc3j1u0n4</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">291e5f16dd06bdf4ee019e2ee0da0c3e</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Fina off NT&amp;apos;s Top End intensifies into a category two storm</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tropical-cyclone-fina-nt-top-end-weather/vmb9ycepa</link><description>A weekend of heavy rain, destructive winds, felled trees and power cuts awaits the Top End as the first cyclone of the season approaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">632b27c6b0618695321145b87348585a</guid></item><item><title>Socceroos lose to Colombia in New York as World Cup preparations continue</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/socceroos-vs-colombia-international-friendly-results/7wlu8shlj</link><description>Australia took on Colombia in an international friendly in New York, following their loss against Venezuela on Saturday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e9f1d47b7b31aaa7f75f29202541fa29</guid></item><item><title>Flattery, fighter jets and a trillion dollar pledge as Saudi Crown Prince meets Trump</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/flattery-fighter-jets-and-a-trillion-dollar-pledge-as-saudi-crown-prince-meets-trump/ggli2fgn7</link><description>Saudi Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, returning to the White House for the first time since the murder of journalist Jamal Khashoggi, has met President Donald Trump at the Oval Office. The two leaders discussed a number of matters including Saudi Arabia investing a trillion US dollars in America for AI Chips, F-35 fighter jets, the Khashoggi assassination and Gaza&amp;apos;s reconstruction.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">449550480d9a814bead6449795bc79c9</guid></item><item><title>Curaçao makes World Cup history after completing fairytale qualification campaign</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/curacao-the-smallest-nation-to-qualify-for-fifa-world-cup/d8s2koj01</link><description>Curaçao has replaced Iceland as the smallest nation by population to qualify for a World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a1f621a902ac4ab687706af40150557e</guid></item><item><title>Waste, harassment claims and walkouts: Behind a city&amp;apos;s months-long bin workers&amp;apos; strike</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-are-birmingham-bin-workers-on-strike/fe6fle5pm</link><description>The situation became more complicated when agency workers covering during the strike voted to take industrial action themselves.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64b67719cbe09c2c0dbc12ce51c83874</guid></item><item><title>Eyes on Nvidia &amp;amp; wages rise above inflation</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/eyes-on-nvidia-wages-rise-above-inflation/41eyofmex</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Matt Sherwood from Perpetual about the day&amp;apos;s market action including why Nvidia&amp;apos;s quarterly results tomorrow may be a turning point; plus Paula Gadsby from EY goes through the latest wages data and what it means for interest rates.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd643cd5d764470059617dff1a05f30e</guid></item><item><title>Chris Minns on hospital funding row: we can&amp;apos;t all be wrong</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/chris-minns-on-hospital-funding-row-we-cant-all-be-wrong/b6qoqlhwf</link><description>State premiers have come together for an urgent meeting, as tensions rise over reaching a new public hospital funding deal with the federal government. A new report from the Grattan Institute also finds Australia&amp;apos;s hospitals are wasting more than $1 billion a year on avoidable spending.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60632243963ab5d32461ccaa5e7a5122</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Sheer terror&amp;apos;: Palestinians arrive in Australia after &amp;apos;mysterious&amp;apos; South Africa flight saga</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-australian-link-to-mysterious-flight-of-palestinians-arriving-in-south-africa/7ymf696hr</link><description>A small group of Palestinians with Australian visas were onboard a flight to South Africa making headlines around the world, and have since made their way to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa4e345edfa263124b444dca67f4b4e2</guid></item><item><title>Calls for superannuation protections as some retirees could lose up to $205,000</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/calls-for-superannuation-protections-as-some-retirees-lose-up-to-205-000/f8oephznl</link><description>A new report is calling on the federal government to include protections for retirees when it comes to super performance testing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e07ef14abd301da19e98d46506dcec58</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The worst we&amp;apos;ve seen&amp;apos;: The type of job that&amp;apos;s getting harder to find in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-jobs-disappearing-at-a-growing-rate/lk203bdkr</link><description>A new report has painted a grim picture of Australia&amp;apos;s employment system, calling on the federal government to urgently intervene.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0e62fd58c2745ed7c59032c6898a10c</guid></item><item><title>Children among 25 killed in Russian strike on apartment block in western Ukraine</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/children-among-25-killed-in-russian-strike-on-apartment-block-in-western-ukraine/0j2vlt6kv</link><description>UN human rights chief Volker Turk said he was &amp;quot;appalled&amp;quot; by the number of civilian casualties.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ed28a0862430990d038cf0ac9ebf23ee</guid></item><item><title>Indonesia’s drowning island takes historic climate case to court</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/indonesias-drowning-island-takes-historic-climate-case-to-court/902jxfpoi</link><description>Indonesia is home to more than 17,000 islands, but its smallest are highly vulnerable to the impacts of climate change. The tiny community of Pari Island is facing multiple climate-induced threats, including to its entire existence.Four people on the island are now trying to launch a landmark legal case against a European cement giant over its historic carbon emissions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">69b53c546e00b2669b258b453e0eabd5</guid></item><item><title>At least 25 Palestinians killed in Israeli airstrikes across Gaza, medics say</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/at-least-25-palestinians-killed-in-israeli-airstrikes-across-gaza/xtik6ym7u</link><description>Wednesday&amp;apos;s strikes were among the deadliest in the territory since the ceasefire came into force.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">641e5c2716bedf95f0344980529a078d</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Fina to swing toward the Northern Territory as it holds at category two</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cyclone-fina-to-swing-toward-the-top-end-as-it-holds-at-category-two/v8o89qz9n</link><description>Residents are stocking up on basic supplies as the cyclone is expected to turn south on Thursday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5f1733d9061e652e48b89d872225bcb</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Pushing its own agenda&amp;apos;: PNG&amp;apos;s top diplomat lashes Türkiye after Australia withdraws COP31 bid</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-concedes-cop31-hosting-to-turkiye-bowen-to-lead-negotiations/o0dv8xuy2</link><description>Australia has abandoned its bid to host COP31 in Adelaide, meaning the event will be held in Türkiye.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbfcadfad7e6df68b5c36685a82f12c2</guid></item><item><title>Meta admits there may be mistakes as it brings teenager social media ban forward</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/meta-admits-there-may-be-mistakes-as-it-brings-social-media-ban-for-under-16s-forward/wijsh0k3r</link><description>Meta warns some teenagers may &amp;quot;mistakenly lose access&amp;quot; as it rushes to implement new social media restrictions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d5c994c690c36ddd11af3e856f0238f</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 20 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-20-november-2025/u3l9mlf59</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb96c6f536b0cc6fc4570ca3ade50d92</guid></item><item><title>Bicycle kicks and tears: Here are the teams who have qualified for the 2026 FIFA World Cup</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/who-have-qualified-for-the-fifa-2026-world-cup-and-who-is-still-in-the-hunt/1jte6ykoy</link><description>In the November qualifying rounds, 14 additional teams, including some surprising names, secured their places for the 2026 FIFA World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50830a96aa1331cda0253c1cbd8d5446</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Completely emptied&amp;apos;: Human rights report alleges Israeli war crimes in West Bank camps</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/human-rights-report-alleges-israeli-crimes-against-humanity-displacement-in-west-bank-camps/y68thxfuc</link><description>Human Rights Watch reports 32,000 Palestinians were forcibly displaced from West Bank camps in 2025.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1f7ef83973531b2270c82f03b6b0864b</guid></item><item><title>Trump, Epstein &amp;amp; the Saudi Crown Prince, and autocrat karaoke</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trump-epstein-the-saudi-crown-prince-and-autocrat-karaoke/xlpen4ps3</link><description>Trump wipes the slate clean of murder for Mohammed bin Salman because ‘things happen’. The Epstein files move a big step closer to being released and what it’s like reporting on the ground in the Democratic Republic of the Congo. Plus, the comment that sent China-Japan relations plummeting.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc75745de742a7e4a359d5b0ad97eedc</guid></item><item><title>Nvidia goes off the charts as ASX recovers</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nvidia-goes-off-the-charts-as-asx-recovers/wipyytn89</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Ben Clark from TMS Private Wealth to go through AI chip giant Nvidia&amp;apos;s record results and whether this is the turning point the market was looking for.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc3f55637738c5065df9439bcaff9a66</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Can&amp;apos;t have it all&amp;apos;: Australia abandons bid for COP31 climate summit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/cant-have-it-all-australia-abandons-bid-for-cop31-climate-summit/shmhxtcsh</link><description>The federal government has abruptly abandoned its bid to host the United Nations climate conference next year, conceding Turkiye will oversee the COP31. The Pacific countries and environmental activists have criticised the federal government&amp;apos;s failure to bring the event to Adelaide.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d89a21e8192a1c342fc3b08f734670b7</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Daily challenge&amp;apos;: The hidden cost of living crisis affecting families</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/food-and-school-supply-charities-overwhelmed-with-demand/xqpsveb7g</link><description>A food relief charity says it has so much demand it&amp;apos;s forced to turn schools away.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a5e35f45f010c38ace703556982a336</guid></item><item><title>PNG questions &amp;apos;what planet&amp;apos; the Opposition is on, after it ditches net zero support</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/png-questions-what-planet-the-opposition-is-on-after-it-ditches-net-zero-support/yxyrbeab7</link><description>Papua New Guinea&amp;apos;s foreign minister has said the Opposition&amp;apos;s position on climate change &amp;quot;won&amp;apos;t do them any favours, or us any favours&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5b641fe8a5004caad4a2d67c4058984</guid></item><item><title>Albanese&amp;apos;s deposed attorney-general urges Labor to embrace ambitious reform</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albaneses-deposed-attorney-general-urges-labor-to-embrace-ambitious-reform/rxk7kqxkx</link><description>Mark Dreyfus has said &amp;quot;early Labor figures would be mightily disappointed&amp;quot; in the Labor party&amp;apos;s track record on constitutional reform.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a95a9f7c7977ddc40d27088be3204c2b</guid></item><item><title>Why government debt matters: spoiler, it’s not just Monopoly money</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/why-government-debt-matters-spoiler-its-not-just-monopoly-money/casb5am3m</link><description>We know government debt is around $1 trillion, we&amp;apos;ve heard it&amp;apos;s bad for younger generations -- but we don&amp;apos;t really know what any of it means. This week, Elfy and Rania chat with Professor Richard Holden from the University of New South Wales about government debt and why it matters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fd1d1d7b70fae465b29b2dbd0839abb</guid></item><item><title>Fire forces evacuation of Brazil climate conference with negotiations still short of a deal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fire-forces-evacuation-of-brazil-climate-conference-with-negotiations-still-short-of-a-deal/vpoditrg5</link><description>The fire has now been brought under control and 13 people have been treated for smoke inhalation, officials said.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8829b7616954f007543c2463600cc9f</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy open to &amp;apos;constructive&amp;apos; work on peace plan as Europe warns against &amp;apos;capitulation&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/zelenskyy-open-to-constructive-work-on-peace-plan-as-europe-warns-against-capitulation/8z62cxak2</link><description>The Ukrainian president has said he&amp;apos;s open to &amp;quot;constructive, honest and prompt work&amp;quot; on a US-backed peace plan that&amp;apos;s facing pushback from Europe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">07fd7e2ca32560e692595efe9fa4301f</guid></item><item><title>Former journalist and Healthy Harold&amp;apos;s CEO Kellie Sloane to lead NSW Liberal Party</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/former-journalist-and-healthy-harolds-ceo-kellie-sloane-leader-nsw-liberal-party/9uguom7tt</link><description>The first-term Liberal MP has 18 months before the party contests the next state election.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fa219a2eeb6467ffa857cabd2c2bf998</guid></item><item><title>Potential &amp;apos;severe&amp;apos; consequences: Why you won&amp;apos;t be allowed to use these on some flights</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/power-banks-banned-planes-qantas-virgin-explainer/odb7ekq16</link><description>Rules around power banks are increasingly tightening after a string of incidents. How do you know if yours is safe?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7863138c9b0d35ab4d910cd09a7b2b5</guid></item><item><title>Warning issued over &amp;apos;quick cash&amp;apos; scam targeting international students</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/warning-issued-over-quick-cash-scam-targeting-international-students/i8rb75ts6</link><description>An urgent warning has been issued to international students departing Australia to not sell their bank accounts and ID to criminals. The Australian Federal Police says students are offered &amp;apos;quick cash&amp;apos; - but accepting it could see them indelibly linked to crime networks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8cb495e93082f9fb1b0283958022e1a0</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;That courageous girl&amp;apos;: Matildas coach&amp;apos;s support for Mary Fowler after alleged racism experience</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/its-happening-everywhere-advocate-says-mary-fowler-racism-incident-goes-deeper/kj0buoxg2</link><description>Matildas star Mary Fowler has alleged she experienced racism during her time with French club Montpellier, which has denied the allegations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">24e0c5dea70f66757998dba3ad915399</guid></item><item><title>Where Kunzang&amp;apos;s from there&amp;apos;s no ocean. Now in Darwin, he&amp;apos;s worried about the cyclone</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tropical-cyclone-fina-expected-to-strengthen-as-it-approaches-the-northern-territory/kh7n09ii5</link><description>The man from Bhutan has only been in the NT for three months, and says he doesn&amp;apos;t know what to expect from Fina.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">50e4aa438696d5d562c29512f7a79f5d</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 21 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-21-november-2025/czqbf7wpg</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">683e0fc781c2718b3dd4a84a996ac297</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;On notice&amp;apos;: AFP charges three for alleged threats to politicians including Anthony Albanese</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/on-notice-afp-warning-as-it-charges-individuals-with-harassing-federal-politicians/m1jboti87</link><description>The AFP has seen a 63 per cent increase in threats against parliamentarians over the last four years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">717447aca1b755bd90e9ae0eb7d3f4d1</guid></item><item><title>Wieambilla police shootings &amp;apos;not a terrorist act&amp;apos;, Queensland coroner says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/wieambilla-shootings-not-a-terrorist-act-coroner/uukdipkb2</link><description>An inquest last year heard expert evidence that the Trains engaged in terrorism that was religiously motivated.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">58a3e1dbbbaece4e78d9875e96426156</guid></item><item><title>US rate fears trump Nvidia&amp;apos;s better than expected result</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-rate-fears-trump-nvidias-better-than-expected-result/l3s5d95k7</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Lochlan Halliday from Morningstar to find out what spooked investors despite Nvidia&amp;apos;s better than expected profit and if it&amp;apos;s likely to last.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b186488bf4baf6f40c48f76afb5b64b5</guid></item><item><title>Residents urged to remain sheltered as Cyclone Fina closes in on Darwin | Morning Bulletin 22 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/residents-urged-to-remain-sheltered-as-cyclone-fina-closes-in-on-darwin-morning-bulletin-22-november-2025/urd50d0an</link><description>In this bulletin, Residents urged to remain sheltered as Cyclone Fina closes in on Darwin; Vladimir Putin confirms Russia has received US peace proposal for ending war in Ukraine; and in cricket, Mitchell Starc dismisses claims of Australia panic amid dramatic Ashes collapse.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a3d13fb3553e32b4d10fcdab1df5b0c3</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;The odds are against us&amp;apos;: Why some Australian homeowners may never upgrade</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-three-bedroom-properties-are-getting-harder-to-find/6h2g8zswv</link><description>The property ladder has changed since the COVID-19 pandemic. Data shows some homeowners may never get the chance to upgrade.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7173759bc140448eef7e5aa28983d6f4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Crisis of identity&amp;apos;: Why state Liberals aren&amp;apos;t following Sussan Ley on net zero</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/crisis-of-identity-why-state-liberals-arent-following-sussan-ley-on-net-zero/ijxywwxxa</link><description>Liberal Party leadership spills in NSW and Victoria have seen two moderate women leaders emerge.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96fc5e1ee8cfd7ebc8adc56eaa34cfe6</guid></item><item><title>‘No food, no money’: Khoa was abandoned and owed $10,000 in unpaid wages. He’s not alone</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/no-food-no-money-khoa-was-abandoned-and-owed-10-000-in-unpaid-wages-hes-not-alone/o9uj8zvmv</link><description>As the academic year ends, thousands of international students are signing on for holiday work. But if things go wrong, experts warn that few understand their legal entitlements or how to recover unpaid wages.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a92900f996f08d932d1290e03cc9d249</guid></item><item><title>Leadership spills and policy reversals: How healthy is our democracy?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/leadership-spills-and-policy-reversals-how-healthy-is-our-democracy/nj201gjdp</link><description>With the abandonment of its net-zero policies, and leadership spills in two of Australia&amp;apos;s largest states, the Coalition is undergoing a period of major upheaval. So what does that mean for a Westminster democracy which analysts say depends on two different political positions to succeed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">535650e0f953ceb60e6b9c1d25412719</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine faces &amp;apos;difficult choice&amp;apos; on US plan to end Russia&amp;apos;s war, Zelenskyy says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ukraine-russia-war-zelenskyy-putin-us-plan-trump/5l1zz9a7d</link><description>Donald Trump has given Ukraine a week to accept the proposal, which would see it cede territory, among other concessions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c5f4deea43ee62f6e2b608a16a1dde8</guid></item><item><title>Darwin escapes major damage as residents praised for heeding Cyclone Fina warnings</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tropical-cyclone-fina-darwin-nt-top-end-weather/4vc7p1yn1</link><description>The storm was the strongest cyclone to approach Darwin since Tracy in 1974, but there were no reports of serious injuries or damage.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46e145a4118b32602202d5bb36e3f21a</guid></item><item><title>Five key moments from Trump&amp;apos;s surprisingly warm meeting with Zohran Mamdani</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-mamdani-meeting/pwjcgodb4</link><description>After months of trading barbs, the US president and incoming New York City mayor found some unexpected common ground.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75750b73cf806733a869c32d2734de53</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Fina closing in on Darwin | Midday News Bulletin 22 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/cyclone-fina-closing-in-on-darwin-midday-news-bulletin-22-november-2025/6zblj50xz</link><description>In this bulletin, Cyclone Fina making landfall in Top End; Gunmen in Nigeria abduct 200 students and staff from Catholic school; and in Rugby Union, Wallabies hit by fresh injury blows ahead of France Test.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">44c7e757f07423e2aa590be305679adb</guid></item><item><title>Owed $10,000, Khoa was left stranded on a farm with no food or funds. He&amp;apos;s not alone</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/migrant-worker-exploitation-underpayment-australia-khoa-nguyen-story/0h7n03pah</link><description>Despite recent reforms, exploitation of migrant workers remains a serious issue in Australia, experts say.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">600fee42e8c84363f2fad600282a271f</guid></item><item><title>Marjorie Taylor Greene quits Congress | Evening News Bulletin 22 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/marjorie-taylor-greene-quits-congress-evening-news-bulletin-22-november-2025/az2r8s57v</link><description>Tropical Cyclone Fina intensifies to a category 3 storm; Republican Marjorie Taylor Greene announces her resignation after a fallout with Donald Trump; England seizes control on day two of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc03be9450b854902dbfdf0a75596399</guid></item><item><title>The two words missing from the world&amp;apos;s most important climate conference agreement</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cop-negotiations-fossil-fuels/3mbq2dzbc</link><description>An agreement on climate action has been reached at COP30 in Brazil — but not everyone is happy with the final result.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4fcf416d792fcc7b7c0cc062c7a442b8</guid></item><item><title>Some world leaders make decisions while chronically sleep-deprived. Should they?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sanae-takaichi-two-hours-sleep-raises-leadership-questions/fynnp01gj</link><description>Sleep deprivation undermines our ability to think clearly. So what should we make of leaders who say they run on just a few hours?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">113cf7d3e3561f639ad8e3b434551f83</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;You don&amp;apos;t have the freedom to leave&amp;apos;: The human cost of Australia&amp;apos;s solar boom</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-human-cost-of-australias-solar-boom/ztxkq52wj</link><description>As Australia&amp;apos;s uptake of solar panels booms, human rights groups have raised alarm about links to Uyghur forced labour in the supply chain.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4f0eb8bad5e36aa2b39485c38ac6b0f7</guid></item><item><title>A tough night for Darwin as Cyclone Fina barrels through | Morning News Bulletin 23 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-tough-night-for-darwin-as-cyclone-fina-barrels-through-morning-news-bulletin-23-november-2025/mlic1dojl</link><description>Darwin residents endure a difficult night as Cyclone Fina barrels through the Top End; Israeli strikes in Gaza kill at least 20 people; And North Melbourne powers into AFLW Grand Final after overturning a six-point deficit.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6f502a411411fede598c9118ae2fe11a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Isolation and shame&amp;apos;: Australians are avoiding perinatal mental health support, new research reveals</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/isolation-and-shame-australians-are-avoiding-perinatal-mental-health-support-new-research-reveals/71wsofd52</link><description>Around one in four Australians are failing to seek support when experiencing perinatal mental health issues. Experts say the data released by the Gidget Foundation highlights a lack of awareness around signs and symptoms, and ongoing stigma around the issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffe9d58fbdecd408b34a4d247b57a81c</guid></item><item><title>Underground struggles: Illegal miners risk death in Morocco&amp;apos;s forgotten coal town</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/underground-struggles-illegal-miners-risk-death-in-moroccos-forgotten-coal-town/xszzlmjvx</link><description>In one of Morocco&amp;apos;s impoverished coal towns, illegal miners continue to risk their lives to make ends meet. In an exclusive sit-down interview with SBS News, a photojournalist has shared the harsh realities he witnessed of the miners in Jerada. Ahead of the International Mining Congress in Morocco, experts are calling for better health and safety regulations to be implemented in the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0e712e9db3008d66e19ed0eaf2e697e</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Associate Professor Bassina Farbenblum</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-associate-professor-bassina-farbenblum/0qnmbvopq</link><description>As thousands of international students prepare to take summer holiday jobs, Associate Professor Bassina Farbenblum, an expert on migrants&amp;apos; rights from the University of New South Wales, warns that more is needed to protect students from wage theft and abuse. She says Australia has a ‘pervasive problem’ with workplace exploitation of international students and those on temporary visas. Dr Farbenblum is speaking to SBS’s Sandra Fulloon.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0c18729dd2be5ce7d71063e89149364</guid></item><item><title>New names added to migration Welcome Wall at National Maritime Museum</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/new-names-added-to-migration-welcome-wall-at-national-maritime-museum/m1j44tn0z</link><description>Two panels have been unveiled at Australia&amp;apos;s National Maritime Museum to honour a new group of migrant families. Museum Director and CEO Ms Daryl Karp and Home Affairs Minister Tony Burke say the Monument is a celebration of the long history of migrants who have shaped modern Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48d94554856bd3c7a4352b62cf02903e</guid></item><item><title>Fresh wave of Israeli airstrikes kills more than 20 people in Gaza</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-airstrikes-gaza-ceasefire/3b5hykn8n</link><description>Israel and Hamas have accused each other of violating the tenuous ceasefire in Gaza multiple times over the last six weeks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e156783fc8e88b549950ef2040793c7f</guid></item><item><title>Investigation into fatal Brisbane house fire | Midday News Bulletin 23 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/investigation-into-fatal-brisbane-house-fire-midday-news-bulletin-23-november-2025/r662d3vse</link><description>In this bulletin, four people fighting for life after a house fire in Brisbane, Brazil&amp;apos;s former president Jair Bolsonaro deemed a flight risk for trying to escape arrest. And in sport, the Wallabies lose to France, ending a winless tour of Europe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1c372c769d07ec586f36afd199b19a7</guid></item><item><title>How a major MAGA figure went from Trump devotee to calling quits on Congress</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/marjorie-taylor-greene-resigns-congress-donald-trump-feud/eg8yg2qb6</link><description>Marjorie Taylor Greene announced her resignation this weekend after a dramatic falling out with the president that was months in the making.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">610bf75ad657d889b44ec4d008216c62</guid></item><item><title>European leaders to meet over US Ukraine plan | Evening News Bulletin 23 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/european-leaders-to-meet-over-us-ukraine-plan-evening-news-bulletin-23-november-2025/g5ziz1wuc</link><description>A cautious return to business as usual in the Top End after Cyclone Fina; European leaders meeting in Geneva over a US plan to end the war in Ukraine; Australia crushes England in the opening test of the Ashes.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2b16aefc89f87064318b3343f8744416</guid></item><item><title>Trump signals room to negotiate Ukraine peace deal, as Rubio insists plan is US-led</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-signals-room-to-negotiate-ukraine-peace-deal-as-rubio-insists-plan-is-us-led/7aa9whego</link><description>The US president had given Ukraine until Thursday to approve the plan, which requires it to cede territory to Russia, cut its army and pledge never to join NATO.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa3f1903cb33884f79c0b2212b8ee126</guid></item><item><title>A &amp;apos;massive&amp;apos; number of wildlife die on our roads. Experts say protections are falling far short</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/wildlife-road-kill-protections-falling-short/79d7h3jxe</link><description>Wildlife-safe road features remain largely optional, a “nice-to-have, not need-to-have”, the author of new research warns.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f2128ae7262c4be046d60ef641d5e50e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;No way out&amp;apos;: Vietnam flooding death toll reaches 90 as search continues for missing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/vietnam-floods-death-toll-reaches-90-amid-relentless-rain/csxvjkk6s</link><description>Relentless rain has lashed south-central Vietnam since late October and popular holiday destinations have been hit by several rounds of flooding.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">170c0e6bd14ce5e4128db7ad7ef7ad33</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;It&amp;apos;s just impossible&amp;apos;: The rental crisis pushing working families to the brink</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rental-crisis-single-mothers-affordability-perth-housing/sanyz35v6</link><description>Rental stress is at its worst levels on record, with renters in one city now spending nearly a third of their income on housing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f60cd36a2f99c12adadce25001cda37</guid></item><item><title>My daughter’s alleged killer is dead. This law makes me wish he wasn&amp;apos;t</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/law-that-makes-me-wish-my-daughters-alleged-murderer-was-alive/5x2l0v5h1</link><description>A coronial inquest found Sandi Harvey&amp;apos;s daughter was murdered. But she&amp;apos;ll never know if the alleged killer was found guilty or not.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48fbb0a6c6594e32e7753b75f2ddb1e6</guid></item><item><title>Ukraine peace plan talks &amp;apos;productive&amp;apos;| Morning News Bulletin 24 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ukraine-peace-plan-talks-productive-morning-news-bulletin-24-november-2025/2dzrkawet</link><description>In this bulletin, US and Ukrainian officials say peace talks have been productive; the government aims to pass its environment reforms in Parliament this week; and in sport, Oscar Piastri and Lando Norris disqualified from the Las Vegas Grand Prix</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6ecca5452858deae56591459056acd29</guid></item><item><title>A Russian &amp;apos;wish list&amp;apos; or path to peace? The evolving plan to end Russia&amp;apos;s war on Ukraine</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rubio-calls-geneva-talks-the-best-meeting-yet-in-ukraine-peace-effort/e2zu5s50l</link><description>Donald Trump has given Ukraine until Thursday to accept the US proposal to end Russia&amp;apos;s war. But European leaders have now stepped in with different plans — more palatable for Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">316981ddc6500675457bc5c1ae0ce1e1</guid></item><item><title>What we know about Israel&amp;apos;s latest strike on Hezbollah in Beirut</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/senior-hezbollah-official-ali-tabtabai-killed-in-israeli-air-strike-on-beirut/qfw29fas3</link><description>The strike came a week before Pope Leo was set to land in Lebanon on his first foreign trip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b58ebe658101a6ab259c0195190c9c3d</guid></item><item><title>What we know about Israel&amp;apos;s latest strike on Hezbollah in Beirut</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-we-know-about-israels-latest-strike-on-hezbollah-in-beirut/qfw29fas3</link><description>The strike came a week before Pope Leo was set to land in Lebanon on his first foreign trip.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8ee3b2ff90230112623fed9bc5b924be</guid></item><item><title>Vietnam floods death toll reaches 90</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/vietnam-floods-death-toll-reaches-90/yeuybakyu</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc5ace64039a8cf2138f5034660c1519</guid></item><item><title>Fifty schoolchildren escape mass kidnapping in Nigeria, but hundreds still missing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fifty-schoolchildren-escape-mass-kidnapping-in-nigeria-but-hundreds-still-missing/iurwjvoi1</link><description>If confirmed, Friday&amp;apos;s attack on St Mary&amp;apos;s School would be Nigeria&amp;apos;s worst school abduction since the kidnapping of 276 girls by Boko Haram in 2014.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">86cae461f1a366361abd5717ef649fd1</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;A $96 million fiasco&amp;apos;: BoM under pressure over website redesign cost blowout</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bom-under-pressure-over-website-redesign-cost-blowout/mjb611x0p</link><description>The BoM website is one of the most popular in Australia, with millions visiting each day for their weather forecasts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41b4564c094e36f15fec86b985bac945</guid></item><item><title>The human cost of renewables: Why Australia should build solar here</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-human-cost-of-renewables-why-australia-should-build-solar-here/hpelo3l2p</link><description>With the renewable energy transition underway in Australia, the higher than expected uptake of solar panels has human rights groups concerned about links to Uyghur forced labour in the supply chain. As Australia looks into developing its own solar panel industry, rights groups say government and industry should work to ensure the clean energy transition isn&amp;apos;t at the cost of freedom.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0782864d709d68c8e0cb337d2f8653d3</guid></item><item><title>What Black Friday sales shopping does to your brain, and how to stay in control</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-black-friday-sales-shopping-does-to-your-brain/b2z4qtdbz</link><description>Black Friday feels like a celebration of savings, but it is also a masterclass in behavioural and brain science.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">93083da307adb1c9a9dc90eee4767c29</guid></item><item><title>Cyclone Fina approaches northern Western Australia |Midday News Bulletin 24 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/cyclone-fina-approaches-northern-western-australia-midday-news-bulletin-24-november-2025/3gbs365tb</link><description>Cyclone Fina approaches communities in northern Western Australia, Pioneering Australian chef Skye Gyngell dies aged 62, India makes history, winning the inaugural Blind Women&amp;apos;s T20 Cricket World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">22592cc696b3a480d534a65337cf2756</guid></item><item><title>COP30 deal keeps humanity &amp;apos;in the fight for a liveable planet&amp;apos;: UN chief</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/cop30-deal-keeps-humanity-in-the-fight-for-a-liveable-planet-un-chief/654vdjsqd</link><description>Delegates to the COP30 summit in Brazil have reached an agreement to address still rising global emissions. The deal increases money to countries hit by climate change, but contains no explicit fossil fuel plan. The agreement has mollified some - and horrified others.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">64f58575410d7cfc33c4407be8371b20</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 24 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-24-november-2025/jykb577a3</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0767bc1f192244212731e4a51e57bc04</guid></item><item><title>Ashwini&amp;apos;s biggest concerns now will cost the country &amp;apos;billions&amp;apos; in the future</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/childrens-report-highlights-growing-anxieties/zbtpw7pin</link><description>Children are growing more anxious and worried as they age, a new report says. Failing to address their concerns is costly.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">989ae58b0963a655763c8b277405e6d1</guid></item><item><title>Police to resume search for missing four-year-old Gus Lamont | Evening News Bulletin 24 November 202</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/police-to-resume-search-for-missing-four-year-old-gus-lamont-evening-news-bulletin-24-november-2025/77e51z2vi</link><description>Gunmen and suicide bombers attack a paramilitary force headquarters in Pakistan, Police to resume search for missing four-year-old Gus Lamont, Jeeno Thitikul receives biggest winning cheque in women&amp;apos;s golf history</description><guid isPermaLink="false">63dbc715098142b654a39f34b1bfad55</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Women have choice&amp;apos;: Anne Aly says Pauline Hanson&amp;apos;s burqa stunt &amp;apos;unacceptable&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/pauline-hanson-reprises-burqa-stunt-as-senate-suspended/4uxl3ozms</link><description>Multiculturalism Minister Anne Aly says Pauline Hanson aims to divide with burqa stunt, arguing women &amp;quot;have choice&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8b91d1a6e2df0e841e970fb6b04b0945</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Women have choice&amp;apos;: Anne Aly says Pauline Hanson&amp;apos;s burqa stunt &amp;apos;unacceptable&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/women-have-choice-anne-aly-says-pauline-hansons-burqa-stunt-unacceptable/4uxl3ozms</link><description>Multiculturalism Minister Anne Aly says Pauline Hanson aims to divide with burqa stunt, arguing women &amp;quot;have choice&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ebc36f9deb7fe78ef61661bf1b73453e</guid></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology weathers website storm</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/bureau-of-meteorology-weathers-website-storm/y5in22ruo</link><description>The Bureau of Meteorology&amp;apos;s controversial website redesign carries a staggering 96 million dollar price tag. The cost blowout has drawn sharp criticism from both government ministers and the opposition. Federal Environment Minister Murray Watt has expressed deep concern over the massive expenditure, while Nationals Leader David Littleproud warns the public that the exorbitant cost will further erode trust in the agency.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0f2ef1b6c4b7546ca9f9344c743b3add</guid></item><item><title>ASX bounces back as BHP walks away from AA</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asx-bounces-back-as-bhp-walks-away-from-aa/nakjhnvqw</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Raymond Chan from Morgans Financial Limited about the day&amp;apos;s sharemarket action including a recovery on the ASX as the chance of a US rate cut in December swings back up and why BHP walked away from a second crack at Anglo American.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d564190e5e12a3619dccf700536901db</guid></item><item><title>Victoria Police banned racial profiling a decade ago. Has it made a difference?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/victoria-police-banned-racial-profiling-decade-ago/z73w3ya19</link><description>Researchers said that in 2024, Aboriginal people were 15 times more likely to be searched by Victoria Police than white people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">498e1152cb79491590440a18d806e1e7</guid></item><item><title>Not just a &amp;apos;women&amp;apos;s issue&amp;apos;: New fertility guidelines bring men into focus</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-new-health-guidelines-changing-the-narrative-on-fertility-being-a-womens-issue/2yfu2j0fg</link><description>Australian researchers have unveiled the first male infertility guidelines, standardising care and recognising men&amp;apos;s significant role in fertility challenges.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">822099d8c6c29f662682e161a22944ab</guid></item><item><title>Political leaders condemn Pauline Hanson&amp;apos;s burqa stunt | Morning News Bulletin 25 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/political-leaders-condemn-pauline-hansons-burqa-stunt-morning-news-bulletin-25-november-2025/2t3j3lysc</link><description>Political leaders condemn Pauline Hanson&amp;apos;s burqa stunt; Talks continue on a plan to end the war in Ukraine; And in sport, Ash Riddell named best and fairest at the AFLW awards.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6d1a3c091d49aff50e5f5873bf595ce9</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Extraordinary rise&amp;apos;: Australia&amp;apos;s housing affordability hits worst levels yet</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/housing-affordability-hits-worst-levels-yet-new-report-shows/a4d8b7cni</link><description>In Sydney&amp;apos;s eastern suburbs, it would take 35 years for an average wage earner to save up a 20 per cent deposit for a median-priced house.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2dd73a06ce98b6012accde4405ea113</guid></item><item><title>US judge dismisses criminal case against ex-FBI chief James Comey</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-judge-dismisses-case-against-ex-fbi-chief-james-comey/75k6l7nta</link><description>James Comey was charged in September with making false statements to Congress.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9f23702f0c3148cd4f7d328466ff0e0c</guid></item><item><title>Government injects $41.8 million into domestic violence helpline</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/government-injects-41-8-million-into-domestic-violence-helpline/qk7aem02r</link><description>Social Services Minister Tanya Plibersek has said the funding will ensure the helpline can continue to meet growing demand without delay.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a73043c2b894110fa9a60eef3c9f5b08</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I stabbed another boy&amp;apos;: 15-year-old&amp;apos;s alleged confession to police after fatal stabbing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/teen-charged-with-murder-after-stabbing-behind-school/lcf89nx7e</link><description>The victim, a boy aged 17, died from stab wounds to his thigh after a confrontation at a park in Sydney&amp;apos;s north-west about 4.20pm on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5de4430c1689427cae9775ecd8071305</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I stabbed another boy&amp;apos;: 15-year-old&amp;apos;s alleged confession to police after fatal stabbing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/teen-charged-with-murder-after-stabbing-near-school/lcf89nx7e</link><description>The victim, a boy aged 17, died from stab wounds to his thigh after a confrontation at a park in Sydney&amp;apos;s north-west about 4.20pm on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbc3d429ff4707cebbf6e11d7fbb8634</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Adult’ pressures hit hard as UNICEF warns teens are losing hope</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/adult-pressures-hit-hard-as-unicef-warns-teens-are-losing-hope/jeoepobxn</link><description>A new report from UNICEF Australia has found less than a third of Australian teens are feeling excited or hopeful about their futures. Mental health issues and anxiety around &amp;apos;adult&amp;apos; challenges like housing and money are key drivers of declining wellbeing. For marginalised children and teens, these kind of pressures are felt even more acutely.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adc5369beed4a5f124d249c825c8fe58</guid></item><item><title>Sudan&amp;apos;s RSF paramilitary declares truce after army dismisses US proposal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sudans-rsf-paramilitary-declares-truce-after-army-dismisses-us-proposal/nn5k5slav</link><description>The war in Sudan, which broke out in April 2023, has killed tens of thousands of civilians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a1b9de37f157d262aeeb39df061175e</guid></item><item><title>Hanson&amp;apos;s parting election threat, as she&amp;apos;s censured and suspended for seven days</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fresh-fears-after-hansons-burqa-stunt/a05xlk3gb</link><description>Foreign Minister Penny Wong raised the motion on Tuesday after Hanson wore a burqa into the Senate a day earlier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbca81d1dd83c92c6c6d97decc3d4940</guid></item><item><title>More details emerge about Nauru deportation deal | Midday News Bulletin 25 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/more-details-emerge-about-nauru-deportation-deal-midday-news-bulletin-25-november-2025/j8txdn0pk</link><description>Nauru says it may seek to return people Australia deported to their country to their home countries, A historic deal for food delivery workers in Australia welcomed, Manchester City manager apologises after cameraman confrontation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ffc68cfd477ee08a65315cce1c0a0685</guid></item><item><title>Confirmed: A deadly bird flu strain has reached an Australian territory</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/deadly-h5-bird-flu-confirmed-on-heard-island/im66dxzyw</link><description>Detection underscores the need to prepare for a possible outbreak on the mainland, the government says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">298a118c2a6627848588532a7408a433</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 25 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-25-november-2025/qrx1ygl9t</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a706f5e923af8f05108eed08d5d645fc</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Immediate pause&amp;apos; urged on &amp;apos;secret&amp;apos; Nauru deal, after speech sparks safety concerns</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/calls-for-immediate-pause-of-secret-nauru-deal-after-speech-sparks-safety-concerns/b0w76susd</link><description>A translation of remarks by the president of Nauru has sparked safety concerns for people being deported to the Pacific nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cf180e56879b112da108c0541dcab621</guid></item><item><title>US judge dismisses Comey and James cases, rules Halligan appointment unlawful</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-judge-dismisses-comey-and-james-cases-rules-halligan-appointment-unlawful/6hrejhdne</link><description>A judge in the United States has dismissed two high-profile criminal charges brought by the Trump administration against the president&amp;apos;s perceived enemies. The judge says the administration violated the Constitution in its appointment of Lindsay Halligan to prosecute the pair, rendering the charges she brought unlawful.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d74cce2abe0feaf5b9a90d3fba99888c</guid></item><item><title>Pauline Hanson suspended from the Senate for seven days | Evening News Bulletin 25 November 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pauline-hanson-suspended-from-the-senate-for-seven-days-evening-news-bulletin-25-november-2025/24sshqiyu</link><description>Pauline Hanson suspended from the Senate for seven days, Afghanistan&amp;apos;s Taliban says Pakistan&amp;apos;s strikes kill at least ten, Nick Kyrgios to play at Kooyong Classic as he steps up bid for Australian Open wildcard.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e20076d4e2ae9ed274d4958637ba8e7e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I felt powerless&amp;apos;: calls to improve legal literacy for victim-survivors of sexual violence</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/i-felt-powerless-calls-to-improve-legal-literacy-for-victim-survivors-of-sexual-violence/qxrrho3mm</link><description>One in five women and one in 16 men have experienced sexual violence as adults in Australia, according to the 2023 Australian Bureau of Statistics - and yet 92% of women don&amp;apos;t report their most recent sexual assault. A new report is calling for legal literacy among victim-survivors, frontline services and legal professionals, to help victims navigate a complex criminal justice system and address high attrition rates in sexual assault cases.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d83da4f593a5f586a74b485371c30aff</guid></item><item><title>Fair Work shake-up: gig workers secure pay rise and protection</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/fair-work-shake-up-gig-workers-secure-pay-rise-and-protection/rnprlmqjx</link><description>In a landmark agreement hailed as world-leading, the Transport Workers Union, Uber, and DoorDash have put forward a minimum standards deal for Australian gig workers to the Fair Work Commission today. This major reform guarantees food delivery riders a 25% wage increase, injury insurance, and protection from unfair algorithmic dismissal, fundamentally changing a commission-based system that workers say left them making virtually no money.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">def87b8d62584786ed39a1c8a39013c3</guid></item><item><title>Bondi stabbings: Psychiatrist downplayed killer&amp;apos;s mental illness, inquest told</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bondi-junction-stabbings-psychiatrist-disingenuous-played-down-killers-mental-illness-inquest-told/haocrug6x</link><description>The inquest is investigating whether Joel Cauchi&amp;apos;s mental health was properly managed and if chances to detect his deterioration were missed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e5f8594aab9b35e8ca3e037c5632f1b2</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Nothing is fixing it&amp;apos;: The devastating numbers in Australia&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;national crisis&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/why-domestic-violence-still-national-crisis/0bwe1lk0b</link><description>Advocates fear momentum for action against gender-based violence has slowed.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4d1865a8e182decd40d65c604369957c</guid></item><item><title>Revealed: Labor&amp;apos;s nature law concessions in bid to win Greens or Coalition support</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/revealed-labors-nature-law-concessions-in-bid-to-win-greens-or-coalition-support/21t9vkjol</link><description>Labor has offered a handful of concessions to both the Greens and Coalition as it urges the parties to &amp;quot;get it done&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3bfa224419c90f1c72c1f45649e1a60c</guid></item><item><title>Sudan military rejects ceasefire</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sudan-military-rejects-ceasefire/npubmrg4r</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">603774e5beaeacf135e5eae15e019d1f</guid></item><item><title>Parties unable to agree on environment laws</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/parties-unable-to-agree-on-environment-laws/uqg4yy7w8</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e3a7132201863c442d912e102b2b412d</guid></item><item><title>LGBTIQ+ Topics to be included in Census</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/lgbtiq-topics-to-be-included-in-census/uun7ysyhp</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3532a2a1a0e796fda2c51945929609b6</guid></item><item><title>Teachers strike in Queensland</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/teachers-strike-in-queensland/ypmdl2q44</link><description>.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b8fab8e054fd44b8c453ce99f45bd092</guid></item><item><title>Investors brace for Aussie CPI data as US rate cut looks increasingly likely</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/investors-brace-for-aussie-cpi-data-as-us-rate-cut-looks-increasingly-likely/7vf7xkf3c</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Julia Lee from FTSE Russell to find out how investors are feeling ahead of official inflation data out on Wednesday, as traders feel increasingly confident of a US rate cut in December.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">850a8c65712d1e862befa2f7940895f7</guid></item><item><title>Rental squeeze intensifies: Perth now Australia’s least affordable city</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/rental-squeeze-intensifies-perth-now-australias-least-affordable-city/itb0xvotp</link><description>Despite interest rates stabilising, rental stress remains unchanged across Australia. In many capital cities, households are still handing over almost a third of their income just to keep a roof over their heads. And once again, Perth has it the worst. The nation’s least affordable capital has slipped even further — recording another four per cent drop in affordability on top of last year’s record low.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c661ec7192458ad808dbfe1067380b87</guid></item><item><title>What is the Cartel de los Soles and why has the US designated it a terror organisation?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-is-the-cartel-de-los-soles-and-why-has-the-us-designated-it-a-terror-organisation/ehhth8itm</link><description>Venezuela says the organisation does not exist and the designation was a &amp;quot;ridiculous lie&amp;quot; by the US to justify an intervention.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bcaa33a871a10ff981af1492967f24b6</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Value per bite&amp;apos;: The Ozempic-sized force turbocharging an Aussie food shake-up</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-ozempic-sized-force-turbocharging-an-aussie-food-shake-up/i7cvou9f7</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s GLP-1 boom is accelerating trends reshaping Australia&amp;apos;s food landscape, according to a new research.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e01b115914fc70e441a3ed57f03d781f</guid></item><item><title>Samantha paid $30k to change her eye colour. She had to leave Australia to do it</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/samantha-paid-30k-to-change-her-eye-colour-she-had-to-leave-australia-to-do-it/v5hdwf5qv</link><description>Samantha travelled to New York into medical territory that Australian experts won’t touch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">743c9d5384918dcf304b32cece8fe5f2</guid></item></channel></rss>