<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>SBS English News (Unofficial Aggregation)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 08:23:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Premier Minns defends police response to rally against Herzog visit | SBS News In Easy English 10 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/premier-minns-defends-police-response-to-rally-against-herzog-visit-sbs-news-in-easy-english-10-february-2026/2wbakjozd</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c427b94df7646ffd126727af34311448</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Speaks of colonialism&amp;apos;: Why Bad Bunny&amp;apos;s performance resonated around the world</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bad-bunny-performance-symbolism/ohcs33wc9</link><description>Riddled with easter eggs, the show brought Puerto Rican history and culture to one of the biggest platforms on the planet.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d33e9956f6b300d662f0ccf9cb0a3039</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Lopsided&amp;apos; foreign worker scheme under fire as most of the money stays in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lopsided-foreign-worker-scheme-where-most-of-the-money-stays-in-australia-under-fire/9q6geobwm</link><description>The PALM labour scheme is under renewed scrutiny after new analysis warned the program carries modern slavery risks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17bec57c73eed7f29b93f7a215309b0b</guid></item><item><title>Government unveils policy to end violence against First Nations women and children</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/government-unveils-policy-to-end-violence-against-first-nations-women-and-children/ehc1ne8tx</link><description>The Federal Government has launched a landmark $218 million national plan to end violence against First Nations women and children. It marks the first long-term strategy designed and led entirely by Indigenous communities. While the policy targets specialised healing and emergency services in remote areas, community leaders warn that real change also requires confronting the systemic racism and high rates of violence perpetrated by non-Indigenous men.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a337e7cf92c43daa725c347b739bb17c</guid></item><item><title>AI industry risks and the Australian dollar nears US$0.71</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ai-industry-risks-and-the-australian-dollar-nears-us-0-71/e0v4hjw1g</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Todd Hoare from LGT Wealth Management about the day&amp;apos;s market moves including the increasing risks AI poses to certain industries, what&amp;apos;s driving the Australian dollar, and the opportunities for investors.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fcfb280b8a7410191b5c512619b6629a</guid></item><item><title>What we know about Israel&amp;apos;s damage to Gaza cemetery housing Australian war graves</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-war-graves-destroyed-israel-gaza/rmimxni60</link><description>The graves include those of Australian Light Horse troops, a World War One force known for their role in the Battle of Beersheba.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1f855981e68ab0d9caecb14bcadee69</guid></item><item><title>Could Keir Starmer become the first world leader to lose his job over the Epstein files?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/could-keir-starmer-lose-his-job-over-the-epstein-files/wn6nt2vuo</link><description>The UK prime minister is under pressure over hiring Jeffrey Epstein associate Peter Mandelson as the UK&amp;apos;s ambassador to the US.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7802a883425ab5f76b4fb5616d6d9328</guid></item><item><title>Israeli minister urges protesters not to &amp;apos;import conflict&amp;apos;, defending Herzog visit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-minister-urges-protesters-not-to-import-conflict-defending-herzog-visit/br7wgmmsh</link><description>Israel&amp;apos;s deputy foreign minister has spoken out against the &amp;quot;absolutely heartbreaking&amp;quot; violence during protests.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">481eecaea0eaaff536eaffc476f1174e</guid></item><item><title>US Congress criticises ICE enforcement as &amp;apos;reckless and creating chaos&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-congress-criticises-ice-enforcement-as-reckless-and-creating-chaos/n2e1srdag</link><description>A contentious hearing of the US House Committee on Homeland Security has exposed deep divisions over immigration enforcement following the death of two American citizens at the hands of Immigration and Customs Enforcrment, better known as ICE. While ICE officials framed the deaths as a result of officers facing increasing threats of harm, the argument was rejected with those holding the agency accountable, calling its tactics Gestapo-like.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bd108b2fcc1be75f6a31a8c58e67b79e</guid></item><item><title>PM thanks Israeli president for providing &amp;apos;comfort&amp;apos;; Herzog describes &amp;apos;emotional&amp;apos; visit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-thanks-herzog-for-providing-comfort-during-emotional-visit/zy5r6eei0</link><description>Anthony Albanese has praised the Israeli president and first lady for providing comfort to Jewish Australians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">47951a8c67905d972255474f475a96dc</guid></item><item><title>Call for transparent investigation into police actions at Sydney rally | SBS News In Easy English 11 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/call-for-transparent-investigation-into-police-actions-at-sydney-rally-sbs-news-in-easy-english-11-february-2026/njfvkswi7</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1a2da90cc1014340d0c4a24622d9935c</guid></item><item><title>Muslim worshippers say NSW police &amp;apos;came in like a wrecking ball&amp;apos; at Sydney protest</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/muslim-worshippers-say-nsw-police-came-in-like-a-wrecking-ball-at-sydney-protest/oqfxv0wte</link><description>Muslim worshippers who were praying at a Sydney protest say police intervened during a vulnerable moment of prayer.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd1091ceba6ed356a5da3580c922dd5a</guid></item><item><title>Review launched into the plan for Australia&amp;apos;s largest river ecosystem</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/review-launched-into-the-plan-for-australias-largest-river-ecosystem/vjp4kwsra</link><description>Public consultation has opened on a review into the management plan for the Murray–Darling Basin, Australia&amp;apos;s largest river system. The announcement has come weeks after Environment Minister Murray Watt listed the lower Murray River region as critically endangered. Conservation groups have reacted cautiously, saying they hope the review leads to decisive action for a Basin that underpins public health, regional livelihoods, and cultural connection for millions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">73a39ed49e1eab014fe6a7416b4cb2d0</guid></item><item><title>ASIO and AFP face Senate questions about the Bondi terror attack</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asio-and-afp-face-senate-questions-about-the-bondi-terror-attack/qxc80pxqw</link><description>The Australian Security Intelligence Organisation and Australian Federal Police have been questioned about their actions before and after the Bondi terror attack, with Australia&amp;apos;s top spy agency defending its failure to prevent it. During a senate estimates hearing late on Tuesday night, the AFP also warned it will take a more aggressive approach to tackling hate and extremism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f891c0eb9dc9fc7365d5ea2803c9f082</guid></item><item><title>Israel&amp;apos;s President Herzog given official welcome in Canberra</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israels-president-herzog-given-official-welcome-in-canberra/5z8guuc6f</link><description>Israeli President Isaac Herzog has enjoyed a ceremonial welcome and a lunch with Prime Minister Anthony Albanese in Canberra. President Herzog and his wife, Michal, were given a ceremonial 21-gun salute by the Federation Guard before attending a garden function at the Israeli embassy. His visit has been dogged by protests, with demonstrators saying he should not have been invited in the first place,</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8486bb78f042e1cd2ca25590ef07797</guid></item><item><title>Trump allegedly said Ghislaine Maxwell is &amp;apos;evil&amp;apos;: What do we know about their relationship?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-called-maxwell-evil-in-resurfaced-interview-as-she-refuses-to-answer-questions-from-us-congress/rhjmukkc0</link><description>Ghislaine Maxwell&amp;apos;s attorney says she&amp;apos;s prepared to speak publicly if granted clemency by the US president.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14c06cf670fff5242b674cc87b1badbe</guid></item><item><title>CBA&amp;apos;s Matt Comyn on why the disruptive potential of AI should not be underestimated</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/cbas-matt-comyn-on-why-the-disruptive-potential-of-ai-should-not-be-underestimated/uijydybwb</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Commonwealth Bank CEO Matt Comyn following the groups $5.45bn half- year cash profit announcement, including a deep dive into artificial technology and productivity; plus Luke Laretive from Seneca Financial Solutions takes a look at the day&amp;apos;s market action.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acd93d068da2a996a59df085ba0f38ff</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Completely over the top&amp;apos;: How tensions built towards NSW police tactics at Sydney protest</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/protest-footage-raises-excessive-force-militarisation-questions-of-nsw-police/ib31jv0tv</link><description>Experts have pointed to new laws and increased police militarisation as factors leading to clashes in Sydney on Monday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f5b81920bd4c359307f3e84e7c06dd72</guid></item><item><title>US Attorney General under pressure over handling of Epstein files</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-attorney-general-under-pressure-over-handling-of-epstein-files/xgr1yl81r</link><description>The US Attorney-General has faced an onslaught of questions into the Department of Justice&amp;apos;s handling of the more than 3 million files released related to late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein. Survivors and critics are demanding transparency and justice for the more than one thousand victims identified, as Pam Bondi faced a Senate congressional hearing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91fcb4171efba3be6a85dda7e4b7c7a7</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor says he plans to challenge Sussan Ley for Liberal leadership | SBS News In Easy English 12 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/angus-taylor-says-he-plans-to-challenge-sussan-ley-for-liberal-leadership-sbs-news-in-easy-english-12-february-2026/6nlz1p8sc</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa78612651e78f73fb524c0908db8ccb</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Smartest policy brain&amp;apos; or controversial deal-maker: Who is the real Angus Taylor?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/who-is-angus-taylor-the-man-taking-on-sussan-ley-ahead-of-liberal-leadership-showdown/pqndd5kxm</link><description>From water dealings to questionable economic credentials — who is the new Liberal Party leader?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e2d2ac43407a6aeda53b0bf0f2d0cad</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor launches leadership bid</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/angus-taylor-launches-leadership-bid/iby8avx5a</link><description>Former Shadow Minister for Defence Angus Taylor has triggered a formal leadership challenge against Sussan Ley, prompting a wave of coordinated frontbench resignations. The coalition is reeling from historic polling lows. While Mr Taylor campaigns for a &amp;quot;decisive&amp;quot; reset of the party’s values, a loyal faction of Liberals is fighting to protect Ms Ley’s position, arguing she deserves more time to stabilise the party room before Friday’s high-stakes ballot.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6663f889a7b951b5853df975838f58b8</guid></item><item><title>Latest report on Closing the Gap targets not a story of &amp;apos;failure&amp;apos;, says PM</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/latest-report-on-closing-the-gap-targets-not-a-story-of-failure-says-pm/jfrqxb8d9</link><description>The federal government has released its latest report card on its Closing the Gap targets, which are meant to improve the lives of Indigenous Australians. The data shows just four of the 19 targets are on track. Anthony Albanese has used his annual closing the gap speech on Thursday to announce a $144 million boost to Indigenous health to upgrade more than 100 services in cities and regional areas. But some - like the incarceration rates of First Nations people - continue to worsen.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb69c377e3fd9af092593e6527c39643</guid></item><item><title>AMP CEO Alexis George on results, super changes and female leadership</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/amp-ceo-alexis-george-on-results-super-changes-and-female-leadership/1shzygtje</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with AMP CEO Alexis George following the financial services company&amp;apos;s full-year results as she prepares to step down, including her advice to aspiring female leaders; plus Stephanie Youssef discusses the day&amp;apos;s market action with market analyst Evan Lucas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">393aa8543e743b5fc2cbfe992d0d404c</guid></item><item><title>Jimmy Lai’s ‘death’ sentence, Japan’s Takaichi takes on China &amp;amp; the bulging Olympic controversy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/jimmy-lais-death-sentence-japans-takaichi-takes-on-china-the-bulging-olympic-controversy/ceaay1r0d</link><description>A massive win for Japan’s hawkish first female PM worries China, conservatives reclaim Thailand and Jimmy Lai, Hong Kong’s most high-profile casualty of draconian security laws gets a ‘death sentence’. Plus, trouble growing at the winter Olympics.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1cfcdaa439d7c09f39d3553ae35be0cf</guid></item><item><title>The results of recent Liberal spills show a clear trend. What does it mean for Angus Taylor?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-results-of-recent-liberal-spills-show-a-clear-trend-what-does-it-mean-for-angus-taylor/opcjunzhe</link><description>Sussan Ley is fighting to defy the odds when it comes to leadership challenges in her party.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e61f8955a6619005782d2d3f629d222</guid></item><item><title>Israeli president wraps up visit feeling &amp;apos;hope in the air&amp;apos; — and with a message to protesters</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-president-wraps-up-visit-with-hope-and-message-to-protesters/xmzgcecv2</link><description>Isaac Herzog&amp;apos;s trip has sparked controversy and national protests, including a Sydney rally that descended into violence on Monday.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df0e2da92f5efdfa7f65dcc584d66467</guid></item><item><title>Pat is living in a &amp;apos;dangerous&amp;apos; and run-down home. They&amp;apos;ve been hit with a rent increase</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/pat-is-living-in-a-dangerous-and-run-down-home-then-their-rent-went-up/etu3vn4b8</link><description>Across Australia, rents are climbing far faster than wages and many can&amp;apos;t keep up.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e542281b234a532d16472815ae553bc0</guid></item><item><title>Immigration crackdown in Minnesota to end, US border chief announces</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/immigration-crackdown-in-minnesota-to-conclude-trumps-border-chief-says/d9yfzizwu</link><description>Border tsar Tom Homan said Donald Trump had agreed to end the operation, which saw 3,000 armed immigration agents deployed to the state.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a582dad7d892bf79c5e8c9f2525647a3</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor has outlined his priorities after ousting Sussan Ley as Liberal leader</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/angus-taylor-ousts-sussan-ley-as-liberal-party-leader/kg601fr3i</link><description>A new Liberal Party duo has emerged, with Angus Taylor becoming its 17th leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9b458b8df596d0335fba7a7117ff3119</guid></item><item><title>ICE&amp;apos;s controversial surge force to quit Minnesota</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ices-controversial-surge-force-to-quit-minnesota/kdmfi1l2y</link><description>The United States&amp;apos; border chief has announced ICE agents will withdraw from Minnesota. This ends a two-month surge operation which resulted in two US citizens being killed by federal agents, and thousands of arrests. It follows mass protests in the state and across the country, as well as condemnation by Democratic Senators over the violent immigration crackdown.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5e2f0e8f4b3a5d9f89b20116336940d5</guid></item><item><title>NSW police to be investigated over protest, as witness shares new account of &amp;apos;dark moment&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/police-watchdog-to-investigate-officers-conduct-a-anti-herzog-rally-in-sydney/pclf5ii03</link><description>The Law Enforcement Conduct Commission said it had received a &amp;quot;significant number of complaints&amp;quot; about police conduct at Monday&amp;apos;s rally.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b673b19ca4e37356dc172928c5c753f0</guid></item><item><title>Angus Taylor elected new Liberal Party leader | SBS News In Easy English 13 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/angus-taylor-elected-new-liberal-party-leader-sbs-news-in-easy-english-13-february-2026/aajopb466</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99cb7c464f39b31ac65e0a2d5041b57c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;quot;There&amp;apos;s not a lot left to burn&amp;quot;: Coalition launches new bid for unity and support under Angus Taylor</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/theres-not-a-lot-left-to-burn-coalition-launches-new-bid-for-unity-and-support-under-angus-taylor/7fiv18n4l</link><description>Angus Taylor has seized the Liberal Party leadership in a decisive party room vote - 34 to 17 - ending Sussan Ley’s nine-month tenure as the party’s first female leader. Backed by new deputy Jane Hume, the Rhodes scholar and former Shadow Treasurer now faces the challenge of rebuilding a fractured base while navigating a political history marked by significant past controversies.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d65e7bf19d62ca8bf8f0a60cbcf32771</guid></item><item><title>Lunar New Year 2026: What to know about the &amp;apos;very special&amp;apos; Year of the Fire Horse</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lunar-new-year-2026-fire-horse-what-to-know/mj0anue2q</link><description>The fire horse, which occurs once every 60 years, is considered to be like &amp;quot;double fire&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">19ecbf28a347a5a6b7cb272d013e45e7</guid></item><item><title>ANZ says AUD heading for US $0.73 as Cochlear warns of currency impacts</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/anz-says-aud-heading-for-us-0-73-as-cochlear-warns-of-currency-impacts/wsgwt9wkq</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Cochlear CEO Dig Howett about the hearing implant maker&amp;apos;s latest results, the link between hearing loss and dementia and the impact the higher Australian dollar will have on its earnings. Plus Mahjabeen Zaman from ANZ looks at the drivers of the surging currency and market implications.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">42f8e2c561a9ae5cf39a98c24d17d495</guid></item><item><title>SBS NITV Radio talks to Charles Pakana about World Radio Day</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-nitv-radio-talks-to-charles-pakana-about-world-radio-day/cqpfy3ovn</link><description>13 February is celebrated as World Radio Day. The day is designed to honour radio as a trusted and powerful form of communication. Today is also the 18th anniversary of the National Apology to the Stolen Generations. SBS NITV Radio&amp;apos;s Kerri-Lee Barry has spoken to Charles Pakana from Victorian Aboriginal News, who says radio is a way to connect with each other as we share our histories and truth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b1abea6e18155d6164f28bfd37caa3f</guid></item><item><title>Australians&amp;apos; personal data could soon be accessible by US agencies. Here&amp;apos;s why</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trumps-america-wants-access-to-australian-biometric-data/ftomgcy5j</link><description>Speculation over a proposal to hand Australians&amp;apos; biometric data to the US is raising concerns among privacy experts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">987aeea1bfcfee4bb17c2ec2db139020</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Not a Ley problem&amp;apos;: The long-standing Liberal issues that may haunt Angus Taylor</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ley-not-the-problem-former-leaders-issues-may-haunt-taylor/yvh6dcl7c</link><description>Among several issues that plagued Sussan Ley, one broke &amp;quot;the camel&amp;apos;s back&amp;quot;, turning voters to One Nation, a polling expert says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3167745dcad5eb3e67851712ae3e3a76</guid></item><item><title>The Lunar New Year DIY dumpling event putting a new spin on a centuries-old tradition</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-lunar-new-year-diy-dumpling-event-putting-a-new-spin-on-a-centuries-old-tradition/9v84r6nfv</link><description>Dumplings are popular dish for families celebrating Lunar New Year. In Melbourne, one restaurant is challenging tradition, with a make-your-own approach and a range of exotic flavours.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eedc6ad00fdae68b5bc59e344ab07f51</guid></item><item><title>Bondi attack stories and memories to be preserved in new digital project</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/remembering-bondi-project-sydney-jewish-museum/6ca0trpar</link><description>The Sydney Jewish Museum has asked people to share memories through an online tool, and hoped the project would &amp;quot;amplify healing&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">309ce5a1ce58ace56ac8362bde45b98c</guid></item><item><title>Gary wasn&amp;apos;t impressed by Australia&amp;apos;s dumpling scene. Now he&amp;apos;s selling thousands a day</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/gary-wasnt-impressed-by-australias-dumpling-scene-now-hes-selling-thousands-a-day/6cqp6gbvw</link><description>Dumplings are a popular dish for Lunar New Year celebrations. However, one Australian restaurant is bringing a twist to the tradition.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb7b517bfea453ff19d2afdbddc7b828</guid></item><item><title>Mariam&amp;apos;s story of survival amid a &amp;apos;war on women&amp;apos; in Sudan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sudan-gender-based-violence-crisis/pq1retgcu</link><description>Nearly three years into a civil war, Sudan is facing a hunger crisis. It&amp;apos;s also facing a crisis of violence against women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b43f4f5700f9567aeaa6bd8cc8cc4164</guid></item><item><title>Bangladesh&amp;apos;s Tarique Rahman poised to be PM as Islamists concede in &amp;apos;credible&amp;apos; elections</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/bangladeshs-tarique-rahman-poised-to-be-pm/62nelflyq</link><description>Nearly 60 per cent turned up to vote in what the Bangladesh Electoral Commission called &amp;quot;by far, the best election&amp;quot; in the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1355e2db4d03cd52aa94978e154eff5d</guid></item><item><title>With their first female leader gone, can the Liberals shake their &amp;apos;women problem&amp;apos;?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/liberals-women-problem-after-sussan-ley-dumped-as-first-female-leader/bamdvwqf3</link><description>Senior Liberals say Sussan Ley&amp;apos;s removal was about polling, not gender. But experts warn it may reinforce doubts about the party&amp;apos;s appeal to women.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d355396c4df18a1ae16f181a7a00f27c</guid></item><item><title>How a hairdressing client list became a campaign to help Jay and Jeremy become dads</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/how-a-hair-stylists-client-list-became-a-campaign-to-change-surrogacy-laws/68mzq9pv6</link><description>Jay always wanted to be a dad, but WA&amp;apos;s surrogacy laws meant significant barriers. So he became the face of a campaign to change them.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53732ac447f6e05155105724ced5769a</guid></item><item><title>Mariam&amp;apos;s story of survival amid a &amp;apos;war on women&amp;apos; in Sudan</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/mariams-story-of-survival-amid-a-war-on-women-in-sudan/559hvyz8u</link><description>Women and girls are bearing the brunt of Sudan’s nearly three-year-old civil war, facing widespread gender-based violence, displacement and deepening hunger as the conflict intensifies. 18-year-old Mariam, a survivor of sexual violence has had to flee escalating violence to an under-resourced displacement camp where food and medicine is in limited supply. With famine spreading and humanitarian access shrinking, organisations like Plan International warn the needs of survivors far exceed the support available.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ccb165ec3003c083b17779b613cc8301</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: What needs to happen to bring the Murray Darling Basin back to health?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-what-needs-to-happen-to-bring-the-murray-darling-basin-back-to-health/flm7l3sho</link><description>The Murray Darling Basin management plan is currently under review. Public submissions on a discussion paper [[see it here: https://www.mdba.gov.au/publications-and-data/publications/2026-basin-plan-review-discussion-paper]] are being accepted until 1 May 2026, as authorities determine their next steps in managing Australia&amp;apos;s biggest river ecosystem. SBS has spoken with the national director of the Murray Darling Conservation Alliance, Craig Wilkins, about what those next steps should be.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">107ced71972b7468aa2d561b3496af10</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Unprecedented times&amp;apos;: Jakara Anthony&amp;apos;s Winter Olympic gold secures record medal haul for Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jakara-anthony-winter-olympics-gold-medal/dbfe6nwgy</link><description>The 27-year-old skier has become Australia&amp;apos;s first ever two-time Winter Olympic gold medallist.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e192cf53d0b05c84d9e8b1713d704f8</guid></item><item><title>Which states get an Anzac Day public holiday this year?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anzac-day-public-holiday-which-states/0nax12a1k</link><description>With Anzac Day falling on a weekend this year, an extra public holiday has been announced for the people of NSW.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">936e15ece260f9f695fc5dad08385b7d</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Standards too low, numbers too high&amp;apos;: Refreshed Liberal Party poised for immigration cuts</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/angus-taylor-anti-immigration-stance/t40pzjmu2</link><description>Angus Taylor called to &amp;quot;shut the door on people who reject our way of life, who don&amp;apos;t believe in our core values&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b46f3e0cce6920d8716dbdc0eb70b962</guid></item><item><title>Weet-bix kimchi: Glynn&amp;apos;s experiment with Australian and Korean favourites may be a hit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/weet-bix-fermented-australian-kimchi-from-regional-tasmania/a2mc6iuwy</link><description>Through Weet-Bix kimchi, Sue Glynn is connecting Australia and Korea in regional Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7ec4b8c1f091ad0d6e73233d81175b3d</guid></item><item><title>A major trade deal with the EU may be closer than ever. Here&amp;apos;s how Australians stand to benefit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-eu-trade-deal/9yiyz75cl</link><description>Australians could see more competitive prices for European products under a deal that could give the economy a billion-dollar boost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">896259c36d2e465690b7f0a7a9b5da61</guid></item><item><title>Darren&amp;apos;s hunted zebras and bears overseas. Now a &amp;apos;trophy&amp;apos; ban is in Australia&amp;apos;s sights</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/killing-or-conservation-inside-australias-trophy-hunting-fight/gwb6i8s0o</link><description>Supporters say trophy hunting is misunderstood. But critics call it cruelty dressed up as conservation.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28ca3e1d648592f5b5689d3046457eb0</guid></item><item><title>What fasting for Ramadan is like for a sailor, a midwife and a miner</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-ramadan-fasting-is-like-in-australian-workplaces/afrnkk8oh</link><description>Australians in high-stakes workplaces — from ships to hospitals to mine sites — reveal the realities of observing Ramadan while on the job.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c1bbaf3d65d4ea06f7ee15a701863a9</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Not fair dinkum&amp;apos;: ACCC rejects Coles&amp;apos; arguments in landmark &amp;apos;illusory&amp;apos; discounts legal case</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/accc-coles-misleading-discounts-allegations-federal-court-case/92p7elywx</link><description>The consumer watchdog&amp;apos;s barrister said increased costs are irrelevant to whether products are promoted to customers as genuine discounts.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">90cb79de359ce0e690dcb4531d1e24e4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Iran is my home as well&amp;apos;: Worldwide turnout of hundreds of thousands in solidarity with Iranian protesters</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/iran-is-my-home-as-well-worldwide-turnout-of-hundreds-of-thousands-in-solidarity-with-iranian-protesters/4wlnbwj7e</link><description>From Munich to Melbourne, hundreds of thousands have turned out to oppose Iran&amp;apos;s clerical leadership in the wake of a brutal crackdown on protesters inside the country. While opinions differ over who should take over the current regime, protesters all voiced their desire for an Iran free from oppression.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">acab2944d9da356f03fbe9dad0de4b16</guid></item><item><title>Court appearance for alleged Bondi shooter | SBS News In Easy English 16 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/court-appearance-for-alleged-bondi-shooter-sbs-news-in-easy-english-16-february-2026/b9qdml1j4</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55d542eef3447d36c32b21b79b6eb568</guid></item><item><title>Opposition was preparing widespread immigration bans under Sussan Ley&amp;apos;s leadership</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/opposition-was-preparing-widespread-immigration-bans-before-liberal-leadership-spill/z89xa831g</link><description>The Opposition&amp;apos;s immigration spokesperson under Ley has said he never proposed nor agreed to the policy.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">75fc8909326c7874899db49ff85e3b52</guid></item><item><title>Accused Bondi Beach gunman Naveed Akram fronts court for first time</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/naveed-akram-court-appearance/pz16q120p</link><description>Naveed Akram appeared in Sydney&amp;apos;s Downing Centre Local Court via videolink on 59 charges, including murder and terrorism offences.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0a6c45cd3c0eefc698aefe8dcffb2d50</guid></item><item><title>Palestinians look to salvage Gaza&amp;apos;s history from the ruins of war</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/palestinians-look-to-salvage-gazas-history-from-the-ruins-of-war/fsx3yp0sc</link><description>.The Gaza Strip is home to some extraordinary remnants of human history, dating from the Bronze Age through to the Ottoman and British empires.Many historic sites suffered from neglect before the war - but the United Nations cultural agency, UNESCO, says it has verified damage to at least 150 historic heritage sites since the start of the Israel-Hamas conflict. Palestinians in the Gaza Strip are reckoning with how to save their historical monuments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">60ffd6545c3d500ffc25cd320e0fadbe</guid></item><item><title>Tech stocks recover and IMF warns Australian states on spending</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/tech-stocks-recover-and-imf-warns-australian-states-on-spending/0s02gxzdv</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Alex Pikoulas from Munjarra Capital about the day&amp;apos;s market action including the latest profit results and the turn around in the tech sector; plus Anthony Walker from SP Global Ratings after the IMF warned Australian states to reign in spending.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">43b0fbadbee53b48850dfbcc9b34ad5a</guid></item><item><title>ACCC alleges Coles claimed to cut prices - but didn&amp;apos;t</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/accc-alleges-coles-claimed-to-cut-prices-but-didnt/l8005aeup</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s competition watchdog is suing supermarket chain Coles in the Federal Court. The ACCC alleges Coles deceived shoppers about discounts on a range of goods. It&amp;apos;s a case that could have wide-ranging implications for consumer law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f04aab88d64e1fb41869591235d5c403</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I want to taste everything&amp;apos;: Why millions of people make this annual pilgrimage</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lunar-new-year-2026-asian-australian-pilgrimage-to-asia/zvkose308</link><description>As many Asians living in Australia return to their ancestral homes for Lunar New Year, what awaits them can be surprising.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f3ee4356f8a27e52978c2ac52cefcc3e</guid></item><item><title>Kath hosted her late partner Nigel&amp;apos;s wake while he was still alive</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/living-funerals-living-wakes-australia/9pst1yh9d</link><description>Living funerals are an emerging practice in Australia, allowing people to say goodbye to loved ones before they die.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fecd296f29f559aafdc724b93616899a</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Very rare&amp;apos;: Israeli prosecutors to charge West Bank settler over killing of Palestinian activist</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/israeli-prosecutors-west-bank-settler-palestinian-activist-killing/gjsv4v806</link><description>The decision is an uncommon legal step amid mounting criticism over accountability for violence in the occupied territories.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c918705833496bb27912438ce6db9d46</guid></item><item><title>Who are the Australians with alleged IS links seeking to return from a Syrian camp?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/who-are-the-australians-with-is-links-seeking-to-return-from-a-syrian-displacement-camp/kteqt8i8c</link><description>The government says it won&amp;apos;t help repatriate a group of Australian women and children with links to the self-proclaimed Islamic State group.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d56243d1db928e888eafea40e2204ee1</guid></item><item><title>The Year of the Horse welcomed around the world</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-year-of-the-horse-welcomed-around-the-world/3lq7ejito</link><description>The Lunar New Year has begun with vibrant celebrations welcoming the Year of the Horse, from fireworks in Vietnam and bustling Hong Kong markets to festive streets in Malaysia and Peru. Families gather for symbolic meals, travellers embrace cultural traditions, and global leaders send messages of unity, marking a holiday that connects communities across Asia and around the world.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ba4953eddbb2b1db8473ffe2f3cc2b2</guid></item><item><title>How the tale of one possum reveals threats to thousands of Aussie species</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/how-the-tale-of-one-possum-reveals-threats-to-thousands-of-aussie-species/udv2e0mic</link><description>Australia’s unique wildlife is facing an escalating extinction crisis, driven primarily by climate change and compounded by habitat loss. 34 new species of plants and animals have been added to the government&amp;apos;s threatened species list this February, including the lemuroid ringtail possum - native to north Queensland&amp;apos;s Wet Tropics region. Researchers say urgent climate action and stronger environmental protections are critical to prevent further irreversible loss of Australia&amp;apos;s signature biodiversity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">722b1ba0b95aff16d1dbd79f09844c98</guid></item><item><title>Landmark study finds &amp;apos;systemic&amp;apos; racism in Australian universities</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-human-rights-commission-report-finds-racism-in-australian-universities/htf3u3rbi</link><description>The survey of more than 76,000 students and staff found Jewish and Palestinian students experienced the highest level of discrimination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5be2df23403b6745f15959e3e8b10fdf</guid></item><item><title>PM rules out repatriation for Australians with alleged IS links in Syria | SBS News In Easy English 17 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pm-rules-out-repatriation-for-australians-with-alleged-is-links-in-syria-sbs-news-in-easy-english-17-february-2026/bmscm041v</link><description>A daily 5-minute news bulletin for English learners and people with a disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">da9a73967005936c2a608aaffb513308</guid></item><item><title>Do migrants feel they belong in Australia? The answer is complicated</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/do-new-migrants-feel-they-belong-to-australia-the-answer-is-complicated-study-shows/x8hre58vx</link><description>Interviews with migrants from Australia&amp;apos;s fastest growing communities show only 32 per cent feel a great sense of belonging.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2a0880652b41e2492d333b9fd92a951b</guid></item><item><title>BHP CFO on copper growth opportunties, iron ore future and growing dividends</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/bhp-cfo-on-copper-growth-opportunties-iron-ore-future-and-growing-dividends/02zrgxnfj</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with BHP CFO Vandita Pant following the miner&amp;apos;s US$5.6bn half-year profit to find out more about its growing copper business and future dividend policy; plus Jonathan Shead from State Street Investment Management on the investment environment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2824a48dbba0de5f40c6e4e216eaeaea</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;It was a no-brainer&amp;apos;: The baby boomer retirement myth being upended</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/no-brainer-why-more-young-people-like-zoe-are-rethinking-their-australian-dream/4mdmrz8w2</link><description>You might think it&amp;apos;s boomers and empty nesters moving to these parts of Australia, according to an expert. New data tells a different story.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62fd14a4e7eefeaebde2c93bd0fd52d4</guid></item><item><title>Sabina quit snacking after monitoring her sugar levels. Is the data that simple?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/sabina-quit-snacking-when-she-started-monitoring-her-sugar-levels-but-is-the-data-that-simple/pbtwrxi7s</link><description>Continuous glucose monitors provide live data for blood sugar levels. But is access to this health data a good thing for non-diabetics?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9949b35d971804969c78494c20b22ba6</guid></item><item><title>Government stands firm on not assisting or repatriating IS families in Syria</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/government-stands-firm-on-not-assisting-or-repatriating-is-families-in-syria/wpbepaasa</link><description>The last remaining Australian women and children with links to the IS Group have been sent back to a Syrian camp after attempting to repatriate themselves home. The group of 34 left al-Roj in the country&amp;apos;s northeast overnight - but a communications issue with Damascus forced their return to the camp.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e9e14d59c3df3ef6949b17a1d9b7674</guid></item><item><title>Tilda Swinton, Javier Bardem and others criticise Berlin Film Festival&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;silence&amp;apos; on Gaza</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dozens-condemn-berlin-film-festival-silence-on-gaza/zojo9eirv</link><description>An open letter signed by film industry figures condemned the Berlin Film Festival&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;neutral stance&amp;quot; on Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fc759321283e6cb70c28b7731efe316c</guid></item><item><title>Mayor responds to Hanson&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;unwelcoming&amp;apos; western Sydney suburb claim</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/aftab-malik-pauline-hanson-invitation-itfar-ramadan/rzxy7cjtx</link><description>It comes as Pauline Hanson faces a backlash over anti-Muslim remarks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb1c7ea938aff755aecf9427f05fb04b</guid></item><item><title>&amp;quot;True giant&amp;quot;: Jesse Jackson, influential US civil rights leader, dies at age 84</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/true-giant-jesse-jackson-influential-us-civil-rights-leader-dies-at-age-84/2x7gkk6fo</link><description>Influential civil rights leader Reverend Jesse Jackson has died at the age of 84. Devoting six decades of his life to political and civil rights activism, Jesse Jackson is being remembered for his charisma and conviction till the very end.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">48755665f04d38da188096d9576266e6</guid></item><item><title>Man with shot gun arrested in Capitol Hill | SBS News in Easy English 18 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/man-with-shot-gun-arrested-in-capitol-hill-sbs-news-in-easy-english-18-february-2026/ksyu4ody4</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English Language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f849dc5eb6244900f98042f437307a52</guid></item><item><title>Government bans woman with alleged IS links from returning to Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/government-bans-woman-with-alleged-is-links-from-returning-to-australia/2tt852ezp</link><description>Human rights advocates say the move could render the Australian &amp;quot;stateless&amp;quot;, stressing the government&amp;apos;s duty under international law.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba7219fc6a23c8927aaaa3908ee5b737</guid></item><item><title>No, not even water: A guide to Ramadan for non-Muslims</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/no-not-even-water-a-guide-to-ramadan-for-non-muslims/tnccci4jz</link><description>Wonder what Ramadan is all about? Here&amp;apos;s why many Muslims fast during the holy month, and how to best support your practising friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3ea3cf88301b12b1bfbbbb35758ee3ad</guid></item><item><title>No, not even water: A guide to Ramadan for non-Muslims</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ramadan-guide-for-non-muslims/54526knpd</link><description>Wonder what Ramadan is all about? Here&amp;apos;s why many Muslims fast during the holy month, and how to best support your practising friends.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">008bc76385c6c58b7e095e90dbcc82a6</guid></item><item><title>Muslim leaders&amp;apos; three requests as Australia&amp;apos;s largest mosque receives new threatening letter</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ramadan-islamophobia-concerns-australia-lakemba-mosque/pacrzf7gp</link><description>It comes amid unease and safety concerns in Muslim communities across the country ahead of Ramadan.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">df5d22a74566b2b2d3754aab27911afa</guid></item><item><title>Racism revealed to be widespread and systemic in Australian universities</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/racism-revealed-to-be-widespread-and-systemic-in-australian-universities/fwtgzu973</link><description>The first national report on racism at universities in Australia has found it is a problem that is widespread and systemic. The report found 70 per cent of students and staff from 42 universities had witnessed racism. Levels of racism were higher among Indigenous, Chinese, African, Jewish and Middle Eastern students and staff; with only six per cent of those who experienced racism making a complaint.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">102a45d8a073aa7a6d8fcded2bf39b88</guid></item><item><title>Inflation eats into wages as cost of living worsens</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/inflation-eats-into-wages-as-cost-of-living-worsens/wwh0xx8vk</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Devika Shivadear from RSM Australia about the latest Wage Price Index which shows real wages has gone backwards; plus a look at the day on the sharemarket with Jun Bei Lui from Ten Cap.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8cf63144fa527125134c8d48ec0ae0c</guid></item><item><title>NSW Parliament tackles &amp;apos;a deeply concerning convergence of extremism&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/nsw-parliament-tackles-a-deeply-concerning-convergence-of-extremism/k9dt4gnbt</link><description>Religious leaders and academic experts have faced a New South Wales parliamentary inquiry into a proposed law to combat right wing extremism. This, as the state government introduced the crime amendment bill following a neo-nazi protest outside state Parliament in November last year. The Law and Safety committee have been investigating the risks posed by certain groups, and are looking into the best ways to counter it.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0f0ca9bb330b122ddc1f802598e4493</guid></item><item><title>The road toll is rising; &amp;apos;we need to do more of everything&amp;apos; say the safety experts</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-road-toll-is-rising-we-need-to-do-more-of-everything-say-the-safety-experts/fp7c4egx1</link><description>Australia’s road toll is rising, and new warnings suggest the country is drifting away from its goal of halving deaths by 2030. More than thirteen hundred people were killed on Australian roads last year, with early 2026 figures showing little sign of improvement. Industry leaders and victim advocates are calling for urgent action, from safer street design to changes in driver behaviour, as families continue to live with the consequences of road trauma every day.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">372c1c8217064f68dfe105d667d912e9</guid></item><item><title>What we know so far about the abduction and search for Nancy Guthrie</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nancy-guthrie-disappearance-search-latest/o300vluwt</link><description>From eerie doorbell footage to a DNA setback, here&amp;apos;s how the Nancy Guthrie abduction has unfolded.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd3233f47a7276db6de24d1ac05e6fb5</guid></item><item><title>What makes people proud to be Australian? The answer might surprise you</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-national-pride-pew-report/0nv0le4l0</link><description>These are the factors that influence Australians&amp;apos; sense of pride in their country — and those that don&amp;apos;t, according to a new report.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eed3ed5fe8f7c27b6189a11768778941</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Means everything&amp;apos;: Australian Danielle Scott claims aerial skiing silver at the Olympics</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/aussie-danielle-scott-claims-aerial-skiing-silver-at-the-olympics/gmb3ohoav</link><description>Freestyle skier Danielle Scott is officially an Olympic medallist, breaking through to win silver in the aerials in her fourth Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2117ad285a4427987359e3f96bdfbf2c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Means everything&amp;apos;: Australian Danielle Scott claims aerial skiing silver at the Olympics</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-danielle-scott-claims-aerial-skiing-silver-at-the-olympics/gmb3ohoav</link><description>Freestyle skier Danielle Scott is officially an Olympic medallist, breaking through to win silver in the aerials in her fourth Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edd808832cf6c806fdb57e97bded519e</guid></item><item><title>The super mistake that could cost you more than $120,000 at retirement</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-not-checking-your-super-could-cost-you-over-120-000-at-retirement/pnthrysuz</link><description>One in four Australians couldn&amp;apos;t answer a key question about their super, a new survey found, prompting a warning from a peak body.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c2cbb25ea15d4fc5be17bfee32b7415</guid></item><item><title>Eight skiers found dead after California avalanche, one still missing</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/california-avalanche-skiers-found-dead/q7villp8m</link><description>Rescuers had earlier reached six survivors in &amp;quot;extreme&amp;quot; conditions near Lake Tahoe.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72c5ca3a4fa51756bcac700262330541</guid></item><item><title>How Palestinians in Gaza are marking their first Ramadan since fragile truce took hold</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/first-ramadan-after-israel-truce-gaza/gf29g2o4e</link><description>Amid the devastation, some in Gaza City are working to revive Ramadan festivities as Palestinian Muslims celebrate the holy month.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c4961f773fd6e01153ce818fa021e04</guid></item><item><title>Local dog goes for gold as he gatecrashes Olympic sprint</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dog-winter-olympics/llc8znnnb</link><description>The unexpected competitor, a &amp;quot;stubborn, but very sweet&amp;quot; resident of a nearby bed-and-breakfast, joined skiers down the home stretch.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8d82bece2ee1785100b99c7809eab33</guid></item><item><title>Zuckerberg on the stand: Why this new social media trial could be a turning point</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/mark-zuckerberg-on-the-stand-why-this-new-social-media-trial-can-be-a-turning-point/te9xkchob</link><description>It&amp;apos;s the first time Mark Zuckerberg has addressed child safety on his platforms before a jury.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e2184b06c5ed621e76c003020623d848</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Outrageous decision&amp;apos;: Why are Ukrainian officials boycotting the Paralympics?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ukraine-officials-boycott-russia-competing-in-paralympics/ri4di1uft</link><description>Paralympians from Russia and Belarus have been given the green light to compete — and not as neutral individuals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ba50d0ec60fa8cc4d3315a1ffa2193e3</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Need to do more of everything&amp;apos;: Australia&amp;apos;s 2030 goal that&amp;apos;s at risk</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australias-2030-goal-thats-at-risk/i1kn803tk</link><description>The figures are heading in the wrong direction — but some believe simple changes could make a difference.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7305d7db5413037867e238b7819dc3b2</guid></item><item><title>Eight skiers die California avalanche |SBS News in Easy English 19 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/eight-skiers-die-california-avalanche-sbs-news-in-easy-english-19-february-2026/9hywmdxd9</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">28f9ca11622df7f0d0a45d4b55e7c3bb</guid></item><item><title>Is Australia facing an economic reality not seen since World War Two?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-government-debt-analysis/b7ibrbt13</link><description>As debt climbs, some economists warn Australia may face difficult choices.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">06199b7b66ecd598be892af76a920d60</guid></item><item><title>Latest labour data increases chance of a rate rise, experts warn</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/labour-data-rate-rise-rba/if516z32w</link><description>A historically strong jobs market has raised the chances of another rate rise in 2026.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b2d56251cd2d54094dad9985d944d963</guid></item><item><title>Is the US approach to Europe softening? Israel moves in the West Bank and, well, cocaine sharks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/is-the-us-approach-to-europe-softening-israel-moves-in-the-west-bank-and-well-cocaine-sharks/eedp75dnt</link><description>Marco Rubio sends mixed messages to Europe, Israel starts registration of large areas of the occupied West Bank and how new is Bangladesh’s new government? Plus, Chinoys celebrate lunar new year in the Philippines and Cocaine Sharks coming to waters near you.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">eedbad5d2a38d20b772a580700fdb5a9</guid></item><item><title>Muslim faithful mark the start of Ramadan in Australia and around the world</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/muslim-faithful-mark-the-start-of-ramadan-in-australia-and-around-the-world/9pqy6rkv9</link><description>The holy month of Ramadan is underway, with Muslims around the world marking Iftar - the first day of the fasting period. In Australia, venues are catering to the growing number of observers, opening their doors until long after sunset and into the early hours of the morning.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">99da299f262385d2c6b17980878b9220</guid></item><item><title>Government blocks return of Australian woman from Syrian refugee camp for IS Group families</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/government-blocks-return-of-australian-woman-from-syrian-refugee-camp-for-is-group-families/ajfnnky6u</link><description>Home Affairs Minister Tony Burke has blocked the immediate return of an Australian woman from Syria via a temporary exclusion order. It follows what the government is calling its no assistance policy for 34 citizens recently turned back by Syrian authorities. While the Prime Minister insists those who joined the IS Group must live with their choices, legal and human rights experts argue that abandoning children and coerced women in detention camps poses a greater long-term radicalisation risk than bringing them home to Australia.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b3c7d83f825ac86c4f3bcad4447fa48a</guid></item><item><title>Jobless rate stays at 4.1% and ASX hits another record</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/jobless-rate-stays-at-4-1-and-asx-hits-another-record/novh8uo7s</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Hugh Lam, CFA from Betashares for his take on the markets as the ASX200 hits another record high, the jobless rate remains at 4.1% and takes a look at the latest company profit reports.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d7f72580089b8a17545290d15b3f2f46</guid></item><item><title>They&amp;apos;re &amp;apos;devastated&amp;apos;: Fresh plea for Australian children in Syrian detention camps</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/fresh-plea-for-australian-children-in-syrian-detention-camps/qb9z6g3xw</link><description>Child welfare advocates are calling for the return of Australians from a detention camp in Syria.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6de4d7e72a9be526b4f3ca30a9a13cc1</guid></item><item><title>Calls for major change after deadly mental health escapes in Sydney</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/calls-for-major-change-after-deadly-mental-health-escapes-in-sydney/ta8d6md7r</link><description>A WARNING THAT THIS STORY MAY BE DISTRESSING FOR SOME LISTENERS The New South Wales government is investigating the circumstances surrounding the escape of two patients from the same hospital, who days later were allegedly involved in separate incidents where three people died. Mental health professionals say it&amp;apos;s again thrown the state&amp;apos;s mental health care crisis into the spotlight.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94250522597c5c31ef86bfbb52a828e3</guid></item><item><title>Former prince Andrew released from police custody after arrest</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/prince-andrew-arrest/zo7uja2z5</link><description>King Charles has responded. Here&amp;apos;s what we know so far.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">846210384241532e281af1c8e8146305</guid></item><item><title>See the full list: Private insurer price hikes — and how to save cash</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/private-health-price-hikes-list/4y8b9j6s8</link><description>The 4.41 per cent increase announced this week is an industry average, and some insurers will raise premiums by more.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">36f65163aacd735aac03c65c61161e7e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Canary in the coal mine&amp;apos;: The possum on the frontline of Australia&amp;apos;s extinction crisis</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/possum-threatened-species-australia/mar3m3qe5</link><description>The lemuroid ringtail possum is one of 34 species that have just been added to Australia&amp;apos;s threatened species list.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">419030bdf41553d86ad5248dc27e49c8</guid></item><item><title>Trump&amp;apos;s Board of Peace flags billions in Gaza aid, as he gives Iran 10-day threat</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-launches-board-of-peace-with-gaza-aid-promise/p22ck786f</link><description>The first meeting of Trump&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;Board of Peace&amp;apos; has heard pledges of cash and troops to rebuild Gaza and maintain order there.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6af8be042223fac434557ea3f30bc67</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Hallmarks of genocide&amp;apos; found in Sudan, UN says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sudan-civil-war-genocide-united-nations/9ci878kco</link><description>A UN fact-finding mission concluded that the RSF paramilitary group had acted &amp;quot;with genocidal intent&amp;quot; during the seizure of Al-Fasher.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0e1b4ca051ed27b50ee05ddef3b60928</guid></item><item><title>Monarchists, anti-monarchists and prime minister react to former prince Andrew&amp;apos;s arrest</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/world-reacts-to-former-prince-andrews-arrest/rcgv754de</link><description>Australia and the world have been quick to react to the news of former prince Andrew&amp;apos;s arrest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1b79e65029b44cae2cc97144c5da96a6</guid></item><item><title>How former prince Andrew went from pilot to fallen figure</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/prince-andrew-arrested-after-decades-controversies-epstein/9okjjpkjc</link><description>Former prince Andrew has left the police station after 10 hours of questioning by UK Police for alleged misconduct in public office.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1c7dbdc38ac27aea868883da9adb3335</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 20 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-20-february-2026/7a0chyaxj</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38c904a9171b7a08a6f889f720a2501e</guid></item><item><title>Former Prince Andrew becomes first senior British royal to be arrested in almost 400 years</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/former-prince-andrew-becomes-first-senior-british-royal-to-be-arrested-in-almost-400-years/lqevb0t3d</link><description>Andrew Mountbatten-Windsor has become the first senior British royal in modern times to be arrested. The 66-year-old was arrested by police on suspicion of misconduct in public office, after it was alleged he sent confidential government documents to late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0221416d437bc113041c3827145c424a</guid></item><item><title>Trump&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;Board of Peace&amp;apos; flags billions in Gaza aid, US issues fresh threats against Iran</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trumps-board-of-peace-flags-billions-in-gaza-aid-us-issues-fresh-threats-against-iran/61ija714i</link><description>United States President Donald Trump has held the inaugural meeting of his so-called &amp;quot;Board of Peace&amp;quot;, pledging AU$14.2 billion for the reconstruction of Gaza. Boasting his role as a peacemaker while leveling fresh threats against Iran, Donald Trump says the board will help achieve peace in the Middle East.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f393c32b05fef7a8e3c624c14447a91d</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Extremely interesting&amp;apos;: Trump says he&amp;apos;ll release files on aliens and UFOs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-announces-hell-release-files-on-aliens-and-ufos-after-obama-comments/bmdifsivy</link><description>The decision comes following Barack Obama&amp;apos;s comment that aliens &amp;quot;are real&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9a2ca6b435b0ae7629751f28d9703320</guid></item><item><title>Two mental health facility escapes ended in tragedy. Now, a push for &amp;apos;urgent&amp;apos; change</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/calls-for-major-change-after-deadly-mental-health-escapes-in-sydney/yjzdwp98q</link><description>Two men escaped the nation&amp;apos;s largest mental health facility and were allegedly involved in separate incidents killing three people.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2c95e47a403357456d72ce3a8bcfd89f</guid></item><item><title>Australian Federal Police says reports of crime received over Pauline Hanson&amp;apos;s remarks on Muslims</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/australian-federal-police-says-reports-of-crime-received-over-pauline-hansons-remarks-on-muslims/gu8yllg4m</link><description>The fallout continues after One Nation leader Pauline Hanson suggested earlier this week that there are no &amp;quot;good&amp;quot; Muslims. The Australian Federal Police says it has received reports of a crime in relation to comments made by Ms Hanson.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8af3d4854dd2454e826f3cfc83a7b91c</guid></item><item><title>UN says siege at el-Fasher shows evidence of genocide</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/un-says-siege-at-el-fasher-shows-evidence-of-genocide/dn8pk0jel</link><description>A United Nations fact-finding mission in Sudan has found the 18-month long siege and subsequent capture of El-Fasher in the Darfur region, last October, bears evidence of genocide. The United States, in response, has imposed sanctions on paramilitary commanders. But experts are calling for far stronger global response, to stop the violence from continuing.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">67b44c87ccd5592d6997297d773fd5d8</guid></item><item><title>NT hit-and-run driver avoids jail again after prosecutors appeal &amp;apos;inadequate&amp;apos; sentence</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nt-hit-and-run-driver-avoids-jail-again-after-prosecutors-appeal-inadequate-sentence/mtgb0de4d</link><description>A five-month home detention term for a fatal hit-and-run driver has been overturned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">14d930b8c32078d5df3a78598b3795c2</guid></item><item><title>US goods deficit widens despite tariffs and market reacts to QBE and Rio results</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-goods-deficit-widens-despite-tariffs-and-market-reacts-to-qbe-and-rio-results/hw7rv3gfm</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Marcus Bogdan from Blackmore Capital on the day&amp;apos;s market action, including a wrap of the major profits and a look at the latest US trade figures.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">580e857a3f35ad08877c8838004e7915</guid></item><item><title>Dreams of being a ballerina: Hopes of Australian child in Syrian camp for IS-linked families</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/dreams-of-being-a-ballerina-hopes-of-australian-child-in-syrian-camp-for-is-linked-families/cirb1lqi9</link><description>An Australian child in a camp for families with links to IS fighters says she wants to come to Australia, a family member told SBS.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">39a2a8627a39f3a12dbf41b107665041</guid></item><item><title>Is there a &amp;apos;sweet spot&amp;apos;? These five charts are key to the migration debate</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/migration-sweet-spot-these-five-charts-are-key-to-the-migration-debate/69sydxzau</link><description>The government&amp;apos;s opponents have fuelled debate over Australia&amp;apos;s migration numbers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">497fbfd7c4bac40ce6fd64181e9e7f19</guid></item><item><title>US Supreme Court strikes down Trump tariffs | Morning News Bulletin 21 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-supreme-court-strikes-down-trump-tariffs-morning-news-bulletin-21-february-2026/ya2pxqtrb</link><description>The US Supreme Court strikes down Donald Trump&amp;apos;s global tariffs, Federal Police say they&amp;apos;ve received reports of a crime after Pauline Hanson&amp;apos;s anti-Muslim comments, Clayton Oliver impresses the GWS Giants in his first match with the club.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">adc4e5b8bddfbcf9bdb4ff3ae122539a</guid></item><item><title>Cafes and restaurants are closing in record numbers. This couple is bucking the trend</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/cafes-and-restaurants-are-closing-in-record-numbers-this-couple-is-bucking-the-trend/idmdixlzv</link><description>Australian restaurants and cafes are in crisis, according to a new report. Rising costs and falling revenue have forced one in ten food service outlets to close over the past year. However, one Australian couple has found ways to survive and thrive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a756f557c58c219c62ff4af75d746bf0</guid></item><item><title>It scares me all the time&amp;apos;: Exploring new ways to improve water safety</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/it-scares-me-all-the-time-exploring-new-ways-to-improve-water-safety/tv4tmgse9</link><description>Australian and Indian drowning prevention experts have come together for a two-day workshop to explore new ways to reduce drowning deaths in both countries. Drowning causes tens of thousands of deaths a year in India, and in Australia, experts say the Indian diaspora is among groups that are worryingly over-represented in the country&amp;apos;s drowning fatalities. Through exchanging ideas and building stronger cultural knowledge, workshop participants have explored new, sustainable ways to improve water safety.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f549fe883614f2768571cddb913e4298</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump imposes 10 per cent global levy after US Supreme Court strikes down tariffs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/us-supreme-court-donald-trump-tariffs/7utfupgbg</link><description>The US president has announced a 10 per cent global tariff for 150 days under a different legal authority.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e4e468b955e1aaaa2658dbfc50edc71</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: New project explores power of language and shared histories</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-new-project-explores-power-of-language-and-shared-histories/1049wei0n</link><description>The Acknowledgement of Country has been translated into 40 languages as part of a project led by Dr Elaine Laforteza. She explains how it started and the vision for what comes next.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5753be9e2251151328da43f539855b9d</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: How students are combating racism at Australian universities</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-how-students-are-combating-racism-at-australian-universities/k7nspp61k</link><description>The University of Melbourne Student Union is preparing to release the findings of its fourth report on racism on campus. The union&amp;apos;s president, Lushy Chinganya, explains what it found and how it connects with the latest Human Rights Commission report on the same issue.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c5f20cdcd4f55b023a69a7b832ab919</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We nearly gave up&amp;apos;: These pizza chefs bought their first home. It hasn&amp;apos;t been easy</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/we-nearly-gave-up-these-pizza-chefs-bought-their-first-home-it-hasnt-been-easy/ksabcq74o</link><description>Australian restaurants and cafes are in crisis, according to a new report. One Melbourne couple has found ways to survive and thrive.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ecdd8b9f5ae06d381bd74defdd7d84d</guid></item><item><title>Trump reinstates 10 per cent global tariffs | Midday News Bulletin 21 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trump-reinstates-10-per-cent-global-tariffs-midday-news-bulletin-21-february-2026/12nz08yfd</link><description>Donald Trump signs new order to reinstate global 10 per cent tariffs after Supreme Court ruled earlier tariffs illegal, More arrests over the Sydney shooting of former NRL star, Australia finishes a disappointing T20 campaign with a bang.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d43abfc04f8cd0d67ed9019dfe1affb</guid></item><item><title>Daylight upon the magic: How former prince Andrew&amp;apos;s arrest could impact the royal family</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/daylight-on-the-magic-how-former-prince-andrews-arrest-can-impact-the-royal-family/chs8quqrz</link><description>The last time a British royal was arrested, it led to the fall of the crown. Could it happen again?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d74a4ba28cf2fe646313cecb9f3b6318</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Attack on all of us&amp;apos;: Jewish leader condemns alleged Brisbane synagogue ramming</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/man-charged-with-hate-crime-over-alleged-brisbane-synagogue-ramming/dluo4w8v1</link><description>It comes after a man allegedly rammed the gates of a Brisbane synagogue with his ute on Friday night.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d2366c8ee482c18330e7af3c6ac3c95b</guid></item><item><title>Major synagogue attacked in Brisbane | Evening News Bulletin 21 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/major-synagogue-attacked-in-brisbane-evening-news-bulletin-21-february-2026/xwvtirf6t</link><description>A car rams into the gates of a major Brisbane synagogue; The US carries out another deadly raid on an alleged drug boat; Matilda&amp;apos;s goalkeeper Teagan Micah forced to withdraw from Australia&amp;apos;s Asian Cup side.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4fd06c9f7054fd29bc7f84f3a681acb</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Green light to violence&amp;apos;: Anti-racism commissioner denounces Hanson&amp;apos;s remarks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/race-discrimination-commissioner-condemns-pauline-hansons-remarks-on-muslims/a49gig1xd</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s race discrimination commissioner says he was deeply concerned by Hanson&amp;apos;s comments that there were &amp;quot;no good Muslims&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d1475292907d0c7e36c7afb6e66761c2</guid></item><item><title>Anna dePeyster, former wife of media mogul Rupert Murdoch, dies aged 81</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anne-de-peyster-former-wife-of-media-mogul-rupert-murdoch-dies-aged-81/aetmewc79</link><description>Anna dePeyster, who served on the News Corporation board, was married to Rupert Murdoch for more than 30 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e60b3d02601aa6823e47d8639f9d9829</guid></item><item><title>Anna dePeyster, former wife of media mogul Rupert Murdoch, dies aged 81</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/anna-de-peyster-former-wife-of-media-mogul-rupert-murdoch-dies-aged-81/aetmewc79</link><description>Anna dePeyster, who served on the News Corporation board, was married to Rupert Murdoch for more than 30 years.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7b9b18353326789eab3c95086d906366</guid></item><item><title>What is the rules-based order and is Trump really threatening it?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/rules-based-order-donald-trump/tucqu8dcw</link><description>Global leaders warn that the post-war rules-based order is unravelling. But is the system collapsing or just under strain?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d8d1fd3bb13d216660cf4b2883624bfb</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;I knocked on every single farm&amp;apos;: How Sammy Jeon went from backpacker to restaurateur</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/chef-sammy-jeon-on-bringing-east-asian-food-to-orange-nsw/icytsfkn8</link><description>Renowned Korean Australian chef Sammy Jeon&amp;apos;s culinary journey started when one regional winery took a chance on him.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8827a22c10d88044d2e8cd199143fc5f</guid></item><item><title>Donald Trump ratchets up global tariffs to 15 per cent | Morning News Bulletin 22 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/donald-trump-ratchets-up-global-tariffs-to-15-per-cent-morning-news-bulletin-22-february-2026/qmxi6l32c</link><description>Donald Trump increases global tariffs from 10 to 15 per cent in defiance of the Supreme Court, Police say the ramming of a Brisbane synagogue gates was not an act of terrorism, Penrith Panthers co-captain Nathan Cleary faces suspension.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f0253bad312977670f47bdf1c77c047a</guid></item><item><title>A purrfect anniversary: Larry the Cat marks 15 years at number 10 in London</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-purrfect-anniversary-larry-the-cat-marks-15-years-at-number-10-in-london/v2wvnbecp</link><description>In turbulent political times, stability comes with four legs, whiskers and a fondness for napping. Larry the Cat has celebrated 15 years as the British government&amp;apos;s official rodent-catcher and unofficial first feline, a reassuring presence who has served under six prime ministers.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef37b8fe297ad3c3f8cb529f3d14cfd0</guid></item><item><title>Trade minister says Australia exploring &amp;apos;all options&amp;apos; after Trump announces new tariffs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/donald-trump-raises-temporary-global-tariffs-from-10-to-15-per-cent-maximum-level-allowed/yzp05dk3a</link><description>The 15 per cent levy, announced after the US Supreme Court struck down Trump&amp;apos;s original tariff program, will be in effect for 150 days.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e955a9d6168f8680863ef5f0f9628fd7</guid></item><item><title>Experts say Russia&amp;apos;s government ensures its longevity by crushing dissent</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/experts-say-russias-government-ensures-its-longevity-by-crushing-dissent/kb1o3ujsw</link><description>This week will mark four years since Russia began its full scale invasion of Ukraine. Since then, experts say President Vladimir Putin has intensified efforts in his ongoing campaign to quash dissent and political opposition - many resistance leaders and activists inside Russia, jailed - or dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76c7d3302660ad4d5c96fb94e6012f20</guid></item><item><title>Australia&amp;apos;s underground hardcore scene just went global — you can thank a flute for that</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-hardcore-band-speed-on-making-community-from-chaos/ejqim6r47</link><description>Australian hardcore band SPEED started out playing for a room of 60 people. Now they&amp;apos;re fronting thousands.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">72750f856a2e2bfa9bc6010676c69b93</guid></item><item><title>World leaders react to Trump tariff hikes | Midday News Bulletin 22 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/world-leaders-react-to-trump-tariff-hikes-midday-news-bulletin-22-february-2026/98duv2bfd</link><description>World leaders react to a sudden global tariff increase by Donald Trump, Calls for transparency around Australian families of suspected IS militants, Manchester City move within two points of Arsenal after a win over Newcastle.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">edb33fab0d10d6a3ccc3ae4f7c895646</guid></item><item><title>No advice from ASIO to block passports of women with alleged IS links, Burke says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/no-advice-from-asio-to-block-passports-of-women-with-alleged-is-links-burke-says/dzan5s9gi</link><description>The home affairs minister said the government had not received advice that would require any further temporary exclusion orders to be issued.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e6a31e58e0e58b09d74b4d7eacb1d35d</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;We don&amp;apos;t want them back&amp;apos;: government stands firm on IS group women | Evening News Bulletin 22 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/we-dont-want-them-back-government-stands-firm-on-is-group-women-evening-news-bulletin-22-february-2026/21fsnnr9h</link><description>Calls for transparency around Australian families of suspected I-S group militants; New York declares a state of emergency as it prepares for a major storm; Norway breaks a Winter Olympics gold medal record.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">77f41647c716f5e021d78ee9e484e890</guid></item><item><title>Burke reveals process has begun to ban Islamist group Hizb ut-Tahrir</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/tony-burke-reveals-process-has-begun-to-ban-islamist-group-hizb-ut-tahrir/lbridgo4j</link><description>The home affairs minister revealed his department had received advice from ASIO that the group met the legal threshold to be banned.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c986cb3aca8526b992992a80c29a1b96</guid></item><item><title>A Chinese museum comes to life in the year of the fire horse</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-chinese-museum-comes-to-life-in-the-year-of-the-fire-horse/76zqqjzx6</link><description>The first museum in New South Wales dedicated to the history of Chinese people in Australia has opened in the heart of Sydney&amp;apos;s Chinatown. The Museum of Chinese in Australia [[MOCA]] dedicates its stories to some of Australia&amp;apos;s earliest migrants - preserving Chinese history and culture in the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dcb79913d49b0f05ca9f2920077a335</guid></item><item><title>Middle East states denounce US diplomat&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;inflammatory&amp;apos; backing of Israeli expansion</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/middle-east-states-denounce-us-diplomats-inflammatory-support-for-israeli-expansion/xcz0nzfp1</link><description>More than a dozen countries condemned Mike Huckabee&amp;apos;s suggestion that Israel had a right to large parts of the Middle East.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb48cd413838cff90538ae4aa515c965</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;What&amp;apos;s fair?&amp;apos;: The wages problem that&amp;apos;s led to some roles being &amp;apos;massively overpaid&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-professions-that-work-the-least-but-are-paid-the-most/0awq6v23l</link><description>Some occupations are very well paid, and here&amp;apos;s why.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">91069aa3eeafdf56aa0c8f9f1502c851</guid></item><item><title>Man shot dead trying to enter Trump&amp;apos;s Florida home | Morning News Bulletin 23 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/man-shot-dead-trying-to-enter-trumps-florida-home-morning-news-bulletin-23-february-2026/2xrp2ltgq</link><description>A man is shot dead trying to enter President Trump&amp;apos;s Florida home, Opposition continues to call for passports to be denied to women and children with alleged IS links, Australian Indra Brown finishes fifth in the Women’s Freeski Halfpipe at the Milano Cortina Games.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec7ca2a14c1c41dc9315b59425215ecc</guid></item><item><title>Armed intruder shot dead at Donald Trump&amp;apos;s Mar-a-Lago resort</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/police-fatally-shoot-armed-intruder-at-mar-a-lago/6i7ta9mub</link><description>Police have fatally shot a man armed with a shotgun and fuel can at US President Donald Trump&amp;apos;s Florida resort.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fd3462e366483d24b8cc38d6d2eb6fe0</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;No thanks&amp;apos;: Greenland, Denmark reject Donald Trump&amp;apos;s offer of medical aid</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/no-thanks-greenland-denmark-reject-donald-trumps-offer/caz3rgmq8</link><description>Greenland&amp;apos;s prime minister says US President Donald Trump should talk to him instead of making &amp;quot;random outbursts on social media&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e17d064e479a5fc99d6ba16c1b15ad70</guid></item><item><title>Afghans mourn those killed by Pakistan&amp;apos;s overnight air strikes</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/afghans-mourn-those-killed-in-overnight-pakistani-strikes/33pvx6q6e</link><description>The two countries have been locked in an increasingly bitter dispute since the Taliban retook control of Afghanistan in 2021.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a2795aa27ec02e7fbe7de25b0a344c4b</guid></item><item><title>Furious Iranian students hold anti-government protests for second day as US threats loom</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/furious-iranian-students-hold-anti-government-protests-for-second-day-as-us-threats-loom/exyghy3fg</link><description>The anti-government protests have led to more clashes at several Iranian universities.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55a40f051f476b08c5cd5eae215990ea</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Unintended consequences&amp;apos;: Coalition&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;terrorist hotspot&amp;apos; proposal raises questions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/terrorist-hotspot-key-question-in-coalitions-plan-to-criminalise-help-to-returning-australians/f6htmey7b</link><description>An element of the plan is &amp;quot;not really known to Australian law&amp;quot;, a legal expert says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fbcd319cd1b1ecf6ef79c885f62bee9f</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Unintended consequences&amp;apos;: Coalition&amp;apos;s &amp;apos;terrorist hotspot&amp;apos; proposal raises questions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/coalitions-plan-to-criminalise-assistance-to-australians-with-alleged-is-links/f6htmey7b</link><description>An element of the plan is &amp;quot;not really known to Australian law&amp;quot;, a legal expert says.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">930921b7960565525b1e9a844475df2c</guid></item><item><title>PM dismisses push to punish those linked to IS group | Midday News Bulletin 23 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pm-dismisses-push-to-punish-those-linked-to-is-group-midday-news-bulletin-26-february-2026/r3glmscpy</link><description>The Prime Minister dismisses a Coalition push for a new criminal offence for those who help people linked to the IS group, Hearings begin on Australia&amp;apos;s capital gains tax, Flagbearers chosen to carry the Australian flag at the Milan Winter Games closing ceremony.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cfb16276f0eaf0c5a37ebae30a867db7</guid></item><item><title>Armed man shot and killed outside Trump&amp;apos;s Mar-a-Lago residence</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/armed-man-shot-and-killed-outside-trumps-mar-a-lago-residence/2ob540w7r</link><description>An armed man was shot and killed after breaching the security perimeter of United States President Donald Trump&amp;apos;s Mar-a-Lago resort in Florida. With the suspect now deceased and no motive established, the FBI says an active investigation is underway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e4c34af2b89fc04ba73c3c42c54c1aed</guid></item><item><title>As rate hikes loom, Australians scramble to take on increasing amounts of debt</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-reactions-to-interest-rate-hikes-take-on-more-debt/fgp5t4ov2</link><description>Instead of tightening their belts, Australians are taking on more and bigger home loans, while demand for credit cards is soaring.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a6deb9a05b3d40701db2ceb6952a8742</guid></item><item><title>Ukrainians mark four years of &amp;apos;pain, despair and disbelief&amp;apos; as Russian invasion continues</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/ukrainians-mark-four-years-of-pain-despair-and-disbelief-as-russian-invasion-continues/5k8s2ix2m</link><description>Four years after Russia launched its full-scale invasion of Ukraine, the war shows no sign of abating, with mounting casualties, continued strikes on civilian infrastructure and faltering ceasefire efforts. As global tributes mark the February 24 anniversary, calls are growing for stronger international action to apply pressure to Russia and bring an end to Europe’s deadliest conflict since World War II.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b44a12aad880620ee02885e8a01082c8</guid></item><item><title>Man shot dead attempting to enter Trump estate | SBS News in Easy English 23 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/man-shot-dead-attempting-to-enter-trump-estate-sbs-news-in-easy-english-23-february-2026/u1vykusqp</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5dae983213250d25a788a97282880640</guid></item><item><title>Australia faces drenching as storm system set to bring heavy rain and flash floods</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australia-faces-drenching-as-storm-system-set-to-bring-heavy-rain-and-flash-floods/882zlhxny</link><description>Heavy rain and severe storms are expected across multiple states, with flash flooding, damaging winds and travel disruptions possible.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9084d5c9c5c15abb63d0d3c745d8ad0f</guid></item><item><title>Coalition plan to criminalise helping of IS group connected families | Evening News Bulletin 23 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/coalition-plan-to-criminalise-the-helping-of-is-group-connected-families-evening-news-bulletin-23-february-2026/2ltaru4li</link><description>The Coalition unveils a plan to criminalise the helping of I-S group connected families, More nuclear talks between Iran and the U-S will go ahead amid threats of war, South Africa ends India&amp;apos;s winning streak in the T20 World Cup.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">657befcd1143e9e1b769fee4799b2e50</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Serious incidents&amp;apos;: Australians issued fresh travel warning amid Mexico cartel violence</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australians-warned-mexico-travel-cartel-violence-el-mencho/r7s5sbc9i</link><description>Australians told to exercise a high degree of caution throughout Mexico as a wave of violence engulfs multiple states following the death of a cartel leader.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7b8ceefd183d4b5822e714c2eb6153c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Abhorrent&amp;apos;: Players targeted with racist abuse after Premier League games</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/premier-league-racist-abuse/e24gullm2</link><description>Just days earlier, an investigation was opened into a Real Madrid player&amp;apos;s claim he was racially abused by another player.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a82d9c87bc1a59019486c9d66df8a26d</guid></item><item><title>Travelling to the UK? Some dual nationals say passport changes have thrown their plans into chaos</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/travelling-to-the-uk-some-dual-nationals-say-passport-changes-have-thrown-their-plans-into-chaos/00rb0iam3</link><description>Travel experts have raised concerns about new border rules for Australian travellers who hold dual British or Irish nationality. From February 25, dual citizens who can&amp;apos;t present a valid British or Irish passport are at risk of being refused entry to the UK. The new regulations are causing widespread confusion, with many not even aware of their links to the country.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">499223419b6869bb02d49b2697b1024c</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Not an empty threat:&amp;apos; Trump builds military presence as US and Iran&amp;apos;s views on talks differ</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/iran-us-talks-differing-views-explained/pnvu2wuvd</link><description>Iran and the United States are set to hold talks in Geneva on Thursday, but an expert says it&amp;apos;s hard to predict the outcome.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">460cbc305adc05c34057618769d77418</guid></item><item><title>Are loopholes undermining Australia&amp;apos;s support for Ukraine?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/loopholes-undermining-australia-ukraine-support/uk9esxhgh</link><description>Australia has slapped nearly 2,000 sanctions on Russia — but some have questioned the effectiveness.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b29a226425129e9b87deb4fcf948ce03</guid></item><item><title>What we know as police turn to bush in search for kidnapped grandfather Chris Baghsarian</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/police-update-chris-baghsarian-kidnapping/c9h91ngfa</link><description>Chris Baghsarian, 85, was kidnapped from his home in what police believe is a case of mistaken identity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">fb056c46e831bb1a111e7376b23fe514</guid></item><item><title>Trump Tower planned for Gold Coast would be Australia&amp;apos;s tallest building, developer says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/six-star-luxury-91-storey-trump-tower-to-loom-over-surfers-paradise/qt2vu2u50</link><description>The skyscraper will reportedly be 91 storeys high and contain a six star resort, but the proposal is far from a done deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">55a2121f400b1aeeb6b42ba0c87eb692</guid></item><item><title>Trump Tower planned for Gold Coast would be Australia&amp;apos;s tallest building, developer says</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/trump-tower-gold-coast-surfers-paradise/qt2vu2u50</link><description>The skyscraper will reportedly be 91 storeys high and contain a six star resort, but the proposal is far from a done deal.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8a33f18a208d79877ce2b7e970898d87</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Grave allegations&amp;apos;: Albanese writes to Starmer backing Andrew&amp;apos;s succession removal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-backs-removal-of-prince-andrew-from-succession/8ywwv101r</link><description>The New Zealand government has since become the second Commonwealth country to voice support for the move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c132a022c94fa6b124df150020078c3</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Grave allegations&amp;apos;: Albanese writes to Starmer backing Andrew&amp;apos;s succession removal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/albanese-backs-removal-of-former-prince-andrew-from-succession/8ywwv101r</link><description>The New Zealand government has since become the second Commonwealth country to voice support for the move.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94a58535e2f79b934d018136eb22840d</guid></item><item><title>Australians urged to share their stories as royal commission begins after Bondi attack</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/antisemitism-royal-commission-explained/hr78vjaq0</link><description>Australians are being encouraged to submit their experiences to assist the royal commission into antisemitism.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5a0ba156f62b5810fb596e0030e76746</guid></item><item><title>UK&amp;apos;s former ambassador to US arrested on suspicion of misconduct | Morning News Bulletin 24 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/uks-former-ambassador-to-us-arrested-on-suspicion-of-misconduct-morning-news-bulletin-24-february-2026/6t68oyjtl</link><description>Peter Mandelson arrested on suspicion of misconduct in public office, Ukrainians share their experiences on the fourth anniversary of Russia&amp;apos;s full-scale invasion, Nathan Cleary cleared to play in the Panthers&amp;apos; season opener.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d836eb876ad2e0494b8910b61f0eb575</guid></item><item><title>Violence in Mexico: What travellers need to know, and what it could mean for the World Cup</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dozens-dead-in-mexico-violence-after-drug-kingpin-killed/wiu30zopf</link><description>Australians considering travelling to Mexico have been urged to exercise a high degree of caution amid violence over a cartel leader&amp;apos;s death.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">27a866e2d433764dda4d3aa7992f4376</guid></item><item><title>UK police arrest ex-ambassador Peter Mandelson after Epstein revelations</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/uk-police-arrest-peter-mandelson-amid-probe-into-allegations-over-ties-to-epstein/xsajzb0di</link><description>British police have arrested a former UK ambassador to the US in a misconduct investigation stemming from his ties with Jeffrey Epstein.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2321d8a56575694645a50f31bd200f3a</guid></item><item><title>Homicide detectives probe &amp;apos;distressing&amp;apos; mental hospital death</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/homicide-detectives-probe-distressing-mental-hospital-death/9rv52gyc8</link><description>A union is renewing its calls for action on staffing and safety concerns as police investigate the death of a patient at a mental hospital.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9361ab435d242394c0d677a22f0ae14</guid></item><item><title>Russia-Ukraine peace talks continue, but will they ever conclude?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/russia-ukraine-peace-talks-continue-but-will-they-ever-conclude/6bhzbo12o</link><description>As Ukraine enters its fifth year of war, another round of talks aimed at ending the war in Ukraine could be held at the end of this week. Ukraine, Russia and the United States have held several rounds of talks in Abu Dhabi and Geneva; as Washington seeks an end to four years of war since Moscow&amp;apos;s 2022 full-scale invasion. But how close is a real peace deal?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e0b0594d425d73b5479306d49968609</guid></item><item><title>Iran would react &amp;apos;ferociously&amp;apos; to US aggression, as student protests continue across the country</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/iran-would-react-ferociously-to-us-aggression-as-local-protests-continue-across-the-country/2unvhn2l2</link><description>Iranian student protesters have defied authorities for a third day, weeks after security forces crushed mass unrest.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e0d9b26f79738a9ab2d9fce078dd6e43</guid></item><item><title>Police suspect they&amp;apos;ve found remains of kidnapped grandfather Chris Baghsarian</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/police-find-what-may-be-human-remains-in-search-for-missing-grandfather-chris-baghsarian/u1b5viwu2</link><description>The 85-year-old was kidnapped from his home 11 days ago, in what police believe was a case of mistaken identity.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">56543526c7bba0c2dcf4a495d0cfc7cd</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Dangerous very quickly&amp;apos;: Victoria braces for severe storms and flash flooding</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/victoria-flash-flood-warning/pg6stgrif</link><description>Melbourne and other communities across northern and central Victoria are bracing for wild weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41f6bc9f08871eb4c3fdd28276c7510d</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Dangerous very quickly&amp;apos;: Victoria braces for severe storms and flash flooding</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/dangerous-very-quickly-states-flash-flood-warning/pg6stgrif</link><description>Melbourne and other communities across northern and central Victoria are bracing for wild weather.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc0d71808754116d9178dff70e27ea7b</guid></item><item><title>Human remains found in the search for missing grandfather | Midday News Bulletin 24 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/midday-news-bulletin-24-february-2026/t90r1g4l1</link><description>Human remains found in the search for Chris Baghsarian, The royal commission into antisemitism and social cohesion commences, And in women&amp;apos;s cricket, Australia faces India in the first of three ODIs.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cbeaf253baeeb4d25ea7c82060aff835</guid></item><item><title>Capital gains tax concessions slammed as unfair and cruel to younger generations</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/capital-gains-tax-concessions-slammed-as-unfair-and-cruel-to-younger-generations/e8f2opgor</link><description>A Senate inquiry into housing affordability has heard urgent calls for tax reform, with advocates warning that current capital gains concessions favour wealthy investors while locking the younger generation out of the property market. The Australian Council of Trade Unions argues that reducing these tax breaks could boost home ownership by four per cent. The Grattan Institute maintains the primary benefit would be a $6.5 billion budget windfall to fund public housing and support struggling renters.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">082d057206771bce5f2e0e85719856a2</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Buyer Beware&amp;apos;: Europe halts US trade deal after Trump tariffs ruled illegal</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/buyer-beware-europe-halts-us-trade-deal-after-trump-tariffs-ruled-illegal/ppz9ikodw</link><description>The European Union has paused the ratification of a US-EU trade agreement after a US Supreme Court ruling and new tariff threats cast doubt on the deal. As Donald Trump threatens new sweeping tariffs, European politicians say they can&amp;apos;t move forward until clarity is provided.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff1eb35c8a29a96b1fe9a971df2cde06</guid></item><item><title>Trump&amp;apos;s tariffs spark fresh round of market uncertainty</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/trumps-tariffs-spark-fresh-round-of-market-uncertainty/qa0u4gk2a</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with David Scutt from StoneX Group Inc. about the day&amp;apos;s market action, including how Trump&amp;apos;s tariffs are causing a fresh wave of uncertaintly, plus why investors are keeping a close eye on the private credit markets</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ab689e68504d6c2658ead1971ce8cdb9</guid></item><item><title>Police believe remains may belong to missing grandfather | SBS News in Easy English 24 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/police-believe-remains-may-belong-to-missing-grandfather-sbs-news-in-easy-english-24-february-2026/mh82bnmvg</link><description>A five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">002eacb46bff4f4abdc6e443034035a8</guid></item><item><title>Politicians urged to tackle &amp;apos;Monopoly-like&amp;apos; issue with iPhone payments</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/apple-wallet-accused-of-freeriding-by-australian-banks/8oxwxsx2l</link><description>Banks and fintech representatives are accusing tech platforms such as Apple of free-riding amid the rapid growth of digital payments.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c158fa3056e3bfc4f20a031a574a35b8</guid></item><item><title>Cartel violence erupts after death of &amp;apos;El Mencho&amp;apos;, killing dozens</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/cartel-violence-erupts-after-death-of-el-mencho-killing-dozens/2aitmjr5p</link><description>Australians are being urged to reconsider travelling to Mexico after a deadly surge in cartel violence triggered by the killing of a notorious drug lord known as El Mencho. The leader of one of the country&amp;apos;s largest cartels was fatally wounded during a military raid in Jalisco, sparking coordinated retaliatory attacks that have killed at least 25 members of Mexico’s National Guard as well as several civilians.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ff4c4edb9c4b5463a6dfa895f334c89b</guid></item><item><title>BAFTAs scandal: What is Tourette syndrome, what are tics, and why are people angry?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/baftas-scandal-what-is-tourette-syndrome-what-are-tics-and-why-are-people-angry/j5ckaimhc</link><description>Tourette syndrome activist John Davidson says he left the BAFTAs ceremony &amp;quot;aware of the distress my tics were causing&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5477a6fb536c5990592291becdb0f8c1</guid></item><item><title>Human remains found by police in search of kidnapped grandfather | Evening News Bulletin 24 February 2026</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/human-remains-found-by-police-in-search-of-kidnapped-grandfather-evening-news-bulletin-24-february-2026/ae3iqzknm</link><description>Human remains discovered in Sydney&amp;apos;s north-west suspected to be those of an elderly man who was abducted; Police to investigate a gynaecologist accused of performing unnecessary surgery; And in the AFL, Carlton has signed a player to the longest contract in its history.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a8ed1137d7cfd76f1e5e73b59f7b8767</guid></item><item><title>$831 billion rebuild cost reveal as Ukrainians in Australia stuck on &amp;apos;hope and heartbreak&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/after-four-years-of-war-ukrainians-in-australia-are-stuck-between-hope-and-heartbreak/a0r6misaf</link><description>As the Russia-Ukraine war enters its fifth year, Ukrainians are exhausted by protracted peace talks and ongoing violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6270cdcd98851c6e95e0ff95a30633ea</guid></item><item><title>How much you need for a comfortable retirement &amp;amp; AI fears continues to spook investors</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/how-much-you-need-for-a-comfortable-retirement-ai-fears-continues-to-spook-investors/k1u6stuw8</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Mike Jenneke from UBS Wealth Management about the day&amp;apos;s market action including investors’ renewed AI fears; plus Stephanie Youssef talks with Jame Koval from ASFA to find out how much you need for a comfortable retirement.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8d920c74970fda10d35a478a6e1f63e4</guid></item><item><title>Australian leading bid to return IS-linked families says Syrian authorities spooked</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-leading-bid-to-return-isis-linked-families-says-syrian-authorities-spooked/hzfy2c98i</link><description>The Sydney doctor and Muslim community leader said Australia has &amp;apos;failed&amp;apos; Yusuf Zahab, now feared lost in Iraq.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">96aa49e7b8945c850a3e31fd0993e5e1</guid></item></channel></rss>