<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" version="2.0"><channel><title>SBS English News (Unofficial Aggregation)</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news</link><description>Auto-generated (headings &amp; summaries only).</description><docs>http://www.rssboard.org/rss-specification</docs><generator>python-feedgen</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 15:54:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><item><title>Anti-immigration rallies ignore Australia's economic dependence on migration</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/anti-immigration-rallies-ignore-australias-economic-dependence-on-migration/gez59p6r5</link><description>Australia in anti-immigration marches.At the heart of what organisers called the 'March for Australia' rallies was a call to end "mass migration", which protesters claimed is to blame for issues like the housing crisis and rise in cost of living. Experts say a paradox exists in the anti-immigration…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">faec4584bdc2aef11e3ce223ecdbed89</guid></item><item><title>Bush medicine program helping keep knowledge and culture alive for future generations</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/bush-medicine-program-helping-keep-knowledge-and-culture-alive-for-future-generations/g07e9seye</link><description>Surrounded by the stringybark forest of Northeast Arnhem Land, a group of Yolngu cultural educators are passing on knowledge of bush medicine to a new wave of First Nations doctors. The remote placement, formed in partnership with Flinders University, explores traditional healing methods, while…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">af4d24eb524fffa48f2bcc6daf3c9db0</guid></item><item><title>Libraries usually like bookworms - but not these ones</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/libraries-usually-like-bookworms-but-not-these-ones/2czbj60ei</link><description>Hungary's oldest library is fighting a beetle infestation. The creatures have been found in a section of the 1,000 year-old Pannonhalma Archabbey library, housing around a quarter of the abbey's 400,000 volumes. It's prompted workers to pull tens of thousands of centuries-old books from the shelves…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b18792cf8d269f8ce70110b441a45cfc</guid></item><item><title>Woolworths and Coles say underpayment court decision could cost them $1 billion</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/woolworths-and-coles-say-underpayment-court-decision-could-cost-them-1-billion/yvdzqzkcr</link><description>The supermarket giants were found not to have complied with their obligations to keep accurate employment records and paid workers&amp;apos; salaries without tracking other entitlements.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">636596933cf8b494e7c1090adaaf96d8</guid></item><item><title>Grants for social enterprises look to break cycles of disadvantage</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/grants-for-social-enterprises-look-to-break-cycles-of-disadvantage/mqrja41is</link><description>The federal government has announced there'll be 22 grants made to social enterprises to help support marginalised communities. It's part of an $11 million investment aimed at tackling issues like long-term unemployment and discrimination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">293b9b718ad83cd0dd2a67e683c4cd41</guid></item><item><title>Spain prepares for future extreme weather after 'environmental catastrophe'</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/spain-prepares-for-future-extreme-weather-after-environmental-catastrophe/c8dgmob01</link><description>After a summer in which much of western and southern Europe were impacted by catastrophic fires and searing heat, Spain now forming a plan to prepare for future disasters.Scientists say action is needed to reduce emissions and increase resilience, in the face of inevitable worsening conditions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad6afe03228b625046485667e1148f5c</guid></item><item><title>Autism stakeholders welcome new government commitment - but are perplexed they weren't consulted</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/autism-stakeholders-welcome-new-government-commitment-but-are-perplexed-they-werent-consulted/kiiuulbjy</link><description>The number of children being diagnosed with autism is rising, putting a heavy strain on the National Disability Insurance Scheme. The government has responded, announcing a plan to divert children away from the NDIS to a new scheme called Thriving Kids. Parents and autism advocates say they were…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cdfc99eb0ea1eba62f8ce8f17ed5e564</guid></item><item><title>'Bullying, yelling, sexual harassment, underpaid': study finds one in three young workers are ripped off</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/bullying-yelling-sexual-harassment-underpaid-study-finds-1-in-3-young-workers-are-ripped-off-by-employers/adl9otfgr</link><description>A third of young workers in Australia are being paid less than $15 an hour - that's almost ten dollars below the minimum hourly wage. It's one of the key findings of a Melbourne University report showing 15 to 30 year olds are experiencing widespread breaches of labour laws. And those from…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d0be5e83c6c69302329ebc3a114078de</guid></item><item><title>Guiding Indigenous students to careers in science and technology</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/guiding-indigenous-students-to-careers-in-science-and-technology/0v0c9mwvq</link><description>Around Australia, some educational and fun workshops for Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander students are aiming to contribute to an inclusive and diverse future science and technology workforce. Victoria’s largest health service and an Indigenous-owned organisation are helping to guide students…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9cc89170d9d05fa3419efc4af2b9f8e0</guid></item><item><title>Call for action after report details racism faced by nurses, midwives</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/call-for-action-after-report-details-racism-faced-by-nurses-midwives/ow12fdojj</link><description>A new report from the New South Wales Nurses and Midwives Association has revealed the alarming rates of racism and discrimination experienced by Aboriginal and culturally diverse healthcare workers. The union has called for action to address the issue, with nearly 70 percent of survey respondents…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">02b9b7ef24bead8b92dbf5152ac8752f</guid></item><item><title>Refugees in visa limbo for 13 years take their plight to Parliament</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/refugees-in-visa-limbo-for-13-years-take-their-plight-to-parliament/0i0amscbz</link><description>A group of refugees who say they've been living in limbo in Australia for 13 years have taken their fight for permanent residency to federal parliament in Canberra.They're part of a group of more than 8,000 people who had their refugee protection claims rejected under a now-abolished visa system.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4dfc27b622e30156cfe77bcfba6e0eb0</guid></item><item><title>Thousands rally against immigration with neo-Nazis taking the spotlight</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/thousands-rally-against-immigration-with-neo-nazis-taking-the-spotlight/amfab4ulu</link><description>A wave of nation-wide anti-immigration rallies have swept Australia's capital cities, with thousands joining marches and clashing with police and counter-protesters across the country. Organisers say the events were calling for an end to what they consider "mass migration" into Australia, while…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b6668353c17b48410a1d7344cc81ff6</guid></item><item><title>Are you delaying the dentist because of cost? Your children shouldn't be.</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/are-you-delaying-the-dentist-because-of-cost-your-children-shouldnt-be/gizi84g5z</link><description>The Australian Dental Association says around 1.5 million kids are missing out on free dental care every year. This Dental Health Week, dentists are urging parents to check if they're eligible for the free dental cover and to brush up on their understanding of good oral hygiene. Meanwhile,…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c83d0ae09a5f66ecfc041a7e02fb27af</guid></item><item><title>All about the federal government's productivity summit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/all-about-the-federal-governments-productivity-summit/ufiy8ts54</link><description>Top economists, business leaders and unions will gather in Canberra this week to attend a national roundtable on boosting Australia's productivity. It comes as Australia has followed other advanced economies and recorded consistently low productivity growth in the past several decades. Federal…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d6bd2c3ebd6bb30bb7f4dee5c9951bfe</guid></item><item><title>What is Garma? And why is it important?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/what-is-garma-and-why-is-it-important/b88hxx8ry</link><description>The very first Garma Festival was held just before the turn of the millennium in 1999, led by the late Yunupingu. But the mission of its founders remains: to be a cross-cultural meeting of leaders to discuss improving standards of living for all First Nations people. And a warning - this feature…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0c3f469d30b930a84b9232871a069c66</guid></item><item><title>Gurindji people mark half century since land handback, a milestone for First Nations land rights</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gurindji-people-mark-half-century-since-land-handback-a-milestone-for-first-nations-land-rights/b0x4cmtdf</link><description>This week marks the 50th anniversary since the Gurindji land handback, an historic turning point for Aboriginal land rights in Australia. Fifty years on, people from all over Australia have gathered for the Gurindji Freedom Day Festival to celebrate the anniversary of the land hand-back, and…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">779a57346f0447f7f86cc7ad5ad60c78</guid></item><item><title>This jailed Australian needs help. But a major move has put them in a &amp;apos;horror situation&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/horror-situation-at-least-one-australian-imprisoned-in-iran/f6pzdeune</link><description>Experts warn the Australian government’s decision to expel Iran’s ambassador and designate the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps a terrorist organisation could throw a ‘spanner in the works’ for an Australian citizen detained in Iran.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7a4cfbcce3533a1fd0d99c686133f86</guid></item><item><title>What this grieving daughter found online is helping thousands in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/what-this-grieving-daughter-found-online-is-helping-thousands-in-australia/1pz56yq42</link><description>More than 180,000 people in Australia confront death each year, yet few leave behind a will or clear end-of-life wishes. When Vibha&amp;apos;s mother died, she was overwhelmed by both grief and unanswered questions. But then, she found support.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e7ad10a285249611e8ce80abac9e68f8</guid></item><item><title>I&amp;apos;m an Australian and wanted nothing to do with religion. Here&amp;apos;s what changed my mind</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/christianity-is-declining-in-australia-meet-the-gen-z-converts-bucking-the-trend/kpgccwiom</link><description>While latest Census data pointed to a significant downward trend in Australians identifying as Christian, there was an uptick in religious diversity. Some research suggests 38 per cent of gen Z identify as spiritual and there is an increase of gen Z men turning to religion.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e17da9d041a976bbc9059bfd0dab3c4</guid></item><item><title>The ‘strangest’ press conference, Palestine recognition &amp; Thai-Cambodian feud</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-strangest-press-conference-palestine-recognition-thai-cambodian-feud/mdjerqhjv</link><description>In this episode: President Trump’s shows a deep hatred of windmills during his ‘diplomatic’ trip to Scotland, and Canada moves to recognise Palestinian statehood, the latest US ally to shift its foreign policy. Plus, the Shakespearean drama fuelling deadly border clashes between Thailand and…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2f9597c5602e020e070ad74e91a5c98b</guid></item><item><title>Scottish brothers reach Cairns after record-breaking row across the Pacific Ocean</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lachlan-jamie-ewan-maclean-brothers-cairns-rowing-pacific-ocean-scottish/4qgv8mys7</link><description>After more than four months at sea, the brothers reunited with loved ones — along with pizza and beer — as they reached their final destination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ac9549f38c3e408b6db2d36bd90a1aee</guid></item><item><title>Is Victoria Australia's crime state and what does it mean for insurance premiums?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/is-victoria-australias-crime-state-and-what-does-it-mean-for-insurance-premiums/iqp477ah1</link><description>Car theft claims rose to a record $233m in Victoria last financial year, but fell in every other state so Stephanie Youssef speaks with Insuance Council of Australia CEO Andrew Hall to find out what can be done about it and what it means for premiums, plus SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves takes…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5522aef409671e89a18893236459103b</guid></item><item><title>Hope and hate: how governments around the world are responding to 'illegal' immigration</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/hope-and-hate-how-governments-around-the-world-are-responding-to-illegal-immigration/8uvravt9r</link><description>Recently, local news headlines have been dominated by stories about anti-immigration rallies which were held across Australia on the last day of August. But it's not just in Australia where migration has created such deep feelings - it's also an issue that has been front and centre in the US as…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">94a74b43b5d6abf4754d72ad1f63660e</guid></item><item><title>Netanyahu backs Trump for Nobel, UN pressures Taliban and Mushroom Murder verdict</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/netanyahu-backs-trump-for-nobel-un-pressures-taliban-and-mushroom-murder-verdict/2equexmsa</link><description>In this episode: Israel's Benjamin Netanyahu visits Washington, while a Gaza ceasefire remains elusive, and Taiwan answers China’s military pressure with drills of its own. Plus, The UN ramps up calls for the Taliban to end their oppression on women and girls in Afghanistan - but will it have any…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6c7d7ed4322d7c57fc00afa27bdde87d</guid></item><item><title>Ash secretly worked seven jobs and earned up to $500,000. Inside the &amp;apos;overemployed&amp;apos; community</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/ash-secretly-worked-seven-jobs-and-earned-500-000-inside-the-overemployed-community/na1ne7zrd</link><description>Calling themselves &amp;apos;overemployed&amp;apos;, some Australians are holding down multiple full-time jobs at once, usually without their employers&amp;apos; knowledge. But working long hours and bending the company rules can come at a cost.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">8e4ded0d41ad16d023c1913a2df6425b</guid></item><item><title>Evening News Bulletin 13 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/evening-news-bulletin-13-september-2025/vr99s3bc2</link><description>Police deployed to separate rival protests in Australia's capital cities and regional centres; the widow of conservative political activist Charlie Kirk speaks out; and in sport, Australian Jai Hindley closing in on a podium finish at the Vuelta a Espana.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ef389784f5cf8a5867adb178b7b612c</guid></item><item><title>Pressure on Putin, Syria clashes &amp; what Albanese told Xi</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/pressure-on-putin-syria-clashes-what-albanese-told-xi/xanq2smwp</link><description>Russia faces another Trump deadline to end the war in Ukraine, Prime Minister Anthony Albanese wraps up his trip to China, and violence flares again in Syria as Israeli airstrikes target Damascus. Plus, a secret UK plan to resettle Afghans is exposed, and the world’s oldest president wants another…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c638b8560e994e130f18eb377c222fc4</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Doesn&amp;apos;t cut the mustard&amp;apos;: Indian Australian community leaders demand Price apology</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-indian-community-leaders-demand-price-apology/3t2yqrt2p</link><description>While welcoming an apology from Opposition leader Sussan Ley, one Indian Australian community figure said &amp;quot;the Liberal Party has their work cut out to repair the damage&amp;quot; caused by senator Jacinta Nampijinpa Price&amp;apos;s comments on Indian immigration.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e627c942f9c9434aaec1553129c384be</guid></item><item><title>Concerns over political extremism after rival rallies held across Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/concerns-over-political-extremism-after-rival-rallies-held-across-australia/xpog5r6wa</link><description>Politicians are warning against the risks of extremism and political violence, after rival rallies were held in Australia's capital cities and regional centres.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9c9c122776c42c5cbb71d81f2ff790f3</guid></item><item><title>Protesters clash in Melbourne as rival rallies unfold across the country</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/protesters-clash-in-melbourne-as-rival-rallies-unfold-across-the-country/zc1vt18mt</link><description>Opposing protests took place across all capital cities and some regional areas on Saturday and, as police had predicted, things got most heated in Melbourne</description><guid isPermaLink="false">257c6581530463bd11e3e3a800defacf</guid></item><item><title>Ireland says it will boycott Eurovision 2026 if Israel is allowed to participate</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ireland-israel-eurovision-2026-participation-gaza/yf4scypng</link><description>Irish broadcaster RTE said it would be &amp;quot;unconscionable&amp;quot; to take part in the contest alongside Israel, given its ongoing assault on Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">62cffd1bb18419483053a0ea72f1e5f3</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 9 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-9-september-2025/7pl65i7q0</link><description>A Five minute bulletin for English language learners</description><guid isPermaLink="false">645638e8c6be4a78aaa6378a1dca6105</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Girt by sea&amp;apos; explained: National anthem now in 60+ languages</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/girt-by-sea-explained-national-anthem-now-in-60-languages/z1ycvk2zl</link><description>Ever wondered what &amp;quot;girt by sea&amp;quot; means, especially if your first language isn&amp;apos;t English? SBS Audio has brought Australia’s national anthem to life in more than 60 languages, so everyone can understand the words behind the music.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">04079c2c5f6e829b610f96ef72903390</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk shooting: More clues as search for shooter intensifies</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/charlie-kirk-shooting-more-clues-as-search-for-shooter-intensifies/t1xz9eoy5</link><description>The hunt for the killer of conservative activist Charlie Kirk continues, with US federal investigators pursuing new leads in Utah. The FBI has released images of the suspect and is offering a reward of up to A$150,000 (US$$100,000) for information.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">1faa8d1a144aa699f9be42e7e44c86f9</guid></item><item><title>Weak US data spurs rate cut chance, and the supermarkets court case</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/weak-us-data-spurs-rate-cut-chance-and-the-supermarkets-court-case/hxkq8noia</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Raymond Chan from Morgans about the day's sharemarket action including the weak US jobs data, a rebalancing of the market's main indexes and the potential implications of a supermarkets underpayments court case.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cd0d8ba22d0571807220c65c575aac5a</guid></item><item><title>US stocks benefit from Oracle surge; home ownership dream slipping</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/us-stocks-benefit-from-oracle-surge-home-ownership-dream-slipping/lva29gz3x</link><description>The ASX 200 has closed 0.3% lower with healthcare stocks dragging the index down, despite gains by gold miners. That’s almost despite Oracle’s shares soaring almost 40% in its best one-day performance since 1992, lifting the S&amp;P 500 and other global markets to record highs. For more, Stephanie…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09067c9fdf20c9801c040532d3c16c92</guid></item><item><title>Ley apologises to Indian Australians, says Price remains &amp;apos;valued&amp;apos; party member after sacking</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/ley-apologises-to-indian-australians-says-price-remains-valued-party-member/li9efqs2v</link><description>Sussan Ley&amp;apos;s apology come after she dumped Jacinta Nampijinpa Price from the Opposition frontbench over the senator&amp;apos;s remarks about Indian migrants and her refusal to endorse her leadership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">247454894dec2d9a59ae4e4275dc557c</guid></item><item><title>Melanie was sceptical of this underutilised cancer treatment. It saved her life</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/cancer-patients-are-missing-out-on-this-life-saving-treatment/7gvsskz2v</link><description>One in five eligible Australian cancer patients never receives this form of treatment, according to research cited by Australian oncologists.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aa19076cff7c5e7f80ef947e1b65f922</guid></item><item><title>Scottish brothers reach Cairns after record-breaking row across the Pacific Ocean</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lachlan-jamie-ewan-maclean-scottish-brothers-cairns-rowing-pacific-ocean/4qgv8mys7</link><description>After more than four months at sea, the brothers reunited with loved ones — along with pizza and beer — as they reached their final destination.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">53880f8926f2556582b6c95c8afaf9f1</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;When I wear the clothes... I feel proud&amp;apos;: How these women fleeing conflict find strength</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/karen-women-fleeing-myanmar-find-strength-weaving-western-australia/tlol975h4</link><description>Karen women in Australia use weaving to preserve culture and heal from trauma. However, recent international aid cuts raise fears for more than 100,000 displaced Karen still stuck in refugee camps.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c17959a19232c1709745ea92d7da110f</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;It creates a worry in your head&amp;apos;: International students plan to stay home during protests</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/the-feed/article/it-creates-a-worry-in-your-head-international-students-holed-up-in-fear-ahead-of-protests/fbw6p37ia</link><description>International education is Australia&amp;apos;s fourth largest export, but with protests looming that demand dramatic cuts to migration, some experts think the event could &amp;quot;cast a shadow over the brand of Australia&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">83576a4828238dac9816d9fe0bae6a23</guid></item><item><title>"Terrifying reality" Islamophobia envoy calls for urgent action | Evening News Bulletin</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/terrifying-reality-islamophobia-envoy-calls-for-urgent-action-evening-news-bulletin/nhetlxwy2</link><description>In this bulletin, the Federal Government is handed dozens of recommendations to combat Islamophobia, the environment minister says final approval of the extension of a gas project is subject to conditions. And in tennis, Australia eyes a top 8 qualifying spot in the Davis Cup, playing Belgium this…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">52878b3d2b7f48a88655bba7ad178c50</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;More political in recent years&amp;apos;: Fresh details emerge about suspected Charlie Kirk shooter</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/charlie-kirk-shooting-suspect-captured/h3lp59vqh</link><description>Tyler Robinson expressed dislike for Charlie Kirk in the lead-up to the conservative commentator&amp;apos;s assassination, investigators have been told.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">beca74b0b11cba6c7876be005ad26520</guid></item><item><title>Brazil's former President Bolsonaro sentenced to jail</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/brazils-former-president-bolsonaro-sentenced-to-jail/v1s50igk9</link><description>Brazil's former President, Jair Bolsonaro has been sentenced to prison after being convicted of plotting a coup to remain in power after losing the 2022 election. Mr Bolsonaro, who has denied any wrongdoing, has not attended the court and has only sent his lawyers.He is the first former president…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7d59efe136133d39a3417df21ab88006</guid></item><item><title>What we know about the Charlie Kirk shooting suspect</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-we-know-about-the-charlie-kirk-shooting-suspect/dqnakhike</link><description>More photos have been released of a &amp;quot;person of interest&amp;quot; in relation to the shooting of right-wing activist Charlie Kirk. There is still no suspect in custody.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b355779fc318d8e1e4df044892a1f1eb</guid></item><item><title>Lifting caps from first home buyer scheme will help some but fuel wider price rise</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lifting-caps-from-first-home-buyer-scheme-will-help-some-but-fuel-wider-price-rise/qufj0whee</link><description>The federal government will expand its Home Guarantee Scheme in October, lifting income and property caps to give first-time buyers greater access, but it will also fast-track price rises, a new analysis has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">71f1d32104dd7cab1f85b9385a5703e4</guid></item><item><title>Charlie Kirk 'a man of deep faith' says Trump | Evening News Bulletin 11 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/charlie-kirk-a-man-of-deep-faith-says-trump-evening-news-bulletin-11-september-2025/a51l0n5o2</link><description>Donald Trump condemns the shooting of conservative influencer Charlie Kirk; Australia signs on to the Pacific Resilience Facility as it moves to bolster ties in the region; and in sport, "devastated" paddling champion Jess Fox will not compete at the Slalom World Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c90bd8e6919000758e2fd55c47a91d26</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 2 Sep 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-2-sep-2025/nte6lpfva</link><description>A daily 5-minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89f4f62d7213f4dab0e96018aa0d25fb</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 8th September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-8th-september-2025/61mlt1juv</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">38941ecffd40a862ef31ae721b722543</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 10 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-10-september-2025/hh3zlp7ve</link><description>A daily 5-minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">41a086b5616544320d925dff8713e1aa</guid></item><item><title>Rare double tornado seen in New South Wales | Midday News Bulletin 11 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/rare-double-tornado-seen-in-new-south-wales-midday-news-bulletin-11-september-2025/8xf86rdhn</link><description>In this bulletin, a rare double tornado phenomenon in New South Wales, Sussan Ley apologises to Indian Australian community, for comments by ousted frontbencher. And in tennis, Lleyton Hewitt to captain Australia in this weekend's Davis Cup match, after an improper conduct fine.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ad86c604f0700440f0b7e0bad63c9afc</guid></item><item><title>MORNING NEWS BULLETIN 12 SEPTEMBER 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/morning-news-bulletin-12-september/ecn9wyrk5</link><description>US authorities search for the gunman that allegedly killed Charlie Kirk; Two Victorian Police officers charged with negligent manslaughter; Former St Kilda star Nicky Winmar appears in court on a charge of domestic violence.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">db81420cd24278b361c5df77122a3f2e</guid></item><item><title>Israel strikes Qatar, why it's been a bad week to be a PM &amp; the real 'Succession' finale</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/israel-strikes-qatar-why-its-been-a-bad-week-to-be-a-pm-the-real-succession-finale/v3tnyfj2b</link><description>Israel's strike on Qatar blows up ceasefire talks, the prime ministers of Nepal, Japan and France depart in a hurry, and Albanese battles for influence in the Pacific, while Moldova battles to stop Putin’s influence ahead of elections. Plus, the Murdoch succession is finally settled.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b7e0eaabc8585d03e4f518e25a324473</guid></item><item><title>Police in Australia raise concerns ahead of protests | Afternoon Bulletin 13 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/police-in-australia-raise-concerns-ahead-of-protests-afternoon-bulletin-13-september-2025/uobvjm6fm</link><description>In this bulletin, Police are concerned about chaos, as left and right wing protests begin; Social media platforms urged to take down videos of the Charlie Kirk shooting; and in sport; Officials found to have placed hundreds of bets on races in Tasmania.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9ffa6752eba31ad8e0a0bb20946e7394</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 12 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-12-september-2025/la1ex1kfj</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6152830b72d22eecc9fd00ff5b880c68</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;People starting to act out&amp;apos;: How the Charlie Kirk shooting suggests a &amp;apos;vicious spiral&amp;apos; in the US</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/people-starting-to-act-out-how-the-charlie-kirk-shooting-suggests-a-vicious-spiral-in-the-us/a105398va</link><description>Is the US seeing a rise in political violence, and could it spread to Australia?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">aeedaa8ed91e546ae737e8dd9f9ef74f</guid></item><item><title>Why the final approval for North West Shelf gas plant has Indigenous groups and environmentalists worried</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/why-the-final-approval-for-north-west-shelf-gas-plant-has-indigenous-groups-and-environmentalists-worried/v12sc9i5e</link><description>The federal government has given the final approval for the Woodside North West Shelf gas project with a series of conditions. The approval comes ahead of the Albanese government's announcement of a 2035 emissions reduction target, and after Australia emphasised its commitment to tackling climate…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0996f56dc4418abd3998966386a8cca9</guid></item><item><title>Federal election results 2025: Search for your electorate on our interactive map</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/federal-election-results-2025-search-for-your-electorate-on-our-interactive-map/85l5np7bz</link><description>Check live election results for your local electorate using the SBS interactive map.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a0c09ed15e71ed58c01da4c00d032473</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 5 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-5-september-2025/dn8y3bjig</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">09f805b8314d81e4ff90e19d59400831</guid></item><item><title>A suspect arrested in the shooting of Charlie Kirk | Morning Bulletin 13 September</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/a-suspect-arrested-in-the-shooting-of-charlie-kirk-morning-bulletin-13-september/a2wlwmlsw</link><description>In this bulletin, A suspect arrested in the shooting of Charlie Kirk as local supporters hold a vigil; Australia's Muslim community welcomes a report into Islamophobia; and in sport, Australian basketball star Tiana Mangakahia dies of cancer at the age of 30.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c4c95131de8bfa331f42b43694b49170</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 11 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-11-september-2025/cmk9s3xbb</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d85ecaf226af85d3584b0eef3f689ef0</guid></item><item><title>A generation to lose it, three to restore it: One man&amp;apos;s quest to revive a language at risk</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/a-generation-to-lose-it-three-to-restore-it-one-mans-quest-to-revive-a-language-at-risk/9vo5uavn8</link><description>Once punished for speaking, now celebrated in song — te reo Māori is finding new life. For Marlon Williams, music has become both a personal reckoning and a powerful tool for revival.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6b3898f7eed595f5272fcb0165d193ad</guid></item><item><title>Nepal announces interim leader, sets election date after week of violent protests</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/nepal-elections-date-interim-leader-gen-z-protests/lw4fj0gsu</link><description>Sushila Karki has become Nepal&amp;apos;s first woman prime minister, following two days of intense negotiations between the president, army chief and protest leaders behind the country&amp;apos;s worst upheaval in years, which left at least 51 people dead.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ef4f5549e3c7082a2fee06bfd86a5079</guid></item><item><title>Matildas captain Steph Catley scores Ballon d&amp;apos;Or nomination</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/matilda-named-in-2025-balloon-dor-shortlist/ujyi1uiez</link><description>Steph Catley is the sole Australian nominee among the 30 finalists for the 2025 Ballon d&amp;apos;Or Féminin, marking a milestone in Australian football.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e7d4d595901d79ce913b63908facc60</guid></item><item><title>How much you need for a comfortable retirement? | NAB latest to cut jobs</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/how-much-you-need-for-a-comfortable-retirement-nab-latest-to-cut-jobs/lvwy0rsjq</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with Marcus Bogdan from Blackmore Capital about the day's market action including why banks seem to be on a job cutting cycle, plus Stephnie Youssef speaks with ASFA CEO Mary Delahunty to find out how much money is needed in super to fund a comfortable…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">89a3a01df5e55e9682b60616942b381f</guid></item><item><title>Former Brazilian President jailed for 27 years | Midday News Bulletin 12 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/former-brazilian-president-jailed-for-27-years-midday-news-bulletin-12-september-2025/i92xlyog3</link><description>In this bulletin, Anthony Albanese is thankful for Pacific leaders support on Australia’s bid to host climate talks, a former Brazilian President is jailed for decades over an attempted election coup. And in sport, Greg Norman bows out of the LIV golf tour.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7249ed466b6ee80e5cae8f5e5c6e7e68</guid></item><item><title>Iran ambassador expelled, Trump’s military crackdown &amp; KPop Demon Hunters</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/iran-ambassador-expelled-trumps-military-crackdown-kpop-demon-hunters/p5uwy192i</link><description>In this episode: Australia punishes Iran after dramatic revelations in Canberra, Trump’s latest threats to set troops on more Democrat-held cities in the US, and a mass deportation pitch from the UK’s far right. Plus, why Venezuelan housewives are joining Maduro’s militia and South Korea’s…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2e5a966272c6518d1d483190fc488c3d</guid></item><item><title>I went to search a car for drugs while on duty. What happened next made me re-evaluate my life</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/insight/article/greg-was-run-over-while-on-duty-it-made-the-police-detective-re-evaluate-his-life/n45nsyhh9</link><description>Police recruitment drives in response to chronic shortages have led to more people applying to join their local force. But what were the factors that led to the shortages in the first place?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9049ee608eae75f0ac91bb2c95569d0a</guid></item><item><title>An atomic bomb, a missed train and an extraordinary story of survival.</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/an-atomic-bomb-a-missed-train-and-an-incredible-story-of-survival/toam4v7m2</link><description>Eighty years since the Hiroshima bombing a 96-year-old woman reflects on the twist of fate that saved her life, her journey as a &amp;apos;war bride&amp;apos; in Australia and the lasting lessons for a world facing fresh nuclear tensions.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">34ca1173dbce268d89ad5eb1e338c45e</guid></item><item><title>Muslim leaders call for more government action to mend &amp;apos;severely fractured relationship&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/muslim-leaders-call-for-government-action-after-islamophobia-report/vir8xta2w</link><description>Prominent Muslims have called on the Australian government to mend its &amp;quot;fractured&amp;quot; relationship with their community, as Anthony Albanese says he will &amp;quot;carefully consider&amp;quot; the special envoy to combat Islamophobia&amp;apos;s recommendations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7e0a58b0bfa8d8824c6c2e345ea28e9e</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Paradigm shift&amp;apos;: Over 2 million homes to get internet speed boost starting this weekend</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/paradigm-shift-over-2-million-households-to-get-internet-speed-boost-this-weekend/yun6p6kua</link><description>The free speed boost is one of the biggest changes to Australian internet in history, according to one expert.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6e4e40db6344bf6e5692f51b1208b2ac</guid></item><item><title>Bruce McAvaney on Australia&amp;apos;s emerging athletics &amp;apos;golden age&amp;apos; and the run that inspired us all</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australias-emerging-golden-age-and-the-run-that-inspired-us-all/qtxwgdtgj</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s &amp;quot;golden age&amp;quot; in athletics is gathering steam, esteemed sports commentator Bruce McAvaney says, as the World Athletics Championships gets underway.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">12469788e8cbbc9ab99a655b9d1b3dd5</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 3 Sep 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-3-sep-2025/rqbzuecm0</link><description>A daily 5-minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dc1e50f5913792e815ab35e44f2d7890</guid></item><item><title>$548.5 million: The price the government is willing to pay &amp;apos;to avoid a public trial&amp;apos; of robodebt</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/robodebt-class-action-compensation-whats-next-for-victims/yturl57q3</link><description>The robodebt class action settlement has been billed as the largest of its kind in Australian history. However, one expert argues it represents &amp;quot;accountability avoided&amp;quot;, leaving questions of misfeasance unanswered.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bb35343dd6e2c4f482035b0f9dc74135</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 1 Sep 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-1-sep-2025/c774abcmk</link><description>A daily 5-minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c9b80654f039a36f7b13f920703069c0</guid></item><item><title>Former Brazilian president Jair Bolsonaro sentenced to 27 years in jail for plotting coup</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/jair-bolsonaro-brazil-president-coup-conviction/g4yjsnf6c</link><description>The firebrand ex-president was convicted of plotting a coup after his 2022 election loss, and accused of acting &amp;quot;with the purpose of eroding democracy and institutions&amp;quot;.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d23e8b2153625ef3c78983ad7017de1e</guid></item><item><title>ARIA chart changes to bring diversity of artists - and is the RBA done with cutting interest rates?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/aria-chart-changes-to-bring-diversity-of-artists-and-is-the-rba-done-with-cutting-interest-rates/7qp73zdz6</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves speaks with ARIA CEO Annabelle Herd about the changes to the ARIA Charts will highlight diverse artists in the industry, Madeline Dunk from ANZ explains why she thinks the RBA may be done cutting interest rates, and Bryce Anderson from Morningstar goes through…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">29ae3a67eb9f2f8cb68d64e44190573c</guid></item><item><title>A surfer&amp;apos;s death in Sydney could stir up the shark net debate. So why are they so controversial?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sydney-surfer-shark-attack-death-shark-net-controversy/wv1hqtzrn</link><description>A fatal shark attack on Sydney&amp;apos;s Northern Beaches has come amid debates about the efficacy and environmental effects of shark nets. So do they actually protect swimmers, and what are the alternatives?</description><guid isPermaLink="false">17612a2e8210fdd34cd3db530ec9abe3</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Supermarket sweep: How making wise choices could save you money</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-supermarket-sweep-how-making-wise-choices-could-save-you-money/h0onz3s69</link><description>Making the switch from branded products to a store's home brand alternatives could save shoppers thousands of dollars each year at checkout, according to a financial comparison website. SBS's Cameron Carr has been finding out more from Compare the Market spokesman Phillip Portman.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">46c5b54df60d5bfd31cffb7f7816a7a9</guid></item><item><title>PM&amp;apos;s wardrobe malfunction and SUV diplomacy: What you missed from the Pacific summit</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/what-you-missed-from-the-pacific-islands-forum/87abvie53</link><description>Australia&amp;apos;s fossil fuel exports remain a source of tension as Pacific leaders double down on their support for a bid to co-host global climate talks.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4e8c889433678ad7787f91cfa68e8584</guid></item><item><title>Epstein fallout, Gaza crisis &amp; Japan’s far-right surge</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/epstein-fallout-gaza-crisis-japans-far-right-surge/m4budlv92</link><description>President Trump triggers MAGA mutiny over Epstein files, Japan’s far-right gains ground after an historic election upset, and pressure mounts on Israel as Gaza edges closer to famine. Plus, a climate court ruling shakes up global accountability, and New Delhi's diplomatic imposter.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7dd4be0b770d1eda5c7789d6d9c1e87e</guid></item><item><title>ANZ slashes 3,500 jobs, are there more to come?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/anz-slashes-3-500-jobs-are-there-more-to-come/jxdumykdc</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Gonçalves takes a closer look at ANZ's decision to cut 3,500 employees and 1,000 contractors and what it means for the sector with Nathan Zaia from Morningstar and Damien Boey from Wilson Asset Management.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">223c7b8b1e2de62d573cecc3428e0fb9</guid></item><item><title>ASX 200’s worst day since April; Australian economy grows faster than expected</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/asx-200s-worst-day-since-april-australian-economy-grows-faster-than-expected/xkhcq18co</link><description>The Australian sharemarket has experienced its worst single-day drop since April, with all 11 sectors finishing in the red. For more, Rena Sarumpaet spoke with Perpetual’s Head of Investment Strategy, Matt Sherwood. Plus, Australia’s GDP expanded by a larger-than-expected 0.6% in the June quarter.…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">76b3432d097b0c048c854c1813b1b733</guid></item><item><title>Twenty key seats to watch on at the election as the results roll in</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-marginal-is-your-electorate-and-what-are-the-key-seats-to-watch-on-election-day/629yh6b3v</link><description>Find your electorate and whether it&amp;apos;s a marginal seat by using SBS News&amp;apos; interactive map — you can also check whether it&amp;apos;s one of the key seats experts are watching.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">dd6fb6088642070a31f3f7a207dc2fe4</guid></item><item><title>Gob has been making rafts in his local river his whole life. It&amp;apos;s never made him sick until now</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-this-river-ended-up-with-arsenic-levels-three-times-higher-than-the-safe-limit/5r0buyf12</link><description>Several major rivers flowing across the border from Myanmar to Thailand have been contaminated with dangerously high levels of arsenic, threatening to cause a public health crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">0d5cbc117f5dd1db1f7bf8ce7fde711f</guid></item><item><title>Gob has been making rafts in his local river his whole life. It&amp;apos;s never made him sick until now</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/how-rare-earth-mining-is-destroying-vital-rivers/5r0buyf12</link><description>Several major rivers flowing across the border from Myanmar to Thailand have been contaminated with dangerously high levels of arsenic, threatening to cause a public health crisis.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">099299c6b157b78a58d625ca13a16916</guid></item><item><title>Diana lived in her car while battling cancer. A new housing initiative is offering hope</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/small-business-secrets/article/diana-lived-in-her-car-while-battling-cancer-a-new-housing-initiative-is-offering-hope/1hsxa1i5s</link><description>More women and girls are seeking help for homelessness in Australia, according to a recent study. Many are escaping family and domestic violence. A new project offers the possibility of home ownership.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b6b8fd30962f82b7d3db1eea8147007</guid></item><item><title>A 5-minute guide to the World Athletics Championships – and how to watch from Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/your-guide-to-2025-world-athletics-championships/p7wrafboj</link><description>Australia has kicked off one of its biggest track and field campaigns in history, with a record number of athletes in Tokyo to contest the 2025 World Athletics Championships.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">6857921f0cef4d27931a5efa26154bbe</guid></item><item><title>Zelenskyy returns to the White House, Netanyahu torches Albanese &amp; Xi visits Tibet</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/zelenskyy-returns-to-the-white-house-netanyahu-torches-albanese-xi-visits-tibet/iar43mh8n</link><description>In this episode, we cover Donald Trump's latest attempts at peace for Ukraine, and the growing ties between India and Russia. Also, the diplomatic row between Israel and Australia deepens. Plus, Xi Jinping visits Tibet and the White House embraces TikTok.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3e315f9407f3279054bf788e6450efd1</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Terrifying reality&amp;apos;: Islamophobia report handed down as envoy calls for &amp;apos;urgent&amp;apos; action</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/islamophobia-report-handed-down-as-envoy-calls-for-urgent-action/zo982rvwu</link><description>The special envoy to combat Islamophobia has released his report, finding Islamophobia is &amp;quot;pervasive&amp;quot; in Australia and has &amp;quot;skyrocketed&amp;quot; since the Hamas-Israel war erupted.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c0bbc6f1b5a92f8e3bb4538ad0de1044</guid></item><item><title>Federal government approves Woodside gas project extension, with some conditions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/federal-government-approves-woodside-gas-project-extension-with-some-conditions/goc08nvfr</link><description>The country&amp;apos;s largest gas project&amp;apos;s potential operating life has been extended to 2070.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a12ecbec94d2b938be29e759dfc967ac</guid></item><item><title>Spring season property hotspots &amp; reporting season fallout</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/spring-season-property-hotspots-reporting-season-fallout/u6jn8r0fh</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Goncalves speaks with Tim Lawless from Cotality Australia about the direction for home prices as the Spring selling season begins and to find out where the property hotspots are, plus Mathan Somasundaram from Deep Data Analytics takes a look back at the reporting season…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">823ecf0ba615002992542f409f091c8b</guid></item><item><title>The Trump Putin showdown, Palestinian Statehood gains ground &amp; Haiti's BBQ bounty</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/the-trump-putin-showdown-palestinian-statehood-gains-ground-haitis-bbq-bounty/tfa1d82kz</link><description>Donald Trump and Vladimir Putin face off for the first time in six years, with the future of Ukraine hanging in the balance. Anthony Albanese announces Australia will recognise a Palestinian state, sparking praise and condemnation. Plus, the Haitian gang leader with a US$5 million bounty on his…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">854343572fc7adcc80f276f7c47ebdd6</guid></item><item><title>When will we vote on the Voice to Parliament? We now know</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/when-will-we-vote-on-the-voice-to-parliament-we-now-know/1we5trvbp</link><description>We finally know when we&amp;apos;ll vote on the Indigenous Voice to Parliament. Here&amp;apos;s the day you&amp;apos;ll head to the polls.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">d9bb5c2353dc513ea6c205faf2a919c1</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Failed to apologise&amp;apos;: Ley sacks Price from Coalition frontbench over Indian migrant remarks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sussan-ley-sacks-jacinta-price-from-opposition-frontbench/2bjhqc3gi</link><description>Jacinta Nampijinpa Price has been dumped from the coalition frontbench after refusing to apologise for comments about Indian migrants.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">a5ca36d6c71c3938fd25ccebe1394194</guid></item><item><title>Two men charged over antisemitic incidents in Sydney | Evening News Bulletin 10 Sep 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/evening-news-bulletin-10-sep-2025/6t0hnqt2w</link><description>The Greens condemn what it calls a "tepid" response from the government to Israel's strikes on Qatar; the PM signs $100 million to help set up a Pacific Resilience Facility; in sport, Bolivia stun Brazil in a World Cup qualifier.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">03678123f3a0659bb68d0b1c5c13966e</guid></item><item><title>Former Virgin CEO’s $50m payday; &amp; is a US rate cut locked in?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/former-virgin-ceos-50m-payday-is-a-us-rate-cut-locked-in/l8f9hkzjz</link><description>Former Virgin Australia CEO Jayne Hrdlicka is collecting a $49.9 million pay packet, which includes 10 million shares, as revealed in the company’s annual report. For more on this and the ASX-200’s performance this week, Stephanie Youssef spoke with IG Markets analyst Tony Sycamore. Plus, US…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">926fab565460dcb2749e5787e0bab9e0</guid></item><item><title>Jacinta Nampijinpa Price dismissed from front bench role | Morning News Bulletin 11 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/morning-news-bulletin-11-september-2025/hv017srn0</link><description>Jacinta Price removed from Coalition frontbench; the European Commission calls for sanctions against Israel over its military campaign in Gaza; A-League great Bruno Fornaroli calls time on his career.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5b2a15f9dbb33d7a4aa289db791accc3</guid></item><item><title>PM Ishiba&amp;apos;s resignation plunges Japan into political uncertainty. Here&amp;apos;s what happens next</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/shigeru-ishibas-resignation-plunges-japan-into-political-uncertainty-as-leadership-race-looms/x6ajr5l8d</link><description>Since Shigeru Ishiba came to power in October 2024, his ruling coalition has lost its majority in both houses of parliament.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cc6dbc974d4d16e496a7659fffd5cc4e</guid></item><item><title>An Australian couple bought a French palace for $1.2m. Strangers are helping pay to restore it</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/dateline/article/an-australian-couple-bought-a-french-palace-for-1-2m-strangers-are-helping-pay-to-restore-it/yhko3767h</link><description>Palatial French estates are being snapped up by overseas buyers for less than a median-priced home in Sydney. But the initial outlay is usually just the start of long and expensive restoration journey. One Australian couple is funding their project in unique ways.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">f1f0196efa288448d47ab6bb196f5524</guid></item><item><title>Neo-Nazi Thomas Sewell given community work order for intimidating police officer</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/neo-nazi-thomas-sewell-found-guilty-of-intimidating-police-officer/nd7iwgt3o</link><description>Thomas Sewell was found guilty of intimidating a police officer over threats to &amp;quot;dox&amp;quot; him and his wife.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">e8d96eba1723ccfdcf64f6b855bcd877</guid></item><item><title>Gold and silver prices hit milestones &amp; ASX hit by ex-dividend stocks</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/gold-and-silver-prices-hit-milestones-asx-hit-buy-ex-dividend-stocks/77logsn0k</link><description>SBS Finance Editor Ricardo Goncalves speaks with Josh Gilbert from eToro to find out why gold prices hit a new record while silver reached a 14 year high, plus why the ASX fell as a number of companies traded ex-dividend.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">92b6528409b6e3cb0f3ceb139ac8c6e7</guid></item><item><title>Refugees, foreign students and 'boat people': What it's really like to migrate to Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sbs50-stories-of-migration-since-1975/w4o7q8wg5</link><description>As SBS celebrates 50 years of storytelling, we share the stories of those who made the at times perilous journey across the seas in search of freedom, safety and a sense of home.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7bae5ca5a05eba4b134ba244c5b95381</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Three years after the death of Mahsa Amini in Iran, what's changed?</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-three-years-after-the-death-of-mahsa-amini-in-iran-whats-changed/gn6snvk02</link><description>Dr Dara Conduit at the University of Melbourne explains the impact of the death in custody of Mahsa Jina Amini three years ago on women's rights in Iran today.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">40f0a02fa058d6a63a37c49475557849</guid></item><item><title>Sydney Marathon 2025: Records broken as Sifan Hassan, Hailemaryam Kiros win</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/sydney-marathon-2025-sifan-hassan-hailemaryam-kiros-win-titles/gsusgonxt</link><description>Dutch superstar Sifan Hassan and Ethiopia&amp;apos;s Hailemaryam Kiros have triumphed in the Sydney marathon as Kenyan legend Eliud Kipchoge battled to ninth.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">538665abcb422e0ae3130e53d71a8143</guid></item><item><title>After Australia&amp;apos;s economic surprise, here&amp;apos;s what could happen to your mortgage</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/after-australias-economic-surprise-heres-what-could-happen-to-your-mortgage/pl4mjloqq</link><description>Public holidays and the latest release of a video game console were all important elements in Australia&amp;apos;s recent GDP growth, something that might mean there may not be many interest rate cuts left to come.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">5ec63d565519799ed7afcc96fa470ba5</guid></item><item><title>Lifting caps from first home buyer scheme will help some but fuel wider price rise</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/lifting-caps-from-first-home-buyer-scheme-will-help-some-but-fuel-wider-price-increases/qufj0whee</link><description>The federal government will expand its Home Guarantee Scheme in October, lifting income and property caps to give first-time buyers greater access, but it will also fast-track price rises, a new analysis has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2ec3a25aa5c73604ea010b377fa16240</guid></item><item><title>'We got him': Authorities arrest a suspect in fatal shooting of Charlie Kirk</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/we-got-him-authorities-arrest-a-suspect-in-fatal-shooting-of-charlie-kirk/yb2y56vi5</link><description>A 22-year-old man has been arrested over the shooting death of Charlie Kirk at a Utah University. He's been identified as Tyler Robinson, a Utah resident who family members say had recently become more 'political' and increasingly vocal in his opposition to the conservative activist's ideas.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">c5b9492c38fe03283c54abc173f62c6e</guid></item><item><title>Lifting caps from first home buyer scheme will help some but fuel wider price rise</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/expanded-home-scheme-lifts-caps-but-risks-fuelling-price-rise/qufj0whee</link><description>The federal government will expand its Home Guarantee Scheme in October, lifting income and property caps to give first-time buyers greater access, but it will also fast-track price rises, a new analysis has found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">b1e36aab6f1de41d7d5bf5fcd6f3c098</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Envoy Aftab Malik on 'going to the roots' of Islamophobia in Australia</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-envoy-aftab-malik-on-going-to-the-roots-of-islamophobia-in-australia/z304cb4rk</link><description>The Special Envoy to Combat Islamophobia has handed down his long-awaited report, containing 54 recommendations to the federal government.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">3db018cc45a6c7dcdbceae83cb354483</guid></item><item><title>Anthony Albanese says shooting of Charlie Kirk &amp;apos;horrific&amp;apos; and world is &amp;apos;shocked&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/images-of-person-of-interest-in-charlie-kirk-shooting-released-as-150-000-reward-offered/hicmjuzm3</link><description>Other Australian politicians have also reacted to the fatal shooting of the American right-wing commentator. It comes as investigators in the US said they are searching for a &amp;quot;college-aged&amp;quot; person.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bfd7f9e2ee354c28997dbf71d22596f0</guid></item><item><title>Muslim leaders call for more government action to mend &amp;apos;severely fractured relationship&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/islamophobia-report-muslim-leaders-call-for-more-government-action/vir8xta2w</link><description>Prominent Muslims have called on the Australian government to mend its &amp;quot;fractured&amp;quot; relationship with their community, as Anthony Albanese says he will &amp;quot;carefully consider&amp;quot; the special envoy to combat Islamophobia&amp;apos;s recommendations.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">cb156927053370682e56d998d743a45b</guid></item><item><title>The simple shopping swap that could save you $4,000 a year</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/the-simple-shopping-swap-that-could-save-you-4-000-a-year/v30obn3he</link><description>A comparison group examined the cost of 20 staple items at two major supermarkets. Here&amp;apos;s what it found.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">00a0f1ae3c3076476213a122c781625b</guid></item><item><title>Xi’s 'new world order', Indonesia unrest &amp; Thailand’s political plight</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/xis-new-world-order-indonesia-unrest-thailands-political-plight/gf52cf61m</link><description>In this episode: China’s military parade and its guests of honour the US media has dubbed ‘the Axis of Upheaval’, protesters mobilise across Indonesia as parliamentary allowances trigger mass unrest. Plus, Thailand faces yet another political crisis while environmental concerns escalate across the…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">4a301c53679e2f46c08e8310db39c9bd</guid></item><item><title>Radiotherapy could save your life: dispelling the misconceptions</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/radiotherapy-could-save-your-life-dispelling-the-misconceptions/uno2r91al</link><description>Despite being a proven life-saving treatment, 1 in 5 Australians who need radiotherapy never receive it. This year, on September 7, the first-ever World Radiotherapy Awareness Day will be launched, and experts say it's an opportunity to dispel fears of the treatment.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">2be2c9a4a00462aa89c636361cd468ff</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Loved by everyone&amp;apos;: Shark attack victim remembered as community &amp;apos;keystone&amp;apos;</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/loved-by-everyone-sydney-shark-attack-victim-remembered-as-community-keystone/0xww0e922</link><description>Tributes are being paid to Mercury Psillakis, the 57-year-old victim of a fatal shark attack on Sydney&amp;apos;s northern beaches.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">bc780a6a738c4ba51a5b755e7069bf8a</guid></item><item><title>Does Putin really want Peace? Netanyahu’s plan to ‘conquer’ Gaza &amp; all quiet on the Korean front</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/does-putin-really-want-peace-netanyahus-plan-to-conquer-gaza-all-quiet-on-the-korean-front/4miggqg81</link><description>Another deadline to Vladimir Putin comes and goes without a ceasefire, as Donald Trump eyes a high-stakes meeting on Ukraine’s future. Benjamin Netanyahu’s reported plan to ‘conquer’ Gaza sparks an unprecedented backlash from current and former military chiefs, while Lebanon moves to disarm…</description><guid isPermaLink="false">7fb5f4c45f3ac7205eb5963cf1b95249</guid></item><item><title>SBS News in Easy English 4 September 2025</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/sbs-news-in-easy-english-4-september-2025/6tsull01j</link><description>A daily five minute news wrap for English learners and people with disability.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">ec2718b67b168f48fb689b8d3154b80e</guid></item><item><title>INTERVIEW: Cricketer Usman Khawaja on why he is calling on sporting bodies to consider banning Israel</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/podcast-episode/interview-cricketer-usman-khawaja-on-why-he-is-calling-on-sporting-bodies-to-consider-banning-israel/8q0qvuywq</link><description>Usman Khawaja says he raised the issue of imposing sanctions on Israel over its actions in Gaza during his meeting with Prime Minister Anthony Albanese.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">422348dd235b1a2ad21af885a71f1076</guid></item><item><title>&amp;apos;Like the Castle&amp;apos;: The Australian families who could lose farms in Trump&amp;apos;s rare earths push</title><link>https://www.sbs.com.au/news/article/australian-families-who-could-lose-farms-in-rare-earths-minerals-push/o3shp981l</link><description>In north-west Victoria, a David and Goliath battle is playing out between farmers and the rare earths mining industry which has been backed by state and federal governments as the world scrambles to extract key minerals.</description><guid isPermaLink="false">9724dc5ede0aef6038ef0e9aebce6151</guid></item></channel></rss>